<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>&lt;b&gt;One Schlock's Requiem&lt;/b&gt; is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher on English living in central Japan.</description><link>http://theschlock.com/</link><item><title>Vivillion Shiny Hunt</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Pokemon is filled with some unique evolution methods and forms across several species. Some may say that Vivillion is one of the more annoying Pokemon with its forms. But I think it was pretty interesting. It debuted as part of Pokemon X/Y, the first pokemon game on the Nintendo 3DS in 2013. Depending on the region of your game, a single certain form of Vivillion would be available out of a total of 18. There were 2 additionally forms released later as events, for a grand total of 20 forms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impetus was to connect and trade with people all over the world to get all of the forms, if you wanted them. But, because of this obtuse mechanic, they have not been available in any main game since. Two years ago, with the release of Pokemon Home, I decided to try and get all of the forms by doing trades and it didn't take me too long to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the release of Pokemon Scarlet/Violet in November, Vivillion had finally returned. However, only the &lt;b&gt;Fancy&lt;/b&gt; pattern (which was previously event only) was available in the game. All of the other forms were available in the game's code, but how could we get them? Things started to become slightly clearly when Scatterbug and Vivillion became available in Pokemon Go in December. Oh, we could just transfer them from Pokemon Go once Pokemon Home support came to Scarlet/Violet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to catch Scatterbug and Vivillion in Pokemon Go, you had to save Postcards received from Presents which you receive from Friends on your Friend's List from all over the world. If you saved 3 Postcards from a region, you'd get an encounter with a Scatterbug from that region. Evolve it to Vivillion to get that form. Some regions are more obscure than others, like Saudi Arabia and Hawaii essentially being their own regions, but it was not too tough to get them all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Vivillion Forms in Scarlet/Violet&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the release of Scarlet/Violet, connectivity between Pokemon SV and Pokemon Go had been hinted at with the new pokemon, Gimmighoul. Treasure Chest forms were available in Pokemon SV, while a separate exclusive Roaming form would be available in Pokemon Go. And, with the most recent &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qyfyd_t9mzs"&gt;Pokemon State of the Union&lt;/a&gt;, it was announced how you would do this and it had an extra benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to get Gimmighoul, you need to send a Postcard from Pokemon Go to Pokemon Scarlet/Violet. This gives you a Coin Purse in Pogo that works like an incense. Run the incense and Gimmighoul will spawn for the next 30 minutes. Additionally, every five days you'll get a Golden Lure. In order to evolve Gimmighoul, you need 999 coins, just like Pokemon SV. You get some by catching Gimmighoul, but you get a lot from Poke-stops with Golden Lures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, on the Scarlet/Violet side of things, whichever region was the origin of the Postcard determined which form of Vivillion would spawn over the next 24 hours. Now, it was possible to collect all of the Vivillion forms by yourself! AND, with shiny hunting specific pokemon SO SO easy in Pokemon SV, I decided that this would be my new goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Shiny Vivillion&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vivillion does spawn in the wild up in the north by the Fairy base. My route starts at where the Tera Sylveon spawns. I set down my pickup there, make a Bug Sandwich, and basically drive around in circles spawning and respawning Vivillions. Several other things spawn, too, which is annoying, but I quickly caught my first Shiny Vivillion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZAFRaU227K2dZq7_cHsxggkcvTfNmb09" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pattern of Vivillion's wings is identical to its non-Shiny form. The body is the only difference. It's pure white, rather than white and gray. It's difficult to notice at a glance, but when you are paying attention and now what to look for, it is noticeable enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can only send one postcard from Pokemon Go is a single day. However, you can connect multiple accounts and send multiple Postcards to Scarlet/Violet. I have two main accounts for Pokemon Go, plus an extra one that I only use for extra free stuff. So, I'm able to send 3 postcards in a single day. 18 regional forms with 3 postcards a day. That's only 6 days. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shiny Hunting is Pokemon SV still depends on random chance, but I can usually get a shiny to spawn within 30 minutes with a sandwich. If not? Just reset the game and try again. Just don't save after making a sandwich unless you get something you want to keep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got my first Shiny Vivillion on March 4th, and now only 2 weeks later, the collection is complete, including the whole evolution family, and a few extras that showed up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bCWUQT0Dko3Xk1BQmAKolXyf9fz-MBgQ" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See all the individual shiny catches in the gallery below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Remains&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the 18 regional forms and the base Fancy form, there are 19 total forms available out of a total of 20 in Pokemon SV. Actually, only the regional forms are available in Pokemon Go at the moment. Maybe when Pokemon Home gets an update to include Pokemon Scarlet/Violet, we'll get some way of getting the Fancy form in Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, it's unclear how the &lt;b&gt;Pokeball Form&lt;/b&gt; of Vivillion will be introduced. Previously, it was available through an event only. Although, it makes the most sense that they'd be available through an event in Pokemon Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe for this year's Go Fest, when you spin stops at the event, you'll get a gift, and the postcard for that gift will give you the Pokeball form of Vivillion. Then, transfer that to Scarlet/Violet, and get your Vivillion that way, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/vivillion-shiny-hunt</link></item><item><title>Website Revival</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the Spring of 2014, I had finally built the website I had always wanted. Using the Tapestry framework and my web development experience, I wrote a site that could host all of my blog content I had written over the years and be extensible enough to easily change and build whatever I wanted into it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t manually building pages anymore, like I had been when I first made my website in 2003. My blog content wasn’t orphaned on another server, like when I moved to Movable Type in 2005. And, I was no longer stuck within the constraints of someone else’s design, like when I moved to Wordpress in 2006. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With my new website, I had built everything from scratch, which gave me complete full control over everything, which gave me the freedom to do anything. It was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost, anyways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tapestry is a very powerful framework, but for my particular setup at the time, it often crashed. Tapestry ran in Java, so to deploy the site on the Internet, it needed to be run in Tomcat. Once running Tomcat would serve the pages to whomever requested them. But, every two or three days, something within Tapestry or Tomcat would cause the site to be unresponsive. To fix this, I would turn it off and turn it back on again. Not a lot of people actually visited my site, so I don’t think anyone noticed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost three years, things were pretty good. Though, as usual, my posting became less frequent and I stopped visiting my site as often as before. One day, when I power cycled my website, it was gone. There was nothing on my server. Apparently, a month or two prior, my web server had failed its migration. Well, whatever. All of my code was a mirror of what I had locally. I’ll just copy everything over again and start it up. Not so. My web server had also dropped Java and Tomcat support after this migration. No word about this at all. They just deleted all of my stuff, dropped support, but still billed me every month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I looked around a little bit for a new web server. I tried one service, but I couldn’t get the site running. I continued to look around, but Tomcat support had become expensive for some reason. Maybe demand had dropped. I had thought about using cloud servers with Google which would homogenize my Internet eco-system further, but that was also more expensive that what I wanted. Also, it took me a while to figure out how to do it, and I was getting no where.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the site was dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of months, I have been doing a lot of programming and using GitHub thanks to the Analogue Pocket. One day I saw that someone had “hosted” their blog on Github. Looking further, you could also have your web domain point to these pages and mask itself as a real website. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh shit. Could I do this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHub is not a webserver, so it can’t run anything on the backend. Any webpage it hosts, would have to be static. Despite my website running Tapestry, almost all of my content is static. Yes, it uses a database, and Yes, the server is generating pages. But, the result is always the same. Anything that was dynamically generated from the server, could be changed to a separate page or rewritten in Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had often thought that if I could simply make my website a huge mess of HTML pages, then I could easily find hosting and it would absolutely never crash or be inaccessible. And GitHub was answer, because not only could it host these html pages, but it could do it for free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take me long to find the command line program, WGET. When run, it will crawl through a website and save everything locally. It didn’t take me long to write a &lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/schlock-website/blob/master/src/generate_website.sh"&gt;terminal script&lt;/a&gt; to save my entire website in HTML into a GitHub directory that could push back to the Github to be hosted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were still some broken links, dynamic links that needed to be changed, and the image gallery that needed to be re-written. A few weeks later, those were all solved. I cleaned up some old posts, and removed some problematic ones from 15+ years ago. I'm also hosting images directly from Google Drive. Now, I’ve written a few new posts to cover some topics from the last year. There are still some posts that I haven't written yet. You can see that progress &lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.io/issues/2"&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think everything is good enough to consider my website reopened. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first opened theschlock.com in August of 2003, so in just a few more months, it'll be the 20-year anniversary. My life has changed considerably since then, from college, to studying abroad, to working as a software developer, to moving to Japan and working in public schools, to now working in a private school. It's interesting to be able to look back and recall my thoughts during these times.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/website-revival</link></item><item><title>Application for Permanent Residence</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years ago, I moved to Japan. I didn’t necessarily intend to stay for more than a year or two, but I loved living here and loved teaching students. Teaching had become the most rewarding job I’ve done in my life, so I didn’t want to leave, and it never felt like my time in Japan was complete. Now, this is where I live. A town full of students or parents of students that I’ve helped teach for more than 10 years. And full of friends and connections that I’ve made over the years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that 10 years has passed, I can apply for Permanent Residence in Japan. In simple terms, Permanent Residence means that I no longer have to renew a work VISA after 3 years and I can buy or build a house. But to me, it means that I’m further established as a part of Japan and don’t intend to leave. It’s the near-equivalent to a Green Card in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying for Permanent Residence is not a simple process of filling out a couple of forms. There are many parts to prove your legal employment, payment of taxes, and contribution to Japan. I spent about a month working on the application back in October, only to have it rejected because I hadn’t lived here a complete 10 years yet. Now, 4 months later, my application is complete and it ended up being 47 pages long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VKDo29AZMTz6NCGxvFXU_efaE_egb_tR"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VKhKluWm_6qOqFGcGBfjZFrvs6FRlj6m"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so long that I wrote a Table of Contents describing everything that I included, and sectioned everything into different folders to make it as easy as possible for them to see what I’ve included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;b&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1.      &lt;b&gt;Application for Permanent Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;b&gt;Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3.      &lt;b&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;6.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;7.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;8.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10.    &lt;b&gt;Passport Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.    &lt;b&gt;Residence Card Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;12.    &lt;b&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;13.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Contributions to Japan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;14.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;15.    &lt;b&gt;Application Oath&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The instructions for how to apply for permanent residence can be found on the government Immigration website. They are written in &lt;a href="https://www.isa.go.jp/en/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;. My table of contents follows the list of required materials from that page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though, they have an English version that doesn’t necessarily mean it’s easy to figure out what to do. These instructions are machine translated, and you still need to understand what they’re saying in Japanese because of the specific names for forms, and the specific departments and locations you need to visit. There’s a lot of running around involved getting all the correct documents, so I have detailed everything I did to build my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;手数料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is not required when you submit your application, but it will be required after your application is successful. You must fill out the Payment form and attach an 8000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; revenue stamp to it. Revenue stamps can be purchased from the post office. Obviously, if you’ve been in Japan long enough, you already know how to do this from renewing your VISA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the payment form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application for Permanent Residence &amp; Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;永住許可申請書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;写真&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The first document is the application itself. Again, from renewing a VISA, all the same information is here with the addition of a short version of why you want permanent residence, work history, and guarantor information. For my reason, I wrote "I wish to obtain permanent residence to continue teaching in Japan indefinitely and continue my study of kendo and Japanese culture to further enrich myself." It sounds like a lofty reason, but I have fully explained it in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the application form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll need a 40mm x 30mm photo attached to your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;理由書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perhaps the part of this application that will take the longest is writing about why you want permanent residence in Japan. My short version stated that I wish to teach in Japan indefinitely and continue to learn about Japan, but those ideas are weak unless there is proof. In total, I wrote 3 pages about my time over the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started with detailing my current responsibilities and accomplishments working at my high school: supporting English teachers in class, leading English writing classes, being an assistant Homeroom teacher, leading classes to prepare students for studying abroad, training students for speech contests and winning them, and teaching foreign exchange students Japanese language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I detailed my accomplishments and responsibilities working in public elementary and junior high schools as part of the JET Programme, such as supporting English classes and training students for speech contests, but also volunteering in town for English conversations classes supporting the hospital and library, developing summer English camp and other events for students, and developing a full English curriculum for elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I detailed my responsibilities as a Regional Prefectural Advisory supporting other ALTs in my region and the prefecture by developing our biannual skills conferences and leading lectures and discussions about lesson planning and ideas, as well as lead monthly meeting for the ALTs in my town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I closed my statement of reason with my contributions to the kendo federation in my town. I wrote about how I joined students in their club activities and practiced kendo, what I learned from doing kendo both personally and professionally, and eventually reaching the rank of 3-dan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 pages might have been too much for a statement of reason, but I wanted to completely show everything noteworthy that I’ve done in Japan. It was very direct and unemotional, focusing on the facts. My approach to writing the statement was very similar to writing a resume for an application. Overall, I don’t think the statement has to be completely emotionless, but I don’t think it should be the main focus of the argument. Show, don’t tell, as I say to my students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though I wrote all this information in English, I had to rewrite everything in Japanese, too. I had some help with that. I included both English and Japanese versions of my statement in my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分関係を証明する次のいずれかの資料（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I am not Japanese, so this was not required for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Whenever you move somewhere in Japan, you must register at the town hall so it has a complete and up-to-date record of all of its residents. The application for permanent residence requires a print of this record. It was easy to get from my town’s registrar by filling out a request document and paying 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for them to print the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has information, such as when you moved to town, current address, previous addresses, nationality, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In addition to proving that you live somewhere, you also need to prove that you work somewhere. This was pretty easy for me to get since my school is private and not that big. For a larger organization or a government organization, it might take some time for your request to go open the chain and for the document to come back down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just went to the office and they created a document that proved my employment. Depending on whichever company you work for, it may be an official document or it may not. I think it just needs to include a statement saying you work there as well as information that can be contacted later. My school/company just made up an official looking document with all the correct information on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;直近（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）の申請人及び申請人を扶養する方の所得及び納税状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Things start to get more complicated, as a single piece of paper proving your employment isn’t enough. Of course, you need to show that you’ve been paying taxes on the income that you’ve earned. And also show that you’ve been doing it for at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These documents include the &lt;I&gt;Kazei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;I&gt;Nozei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt;. Both documents translate as either Tax Certificate or Taxation Certificate, so looking at the English information about this section may not be helpful. Overall, the &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details how much taxes you had to pay and what taxes you had to pay on your income within a given year. The &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details the amount of taxes you still owe for a given year. Essentially, &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; is like an itemized bill, and &lt;I&gt;Zozei&lt;/I&gt; is the receipt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each document you’ll need for 5 years. For my town, I had a single &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate for each year. For the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate, each year could be written on the same document. For each document, for each year, it cost 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. So for all the documents, my bill would’ve been 3000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;I&gt;update&lt;/I&gt;, when I initially turned in my application, I forgot to get 5 years for the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate. I was able to turn in my application, but I needed to mail in the correct form within two weeks. They gave me an envelope and a sheet that described the document I was missing. Another problem, though: my town only keeps the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate up to 4 years, instead of the 5 years they wanted. I called them, and they said 4 years was fine. So, my bill was actually 2700&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for these documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally! There’s another version of the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate that is required. Besides the Tax Record office in city hall, I went to my town’s official Tax Office. Requesting the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate from them shows them I’ve paid all debts and taxes across all government departments and agencies, as well as never missed any payment for any bills or loan. This document cost 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; to print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, to these tax documents, I had to include a photo of my bank book that proved I was getting paid the correct income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, for this section, I included the following documents:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt;- Kazei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - Nozei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書（未払いの税金がないことを証明するためのパート&lt;/span&gt;3&lt;span class='ja'&gt;）&lt;/span&gt;- Nozei Cert proving no upaid taxes&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;預貯金通帳（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo proving income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;8.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の公的年金及び公的医療保険の保険料の納付状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now that I had shown that I am legally employed, getting legally paid, and responsibly paying taxes on my legal income, I need to show that I’m paying into either my company’s pension or the government’s pension for at least two years. Also that I have health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section was somewhat difficult to follow. Initially, I just took a photo copy of my annual pension report that I had gotten in mail, but (&lt;I&gt;update!&lt;/I&gt;) apparently that wasn’t enough. A few days after I turned in my application, I got a letter in the mail requesting another form. The form they wanted detailed all of my pension payments, and each pension that I’ve contributed to. It was called the &lt;I&gt;Hihokenja Chousho Shoukai Kaitou-hyou&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt; or the “Insurance Record Inquiry Report,” I think? I’m not sure why it says insurance when its about pensions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get this form, I had to go to my town’s Pension office and request these forms. Prior to going to the office, I had some co-workers give them a call to make sure I was getting the right forms, and they were able to prepare everything for me before I arrived. It turned a possible 40-minute wait into 5 minutes. This document was also 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at this document, I’ve contributed into a government pension when I worked for the city as a teacher, and I’ve contributed to a private pension I have with my current job. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter wanted me to include receipts from any contributions to the government’s individual pension service, but I never did that, so I didn’t have any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the health insurance card, I just took a photo of it and blacked out the account number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, this is what I included from this section:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ねんきん定期便（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;健康保険被保険者証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;9.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人又は申請人を扶養する方の資産を証明する次のいずれかの資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the next part, I had to show all of Japanese financial assets. At minimum, I had to take photo copies of my bank statements to show how much money I have in Japan. I don’t have a house, so I didn’t have anything to show there. I do have a car, but I didn’t include any proof of that. Maybe I should have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Passport Photo and Residence Card Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人のパスポート（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の在留カード（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I included photo copies of my passport and residence card with my application, but this is not really necessary. When you turn in your application, you’ll need to also show them both of these, and they can take a photo copy themselves, at this time. I included these to save time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;12.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証に関する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A current Japanese citizen needs to vouch for who I am, what I stand for, and state that I would make a contribution to Japan by becoming a Japanese permanent resident. This person should be someone you know pretty well, and have a good relationship with. My principal at school has always sponsored my VISA, as well as other documents that required official clearance, so he was an easy choice as a guarantor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They need to fill in the guarantor form and prove who they are. For my guarantor, we included the following:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証書&lt;/span&gt; - the guarantor application&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証&lt;/span&gt; - a photo copy of their ID (driver’s license, in this case)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of employment, wherever they work.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of tax payments. (&lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt; - proof of residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the guarantor form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Japanese)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Contributions to Japan&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;13.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;我が国への貢献に係る資料（&lt;/span&gt;※&lt;span class='ja'&gt;ある場合のみで結構です。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is the last meaty section of the application. For this section, I included my letters of recommendation and other certificates and awards of accomplishments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I had 3 recommendation letters: one letter from the principal, one letter from the head of our English department, and one letter from head of the Kendo federation in my town. Each letter of recommendation talked about the contributions that I made to my school and kendo in town, and talked about why they think I should be awarded permanent residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional documents that I included were proof of things mentioned in either my Statement of Reason or their Letters of Recommendation. I included a photo of my kendo license showing participation for 10 years, my 3-dan diploma, and certificates of participation for 3 years in the international budo conference. I also included a photo of my driver’s license to show that not only do I have a license, but maintaining a perfect and safe driving record to be awarded a 5-year gold license.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, here were my documents for this section.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from principal)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from head of English)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from Kendo Federation)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo License Photo&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;段免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo 3-dan Diploma&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;国際武道文化セミナー&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;修了証&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;（&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt; - International Budo Conference particpation&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo of Gold Driver’s License&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;14.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分を証する文書等（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’m not Japanese, so I did not need to do this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if this one is proof of ancestry or identity, or what the difference is between part 4 above. For one of these, there is some kind of official family document Japanese people have that shows all of their registered family members, and you need to include a photo copy of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application Oath&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;15.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;了解書　&lt;/span&gt;１&lt;span class='ja'&gt;通&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The final document required is signing the application oath form. By signing this, you agree that if anything information within the application changes over the next 4 to 6 months, you must notify immigration about these changes and update your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Complete!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VNEi30qT4tesov-EG7rpGUiiCti8nXDi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VNXzqzhPUCLQLOmmK2tMM4R-Qry6Xyye"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s everything. It doesn’t really seem like all that much once I finished making everything and putting it together. However, a lot of the time spent on the application is figuring out exactly what is required and where to go. The tax and pensions details are pretty tricky. I think my situation is pretty easy because I’ve only had the one job in the last 5 years, and the job is run by a professional organization. I also don’t have a house. Although, getting those documents probably aren’t too tough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 13th, I drove up north to Toyama and turned in my application at Toyama Branch Office of the Nagoya Regional Immigration Bureau. A long time ago, I figured out that very few people actually go to this branch office, so the wait time is never more than 5 minutes. In Gifu, wait times can be as long as 45 minutes. And in Nagoya, a friend of mine waited for an hour and a half once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the clerk instantly noticed one probably with my application (the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate not being 5 years), so I had to submit that afterward. I also got a letter in the mail on February 17th about the pension document. But, they accepted my application, and I’ve mailed those requested document as soon as I could. All documents were submitted as of February 21st, and I have not received any more letters about any more problems.  I think it’s all good!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically these application can take up to six months to be completely reviewed and responded to, but the clerk mentioned that it may only take three months to be complete. Over the last three years, thanks to Covid, the number of people moving to Japan has significantly decreased because the government shut down travel.  Previously, my VISA application would take 4 weeks to get approved, but it only took a week last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, by May, I’ll get the postcard in the mail to come back down and get my card. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/permanent-residence</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Extras</title><description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent release of Capcom CPS2 for the Analogue Pocket, there are a few more games that run on the current version of the core that don't have files included. This is true with a few others cores as well. I have collected all of the extra files and code edits in a single GitHub repository, available below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-extras"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-extras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 main collection of files, which are for (1) Capcom CPS2, (2) Donkey Kong (and Radar Scope), and (3) Pang. You can read the descriptions of each of the additions on Github. It'll have the most recent information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bJ2JCiViucmh4JBnU78mY_aA-264DQFv"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bJOftCi0iQlzqTh8Nlh4PuHvKJRj3zMj" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-extras</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Level 50</title><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2020, Pokemon Go announced that you’d finally be able to go beyond the level 40 cap all the way up to level 50. I started playing Pokemon Go in the beginning in 2016, but I didn’t really seriously start playing it until 2018, and I started a second account and played them both at the same time. My primary account was ahead of my secondary, but it didn’t take long for it to catch up and have pokemon teams just as powerful. After a few months, both accounts were essentially mirrors of each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2020, my primary account was able to hit level 40, but my secondary account still lagged behind.  In order to reach level 40, you need a total of 20 million XP in the game. I think my primary was at 25 million at that point? And my secondary may have been at 18 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the increased level caps set, you’ll now need a total of 176 million XP to reach level 50. In fact, the gap between level 49 and level 50 alone with 30 million XP. With these requirements and my current progress, I resigned myself that it would take years upon years to actually get there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it only took 2 years and a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - Jan 29th&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Voh41tVx137zribxBIZ7IHX28VfR4Rx9" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - Jan 31st&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W-bgKltUU-xFPCa-UyamC4kuzZs945lY" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both of my accounts hit level 50 last week after a long 7 months of being stuck on level 49.  In addition to needed XP to gain a level, you also have unique level requirements, like hatching some amount of eggs, or defeating some amount of rocket members. Level 49 requires you land 1000 excellent throws on Pokemon, which is very time consuming and annoying if you don’t manually play so often. I was able to grind them out with the most recent Electric event, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, if it took me more than two years prior to 2021 to gain 20 million XP, how was I able to get more than 150 million in just two years? Overall, 3 main factors contributed to my XP, but a few other things also changed how I played.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;XP Gains&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, as the level cap was raised, so was the XP you gain for doing various things in the game. Catching Pokemon gave you a little more. Spinning stops gave you a little bit. Defeating Raid bosses gave you a little more. And, most notably, excellent throws now gave you 1000xp.  Before, I think it was 200xp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, additionally, evolving Pokemon now gave you 1000xp, too. Throughout the weeks, as I caught a lot of Pokemon, if I could evolve them, I would put them into their own group. There are many Pokemon in the game, and many of these Pokemon are not useful in battles. Because of this, I’d just throw them away to make room to catch more. But, if I have a lot of candy for those Pokemon, may as well make them useful by evolving them for the XP. When you use a Lucky Egg, you’ll get double XP for the next 30 minutes. AND! I logged into a single account using both of my phones. I could evolve double the amount of Pokemon and get double the amount of XP. &lt;b&gt;In 30 minutes, I could get about 750 thousand XP&lt;/b&gt;. I caught enough Pokemon that I could do this every 2 or 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, the absolute best way to get XP in the game is through friendships. After 7 days, 30 days, and 90 days, you’ll increase your friendship level for 10 thousand, 50 thousand, and 100 thousand XP. Use a Lucky Egg to double it. Making friends in Pokemon go wasn’t easy to begin with, but it became very easy when they introduced Remote Raids. Other people built match making apps where you friend each other to do raids. After hosting MANY MANY raids, I continue to send gifts to people and increase friendships. Every 2 or 3 weeks when I did evolves, I would get the XP from friendships, too. After one of these sessions, I would routinely make around 1.5 million. One night, I made more than 5 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Play Style&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those were specific things I did to significantly increase my level, but overall, my play style is much different than it was prior to 2021 and the game has changed a lot, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main way my play style changed was using these two things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W_EZqdLdJSsa3kK6IcJSsYo47pn0MuoG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pokeball Plus was released in 2018 with the release of Let's Go Pikachu / Eevee, and meant to be used as a controller, but you could also connect it to Pokemon Go. When connected it will automatically spin stops for you. Also, when you're near a Pokemon you can click the button to try to catch it. Well, if you buy those rubber protectors above and shove a coin or two over the button, the button will automatically be pressed down and it will automatically catch a Pokemon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With these two Pokeballs, I can turn on Pokemon Go, turn on the Pokeballs, and it will automatically capture Pokemon as I drive around town. This is an amazing efficient way of getting a lot of Pokemon very quickly and catching a lot of Pokemon that I wouldn't have caught otherwise. It's not a 100% catch rate, but it's still doing a lot more work than I would have to do manually, and it frees me up to focus on driving and moving around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, the radius that allows you to spin stops was increased and the overall number of pokemon that spawn has increased, too. I'm catching far more Pokemon than I ever had before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Level History&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn't take too long for both of my accounts to go through level 41, 42, 43, etc. Once I hit the mid-40s, I would take about a month or two or three to make it to the next level before I finally hit level 49. Each time you gain a level past 40, you have the option of saving your stat sheet, so I saved all of these images when I could.  Here are my past few levels as a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - June 12th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Vo0E5E5vv9ffNPvtlMta7u-4w7UC9yJI" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - June 16th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VzNnaQlR_6_YhK3wjgyyJQxqBkd5qimU" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - March 29th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VroWQwXYHuRNJs0oGjNs3BQfeuPGFABf" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - May 7th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W034kpm_3v3-Y_GHdHJCdfE796x6UM31" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - Dec 25th 2021&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Vp3H4Ck8Xcd3OwZXjRk2BbXm9bnx9Tff" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - Feb 26th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VucrH3Z5v8PNr61sbVQ24lzhQEEAdwml" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;End Game&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe they'll increase the level cap again in the future, but I doubt it. There's no real benefit of having your character reach level 50 compared with level 40. Once you hit level 35, you can boost your individual Pokemon to level 50, so it doesn't matter what level you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been playing Pokemon Go more casually and only focusing on certain events. Part of the reason it took me 7 months to gain a level was because I was barely playing the game. It's always fun to explore around town playing Pokemon Go, but with one less goal overall, it is one less reason to play, and that's a good thing. I can focus on other stuff instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-level-50</link></item><item><title>Car Mileage</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Every 2 years in Japan, cars must go through a vehicle inspection called &lt;I&gt;Shaken&lt;/I&gt;. This is to ensure that the cars are still safe to drive and that they haven't been illegally modified. It's usually costs at least $1000, which is annoying, but it's even more annoying when you have a bunch of repair costs tacked on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in Japan, I had to buy a car because public transportation up in the mountains was not feasible. The car mechanic in town had a pretty good deal on a 2004 &lt;b&gt;Subaru R2&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1baxsQ1xqYj34o4wfQ7QZDK_ukrb5TiWX"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bg8coJD2s64nqNm6st_rcfK4WvQyB9OE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Subaru R2 is a Kei car, denoted by its yellow plate. Kei cars are smaller and have smaller engines. This also means they get some pretty great gas mileage.  I bought the car in 2013, but as &lt;I&gt;Shaken&lt;/I&gt; loomed in 2021, the bottom plating had begun to erode away and it was no longer road-worthy. My mechanic information me that the repairs would be too much, and I should buy a new car. I had a bunch of money saved up from stimulus checks and not traveling due to lockdown, so it wasn't too bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My mechanic and I went through a bunch of cars on the open market, and I finally settled on a 2017 &lt;b&gt;Daihatsu Mira ES&lt;/b&gt;. I wanted to continue owning a Subaru, but they discontinued their line of Kei cars, and Daihatsu has purchased their designs. The Mira is a slight evolution of the R2 mixed with Daihatsu designs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bRQVmZLC0ekZuBuUgGiYVPljcdCRq51d" &gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1beIA0E86tyfPouYCdPxF5pB85zdxF36z" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went with Red to try and set myself apart from the conformity of all the White, Off-White, and Grey cars of Japan. Nobody likes colors in their cars over here. It's still not completely unique, though, as the Mira ES is one of the most popular Kei cars on the road. I think that's good because it'll be easy to find replacement parts in the future if stuff breaks. Also the mechanic can easily figure out how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, and I've finally made the final payment on my car. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Car Mileage&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever I pay for gas, I've gotten in the habit of writing down the Odometer on the receipt in order to calculate my own gas mileage. These receipts pile up, and I eventually take all of the data and enter it into spreadsheets in Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bTBbMdmDuzkUiPbtNXqeah42jaE9jgtU"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bXmI_ITqQwTtFXDLaB8EeeJ0ZlGcLRQk" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bOCRexVfP4uhAKUnvW1uN3dTpNPJTJL7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bPSv8J0QKV1konCC4SrFKLu3YsJOJflT" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those are both a year's worth of receipts. One pile is from 2020. The other pile is from 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the 8 years I owned my Subaru R2, I drove it 105,000 kilometers. I took some roadtrips to Hiroshima, Kyoto, and Chiba. Many times I drove to Tokyo, too. Throughout its life, it had an average of 32.93 or 33.67 mpg, after conversions from liters and km. Towards the end, it started losing some of its mpg, and after Covid started, I was really only driving around town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the full stats on my &lt;b&gt;Subaru R2&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1jEUeqESvioxxYmGwsYPkDsx453hCRjZDRJQlesGGBvI"&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/1jEUeqESvioxxYmGwsYPkDsx453hCRjZDRJQlesGGBvI &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have continued to do gas accounting with my &lt;b&gt;Daihatsu Mira ES&lt;/b&gt;. Here are its stats:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1FLFwmXzWKFbDLktdGgCvOMgRo9nMpoRom_beND6gmcE"&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/1FLFwmXzWKFbDLktdGgCvOMgRo9nMpoRom_beND6gmcE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Gas Cost&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March 2022, the war in Ukraine began and gas prices began to climb in the United States. People were paying as much as $70 for a tank of gas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not so much in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the whole year of 2021, I spent 97390&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on gasoline. In 2022, I spent 104654&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on gas. It did go up, but only by 7000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. In fact, if you wanted to go further with it, the exchange rate for Yen to Dollars tanked after the war started. If you convert this to dollars, I paid $881 in 2021 and only $792 in 2022. It's $90 less, in this case. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparatively, I bought 600 liters in 2021 and 603 liters in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/car-mileage</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Platform Images</title><description>&lt;p&gt;We're now up to 60 cores released for the Pocket from 9 different developers. The most visible front-facing part of these cores is the Platform information and image. This includes how cores are sorted in the openFPGA menu, the titles of the core in the menu, and the image that appears when selected. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some core information is slightly inconsistent with others, so I've been rewriting Platform information on my own and making new images as well. I made in initial release back in November covering some cores to make them consistent with others. But now I've finished making a complete image set that covers all currently released cores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bAmRyu5hmpWepA81nz-qZR82ifVVJ2zd"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bAmaBh0694uONCfLk-tORKL89yqNeFfo" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Arcade Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For each of the Arcade core, I've tried to make an image like the original marquee for the Arcade cabinet. Usually these images are available, and it only takes 5 minutes to make the image. But, for some Arcade games, those images can be hard to find in good quality. Often too, if I do get a good image, the original artwork looks lame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been recreating many of these images using key art from officially marketing at the time. I put the image on the canvas and try to make it fit. Often I need to blend things around, move the title and other things in the background for a good composition. Now, I tend to spend around an hour of two making an image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are some Arcade cores that can run multiple noteworthy games since manufacturers often reused their boards for other games. Later still, some game companies made board that would specifically run multiple games. Images for those cores are different than just a simple marquee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view them all here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/blob/main/image_overview_arcade.md"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../image_overview_arcade.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are some of my favorites that I spent some time on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/xevious.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtcps1.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/radarscope.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtcps2.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtexed.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/tecmo.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Home Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;People had like my images, but some people complained that my image set wasn't complete. Thus, I created a "Home" image set to complement my Arcade images. Home would include cores for Consoles, Handhelds, and Computers. Technically, handhelds aren't specifically made for the home, but I think this monicker is pretty descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really liked &lt;a href="https://github.com/terminator2k2/Analogue-Pocket-Core-Art"&gt;Terminator2k2&lt;/a&gt;'s Image set which just had the logos of the systems, but I needed to do something else to distinguish my set. I got the idea when I started looking at old ads for consoles that showed off their game libraries. Also on Twitter, many people like to post a smattering or a pile of game boxes when they have a large haul from a shopping spree. I thought that I should try and do that. Games are the most important thing for any console or handheld after all. They should be displayed front and center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I already had a bunch of box art downloaded thanks to my &lt;a href="/pocket-utils"&gt;Pocket Utils&lt;/a&gt; project, so I made a collage of them in photoshop, added some perspective, shrunk down to the correct size, and color-corrected some things to make it look alright in grayscale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/snes.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/ng.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/nes.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/genesis.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think they turned out pretty good. I think it gives a great sense of the number of options you have available for each platform. They may be a bit overwhelming and gaudy though since the Analogue Pocket prides itself on minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view them all here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/blob/main/image_overview_home.md"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../image_overview_home.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Unreleased Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is still lots to look forward for the Analogue Pocket in the future. The MiSTer is another FPGA device that has been around much longer than the Analogue Pocket, and there are hundreds of cores that have been created. All cores available for the Analogue Pocket today are ports of these cores. Because of this, it's easy to see a roadmap for future cores to be released on the Pocket. In particular, core developers &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/jotego/posts"&gt;Jotego&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengateware"&gt;Open Gateware&lt;/a&gt; (aka Boogerman) have a wealth of cores they plan to bring to the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've worked ahead quite a bit so when new cores are released, I don't have to spend that afternoon making the image. It's already done, and I can quickly make a new release of Platform Images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some images for possible future cores:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jthcastle.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/galaxian.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jtmx5k.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/tropicalangel.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jtcps3.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/druaga.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view all of these images here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/tree/main/_unreleased"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../_unreleased&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As these cores get released, these images are moved into their released folders, so hopefully this category will be zero someday.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-platform-images</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Utils</title><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month, the Analogue Pocket has continued to be an absolute monster. The Sega Genesis is now available. The Nintendo Entertainment System is now available. Sega GameGear is available, too. And there have been many cores of 1980s Arcade games released, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's starting to get unwieldily, so I've created a collection of programs to help me organize and process games so they can be played on the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-utils"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-utils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been working on this pretty solidly for the past three weeks, and I think it's finally feature finished. The GitHub repository has straight forward information of how each process is set up and what exactly each process does. But, overall…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pocket Utils is a collection of scripts and programs that do several things, including the following: (1) Process MRA files and Create Arcade Roms, (2) Create Library Images for sorted Games, and (3) Update Platform information for cores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Process MRA Files&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Multi-Arcade Machine Emulator, or MAME, on computer standardized how to emulate arcade games. When ripping games from their original boards, each component had their own file, and everything was put together in a zip file. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FPGA emulation of arcade games doesn't like this. The chip wants direct read access to the data it wants and unzipping a file in memory is extra useless overhead. Thus, the idea of a MRA file was introduced. A MRA file contains specific instructions on how each piece of the arcade board can be assembled into a single ROM file. This file is not compressed and allow free access to all the data the FPGA wants. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A separate program is required to process these MRA files, though. I use this &lt;a href="https://github.com/nullobject/mra-tools-c"&gt;MRA Tool&lt;/a&gt; found in NullObject's GitHub. When an arcade core is released for the Analogue Pocket, it'll come with MRA files to create ROMs from ZIP files of arcade components. You must get the arcade ROM zips, process the MRA file in the program giving it the zip files, and then place the generated ROM into the core's folder on the Analogue Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of steps to getting this to work, and many arcade cores released for the Analogue Pocket play multiple games. Some releases come with 10 or more games. In fact, arcade systems like Capcom CPS1 and CPS2 have as many as 300 variants of their games. Doing all of this manually is not feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This program solves this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put all of your MRA files in the to-be-processed directory. Run the program. It'll attempt to download any and all ZIP files required to make the arcade rom, and store them locally. If the Arcade ROM is successfully generated, it'll copy it to the correct directory on the Pocket, and also copy the MRA file to the Pocket, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it can't find the ZIP files online, you can manually search for them and put them in your local store. If a ROM was already generated, it'll copy over the MRA file anyway. If the MRA file is already there, it'll copy it to a duplicate directory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Standard games, everything works really well and there are almost never any problems. Problems usually only come up when trying to generate bootlegs or hacks of roms. Those often require extra steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Create Library Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most appealing features of the Analogue Pocket is the Library feature. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something I've never liked about using emulators is having to choose the games I want to play from a list. It's so sterile and clinical. The Super Nintendo Mini was so amazing because of its visual presentation. You had a line games presented with their box art. And you could visually choose the game you wanted to play by selecting that box art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Library feature of the Analogue Pocket was just that. It gave you a visual list of all your games to select from. Further still, you could organize all of your games in Playlists. This was promised in Analogue's Tweet about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/analogue/status/1449389698493861888"&gt;Analogue OS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, the Analogue Pocket has an internal list of game data but it doesn't have an images. Early on, you could download an image pack that gave you all the title screens for every game. But I don't want title screens. I want box arts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took a little while to figure out, but the Analogue Pocket uses a CRC hash of the file to reference which image is uses in the Library. If you have a correctly sized PNG file, you can run it through &lt;a href="https://github.com/DerTolleEmil/AnaloguePocketLibraryImageConverter"&gt;DerTolleEmil&lt;/a&gt;'s Image Converter and it'll give you a BIN file. Put this bin file in the correct folder named with the CRC hash, and it'll use this image in the Library.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, my program goes a bit further with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In each of the folders for Consoles and Handhelds on the Analogue Pocket, I have the ROMs that I like sorted into genre folders. My initial "CreatePocketEntries" program will collect all of these games in my database. "CreateLibraryImages" will look at every game in my database and attempt to download the box art image from &lt;a href="https://github.com/libretro-thumbnails/libretro-thumbnails"&gt;LibRetro&lt;/a&gt; on Github. With this image, my program will resize it to the correct dimensions for the Pocket, convert the PNG image to BIN, name it correctly, and copy the file to the System folder on the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, when using the Library, the image matches the box art. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X410RG1-exlXvJu5KNhbrzNSjsj5CYYE"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X4zNYo7awR45Z2_TIB0gmc4ptZprabSB" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Update Platform Information&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I collect in my database is Core information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a user chooses a core from the openFPGA menu on the Pocket, it lists certain information about itself, such as when the console or handheld was original released, who was the manufacture, and also the name and category of the core, too. All core developers are very particular about the accurate representation of the consoles, games, and their code, so this information is usually correct, but sometime it is not to avoid copyright and trademark violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the database, it's easy for me to edit this information and also collect all the information into categories. My program will rewrite all of the information in the Platforms directory with what I have in my database. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it'll create Platform Images using agg23's &lt;a href="https://github.com/agg23/Analogue-Pocket-Image-Process"&gt;Platform Image Creator&lt;/a&gt;. Any new images that I've made and placed in the processing directory will be converted and copied over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Run the Updater&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also a simple shell script that runs &lt;a href="https://github.com/mattpannella/pocket-updater-utility"&gt;Matt Pannella&lt;/a&gt;'s command line program with all of the settings that I like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Future&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this stuff pretty often when new cores and new features are released, so there continue to be more updates. When Playlists eventually come to the Pocket, I'll have a new program to make those. I'm also working on another program that will make a list of games I have in my "unsorted" directories for each core.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket continues to be one of the absolute best gaming devices made, and being able to make all this stuff to organize games has gotten back into programming on the side. It's been pretty great. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Analogue Pocket has become one of my favorite gaming consoles (or handheld) of all time. Initially announced as a modern device that plays games from the family of GameBoys, it has grown to become exactly what I wanted and has yet to reach its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bK_58j62X-XspF__41c0OiI-OJg6xG8u"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bKgW_402-9SHqaj0MLqqziSOvzyQX2BP" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analogue is a company that specializes in creating retro gaming consoles. They are most widely known for making a $200 Nintendo and a $200 Super Nintendo. You can plug your original cartridges from these systems into these new ones, and everything still works. There have been several other machines that have done this in recent years, but Analogue’s edge is its use of the FPGA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internally, Analogue has reversed engineered and replicated the original chipsets of the Nintendo and Super Nintendo and have them running on a chip called an FPGA. This means that the games aren’t running in emulation on a PC or on Linux or something. It’s running the original processors EXACTLY the same way the original hardware did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By doing this, Analogue has replicated the exact original look and feel of the original console to near perfection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket Announcement&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;October 16th, 2019&lt;/b&gt;, Analogue announced its newest hardware recreation, the Analogue Pocket. The Analogue Pocket would be their first handheld device, and it would play GameBoy, GameBoy Color, and GameBoy Advanced games. Sold separately, you could also buy a Dock that would charge the device and hook up to a TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the biggest hint at its potential was the inclusion of a second FPGA chipset. A primary FPGA was included that would run a Game cartridge, but the second FPGA would be open to developers to do whatever they wanted with. This meant that it may be possible for people to play their own Game roms on the device. And this also meant that people could write code for other consoles to be played, like a Game Gear, or a Sega Genesis, or a Super Nintendo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I had been able to rediscover many amazing retro games thanks to the Super Nintendo Mini. But, the Mini was cumbersome and could only play certain games. If the Pocket could play Super Nintendo and other stuff, too, it would be like the Nintendo Switch for retro games. I could play Super Nintendo portably, or plug it into the TV and play them there. It would be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket Release&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost a year later on August 1st, a date and time was announced when you could buy one. For me, it would be Midnight on &lt;b&gt;August 4th 2020&lt;/b&gt;. Hype for the device began to buzz around the Internet with even Elijah Wood posting about it. Of course, this was the height of global lockdown from the Coronavirus, so any news on the Internet spread very quickly. I planned on staying up to secure my order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analogue’s Store page went live at Midnight, and I knew exactly what I wanted: Black Pocket, Dock, Case, Screen Protector, and Cable. Putting things into my cart was easy, but actually purchasing was a nightmare. The pages took a while to load, or didn’t load at all. I typed in all of my information and hit save, but international shipping took a while to appear. I kept hitting that Purchase button to conclude the sale, and eventually it went through. After waking up the next day, a purchase confirmation email was in my inbox. It was a success! My order was in the #54xxx range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket was expected to release in early or mid-2021. That was pushed to October, and then it was pushed again. Finally, orders began shipping in December, and on &lt;b&gt;December 24th, 2021&lt;/b&gt;, my Pocket arrived in the mail. Over 2 years after its announcement, and over 1 year after its purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XAYsIrLiH9tihkkP-CIZspeTXJ_pFZqc" &gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XC_VmDcnjjqZgKbpUyGtXZHXslHzGwN3" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, the Analogue Pocket does exactly what it says it would do. You plug in a GameBoy game, it plays perfectly fine. You plug in a GameBoy Advance game, it plays perfectly fine. But that was all that it did. On release, the second FPGA chip was not yet available for other developers to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to &lt;b&gt;July 30th 2022&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/analogue/status/1553032922143330306"&gt;the first firmware update&lt;/a&gt; was released. The second FPGA was now available and the first core was released which recreated Spacewar, the first interactive game ever created on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Neo Geo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day later, something amazing showed up online. There was a &lt;a href="https://github.com/Mazamars312/Analogue_Pocket_Neogeo"&gt;core for the Neo Geo&lt;/a&gt;. The Neo Geo was a console released in the 90s which was identical to the company's Arcade hardware. It was the first time you could play perfect versions of Arcade games in your home. It was very expensive, so very few people actually bought it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Neo Geo is home to some of my favorite games of all time, now they were available on the Pocket. And they looked absolutely stunning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X7Xm_fMEg0C4U9Dc138UUbZreARGK4ys"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X8jFtPkME2kdiQuObXPBvJ9gIBEDYMUD" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X59ANqq_PM5aCg5HLPf3LGmISiRTEFTZ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X5PH8qr2_rFh9Mgdla8v7UwrNqBxjADi" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all games played at first, but the ones that worked were perfect. They looked amazing, sounded amazing, and played amazing. As of today, &lt;b&gt;September 19th, 2022&lt;/b&gt; with its most recent update, all Neo Geo games are playable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Super Nintendo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, today-ish the dream has finally come true with the first release of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/agg23/openfpga-SNES"&gt;Super Nintendo core&lt;/a&gt; for the Analogue Pocket. 3 years after its initial announcement, preorder, release, update, the Analogue Pocket had reached the potential that many of us initially saw in the device, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ photos ]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actraiser looks and sounds absolutely stunning on the Pocket. Super Metroid looks and sounds amazing. It's all so beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;A Dream Device&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With both &lt;b&gt;Neo Geo&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Super Nintendo&lt;/b&gt; released, I'm able to play these games in the perfect environment without any of the problems of the Super Nintendo Mini. Adding and organizing games on the Pocket is FAR simpler than the Mini, and there is virtually no storage limit since everything is on an SD card. I'm able to play every game ever created on this device, and then organize the ones I want to play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For me, there are still a few more consoles needed to make the Analogue Pocket the perfect device for me. Obviously, the &lt;b&gt;Nintendo Entertainment System&lt;/b&gt; has an incredible number of classics, but I want to also play Sega Genesis with &lt;b&gt;Sega CD&lt;/b&gt;, in order to play Snatcher, and &lt;b&gt;Capcom CPS2&lt;/b&gt; for arcade perfect Street Fighter Alpha, Super Puzzle Fighter II, and some other amazing Shooters and Fighters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If all &lt;b&gt;five&lt;/b&gt; of these consoles were available on the Pocket, my Retro dreams would completely come true.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Raid Counters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Linked below is my collated list of all the best raid counters in Pokemon Go. These numbers of based on the calculations made by Gamepress’s &lt;a href="https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/comprehensive-dps-spreadsheet"&gt;Comprehensive DPS Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; but put together on a single page, rather than multiple ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VY-8qOf09VGMlhyHcAXL02w97P_914oA" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not the prettiest page, but it shows everything I need in order to build my raid team. Each cell shows the following:&lt;br/&gt;- the name of the Pokemon&lt;br/&gt;- the level of the Pokemon used for the calculations&lt;br/&gt;- the fast move&lt;br/&gt;- the charge move&lt;br/&gt;- the DPS&lt;br/&gt;- the TDO&lt;br/&gt;- the final figure is DPS*4 x TDO / 100000. This is the number I used to sort each list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing more damage quickly is more important than staying alive, so I prioritize DPS. But, it’s not solely sorted by DPS because if you die immediately with no defense, it’s totally worthless.  Therefore, I’m using DPS*4 rather than DPS*3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m including level 40 for all Pokemon, but I’m also including level 50 for all non-legendary pokemon and level 45 for all legendaries. It’s not too difficult to boost Pokemon up to level 40, but even though you can boost them all the way up to 50, getting XL candies for legendaries is not so easy. Includes two levels for each Pokemon can show you how much more powerful one is compared to the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Purpose&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some quick background, in Pokemon Go, there are these Pokemon battles called raids that multiple people can join to defeat the boss. Once the boss is defeated, each player has a chance to catch that Pokemon for themselves. These Pokemon are strong enough that you cannot defeat them by yourself. Each boss is different, but you usually must have 3 or 4 players minimum to win, assuming they have the best Pokemon for the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what are the best Pokemon for the battle? A while ago, the Pokemon community on &lt;b&gt;Gamepress&lt;/b&gt; wrote a calculator that would tell you just how powerful a Pokemon was versus a raid boss. If you typed in the Pokemon you wanted to fight, it would give you a numbered list of all the best pokemon you’d need to defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was first doing raids, I found this calculator very useful to determine which Pokemon to catch and boost. However, for this calculator, you need to type in each individual Pokemon one by one to see each of the best counters.  I wanted a page that I could look at and see ALL of the best pokemon versus ALL of the raid pokemon in Pokemon Go. So, I made one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Raid Counter List&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The calculator will save a CSV will all the data for the raid counters.  So, back in 2019, I made this page to display all the information from these CSV files. Over time, this became unmanageable because the number of raid bosses continued to grow and the number of best Pokemon and best moves began to grow too. It would take me about an hour to download each individual sheet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gamepress Calculator does all of its calculations in JavaScript. So over summer, I went through that code and ported it to Java. Now, rather than compiling data from generated CSV files, I can generate that data myself. And, rather than downloading 30+ CSV files, I only need to download the raw data files and rerun the page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The General list says which are the best raid pokemon overall, but I also wrote a page that shows me which of my Pokemon are the best. I have to manually add every one of these, so my list is often out of date, but it gives me a general idea how much damage my team can do or how many people I’ll need to recruit to beat the boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/custom"&gt;Personal Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if any of this is readable to anyone else, but it helps me out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Cards</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my Twitch channel, and the overall general rise and demand for all things video games on the Internet during the pandemic, I had been getting into Pokemon Cards lately. Not spending too much money, but maybe spending more money than I had to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, it was announced that the Pokemon Card company would finally be doing a proper crossover with Pokemon Go. Generally, Pokemon card sets follow the main series of Pokemon games, such as X/Y, Sun/Moon, and Sword/Shield. Sometimes there would be novelty cards that would show up from other spin-off games, but no other spin-off game has been as popular as Pokemon Go.  In fact, the overall brand awareness of Pokemon increased significantly after the release of Pokemon Go in 2016, and it has stayed around the same ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new Pokemon Go set of Pokemon Cards would be an entire expansion of 72 cards, too. Previous novelty sets, like Detective Pikachu and the 25th Anniversary sets were only 20 or 25 cards, and these cards weren’t really all that useful passed their novelty. I don’t actually play the game, so I can’t say whether or not these Go cards are actually useful. But, it seems like they’ve put some actually work into them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was able to preorder a box of cards and the long box set from Pokemon Center online, so I got them in the mail as they released on Friday (June 17th). I was able to pick up a few more packs, plus the folder set from a convenience store on the way home after work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XGvRExu37YeO7yFlAhkVHfcK2Ucfdxdz"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XJDqTloqgtuVv8RgVqbDeyLWQZ8y8bvV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The long box came with a photo frame to hold a card, and a card box that looked like an egg incubator from Pokemon Go. It had some packs of cards, too. The folder pack came with that little folder to hold some cards. It also came with a Pikachu promo card. It also got 5 other promo cards from buying a booster box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each booster pack comes with seven cards: a special flashy energy card with the Pokemon Go logo, an item/sticker promo card with a code for Pokemon Go, 2 or 3 common cards, 1 or 2 uncommon cards, and a rare pull. The rare pull could be a simple rare, a V card, V-star card, V-max card, or any other rare card in the set.  There are a total of 72 cards in the base set, but an additional 12 or 15 secret rare cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xth-WIhATFwTD6jAnhMbKtFJAJ-30_h4"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xv2ps_JdvObsAMOsxDcyobeNQh70oKML" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my first pack, I really didn't get anything special. In this case, my rare card was a Gyarados denoted by the &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt; next to the number at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The promo code in Pokemon Go can give one of eight different sets of items. There are six common sets and one uncommon set of items with stickers, and there is one rare set which gives clothing for your character.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - 3 months later&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I streamed over the following weekends, I opened up some packs for my followers. Immediately, I started getting some good pulls, like the shiny Venusaur and Dragonite V-star card. As my streams continued, I started getting some other good stuff too, like the shiny Blastoise, Mewtwo V-star, and a full art Candela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XEF7_Ud7lzrN4PqyJvDCfyto1CU5GStn"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XELgYcOp6defbAyIZcVTF1-8UYwYP6Xh" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XFDo65WnM6KnNc4QGE7mMd34a1tqUvi0"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XpsSKOwOp1Ipv2JUo4As8j4tsEoFMQJw" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was getting very few duplicates of rare and uncommon cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, I had opened up all my packs of cards and was only missing 8 from the base set. Each pack of cards gave a chance to pull a rare card, and those were the 8 that I was missing. Obviously, I could buy more packs for more chances, but it is way more cost effective to just buy what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cards weren't too expensive, and I was able to quickly get most of them from Yahoo Auctions, except for one. Within the base set of 72 cards, the most expensive card was Shiny Charizard. My auctions were selling the card for $40, which was way too much for me to spend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update 2&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward six more months and the Shiny Charizard was now only $10 on Yahoo Auctions. I am totally fine with spending $10 on a single Pokemon card as it was the ONE piece remaining from my collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now my collection is complete!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the photo below to see the whole set, or individual pages in the gallery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YnKmc4Y-tN5hC33xp0NdO9Sr9-VDAYBA"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YoMoUzI9ly5iB-TzRmGP-jXXd_ph7v3-" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-cards</link></item><item><title>Virtual Tokyo Marathon</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As the pandemic began, live events around the world were canceled and marathons were no exception. Luckily for them, the virus landed under their “acts of god” clause in their contracts, so they didn’t need to issue any refunds. But they had to adapt to the situation, just like everyone else and all other companies in order to stay in business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In lieu of being able to do physical marathons, many organizations began to host Virtual marathons, and many of these virtual marathons were free or significantly cheaper than doing them in person. To run them, you needed to download a GPS tracking running app, like Strava, and record a run with the same length as the race within the correct time period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These virtual marathons became so frequent and so cheap that throughout 2021 I was running one nearly every weekend. In 2018, I set a new personal record in distance having run a total of 367km in official races over the entire year. I spent nearly $1000 doing this, too. In 2021, I ran 365.6km in all of my races combined, only spending $200. This was an absolute godsend, even though my race times weren’t nearly as good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Marathon was a race that had been on my bucket list ever since I started running in Japan. Every year I applied, but every year, I was unable to win the entry lottery for general entry. Much like all other marathons, it had been canceled in 2020 and pushed to 2021. Then canceled again and pushed to 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, this year, the Tokyo Marathon was finally held again, but only for the elite and career marathon runners. There was no general entry. To make up for this, they added an online component. Anyone who had general entry in the race could participate online for free. Additionally, the general entry became open to everyone for 5000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. This was finally my chance! Not only that, I only had to run a half marathon rather than a full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 5th, in the yet still snowy country-side, I ran my half marathon and completed the race. The app was very cumbersome, and I wasn’t really sure if my time actually registered. But today! I got my medal in the mail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XQ-3W31USV5-_ZnTSAcq7Wz1HwhBRWoJ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XQBgGe_PATMiAqmaPY2ualY-nVRKbsYq" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XNUgxNK6bguXVg4Oyn2kqj_jsYKLNy0P"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XOhO-qBgTM4XWu9X9-X72SfYu_dxhLXG" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XMMp9mE8CToqunfTN1Qsk2rTes_KI0Of"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XMfPtRhMl4YaQdM7_u2ZBvnf-noyaFwJ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is not a legitimate Tokyo Marathon medal, but it is good enough for me! Now it can join the club with all of my other marathon medals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XJScvgFJR8hluL1fcY7v_nmDVCj2ddfs"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XMASSb9UqXzk9n7eYjyVKadiT42UDw97" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Virtual marathoning, I could continue having motivation to run and exercise during lockdown. Running in the fields and the forests of the countryside have been an excellent break from being online 24/7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Tokyo Marathon medal, I've gotten a few more medals from Virtual races. Now I have so many that my medals have outgrown the box that I was keeping them in. It took some searching as I drove around to various antique stores, but I think I found the perfect box as my marathon medal collection's forever home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XnGOMBvv5NzVDrakvE-SnY5YCI1sOjr8"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XoBaHG0zErvLBEfCcvanmfr5lNdRCH_Q" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XlDuFKyU-3s_HwRCrDvEY_aWzPCxKNZL"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XmhsBttQiWB9KDXnI5CwhEZhV_p-RHnJ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XkZQBuXI7_ckVXF7nXaPdwyotQ5OmUFH"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XkyE4juWD1pyBDrEdMk-JWH8VXxYwi1s" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/virtual-tokyo-marathon</link></item><item><title>Capsule Machine Capsule</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I had to escort a student to the Narita Airport in Tokyo so he could fly back to his country. We arrived very early before his flight so he could get a PCR test and be cleared to fly. We walked around while waiting for the results, and I found a pretty amazing sight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XYQiJGzbboJsWaTyZq1XyhKi_BjsdtlQ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XYb0RAaubp_r8H5W0njRuPTerW52zJ-y" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a capsule machine that gave out miniature capsule machines! I absolutely had to have this thing. I got some change and turned the crank. My first pull gave me a pack of capsules! Pretty meta. I got a capsule ball full of tiny capsule balls. Well, now I needed to roll again to actually get a machine. My second pull was a success! I got the red version of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XT6Jgw0aDF146H2fZN1n1TjbNmlL9sct"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XVfB-F29Ie1GWNf4GPy3yiXfwdVbd5eJ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XXIK1XFh1rCkpTRGiRskEbig70zba8u2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XY6sPCdyb9m3_aqM8W0b42vrh2gq0EJu" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given all the moving parts of this little capsule machine, it was best to leave everything in its package for later. I said my goodbyes to my student as he got on his flight, and I returned home. At home, I assembled the machine together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XQr7NSCTb9OCp-Fpy7_PwjP7vPmLzPlG"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XRCXWRuJ9C0jyyrfr9MdxbxFU0WhHOOc" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Success! A miniature capsule machine for my shelf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I had one, I needed to have them all! I searched for the set on the Internet and learned what I could. This particular set was called &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ガチャガチャマシーン&lt;/span&gt;３ (or Gatcha Gatcha Machine 3), and it was released in December 2021. So, it was already out in the wild for 3 months. I learned that you can buy full distributions of some capsule times on Amazon.  For Gatcha Gatcha Machine 3 that consisted of 24 capsules, which was 3 complete sets of 8 items: 3 red machines, 3 white machines, 1 pack of capsules, and 1 set of metal shelves.  So, the Capsules I had gotten were a 1/8 rare pull. The red machine was a typical 3/8 pull.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continued searching on Yahoo Auctions to find someone selling the missing items in my set, but most people were selling a full set of 8 or selling the rare pulls for a lot of money. Eh. I gave up. One capsule machine is good enough. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/capsule-machine-capsule</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Unown Availability</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Unown is a Pokemon from Gold/Silver that has 28 different forms. Each form is a letter of the alphabet, plus a question mark and exclamation point. Unown is special because it was originally only available at physical events. And at those events, only specific letters were available. Over time, it's become easier to catch at least one form of Unown, but certain letters have only been available a few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, which letters are the most common? Which ones are rare? And where have they been released?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been keeping track on this page: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/unown"&gt;/apps/pokemon/unown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This page shows the data in 4 ways:&lt;br/&gt;1. It shows which ones I'm missing and which events they were available at.&lt;br/&gt;2. It shows an ascending list of the rarest Unowns and their events from the last 3 years.&lt;br/&gt;3. It shows an ordered list of how many times each Letter has been available, and which events.&lt;br/&gt;4. And, it shows each individual event where Unown had been available, and which ones were there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this page to determine whether or not I should throw away some Unown after I catch them. If I go to an event in Japan, and a particular form appears that has not appeared back in the US, I'll hold on to more than usual so I can trade with people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Exclamation Point, for example, was available at Go Fest in 2019, but has not been available since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1az8AD8TNvkBi1qQ25jSPgqLjib55xX1L"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1azdZKApyKG7MiD19UpToRQCfpXxFWwza" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/unown-availability</link></item><item><title>New Pokemon Snap</title><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most beloved and revered spinoffs of Pokemon is Pokemon Snap for Nintendo 64. The idea of roaming around in a land while wild Pokemon "naturally" interact with each other and the environment has always given reality to people's imagination of how the real world of Pokemon could be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, people have always said that they should make a modern update to Pokemon Snap and they finally did. Release on April 30th, &lt;b&gt;New&lt;/b&gt; Pokemon Snap is the modern update every one had been asking for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back on the Nintendo 64, only 151 Pokemon were available, but 20 years later, there are now over 900 Pokemon. This game doesn't have all 900, but it has an incredibly balanced variety of Pokemon from all the different generations. It's pretty amazing how much New Pokemon Snap doesn't focus on just one generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Gameplay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Pokemon Snap plays almost identically to the original. You character hops into a pod and is pulled through the world on a mostly linear track. Your job is to take photos of Pokemon that appear in the environment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the game, you unlock some ways to interact with the Pokemon. In New Pokemon Snap, you can throw out food for them to eat, throw orbs to light up pokemon, and play music. These interactions can change the course of your pod, or unlock other things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expanded from the original is the possibility of different tiered photographs. Depending on the interactions you before with Pokemon, they could perform a unique pose or even a special pose.  Every Pokemon now has 4 level of photographs to be taken. Tier 1 is a stand photo and Tier 2 is typically the Pokemon eating food. Tier 3 and Tier 4 are reserved for unique poses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With 200 total Pokemon in the game and each Pokemon having 2 unique poses, that's 400 unique photographs you need to take. It is a bit overwhelming, especially towards the end of the game when you're missing many of these photos. When you only get 1 or 2 new photos in a single run, it gets VERY repetitive and VERY boring quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;High Score&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All photos in the game give you a score. If you get a "perfect" photo, it'll be worth 4000 or more points. All of these points add up to the total score of your Photodex. Pokemon Snap came out right at the beginning of Golden Week, so I had an entire week off from work to devote to this game. I was playing this game almost every day for HOURS after its release, so I was flying through the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can connect online and compare your Photodex score to everyone in the world. At my peak, I was able to become nearly 800th place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z60V1w6EIY3Knl-UkH1C5z50xrNt2l4o" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I could not keep up this pace forever. Vacation had finished, and I had to get back to work. Everyone else in the world who played video game for a living continue on without me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Burnout&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, once you do the broad strokes of everything in the game, all that is left is grinding. Finding all of the remaining photos, one by one. Slowly increasing the scores of your photos, one by one. Doing the same tracks, again and again and again. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's not really much skill involved with the game. You wait 5 minutes to get the perfect photo, and if you miss it by a fraction of a second, you gotta do it again.  You try to get Pokemon to do what you want, but it occasionally goes wrong, and gets frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eh, there's really no reason to push myself too hard in this game just to build my hatred for it. It's a good game and I like it, otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I put the game down. Here are my final stats in the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z82rG_K0rF0JfCf2KRQStVvIQ_CZhI7T" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, it's a fun game with a lot of stuff to do. The Pokemon interactions are fun and interesting. Plenty of Easter eggs and hidden interactions to find that are really satisfying when you naturally find them.  Definitely worthy of the Pokemon Snap name. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/new-pokemon-snap</link></item><item><title>Legend of Crystania Memorabilia</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Crystania is a film that has had a significant impact on me. Unlike any of movie, it wasn't because of the story, characters, art, or music. It was because, 14 years ago, my college friends and I and over 25 members of our college anime club, SPAMM, created a feature length fandub of the film. To this day, I have yet to know anything about the official story or characters other than it's connection to Lodoss War.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our film was entitled The Secret of Crystania, and you can view it here: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="/the-secret-of-crystania"&gt;theschlock.com/the-secret-of-crystania&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every since moving to Japan, I often go to Yahoo Auctions and when I'm there, I always search for Crystania. Over the last 10 years, many pieces of Crystania memorabilia has surfaced. Usually the prices are very cheap compared to well known anime productions of the time, so buying these things has worked on quite well. Recently, some very interesting things has shown up there, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have scanned in all of my memorabilia, and you can take a look at it all below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Theatrical Run Items&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Crystania premiered in Japanese theaters during the Tsunogawa Anime Festival on July 29th, 1995. It was part of a double feature along with the Slayers movie. Obviously, Slayers was incredibly popular, so people were basically suckered into seeing Crystania, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have found a ticket from that event, which has a March 27th, 1995 date on it for some reason. Were they selling tickets that far in advance? Looking around all tickets have that date on them. I don't know why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I found a flyer for the premiere event as well as a film pamphlet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[photo]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As films release in Japan, theaters will sell a pamphlet book of the film with shots from the film, story explanation, and occasionally production notes, interviews, and other behind the scenes stuff. This particular book also has several pages of ads for additional Crystania mechandise. Most of the time these books are sold, but maybe these were given away with the premiere. I've scanned the pamphlet and included it below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legend of Crystania - Film Pamphlet (20 pages)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;はじまりの冒険者たち　レジェンド・オブ・クリスタニア&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;パンフレット&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1c8g83Hvg7Z6VQ0-c5SMrJeXM-NJNapjm/"&gt;https://drive.google.com/.../1c8g83Hvg7Z6VQ0-c5SMrJeXM-NJNapjm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Home Release Items&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dHiYKO-EozkKcPsI9s5f5YtkiV-TJL6G"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dImUskKdar2whCPysbi_O4ETmZQZmXQe" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original home release of Legend of Crystania was on VHS in Japan on March 8th, 1996. But, it was a decaying format and LaserDisc was the new hotness. LaserDisc took an incredible hold in Japan and almost all the modern popular anime releases got a LaserDisc release through the late 90s. The LaserDisc version of Crystania was released on March 23rd, 1996, and by the end of the year, the 3-part 6-episode OAV sequel was released on LaserDisc, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LaserDisc version of Legend of Crystania is the most high quality release to date. In America, we got a DVD version in 2000, but the DVD version released by ADV was a transfer of the LaserDisc. Additionally, the American DVD has subtitles and other English edits burned directly onto the video. This cuts out some of the original video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I picked up two copies of the movie as they weren't too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The VHS tape shows up on Yahoo Auctions from time to time, but I think it's unnecessary to own since the LaserDisc is the definitive version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Animation Cels&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 7 years ago, as I was looking through Yahoo Auctions, I first searched for Crystania and saw that some was selling animation cels. I had always dreamed or had a fantasy of owning animation cels of Crystania, but owning such things seemed incredible cost prohibited in my mind, considering cels of popular shows go for hundreds of dollars.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Crystania is not popular, nor even really all that good. I purchased my first cels and posted about it here: &lt;a href="/animation-cels-from-the-legend-of-crystania"&gt;theschlock.com/animation-cels-from-the-legend-of-crystania&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The years went on, and occasionally more and more cels would appear on Yahoo Auctions. Today, I own 15 cels from the film. I have scanned them all, and added them in the gallery below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dIHFiYU5NZaMxVJB441r0x4ZYrNqW39Q"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dJJWApd-MX85ruA030VmuAek5ZyOvqpb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Production Collections&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, these two items appeared on Yahoo Auctions and I immediately put all of my money behind acquiring them. Although, the final price of the auctions weren't really that expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bvvwdkxDWqnQKZCwUQoqH-0iyHpuZNTn"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bwSbibe-gbK1paWdbAe4LH4bmP57QcKE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bh2F_tnR0NxsIYYiDBmqMULmmjBtUTRw"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bi66KV0QmX1XW4He_yNgjm_ynAYET1-1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have a collection of Character Reference sheets and a collection of Cel Layout Corrections, both used during the production of the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Character Reference was used by key animator on the film the accurately and correctly draw characters with the correct clothes, items, as well as size and dimensions. When characters face different directions or do move in various ways, animators will use these references to make sure everything is okay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cel Layout Corrections collection is pretty self explanatory from the title, although after flipping through the pages, I don't really see that many corrections. I think it's mostly a collection of line art used for Key frames in the film. Once these frames were drawn, they were traced onto cel paper. From there, the colors were onto the cels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can download and page through each collection from the links below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legend of Crystania - Character Reference Collection (65 pages)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「レジェンド・オブ・クリスタニア」キャラクラー設定集&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RbCooF9dTjEmcYfd31qo9zoUJpTqlOXW"&gt;https://drive.google.com/.../1RbCooF9dTjEmcYfd31qo9zoUJpTqlOXW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legend of Crystania - Cel Layout Corrections (96 pages)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「レジェンド・オブ・クリスタニア」レイアウト時のキャラ・修正集&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/19v8gTPq7vYGSlZt6WmOl79SysB_nYnVV"&gt;https://drive.google.com/.../19v8gTPq7vYGSlZt6WmOl79SysB_nYnVV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;…any more?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continue to look for unique Crystania items on Yahoo Auctions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;I&gt;(Update 2023)&lt;/I&gt;: It has been a while since anything interesting Crystania related has showed up on Yahoo. I haven't seen any animation cels in the last 2 1/2 years.  Originally, there were quite a bit, but things have dried up.  Maybe I've bought them all?  Maybe it's time to move to a different platform to find stuff?&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/crystania-memorabilia</link></item><item><title>Chrono Cross Anniversary Tour</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My absolute favorite video game soundtrack of all time is from Chrono Cross. It was composed by Yasunori Mitsuda and had the perfect blend of atmosphere, mystery, and comfort. It perfectly complemented the dreamy and whimsical world of Chrono Cross.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year is the 20th Anniversary of Chrono Cross, and to celebrate Mitsuda has gotten his band together to give a live tour of the Chrono Cross soundtrack. It will be performed 5 times in 3 cities, including Tokyo, Osaka, and Nagoya.  Tickets were not so cheap at 16800&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; (equivalent to $168), but it would be an absolute dream to hear my favorite video game music performed by the actual creator of the music. Easy buy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Morning of the Concert&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the concert, I met up with someone from the Internet who was also attending. We had our tickets reserved, but had to go to the venue early to actually get our tickets. Additionally, I wanted to visit the venue early because the merchandise booth was going to be open, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went to the venue around Noon and waited for it to open. Plenty of other people were there, too. At 1:30pm, doors open but only a few people were allowed entry at a time. We eventually made it in at 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aGrppRAA4zq7_d9b4DHUzMcuUc3WaoD4"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aHCmY6JK_P3E7bepsuuT0nq5v3FVo3kO" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a7FlkWA0AfFysyJtmpXxbPDepwL1DYnA"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aAA1hkh5BHwevISZYpiQGIMNARIokmEn" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the entrance, we gave our reservations to the clerk, and they gave us our tickets. Inside were only a few people, and it was a line for the merch booth that curved around the room. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My goal was to purchase the concert towel for the event. In Japan, almost every concert or tour has a towel associated with it. It's kind of like a band's tour T-shirt in America. Tell 'em where you've been by buying a towel. The towel was 1800&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; and I bought some stickers, too, for 1000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. The tickets included a pamphlet of the concert, so I didn't buy that. Minutes after I purchased the towel, they were sold out, so I was able to get one in the nick of time. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went back to my car to dump off our stuff, got some lunch, and went right back to the venue for the evening concert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;The Concert&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We probably got back to the venue at 3pm or 3:30pm, and waited in line again. When the doors opened at 4pm, they were letting people in by sequential order of their tickets. Each individual ticket number was checked and let in by the order of when their tickets were purchased. You'd think this would take forever, but it went pretty quickly.  We made it in around 4:30pm, and the show began around 5:15pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a68cii08JBbmQghZR4bep32JW0G5Q9_X"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a729kSufJToxMF-N6sUKChyuZsEmutjw" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The venue was tiny. Capacity was probably 1000 people? (as long as they were all smashed together) WAYYY smaller than the Tokyo or Osaka venues. It was nice, though. Much more intimate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band members took the stage in darkness, tuned their instruments, and the opening sequence for the concert began to play on the screen behind them. The dreamy motions of the title of screen of Chrono Cross. It detailed the preamble of the story.  And then, the heavy reverberations of the guitar being plucked as &lt;b&gt;Scars of Time&lt;/b&gt; began, which moved into the light Flute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was incredible. It completely opened up my mind to hearing this music for the first time around 20 years ago when that first trailer dropped on the Internet, and when I imported the game on Playstation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitsuda quickly introduced himself and the band as they played the opening menu music to the game. As "New Game" was selected, they played the battle music, which is how the game starts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, they played through the entirety of the game on the screen, and played the entirety of the soundtrack to accompany it.  I wrote down a rough setlist of what they played:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Main Set&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;	1.	Chrono Cross - Scars of Time&lt;br/&gt;	2.	The Dream that Time Dreams&lt;br/&gt;	3.	Garden of God (Title Screen)&lt;br/&gt;	4.	Between Life and Death (Battle Music)&lt;br/&gt;	5.	Arni Village - Home World&lt;br/&gt;	6.	Arni Village - Another World&lt;br/&gt;	7.	Fields of Time - Home World&lt;br/&gt;	8.	Lizard Dance&lt;br/&gt;	9.	Termina - Another World&lt;br/&gt;	10.	Forest of Illusion&lt;br/&gt;	11.	Viper Mansion&lt;br/&gt;	12.	Gale (Boss Music)&lt;br/&gt;	13.	Victory (A Gift of Spring)&lt;br/&gt;	14.	Guldove - Another World&lt;br/&gt;	15.	Fortress of Ancient Dragons&lt;br/&gt;	16.	A Narrow Space Between Dimensions&lt;br/&gt;	17.	Dead Sea / Tower of Destruction&lt;br/&gt;	18.	Prisoners of Fate&lt;br/&gt;	19.	Magical Dreamers&lt;br/&gt;	20.	Zelbess&lt;br/&gt;	21.	Fate - The God of Destiny&lt;br/&gt;	22. Burning Orphanage??&lt;br/&gt;	23.	The Girl who Stole the Stars&lt;br/&gt;	24.	Frozen Flame&lt;br/&gt;	25.	Dragon God?? (Explanation for Elements. Screwing up, then Game Over)&lt;br/&gt;	26.	A Light for Lost Hopes (Game Over music)&lt;br/&gt;	27.	Life - Distance Promise (Elemental Song)&lt;br/&gt;	28.	Radical Dreamers - Unstolen Jewel&lt;br/&gt;	29.	Fragment of a Dream&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Encore&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;	1.	Song to get Mitsuda back on Stage&lt;br/&gt;	2.	Band Members Introduction Song&lt;br/&gt;	3.	Voyage - Another World??&lt;br/&gt;	4.	Voyage - Home World??&lt;br/&gt;	5.	Marbule - Another World&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn't like they just "played" the soundtrack to Chrono Cross. All of these were live variations of the original score. They deviated and mostly improved upon what they had before, and were able to match the crowd's reactions as they played. Much of the concert felt very interactive and Mitsuda explained a lot of his feelings and ideas for each song through the concert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the concert finished, there were credits on the screen, too. I have never been to a concert before with a credits screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Stuff&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concluding the show, this was all the stuff I came away with. I grabbed some of the heart confetti that were shot in the air during the concert, my light stick, and the things that I purchased earlier. Also included is a book of artwork we received as part of our ticket purchase. We also got a flame pendant, too, but that's not pictured here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a3pMhfKOW-yUZX0aHUh_Y0CcCoW4PK5H"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a4Ui0YXcBwfNBUp0TfaVZXyp1u9-6H4d" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, it was absolutely incredible and a dream come true to see, hear, and feel the music that has shaped my music tastes in video games. It was super dorky to rock out to RPG battle music. It was moving hearing Scars of Time and the other intro song live. And it was fun getting the audience to work together with their colored glowsticks to get the elements in the right order to get the true ending of the game/concert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitsuda created an amazing concert, and with all of the production that went into the lights and video on display, I understand where the $168 price tag came from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - January 27th, 2020&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the conclusion of 2 additional final dates in Tokyo, Mitsuda has released an official set list from the concert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aJu0Gi3qYwfv0vTXIObZsA63cm288da5" &gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aJu0Gi3qYwfv0vTXIObZsA63cm288da5" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They also made an Apple playlist as well, so you can hear the music from the soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://music.apple.com/jp/playlist/chrono-cross-20th-anniversary-live-tour-2019-radical/pl.u-vVvDTdWe44"&gt;https://music.apple.com/.../chrono-cross-20th-anniversary-live-tour-2019-radical/pl.u-vVvDTdWe44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - February 12th, 2020&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a tweet, Mitsuda mentions that the final Nakano performance was recorded, and he is in the process of mastering the audio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - February 27th, 2020&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of our ticket purchase, we were to receive a concert booklet of the event. We received an art book, but it was pretty short and didn't include anything about the concert itself. We filled out a card in order to receive this booklet later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got mine in the mail today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aKShNhiHQiCzFuWBmd62YnXsql6rGcWX"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aLyv_yG2IA2HcIttkaQbfMfJBAf8kx2p" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calling this thing a booklet doesn't do it justice. In fact, this thing is thicker than most pre-order bonus art books. There are tons of photos from each of the events, interviews, sheet music, and logo designs. Almost all the production that went into planning the concert is included in the book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was BY FAR the most production value I've ever seen packed into a single musical event. In the beginning, it seemed like the concert was a huge expense, but it's clear how much love and care went into the event. Mitsuda clearly loves his music for Chrono Cross as much as his fans, and he loved this experience as much as we did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's an incredible memorial of the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - June 24th, 2020&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the concert that keeps on giving. Today, Mitsuda and Procyon Studios released their recording of the final concert in Nakano Plaza. For only 1800&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;a href="https://mora.jp/package/43000033/A86298/?fmid=TOPNEWRL01"&gt;Mora&lt;/a&gt;, you could download the complete concert in FLAC format. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been listening to this nonstop on repeat at work while I check student's writing. It's absolutely incredible to be able to relive this concert again and again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - January 25th, 2021&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone said it was going to happen, and today Procyon and Mitsuda announced a live Bluray release of the final concert performance at Nakano plaza. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I purchased the limited edition version of the Bluray which comes with a download for an arrangement album of Chrono tunes, and some extra stuff.  This cost a total of 14100&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, which is a lot for a Bluray, but this'll be the very last Mitsuda can ring out of me from the concert. 14100 for the bluray, 16800 for tickets, and 2800 for merch. This totals 33700&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, or about $337.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was totally worth it, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - April 15th, 2021&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The preorder for the Bluray concluded on March 1st, and 6 weeks later, I was finally able to catch my deliveryman and get my Bluray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aSNo4PbycmcdfVSVr_yRPHNnx7jfjYAc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aTpdrlltCLJtCxjjPfsW9Zn-W2FGTjOj" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It includes a full Dolby 5.1 surround sound experience of the concert with absolutely crisp audio and a full video recording of the event, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also included is a short pamphlet of photos from the event, and a download code for the arrangement album. This arrangement is okay. I don't think it's as mind-blowing as the actual concert, but it's still a great listen. Much more low-key, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…And now, finally the saga is concluded. An absolutely amazing concert with many ways to relive and cherish those memories.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/chrono-cross-tour</link></item><item><title>Schlock</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 20 years ago, when I was in high school, there was a show on the Sci Fi Channel called Trailer Park.  It was 30 minutes long, and only showed movie trailers.  Mostly trailers for new movies, but some old ones, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One such episode featured a movie called Schlock&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YhsR0hnyFVY"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YhsR0hnyFVY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was one of the most ridiculous, bizarre, hilarious-not-hilarious, trying-too-hard things I'd ever seen at that point.  Over the next few years, I searched around pawn stores, video stores, and old rental stores trying to find a copy of it on VHS, but it seemed like no one even heard of it.&lt;br/&gt;The name was pretty unique, so I used it as my screen name for AOL and everything else since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In October 2001, it was finally released on DVD, and on my birthday that year, I was finally able to see it.  I had a bunch of people over to my dorm room, both friends from MN and college.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn't necessarily live up to my expectations, but I wasn't disappointed.  In fact, there were some pretty great moments in the film.  I don't really think any of my friends had quite the reactions I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last 17 years, the Schlock DVD had become quite scarce.  I think 10 years ago, the DVDs were going for the same price they are now, $150.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now, once again in my birthday month, Schlock has been released again, now on Bluray, and in a rather nice package.  The booklet had a story about how John Landis scrapped together what he had to make it.  There's a reversible cover.  The movie is a 4k restoration.  There's a few commentary tracks.  New interviews.  Old TV spots, and other things.  It's the complete Schlock package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1f2wiQ2J8CIOkKb6smcdAbLexWdM1WN-h"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1fCtg8T-4-zaVuS5FLi5AhZqoHPLh3a7X" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a week late, but now I have a new version of Schlock near my birthday, and new people to show this awful movie to.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/schlock</link></item><item><title>The Features and Potential of Japanese Budo Culture</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I attended the 30th Annual International Seminar of Budo Culture, which coincided with the 150th anniversary of the start of the Meiji era in Japan.  This year’s main lecture was &lt;b&gt;The Features and Potential of Japanese Budo Culture&lt;/b&gt; given by Seiichi Takeuchi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹内&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;整一&lt;/span&gt;.  He is currently a professor at Kamakura Women’s University, and former professor of the University of Tokyo.  His field is the study of ethics and Japanese thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lecture was given in Japanese and translated into English by Alex Bennett, who is currently a professor at Kansai University and has written and translated many books on the Japanese Budo arts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qkz7Dr0LdIt_c1uUzVlLqe0Un5KgBCNV"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14si24DDGrQOgoATrPpZQr5yQqXh0iIHK" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was my 3rd time attending the seminar.  Every year I’m able to get amazing insights into budo martial arts and learn about their connection to Japanese psychology and culture.  I previously wrote about the main lecture from the first seminar I attended two years ago: &lt;a href="/the-cardinal-virtues-of-japan"&gt;March 4th, 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I felt the contents of the lecture did not match the title, but the main idea expressed in the lecture was another fascinating look at an explanation for Japanese culture.  The theme carried through the explanations and examples was that of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「おのずから」と「みずから」&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; explained the cooperative duality of these two forces behind the decisions and actions of people in Japanese culture and society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;おのずから&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class='ja'&gt;自然の働く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;みずから&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class='ja'&gt;自分の能力&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s do &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;, first.  &lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; is the effect from oneself.  It’s the idea that an action or decision you made came as a result of your own willpower.  &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the workings of nature, the idea that there is an overwhelming force behind a decision or action that made or allowed it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; is pretty easy to understand, but &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is much more ambiguous.  In western countries, &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; could be similar to the will of god.  God is an outside influence, and people often thank God for giving them fortunes, or blame God for misfortunes.  This was brought up in a question after the lecture had finished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But for Japanese people, the idea of God is not a singular entity.  Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; mentioned if you asked a Japanese person who they pray to when they pray, they would not have an answer.  They wouldn’t know.  The will of nature is a result of many different factors and moving parts within the world and society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As another example, another question was asked, "Did you decide to do this lecture? Or was it the will of nature?"  He replied that he did want to do lecture, but he was also asked by many people to do it.  The people he knew and the connections he’s made throughout his life knew his expertise that made him qualified to give a lecture on this subject.  In that way, there was a force that created the opportunity for him to accept.  So, this lecture was a result of the actions of both nature and self.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the idea of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the force of everything around us.  It’s the connections we’ve made with people in our lives, the opportunities society gives us, and nature itself.  It is not, directly, "the will of God."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Example within Japanese Language&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two concepts aren’t something that is thought of on the surface level.  People aren’t consciously thinking about the will of themselves or nature when making decisions.  But there are examples within the Japanese language that build on this idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main example given was &lt;b&gt;I am to be married&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;結婚することになった&lt;/span&gt;.  When people get married in Japan and they announce it to their family and friends, they use this phrase.  It’s very passive and reflects the idea of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.  Getting married is simply a matter of course.  It’s natural.  Additionally, the effect of getting married wasn’t just decided or caused between the two involved.  It was the culmination of the people around them and their families’ blessings and good intentions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He did mention later in the lecture that a lot of young people these days use a more affirmative phrase when speaking informally about marriage, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;結婚することにした&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;we’ve decided to get married&lt;/b&gt;.  The two getting married take responsibility for their marriage as opposed to passively excepting it as a matter of nature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There could be any number of reasons for why this is becoming more popular.  Perhaps young people aren’t being taught more tradition methods of speaking than they were before.  Maybe people aren’t getting married as often as before, so they don’t hear the phrase enough.  Or perhaps, as English and the western world becomes more prevalent in Japan, people are becoming more direct and affirmative when expressing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Connections to Budo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a practitioner of a budo martial arts, we also seek for our movements to become natural.  In the beginning, we chose to study a martial art of our own free will (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;).  We all have our reasons for wanting to do it, whether it be for health, for friends, for fun, or because it looks cool.  We start from ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There Japanese word &lt;span class='ja'&gt;習う&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;narau&lt;/i&gt; means "to learn", but literally, it means "to continually repeat things" and becoming accustomed to it.  As a result, over time, these actions become natural.  You no longer need to think to do them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Budo, we strive for this level of movement where the thought process is no longer a factor, and to become part of nature, the natural flow of life (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  When movements and actions are not performed naturally, they are not seen as being complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Kyudo (archery), for example, when one reaches the level of complete mastery, the practitioner feels that the bow no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;The 3 points of Japanese Thought&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the balance of &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the concept of Japanese thought and 3 points that define it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;自然&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;shizen&lt;/i&gt; - nature&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;意気&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt; - will power&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;諦念&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt; - resignation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of &lt;b&gt;nature&lt;/b&gt; leads to accidental fury that was must put up with.  It’s something that we must endure and grow from.  &lt;b&gt;Will power&lt;/b&gt; is the willingness to put your body on line for what may happen.  And if something goes wrong, it’s your responsibility to &lt;b&gt;resign&lt;/b&gt; yourself to the outcome, and not make excuses for the result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though, resignation does not mean to simply give up.  It’s about reconciling the efforts of one’s will with the movement of nature, and to be able to see something clearly for what it is.  And in some cases, recognize your powerlessness to deal with whatever comes.  We take for granted our power over nature and often think that we can overcome it, but in reality we cannot.  Nature is a much greater force.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;申し訳ない&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;moushi wakenai&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This phrase literally translates to "there were no reasons behind my actions" or "there is no verbal excuse for what I have done."  This is used as a strong apology in Japanese, but an actual apology means to explain your actions and why you were wrong.  This goes one step further by saying there can be no excuse for the action I’ve done.  In this way, you’ve accepted the outcome (resigned) and take full responsibility (will power).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;すみません&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumimasen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is used as a light apology and basically means &lt;b&gt;excuse me&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;sorry&lt;/b&gt;, but the direct and complete translation is something closer to "my actions were not clear or clean or complete," or "I wasn’t able to completely do this action myself."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Other Japanese Words&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like the lecture on the cardinal virtues of Japan, speaker Seiichi Takeuchi wrote several books on the subject of &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.  He wrote 4 books, actually.  3 of which are out-of-print and expensive!  On Amazon, they are being sold for nearly 7000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.  But, there was one book I could buy for only 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1QxsUo-FzLcdJABzLKDwiUVNpwp_yaZs5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1tGlVlvR5HrQPmrJ7ZLMIuOIi5RwR-5aq" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「おのずから」と「みずから」のあわいで&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;やまと言葉で&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;哲学する&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;i&gt;onozukara to mizukara no awai de yamato-kotoba de tetsugaku-suru&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;i&gt;Awai&lt;/i&gt; isn’t so easy to translate, but I was told, in this context, that it basically means between.  Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; talked about this balance between both &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; in his lecture, so I think it makes sense.  &lt;i&gt;Yamato-kotoba&lt;/i&gt; basically means words (&lt;i&gt;kotoba&lt;/i&gt;) that encompass the spirit of Japan (&lt;i&gt;yamato&lt;/i&gt;).  And lastly, &lt;i&gt;tetsugaku&lt;/i&gt; is philosophy.  So, the title is basically &lt;b&gt;The Philosophy of Japanese Words and Their Existence Between the Balance of &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book starts off with a quick summary and definition for &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;, and then has chapter on specific Japanese words, phrases, or expressions, their history, and their connection to &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=15O--vfjvvxTUILT3ud41EMwJL4zKpuTD"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nviBkuSfALzyaI8H-lfMf_MTc3U862kR" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ありがたい&lt;/span&gt; (thanks), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;めでたい&lt;/span&gt; (congratulations), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;あう&lt;/span&gt; (when meeting someone), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;あいする&lt;/span&gt; (loving someone), and so forth.  Maybe in the future, I’ll try and go through some of these chapters and write something about them.  For many people, though, Japanese philosophy is an incredibly dense topic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Relation to Myself&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1vatrNiCsgOmRwnn3vtQTS-EC-BD_hQD0"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14f_ebtjeh6vlsqM3467R6HhCVaV8BCGC" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Lecture Abstract&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese will often say things like &lt;i&gt;kekkon suru koto ni natta&lt;/i&gt; (I am to be married) or &lt;i&gt;shuushoku suru koto ni natta&lt;/i&gt; (I am to start work).  It should be expressed as "I decided to …"  Even if something is decided by the will of the individual (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;), it is expressed as something that has been predetermined for him or her as a matter of course (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  This in turn indicates a tendency to accept things in one’s life and the world as being naturally preordained and to be accepted passively.  The Japanese philosophers Kuki Shuuzou identified three elements in the features of Japanese thought: "nature" (&lt;i&gt;shizen&lt;/i&gt;), "chic" (&lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt;), and "resignation" (&lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt;).  This means that based on "natural" (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) conduct, when something occurs the individual decides from one’s self (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;) to confront the situation putting their own body on the line (for example, seppuku) in the spirit of "chicness" (&lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt;), while also resigning (&lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt;) the self to go with the natural flow (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  The culture of Japanese thought is considered within the encounter between the movement of nature (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) and exertion of the self (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese budo culture is the same.  According to Kuki, "The ideas of Japanese morality maintain a significant meaning in universal nature (of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;)…  Morality which must reach the stage of becoming 'natural' cannot be seen as complete."  The term "morality" (&lt;i&gt;doutoku&lt;/i&gt;) can be replaced by the word "budo" here.  In bud, first engaging in rigorous training or study from your own volition (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;), if it does not ultimately become an inevitably natural (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) activity then it "cannot be seen as complete."  To "&lt;i&gt;narau&lt;/i&gt;" (learn) means "to continually repeat things" thereby gradually becoming accustomed (&lt;i&gt;nare&lt;/i&gt;) to it, and "reaching the stage where it is natural."  In the culture of Japanese bud, there are correlations with moral, religious, and artistic thought in that one’s own efforts (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;) will finally proliferate into and connect with natural expansiveness and depth (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  Seen in this way, the features and potential become apparent.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/the-features-and-potential-of-japanese-budo-culture</link></item><item><title>Funayama 船山 in Winter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in a while, I had a day off with no plans at all.  I woke up around 6:15am, as usual, and looked out the window to see a beautiful site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1i74fuBKlhEyfQOVWS_PaMLjQUAfUdGjY"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ONvLmAOR1FTiy2NRGtXhRbc2yg-uw5fk" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mt. Norikura looked gorgeous.  The sky was quite clear.  And the sun was just below the true horizon about the rise.  I decided to grab my coat, put on my shoes, get in my car, and drive south to Funayama to catch one of the most fantastic views in Takayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to Funayama about a year and a half ago (&lt;a href="/funayama"&gt;November 5th, 2016&lt;/a&gt;) and it was incredibly easy.  Because of the cell reception station and towers at the top of the mountain, there’s a paved road that goes all the way up.  And because of those buildings, I assumed the entire way would be plowed for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I was half right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1usla0Qm7sv5a9A0bXLSkSHScDuPs8Mxi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1SlMRgK40Z8Y560lgaM368Xgmu0TEpzQj" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XXSu9RqxNPIB0glThPMafO_CIqelRglH"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1EoxWtymi4fnU1CEfQmf_2W5AJGQzwhmn" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road leading to the top was plowed up to the cabins.  The sign near the fork of the road said it was another 2 km before reaching the top.  I thought, "that’s not that far.  I can run that in about 15 minutes."  Though, that would be on a flat course with no snow and ice.  I parked my car and started going up the path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow had hardened since it had fallen over a month ago.  With each step, I had to dig my boot into the snow to keep traction and move forward.  It wasn’t hard.  Just annoying.  If I had remembered to bring my snowshoes, I could have doubled my pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1HLgSuhP8w9o8N5DkWEkubFFD90oj8rD9"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1olreQTKrAiaUHVdAIZNFxDrJQwN-Tulb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=11f6gg-VJHw4UMy179lrE8noyCVe8Qzu7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1z7jDrA1OST8XvSEiUg-7YZ6AHNeW2UgR" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me about 15 minutes to travel half a kilometer, and that’s when I reached a fork in the road.  The road was in the process of being plowed, but it was still too slippery for my car.  It was still too slippery for my boots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road curved around back and forth to make up the vertical distance without being too steep.  With each turn, a small building through the trees became more and more visible.  When I moved around the last turn, it was in clear site, as was the edge of the hill it sat on top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1PLGirsYoHGZ2AoHvljrFRoBjZdLeQsr5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=15xM9t0LWWeHfO3CrqDoCTDbHip8eCUME" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LCcMNUnMwCe_N7bnwL-uyz7qrNdMLdHl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qukXS57m2PqnlmInrjXuStHcyKkORZzE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1RT1wh7JfQvwox1uskvGwQS5roYZbYQ0p"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1GiGbgocWPtdhBp_hWi2T4gMqnDuVw3_5" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the top of the Arkopia ski hill on the Takayama-facing side of Funayama.  From the top of the hill, Mt. Ontake, Mr. Norikura, and the Mt. Hotaka range were all in clear view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1RIO0TYGaWjht4bSzNcTZmHp2RqNvnOAF"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1rJ-yLXG5qk6CTDj2Lq-nYP74qL_IFvZd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dQC-UESaYNtfctIvl42HcGbdxPXyKiJu"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aX3KiFPKF_hQmnxH9q46iYMMId5joP37" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a beautiful site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still had another kilometer left to climb, but having been up there before, the view was basically identical.  It would’ve taken me another hour to drudge up through the snow and take more photos of the view I already had in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took several pictures from where I was, but then headed back down to my car.  Most of the trip was sliding down the road using the flat trends of my boots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14gKN4BsnYoUo5c4JKHr-r1gqgO4p4V2q"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LD4ouWIYM2vSdvSNuAaKUD7bVd7tdePt" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ever get the chance, whether it be summer or winter, Funayama offers one of the best views in the whole region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Timeline&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:09am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Camp Site &lt;span class='ja'&gt;キャンプ場所&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026147, 137.253332"&gt;36°01'34.1"N 137°15'12.0"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:22am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Road Fork &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026979, 137.249255"&gt;36°01'37.1"N 137°14'57.3"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:36am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Arkopia Peak &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.027811, 137.246809"&gt;36°01'40.1"N 137°14'48.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:49am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Left Arkopia Peak &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.027811, 137.246809"&gt;36°01'40.1"N 137°14'48.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:01am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Road Fork &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026979, 137.249255"&gt;36°01'37.1"N 137°14'57.3"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:13am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Camp Site &lt;span class='ja'&gt;キャンプ場所&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026147, 137.253332"&gt;36°01'34.1"N 137°15'12.0"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/funayama-in-winter</link></item></channel></rss>