<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>&lt;b&gt;One Schlock's Requiem&lt;/b&gt; is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher on English living in central Japan.</description><link>http://theschlock.com/</link><item><title>Pocket Camera with Zoom Lens</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I finished putting together the Pocket Camera Plus for the Gameboy. This takes all of the original hardware of the GameBoy Camera and puts it into a shell that you can attach actual Camera lens. You can read more about here: &lt;a href="/gameboy-camera-plus"&gt;/gameboy-camera-plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1eQ78nI7iUwrSM6gqmodPLkvpuCi_WSXw" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attached to the Pocket Camera Plus, I'm using a pretty generic and bare bones Zoom lens. I just bought whatever was cheapest on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B07H2VTQX9"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. It has manually focus, zoom, and aperture, and has a focus length of 6mm up to 60mm. I guess that means it has a 10x zoom. Each of the rings has a pin used for movement, but these pins can be screwed in to keep the current setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the manual settings of the lens, the GameBoy Camera game has a Contrast and Brightness setting. Contrast is very important to reduce the harsh lights and darks coming into the camera. There is some automatic brightness control that the camera already does. This makes the manual aperture nearly useless. And even the digital brightness settings in the game can get overridden by the software trying to autocorrect the brightness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the following photos, I really only used the manual Zoom and Focus, and digital Contrast when taking photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with my Pocket Camera and regular Camera, I went around town throughout the weekend and tested it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Sakurano Park &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桜野公園&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's Spring in Takayama, so the Cherry Blossoms are in full boom. One of the best places to view cherry blossoms in Takayama is northwest of the main town. On the way to Kokufu, Sakurano Park is off to the side of the highway on the other side of the river. It's the perfect place to have a picnic on a warm Spring afternoon while viewing the cherry blossoms. (Although, this Spring has been freezing with the occasional snow)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took some photos in late evening as the sun was setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZrDOLk33tDjglBgiVzJe_9bYCCNkWdBO"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZnNN8R-1tKyMIAxZPq7F_MclKiu-9KKr" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xl6fm9JzcIRpNynSD0D5wnrxachWb1hE" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_0ijUhrW47m_Vk5Ly8Rkg-Wox6Im1SrM"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZzdehSSdUBVV3JRA_v-JGpFLYyGPyay9" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xg3_TWUVa3uk9qBE5G6nSQH3u6qzxJdV" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aDsWYM3ewHcfEiIzHKqfwyab5UxIWvbv"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1a4Mgy3Yq-TvvWN0elp7H8CYGV3R86_eQ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y9hZAxZNKj2GfnvjKJkEDTZ6932rcZSf" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aQRly9y16KWiF91lgjK884Jds7xXYJQx"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aQIz5uUuGF2il5wvvQfJhg7sLVLvmTAS" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YHb5xne8-SG0KfkYFCe1kFQ4uSKygXM8" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1b4bK3DQkIVgOj8Aa_u8BqMiwSXX_tuze"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1b1lqGWvn_wAumpUJe3GH4Qj2_jdVG5vs" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YMRgev_VAhCEEe2QEkaHjAz4wXfh_BQ5" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Camera lens gives an incredible amount of flexibility when taking photos. No matter how close or how far away from the subject, the zoom allows you to frame the photo and the focus allows you to get all of the detail. The sensor itself is still primitive by only allowing 4 colors, but you can still get a ton of clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, photos are best taken when the subject is clearly light. If there is no strong light source, then it can be hard to squeeze out detail. 4 colors can only do so much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Shiroyama Park &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城山公園&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day, I went to Shiroyama Park downtown and took a few more photos. Shiroyama sits above the town, so I was able to really test out of the Zoom lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YmVeMYY_GQi062iuBwQgSNB_bdHd_jj2" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YhHAouBBCvocwzg6RbjJrm6lSRNkhE5n" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Yo3LAL7gk4_bj-45boC-0DXq6SXYgrTu" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1b4tMAKI_8Aefk_Tv3ETfPsdusPbusyJ2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bINO3XzrNvMLXl5s-i4TzLM6Zf-yiyjM" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tiny camera lens can zoom in further than my actual camera! It's pretty incredible how far it can go. Each of those photos would be smaller than a pixel using the original GameBoy camera hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a few more photos from around the park. I walked a little bit around town, too, and took some photos there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bOO6mb5yIHLWTjczpMak8jeMjB7Ft-Ng"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bNGHZ2C9nQL00dsj8kMAdfWc44jJM-Wd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YkPBNQAvXN1BdXOS22a6DW1PLeC0PrRy" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bjdkbUG5AreYJZe9wAwgL-zP9K6PCoQb"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1beHiSpnFrMubKn7kjx7QTOQqa-vT4aDS" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z4cQHRtGb8stP-sucWrgKP1ZQWi7AMtb" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dGO6uq0sZnUpf_9wQ3rwrUdlDpD49M2v"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1d8BQwIlNEmqv5nPcU4fIz4BGNNahbcBG" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z81l_fWnDXSrVX8zcJDxqWur2sCCCNMn" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1cOCRCQZLz07ryEs1TVeCOYtIRwIXLhzc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ccv8QaI5jd1wkeV2OI2WAb33b5rVv2XU" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YvCpRmb23bnqvjvEWGdupxjpehYw8CKX" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1cha_YrvPaYR7Gy0vOXN7ZarsM0QaFBDT"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1cfwf5zKnp_Dpq2U3UD2XrreJvAG60A5J" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YuI1iw3i6vJ7t-UVNWCtix3mlAwNFjhY" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the Pocket Camera works best if you have a well-light subject. But, additionally, you need to have a lot of contrast between your subject and the background. If you subject blends into the background a little, the Pocket Camera isn't going to have a way of showing the difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Skypark &lt;span class='ja'&gt;スカイパーク&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To complete the day, I went to Sky Park.  Sky Park is the easiest assessable, most dynamic observation point in town. You can view around half of the town from this point with a clear view. All of the eastern and northeastern mountains are visible, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a massive panoramic with the regular camera and many zoomed shots with the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dXXdmbhTukSh-pIU1H1tuRA3xo2rx5Uu"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dcJ_wNjIW1diwuuSTRQpDI3zTpc5vica" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z7WlSV-5yMVNdKbN-xUZvlc2X-9UNrHL" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZGKoCbotmn5kjwAObkgCYdOxxMa8y3H_" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZF2Xhx0fR9gyvjrKjkMIBaik5blw_gYY" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, it's incredible how much detail can be squeezed into the GameBoy camera with this lens, and how far it can zoom in. But, there is still one small problem. With the lens zoomed in so far, it's a little difficult to steady the camera. I might invest it a heavier, steadier tripod than the flimsy one I already have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a few specific shots of the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1du461UjElVpf056s0uLID-Hv06bPJRgy"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ds1y30EZQYIRsWhpFPdKKpugSaTEZhlH" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZcLcqtipmGuaQ3pUm-JE5oWYT9Nak_mW" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1eMjy2ILBrPikjV6WnsVMH3sl93Hl6h2S"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dxPK61-G4BR5nnBcZRaho-NVWvo5xTcb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZZ6mgu5ACpCSADIXf04UCXZcqm4ROQX-" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the native features of the GameBoy Camera software is being able to adjust the Contrast. By pulling that way down, you can get a lot of detail from the mountains, even if they're mostly white.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I concluded my photo journey by taking a panorama of Mt. Norikura, which towers over Takayama. The resolution of each Pocket Camera photo is 128x112, so taking a panoramic photo can boost the resolution considerably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZW5_JahuLpP2Vv-VsfL_l7I8zTNv1_0j" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dqntHUIwOGfyr-LfMBiptER_OfjhOQyl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dponqr8n6mC5xyPavR6hV4aYY9yhxtXe" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GameBoy Camera is over 25 years old now, so it's pretty fun being to squeeze as much functionality as possible out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-camera-with-zoom-lens</link></item><item><title>GameBoy Camera Plus</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in February, people began circulating a video about a mod for the GameBoy Camera. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xnSb0cRK9xI"&gt;Macho Nacho made a video&lt;/a&gt; about how you could take apart your GameBoy camera, and put it into a new shell created by 2BitToy. This shell used a CS mount ring, which would allow you to attach any CS mount camera lens to the GameBoy camera. People have made GameBoy Camera mods before. But, this was the first non-destructive, compact, and stable modification made easily available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the website detailing the mod: &lt;a href="https://2bittoy.carrd.co/"&gt;https://2bittoy.carrd.co/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looked really simple and it wasn't too expensive. The Analogue Pocket has recently revived my interest in retro handheld accessories, so I ordered all of the parts and let things slowly arrive over time. Now that it's Spring Break, it's time to put everything together!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XGaVqTAMV4gJ2t17C2r_bRvbL9gL-jDY"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XFCpi0BeN9cRHD0pvp72KpcQji8fuS2c" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was really surprised how fast and easy it came together. You can look through the pictures below to see how I assembled everything together. Macho Nacho's video also shows the step-by-step process of putting together the camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;One thing to note!&lt;/b&gt; In Macho Nacho's video, he doesn't recommend using this mod with the Analogue Pocket. However, he's using Version 1 of the 3D printed shell. When I purchased the parts, Shapeways had Version 2. Version 2 is a little fatter than the original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X3PxN8woNIQhSWV9oqIP42iI_JMWN8qT"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X4EhtHk47T4182gfcYiyxZKSchhyTh8S" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the whole thing assembled, it is really tight when fitting it into the cartridge slot of the Analogue Pocket. This may or may not be a problem in itself, BUT there is no movement of the cartridge after it's inserted. It is very solid. That said, when actually taking pictures, I'm not going to hold it like a GameBoy. I plan on holding it in the middle to balance all of the weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Assembly&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 overall steps required to make this once you've gathered all of the parts: (1) taking apart a GameBoy Camera, (2) glueing the CS mount ring and IR filter, and (3) putting everything together. I let the Epoxy sit overnight to harden, but otherwise, it took me no longer than an hour to do everything. It was really fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would recommend glueing the CS mount ring and IR filter first. Then, the disassembly and assembly can be done together very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Required Parts and Tools for Building&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=167-B4p7nlcl8f9Jivzues3sQxyZZrAX0"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16Ye34uRIeE4k-h_7Tz_AauUyKldEROiH" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Macho Nacho's video details all of the parts and tools you'll need, but I'll reiterate them here for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 main set of parts you'll need to create the Camera Plus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. You'll need an original &lt;b&gt;GameBoy Camera&lt;/b&gt;. You'll take this apart and use the insides. If you don't already have one, you'll have to search on eBay for one. I got one from Yahoo Auctions for 2930&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; with shipping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. You'll need a set of &lt;b&gt;3D printed plastic components&lt;/b&gt; to create the new shell for the Camera. You can print them yourself using the files from 2BitToy's website. Or, you can buy printed ones from ShapeWays. There are 4 total: The front and back shell, the sensor mount, and the IR filter mount. With shipping to Japan, this was $92.83&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.shapeways.com/shops/2bittoy"&gt;https://www.shapeways.com/shops/2bittoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. This is optional, but it's probably worth it. You'll need a &lt;b&gt;10mm x 1.0mm IR Filter&lt;/b&gt;. Linked below is the one that I purchased. It was 1200&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B07GFMMK5V"&gt;https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B07GFMMK5V&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. You'll need a &lt;b&gt;5mm CS Mount Lens ring&lt;/b&gt;. This will be glued to the back shell and used to screw in the lens. It was 816&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B01N0XBD6A"&gt;https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B01N0XBD6A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Lastly, you'll need a &lt;b&gt;CS Mount Zoom Lens&lt;/b&gt;. This is the one I purchased. Only 2660&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B07H2VTQX9"&gt;https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B07H2VTQX9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Altogether, the materials cost 7606&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; and $92.83, a total of about $150. Actually, I suppose this isn't so cheap after all. Although, your mileage may vary depending on how cheap you can get a GameBoy Camera and Lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Required Tools&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You'll also need a few totals to disassemble the GameBoy Camera and glue some parts together. This adds a little bit more to the grand total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. You probably already have a &lt;b&gt;Phillips screwdriver&lt;/b&gt;, but you need to have one fine enough to remove small screws. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. You'll also need &lt;b&gt;Epoxy&lt;/b&gt; to glue the Lens ring to the back shell and the IR filter to its mount. You may already have this, but it's easy to buy at your local hardware store. You can see the brand I purchased from my photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Something you probably don't have is a &lt;b&gt;Tri-point screwdriver&lt;/b&gt;. Old Nintendo products used screws with three divots in them, rather than a flat-head or a Phillips. I did not already have this. They are readily available on Amazon, though. I bought the following one.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B0162MMGSS"&gt;https://www.amazon.co.jp/-/en/gp/product/B0162MMGSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Photo Results&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is uncanny how much definition and versatility this modification adds to the GameBoy. You can take a picture from across the room by zooming in and focusing using the dials on the lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XM44_L2fRvtkpvH4NosMQL1S7LNrbZ4o"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XI-thEyYXTcvZHCHOKHD6rtO1p0C-rcY" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XfLjlxyg-yPUIVYQ6OlQTmgiq3Aq9bJF"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XSrN5HPLdQKzLcCJBfu5cOJja_-6-KPa" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can't wait to take this thing out in the field and take some photos.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/gameboy-camera-plus</link></item><item><title>Pokemon x Kogei ポケモンx工芸</title><description>&lt;p&gt;From March 21st through June 11th, the National Craft Museum in Kanazawa, Ishikawa is hosting an exhibit entitled, Pokemon x Kouge. Kouge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;工芸&lt;/span&gt; is Japanese for crafts, such as pottery, woodworking, and any other profession that designs and creates materials and works. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1BbIqdbSVvk0QdqyafIUuAzAsLi8YiTP4"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1BQnSZGqNGuhdJiit2mw0JGs-nt1I6UEN" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;20 Japanese artisans and craftsmen, from young to old, were challenged with how they could incorporate Pokemon into their works. How could they make something that could display the essence of a Pokemon, whether it be through their appearance, gestures, or traces of gameplay through trading, evolving, or battling? How would a particular Pokemon's personality or history clash or match with traditional crafts? With these questions and ideas, they have created over 70 original works displayed in this exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the website: &lt;a href="https://kogei.pokemon.co.jp/"&gt;https://kogei.pokemon.co.jp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, here's the exhibit brochure:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/15OGmZfPQhPQv0CRP-g5c4rFEikUeRzLK/view?usp=sharing"&gt; https://drive.google.com/.../15OGmZfPQhPQv0CRP-g5c4rFEikUeRzLK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A friend sent me a link to this exhibit. I had seen a link about it before, but I didn't realize it was in Kanazawa. So close! I thought it was in Tokyo, or Osaka, or something. So, I went there on Thursday March 30th and arrived around 11:30am. There was a line to enter, but I only had to wait 20 minutes. Not too bad for a Thursday. They had reservation tickets available, which would probably be necessary on weekends. Individual tickets were 900&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. You can buy tickets online, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exhibit was divided into three sections: Appearance, Stories, and Life. All of my photos are included at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;すがたーせまる&lt;/span&gt;！ Appearance - Approach!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1BsoG31uSkerBQhu46ipE6PZroF5kT0jz"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Bt8gjx3lF9bP8CaSutKI4fUdJ7ZOPS1t" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first room were works inspired by the appearance of the Pokemon. How does a Pokemon's appearance inspire these craftsmen to use their mastery to develop artwork that evokes both the spirit of the Pokemon and a demonstration of the mastery of their craft. This section featured artwork from Yoshida Taiichiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;吉田泰一郎&lt;/span&gt; and Mitsuta Haruo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;満田晴穂&lt;/span&gt; (both Metal Works), Fukuda Toru &lt;span class='ja'&gt;福田亭&lt;/span&gt; (Wood Works), and Imai Sadamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;今井完眞&lt;/span&gt; and Hayama Yuki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;葉山有樹&lt;/span&gt; (Ceramics).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite pieces from this section was the Jolteon by Yoshida Taiichiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;吉田泰一郎&lt;/span&gt; (pictured above), and the vase and bowl entitled "Vase with Pokemon of the Universe" &lt;span class='ja'&gt;森羅万像ポケモン壷&lt;/span&gt; and "Beautiful Bowl with the Super-Ancient of Pokemon" &lt;span class='ja'&gt;超古代ポケモン玉盌&lt;/span&gt;. Both were created by Hayama Yuki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;葉山有樹&lt;/span&gt;. (pictured below)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pokemon vase was interesting because you could stare at it for hours searching for various Pokemon and continue to find new ones you hadn't before. Also, I love how the Hoenn legendary pokemon are depicted in the Beautiful Bowl, clashing the power of fire, water, and wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DtLMmXO1FSM4WdTE2GoeZjDoPtxh5IvL"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Doq2tQz81xb47qjcnZvG2LVMTn4eLGma" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DWibCzMt7iR-CDGdFi0OefIR0TsHxqV9"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DTRbLIvgIp6BcbCySmI_q2QSu2u4G61I" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;ものがたりー浸る&lt;/span&gt;！ Stories - Jump in!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second room features works inspired by the aspects of the Pokemon adventure, such as catching, battling, and evolving. While collecting Pokemon themselves is very much core to the series, the journey of the starting off at the beginning and slowly growing and strengthening your Pokemon and yourself as you become the strongest trainer in the land is equally inspiring. Works in this section were created by Tanaka Nobuyuki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;田中信行&lt;/span&gt; and Ikeda Terumasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;池田晃将&lt;/span&gt; (Lacquerware), Niimi Hiroki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;新實広記&lt;/span&gt;and Ikemoto Kazumi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;池本一三&lt;/span&gt; (Glass Works), Hayashi Shigeki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;林茂樹&lt;/span&gt; (Ceramics), Tsuboshima Yuuki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;坪島悠貴&lt;/span&gt; (Metal Works), and Shiromi Eiichi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城間栄市&lt;/span&gt; and Sudou Reiko &lt;span class='ja'&gt;須藤玲子&lt;/span&gt; (Textiles).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1H2X8MMTDvpcFgOH02xJO4lJDHPItMFvZ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1HJdiRT0RGJgjbBsvtEVdkwCZxFYCDvz3" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hayashi Shigeki's Robot (Moonlight) greeted everyone when the reached the top of the stairs. All of the vases were really goofy, and the yukatas were pretty. The Yukatas, created by Shiromi Eiichi, were made using a Bingata pattern-style, traditional to Okinawa. These have repeated patterns of nature using primary colors of red, blue, yellow, green, and pink. The Alola starters, Pikachu, Raichu, and Oricorio fit both the pattern of colors, and island theme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest standouts to me were the transformable Rookidee figures which "evolve" into Corviknight, by Tsuboshima Yuuki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;坪島悠貴&lt;/span&gt;. Obviously the size is off, but the proportions of both Pokemon are perfect, and coming up with a design to allow them to transform into each other is fascinating. The Pikachu forest, created by Sudou Reiko &lt;span class='ja'&gt;須藤玲子&lt;/span&gt; was definitely the center piece of the room. (both pictured below)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1IO0CvcQR5IxFFoO8uGblZDtIJiY0f2Zx"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1IRsMdLjG-oV6xsoJIn7BzZfF4cfQojZ-" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1JIDLPCKNo7YrMkYuGaw1-e0SJO1BL2XK"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1IzYMHHAK5kIsi94CXDoogHAzJb5RsZyq" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LGT_9sYnNNbS8N6SBoAtX49ZEyODgI7c"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LgWyBg4usSlbbTi3T-F1ilL5Ur0CN03S" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;くらしー愛でる&lt;/span&gt;！Life - Cherish&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final room of the exhibit showcased works that incorporated Pokemon into the artists' medium. How can the flame of the Pokemon match the fires of the kiln when baking jars? How can the spirit and energy of Pokemon enlighten kimono and ornaments used in festivals? Craftsmen from this section include Katsura Morihito &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桂盛仁&lt;/span&gt; (Metal Works), Taguchi Yoshiaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;田口義明&lt;/span&gt; (Lacquerware), Kuwata Takuro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桑田卓郎&lt;/span&gt;, Ueba Kasumi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;植葉香澄&lt;/span&gt;, and Masumoto Keiko &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桝本佳子&lt;/span&gt; (Ceramics), and Mizuhashi Saori &lt;span class='ja'&gt;水橋さおり&lt;/span&gt; and Komiya Yasuyoshi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小宮康義&lt;/span&gt; (Textiles).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most notable pieces in the room were the pottery created by Masumoto Keiko. The Charizard and Charmander pots made sense being fire Pokemon. The Ninetales pot was especially interesting as the inside of the pot was brown and burnt like the Kantonian form, but the outside was glazed white, like the Alolan form. I liked her Moltres piece the most. Moltres appears by breaking out of an egg with flames. I think the other standouts in the room where all of the figures created by Ueba Kasumi, especially the Shaymin figure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1NW8E0B_HF81DKmNFmOnZCdOyxTtMNmrN"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1NRjbvr41_JNGUW9k3p2r4Tjopjmqn5Hv" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Ti_wyseQd7h7msf_4R14Hwu6OMk_dI_b"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1TlKwyNUwgyULXCeBvwt1-F3LLVnHbICC" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Kogei Catalogue&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best thing about every museum and museum exhibit in Japan is that the gift shop sells a book detailing each piece on display. All of the text from the exhibit, photos of each piece, and more information about the artists, pieces, and creation are included in this book. It's exceptional as a momento to remember and recall the exhibit in the future as well as learn more about the artists and artwork you were able to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pokemon Kogei Catalogue is 168 pages for only 3000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. As an added bonus, the book is bilingual in English and Japanese. I was able to use it as reference when writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1UiV-NonLSxOfQTNsfZG5zGbht0hsvw2b"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1UgvBaoSzFCrmyLMg3X3utA0DMNQbPpyw" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V9t2qOMksruyqBkBbKRJeqoEwk_mcvx7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V6vwQ3FnUQrswsNfqkZphpW4TpN3FLpK" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the exhibit runs until June 11th, so if you're able to travel to Kanazawa, I would recommend taking a look!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-kogei</link></item><item><title>Takachiyo - Wildlife Resaurant</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Along the Shou river and within the various Gasshou-style villages in southern Toyama prefecture, there is a restaurant that stands alone on the side of the road with a bear of its sign. Underneath, there's another sign that says &lt;span class='ja'&gt;くま丼&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;I&gt;Kuma-don&lt;/I&gt;, or a Bear Bowl, which would be a bowl of rice with bear meat. Nearly 6 years ago, I saw this sign as teachers and I were going exploring on our way to Kanazawa. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19mxrEiXyDFdROub2-WG6lwDoJy01_yEc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19oS7eMqz42aF6TX6ey8reG_Ci2rLWG8s" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;b&gt;Takachiyo&lt;/b&gt;, a restaurant that serves dishes made from the meat of local wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the sign is very noticeable, its location is very out-of-the-way. It's about halfway between Takayama and Toyama along the highway, but it's about 10 minutes away from the highway exit. Most people from Takayama don't take the highway when going to Toyama because Route 41 has no tolls and takes the same amount of time. Route 41 goes a completely different direction through the mountains, so it never connects to the highway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the location: &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/rMrJCJTr8JSQVviW9"&gt;https://goo.gl/maps/rMrJCJTr8JSQVviW9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I went to Kanazawa, so on my return trip, I finally had the opportunity to visit the restaurant again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19yO6x3xG-mXOm6SkPtsQ_uyxHJsNbCNZ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19w_KJtObViiQzK8B-Z7V3ugwhr9qlsBv" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides bear meat, the hunter that owns the restaurant, also traps deer and boar from the surrounding mountains. All of his dishes are prepared using local ingredients, including mountain vegetables, rice, and noodles. Soba noodles are hand-made from buckwheat grown by local people. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The menu mentions that killing animals for money is evil. However, we all live by consuming plants and animals. We must give thanks to them before each meal (and live together with them, in nature). This is the basic explanation of "Ittedakimasu," which is the 'grace' we all say before we eat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1AQ-cLOzlLIHU_eDYgJoBPEk3tFwHTJz-"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1AHJ5yF5p7VHdRBRaOHsBXMXEjapfW20r" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, on my first visit to Takachiyo, I ordered their signature dish, the &lt;span class='ja'&gt;くま丼&lt;/span&gt;. The bear meat was alright. It was tough and had a full taste, like beef. But, it also had a stringy-ness to it. Added with onions, eggs, and served on rice, it tasted delicious. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went with some friends, and they ordered other dishes. One of my friends got some deer nabe. Nabe is a bit bowl of boiling broth with lots of vegetables and meat. It's similar to stew, but stew's main base is meat. Nabe's main base are the vegetables. Nabe is very weak in comparison. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deer meat was alright. Japanese wild animals are much smaller compared with their American counterparts. They don't have gigantic bodies or gigantic muscles. As such, it didn't taste like venison I've had in the past. Again, more stringy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1AyiARkPrHnXIc3GlR0YFq3nmv4_MjfOW"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Av4XrV1z9KVf545PY__a__Tit4FeKHLm" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my meal today, I ordered a Boar Bowl and Boar Udon. Boar was the one animal I hadn't tried last time, so I wanted to complete the triangle. The boar meat in both dishes was rough, like a flank steak. The meat itself had a dry texture, even though it was submerged in the Udon broth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I would say that if you planned on going here to try exotic meats, you may leave disappointed. However, you would not be disappointed with the actual meals. While the meats themselves were just okay, the rice bowls and udon tasted excellent. Very good. Just good enough that I would recommend going out of the way to try and visit at least once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are plenty more things available on the menu than what I've ordered so far. He had English menus available to take, so I scanned it. Also, I still had a Japanese menu from the first time I visited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/15Lw6mF0HrQYN_gBHc9MDhQkoPgIfL4JF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1925JSCu5v6jGRx0gIw1OUKHr5vHpsOTH" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/15NTGQUMN1RD0nUQ8pbpfxWHcgamx_PF1/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19MpRZWC9vLrVcSkzwm3gZIpM-OkF7y01" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/takachiyo-wildlife-restaurant</link></item><item><title>The Last of Us</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Last of Us is a cross-country trek across a post-apocalyptic America. 20 years ago, the infection outbreak occurred, and spread within the highly populated areas and then to the rest of America and the world. People had survived, but many didn't. In present day, a governmental military organization runs strict quarantine procedures in many urban areas. Though, many had fallen to uprisings or further outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You play as Joel. As the outbreak occurred 20 years ago, he lost his daughter. But he continued to survive, doing anything that was necessary. In present day, he is tasked with bringing a young girl, Ellie, across the country in hopes of finding a cure for the infection. Throughout the journey, they experience loss and they gain trust and companionship with each other. Over time, Joel allows himself to love and be responsible for someone else again. Ellie as well, allow herself to trust someone unequivocally after being abandoned by everyone she's known in her life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1w0nQYtqBDJlar8cPB3bha1HfNpYBIkE_"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=136hsxYBop5CitJPgQDEexLViVsfFE5_x" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally released for the Playstation 3 in the fall of 2013, many people regard it to be one of the best stories of all time portrayed in a video game. After playing it for the first time, I thought it was okay. Zombies have been done to death, and this didn't really seem all that original. ESPECIALLY, when Telltale's Walking Dead game come out a year prior and roughly told the exact same story. I guess people liked Last of Us better because there was actual gameplay behind it, rather than only dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, 9 years after the release of the first game, HBO and Naughty Dog created The Last of Us TV show. The first season (of 9 episodes) covers the entirety of the first game. It is incredible how well the tension is portrayed in the show. Everything feels like it has weight. Pedro Pascal truly brings out how much Joel does not want to relive his daughter's death through having to take responsibility for Ellie. And Bella Ramsey perfectly portrays Ellie's care-free attitude that hides her true inner feelings. Their slow personality changes over their terrifying and horrific experiences feel authentic and help you identify with both of their situations and choices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the TV show, I felt like I understood the characters better than I had before. Also, it had been long enough since The Walking Dead and the overexposure of Zombie media, that I was more open to paying attention to the finer details of the story, rather than quickly writing it off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1zNPXsNzbt3rumDuVJVzGY0I1qCd10Gwc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16720wwoP71XSf4wyAiaus4uuePYjIcWp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of the TV show, I decided to replay The Last of Us again. There are 3 separate versions of The Last of Us, plus a standalone story, plus a sequel. Almost a year after the Playstation 3 release, the game was touched up and remastered for the Playstation 4 in 2014. The standalone story was included in this. With the overwhelming success of the game, The Last of Us Part 2 was released in 2020. And, they've remastered the original game again for the Playstation 5. The Last of Us Part 1 was released in September 2022. I played &lt;b&gt;Last of Us Remastered&lt;/b&gt; on Playstation 4 because I already owned it, and the Playstation 5 version was expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I finished it. It was very interesting comparing it to the TV show. There were plenty of parts that they changed to adapt the video game to television, but I was really surprised how much of it was identical. Same basic overall story beats, but with a bit more context added and a lot of action and fight scenes removed. I'm curious how much things changed in the Playstation 5 remaster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as I originally played the Playstation 3 version 9 years ago, I was very impressed with the environments. So much vegetation had reclaimed the concrete building over the 20 years since civilization had fallen. The Playstation 3 never had an option for screenshots, so I could never roam around taking photos in the game. Thankfully, screenshots became a standard addition with video games for the Playstation 4.  As I replayed Last of Us Remastered, I was to take all of the screenshots that I couldn't before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1rmSP6XXpMpvfsUcNanPYRHvwp_MY3AB8"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-04uhi2R6cki55MNSQjZik_baNUW6ueD" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1vQ4xYTuhBoT9pmyC2C2a6iSkYzMyBzcu"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=12M4TPzBCT7Imwz-qvbefRKcLKW2dr6dk" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1z-3hVOXQQlPsAMh6BspXH4jRB-QyhTFh"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=15wJI0m7sm-6SWp0J3ljvPzixcqWQG36C" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think in some areas, the age does show in the game. If you look close enough, you can see the seams in the graphics. But, even though the game is 8 or 9 years old, the overall composition of level design and art direction is undeniable gorgeous. It still looks quite incredible today.  All of my screenshots are included below, so take a look. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Last of Us complete, I plan on planning Last of Us Part 2 next, mainly to get ahead of any spoilers for the next season of the TV show. Although, there is an absolute major spoiler that I already know about as it was unavoidable to know unless you played the game immediately upon release. Thankfully, that's all I know about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope Last of Us 2 is just as beautiful as the first game.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/the-last-of-us</link></item><item><title>Vivillion Shiny Hunt</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Pokemon is filled with some unique evolution methods and forms across several species. Some may say that Vivillion is one of the more annoying Pokemon with its forms. But I think it was pretty interesting. It debuted as part of Pokemon X/Y, the first pokemon game on the Nintendo 3DS in 2013. Depending on the region of your game, a single certain form of Vivillion would be available out of a total of 18. There were 2 additionally forms released later as events, for a grand total of 20 forms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impetus was to connect and trade with people all over the world to get all of the forms, if you wanted them. But, because of this obtuse mechanic, they have not been available in any main game since. Two years ago, with the release of Pokemon Home, I decided to try and get all of the forms by doing trades and it didn't take me too long to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the release of Pokemon Scarlet/Violet in November, Vivillion had finally returned. However, only the &lt;b&gt;Fancy&lt;/b&gt; pattern (which was previously event only) was available in the game. All of the other forms were available in the game's code, but how could we get them? Things started to become slightly clearly when Scatterbug and Vivillion became available in Pokemon Go in December. Oh, we could just transfer them from Pokemon Go once Pokemon Home support came to Scarlet/Violet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to catch Scatterbug and Vivillion in Pokemon Go, you had to save Postcards received from Presents which you receive from Friends on your Friend's List from all over the world. If you saved 3 Postcards from a region, you'd get an encounter with a Scatterbug from that region. Evolve it to Vivillion to get that form. Some regions are more obscure than others, like Saudi Arabia and Hawaii essentially being their own regions, but it was not too tough to get them all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Vivillion Forms in Scarlet/Violet&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the release of Scarlet/Violet, connectivity between Pokemon SV and Pokemon Go had been hinted at with the new pokemon, Gimmighoul. Treasure Chest forms were available in Pokemon SV, while a separate exclusive Roaming form would be available in Pokemon Go. And, with the most recent &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qyfyd_t9mzs"&gt;Pokemon State of the Union&lt;/a&gt;, it was announced how you would do this and it had an extra benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to get Gimmighoul, you need to send a Postcard from Pokemon Go to Pokemon Scarlet/Violet. This gives you a Coin Purse in Pogo that works like an incense. Run the incense and Gimmighoul will spawn for the next 30 minutes. Additionally, every five days you'll get a Golden Lure. In order to evolve Gimmighoul, you need 999 coins, just like Pokemon SV. You get some by catching Gimmighoul, but you get a lot from Poke-stops with Golden Lures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, on the Scarlet/Violet side of things, whichever region was the origin of the Postcard determined which form of Vivillion would spawn over the next 24 hours. Now, it was possible to collect all of the Vivillion forms by yourself! AND, with shiny hunting specific pokemon SO SO easy in Pokemon SV, I decided that this would be my new goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Shiny Vivillion&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vivillion does spawn in the wild up in the north by the Fairy base. My route starts at where the Tera Sylveon spawns. I set down my pickup there, make a Bug Sandwich, and basically drive around in circles spawning and respawning Vivillions. Several other things spawn, too, which is annoying, but I quickly caught my first Shiny Vivillion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aFi5nbCtxL187s4FsLldxnD81JVqdKsH" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pattern of Vivillion's wings is identical to its non-Shiny form. The body is the only difference. It's pure white, rather than white and gray. It's difficult to notice at a glance, but when you are paying attention and now what to look for, it is noticeable enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can only send one postcard from Pokemon Go is a single day. However, you can connect multiple accounts and send multiple Postcards to Scarlet/Violet. I have two main accounts for Pokemon Go, plus an extra one that I only use for extra free stuff. So, I'm able to send 3 postcards in a single day. 18 regional forms with 3 postcards a day. That's only 6 days. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shiny Hunting is Pokemon SV still depends on random chance, but I can usually get a shiny to spawn within 30 minutes with a sandwich. If not? Just reset the game and try again. Just don't save after making a sandwich unless you get something you want to keep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got my first Shiny Vivillion on March 4th, and now only 2 weeks later, the collection is complete, including the whole evolution family, and a few extras that showed up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ePuTfSbmi2oXJwRbOz74PkQzGYP3X23V" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See all the individual shiny catches in the gallery below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Remains&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the 18 regional forms and the base Fancy form, there are 19 total forms available out of a total of 20 in Pokemon SV. Actually, only the regional forms are available in Pokemon Go at the moment. Maybe when Pokemon Home gets an update to include Pokemon Scarlet/Violet, we'll get some way of getting the Fancy form in Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, it's unclear how the &lt;b&gt;Pokeball Form&lt;/b&gt; of Vivillion will be introduced. Previously, it was available through an event only. Although, it makes the most sense that they'd be available through an event in Pokemon Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe for this year's Go Fest, when you spin stops at the event, you'll get a gift, and the postcard for that gift will give you the Pokeball form of Vivillion. Then, transfer that to Scarlet/Violet, and get your Vivillion that way, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/vivillion-shiny-hunt</link></item><item><title>Website Revival</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the Spring of 2014, I had finally built the website I had always wanted. Using the Tapestry framework and my web development experience, I wrote a site that could host all of my blog content I had written over the years and be extensible enough to easily change and build whatever I wanted into it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t manually building pages anymore, like I had been when I first made my website in 2003. My blog content wasn’t orphaned on another server, like when I moved to Movable Type in 2005. And, I was no longer stuck within the constraints of someone else’s design, like when I moved to Wordpress in 2006. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With my new website, I had built everything from scratch, which gave me complete full control over everything, which gave me the freedom to do anything. It was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost, anyways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tapestry is a very powerful framework, but for my particular setup at the time, it often crashed. Tapestry ran in Java, so to deploy the site on the Internet, it needed to be run in Tomcat. Once running Tomcat would serve the pages to whomever requested them. But, every two or three days, something within Tapestry or Tomcat would cause the site to be unresponsive. To fix this, I would turn it off and turn it back on again. Not a lot of people actually visited my site, so I don’t think anyone noticed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost three years, things were pretty good. Though, as usual, my posting became less frequent and I stopped visiting my site as often as before. One day, when I power cycled my website, it was gone. There was nothing on my server. Apparently, a month or two prior, my web server had failed its migration. Well, whatever. All of my code was a mirror of what I had locally. I’ll just copy everything over again and start it up. Not so. My web server had also dropped Java and Tomcat support after this migration. No word about this at all. They just deleted all of my stuff, dropped support, but still billed me every month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I looked around a little bit for a new web server. I tried one service, but I couldn’t get the site running. I continued to look around, but Tomcat support had become expensive for some reason. Maybe demand had dropped. I had thought about using cloud servers with Google which would homogenize my Internet eco-system further, but that was also more expensive that what I wanted. Also, it took me a while to figure out how to do it, and I was getting no where.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the site was dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of months, I have been doing a lot of programming and using GitHub thanks to the Analogue Pocket. One day I saw that someone had “hosted” their blog on Github. Looking further, you could also have your web domain point to these pages and mask itself as a real website. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh shit. Could I do this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHub is not a webserver, so it can’t run anything on the backend. Any webpage it hosts, would have to be static. Despite my website running Tapestry, almost all of my content is static. Yes, it uses a database, and Yes, the server is generating pages. But, the result is always the same. Anything that was dynamically generated from the server, could be changed to a separate page or rewritten in Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had often thought that if I could simply make my website a huge mess of HTML pages, then I could easily find hosting and it would absolutely never crash or be inaccessible. And GitHub was answer, because not only could it host these html pages, but it could do it for free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take me long to find the command line program, WGET. When run, it will crawl through a website and save everything locally. It didn’t take me long to write a &lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/schlock-website/blob/master/src/generate_website.sh"&gt;terminal script&lt;/a&gt; to save my entire website in HTML into a GitHub directory that could push back to the Github to be hosted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were still some broken links, dynamic links that needed to be changed, and the image gallery that needed to be re-written. A few weeks later, those were all solved. I cleaned up some old posts, and removed some problematic ones from 15+ years ago. I'm also hosting images directly from Google Drive. Now, I’ve written a few new posts to cover some topics from the last year. There are still some posts that I haven't written yet. You can see that progress &lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.io/issues/2"&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think everything is good enough to consider my website reopened. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first opened theschlock.com in August of 2003, so in just a few more months, it'll be the 20-year anniversary. My life has changed considerably since then, from college, to studying abroad, to working as a software developer, to moving to Japan and working in public schools, to now working in a private school. It's interesting to be able to look back and recall my thoughts during these times.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/website-revival</link></item><item><title>Application for Permanent Residence</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years ago, I moved to Japan. I didn’t necessarily intend to stay for more than a year or two, but I loved living here and loved teaching students. Teaching had become the most rewarding job I’ve done in my life, so I didn’t want to leave, and it never felt like my time in Japan was complete. Now, this is where I live. A town full of students or parents of students that I’ve helped teach for more than 10 years. And full of friends and connections that I’ve made over the years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that 10 years has passed, I can apply for Permanent Residence in Japan. In simple terms, Permanent Residence means that I no longer have to renew a work VISA after 3 years and I can buy or build a house. But to me, it means that I’m further established as a part of Japan and don’t intend to leave. It’s the near-equivalent to a Green Card in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying for Permanent Residence is not a simple process of filling out a couple of forms. There are many parts to prove your legal employment, payment of taxes, and contribution to Japan. I spent about a month working on the application back in October, only to have it rejected because I hadn’t lived here a complete 10 years yet. Now, 4 months later, my application is complete and it ended up being 47 pages long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V2PMuJ0sKPMmE7alxnhF88rrkmkHo71M"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V2PV8yY2R5QhHBFSLqUDaQqbZMvvzmiF"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so long that I wrote a Table of Contents describing everything that I included, and sectioned everything into different folders to make it as easy as possible for them to see what I’ve included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;b&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1.      &lt;b&gt;Application for Permanent Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;b&gt;Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3.      &lt;b&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;6.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;7.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;8.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10.    &lt;b&gt;Passport Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.    &lt;b&gt;Residence Card Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;12.    &lt;b&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;13.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Contributions to Japan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;14.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;15.    &lt;b&gt;Application Oath&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The instructions for how to apply for permanent residence can be found on the government Immigration website. They are written in &lt;a href="https://www.isa.go.jp/en/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;. My table of contents follows the list of required materials from that page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though, they have an English version that doesn’t necessarily mean it’s easy to figure out what to do. These instructions are machine translated, and you still need to understand what they’re saying in Japanese because of the specific names for forms, and the specific departments and locations you need to visit. There’s a lot of running around involved getting all the correct documents, so I have detailed everything I did to build my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;手数料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is not required when you submit your application, but it will be required after your application is successful. You must fill out the Payment form and attach an 8000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; revenue stamp to it. Revenue stamps can be purchased from the post office. Obviously, if you’ve been in Japan long enough, you already know how to do this from renewing your VISA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the payment form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application for Permanent Residence &amp; Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;永住許可申請書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;写真&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The first document is the application itself. Again, from renewing a VISA, all the same information is here with the addition of a short version of why you want permanent residence, work history, and guarantor information. For my reason, I wrote "I wish to obtain permanent residence to continue teaching in Japan indefinitely and continue my study of kendo and Japanese culture to further enrich myself." It sounds like a lofty reason, but I have fully explained it in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the application form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll need a 40mm x 30mm photo attached to your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;理由書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perhaps the part of this application that will take the longest is writing about why you want permanent residence in Japan. My short version stated that I wish to teach in Japan indefinitely and continue to learn about Japan, but those ideas are weak unless there is proof. In total, I wrote 3 pages about my time over the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started with detailing my current responsibilities and accomplishments working at my high school: supporting English teachers in class, leading English writing classes, being an assistant Homeroom teacher, leading classes to prepare students for studying abroad, training students for speech contests and winning them, and teaching foreign exchange students Japanese language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I detailed my accomplishments and responsibilities working in public elementary and junior high schools as part of the JET Programme, such as supporting English classes and training students for speech contests, but also volunteering in town for English conversations classes supporting the hospital and library, developing summer English camp and other events for students, and developing a full English curriculum for elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I detailed my responsibilities as a Regional Prefectural Advisory supporting other ALTs in my region and the prefecture by developing our biannual skills conferences and leading lectures and discussions about lesson planning and ideas, as well as lead monthly meeting for the ALTs in my town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I closed my statement of reason with my contributions to the kendo federation in my town. I wrote about how I joined students in their club activities and practiced kendo, what I learned from doing kendo both personally and professionally, and eventually reaching the rank of 3-dan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 pages might have been too much for a statement of reason, but I wanted to completely show everything noteworthy that I’ve done in Japan. It was very direct and unemotional, focusing on the facts. My approach to writing the statement was very similar to writing a resume for an application. Overall, I don’t think the statement has to be completely emotionless, but I don’t think it should be the main focus of the argument. Show, don’t tell, as I say to my students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though I wrote all this information in English, I had to rewrite everything in Japanese, too. I had some help with that. I included both English and Japanese versions of my statement in my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分関係を証明する次のいずれかの資料（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I am not Japanese, so this was not required for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Whenever you move somewhere in Japan, you must register at the town hall so it has a complete and up-to-date record of all of its residents. The application for permanent residence requires a print of this record. It was easy to get from my town’s registrar by filling out a request document and paying 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for them to print the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has information, such as when you moved to town, current address, previous addresses, nationality, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In addition to proving that you live somewhere, you also need to prove that you work somewhere. This was pretty easy for me to get since my school is private and not that big. For a larger organization or a government organization, it might take some time for your request to go open the chain and for the document to come back down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just went to the office and they created a document that proved my employment. Depending on whichever company you work for, it may be an official document or it may not. I think it just needs to include a statement saying you work there as well as information that can be contacted later. My school/company just made up an official looking document with all the correct information on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;直近（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）の申請人及び申請人を扶養する方の所得及び納税状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Things start to get more complicated, as a single piece of paper proving your employment isn’t enough. Of course, you need to show that you’ve been paying taxes on the income that you’ve earned. And also show that you’ve been doing it for at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These documents include the &lt;I&gt;Kazei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;I&gt;Nozei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt;. Both documents translate as either Tax Certificate or Taxation Certificate, so looking at the English information about this section may not be helpful. Overall, the &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details how much taxes you had to pay and what taxes you had to pay on your income within a given year. The &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details the amount of taxes you still owe for a given year. Essentially, &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; is like an itemized bill, and &lt;I&gt;Zozei&lt;/I&gt; is the receipt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each document you’ll need for 5 years. For my town, I had a single &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate for each year. For the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate, each year could be written on the same document. For each document, for each year, it cost 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. So for all the documents, my bill would’ve been 3000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;I&gt;update&lt;/I&gt;, when I initially turned in my application, I forgot to get 5 years for the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate. I was able to turn in my application, but I needed to mail in the correct form within two weeks. They gave me an envelope and a sheet that described the document I was missing. Another problem, though: my town only keeps the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate up to 4 years, instead of the 5 years they wanted. I called them, and they said 4 years was fine. So, my bill was actually 2700&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for these documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally! There’s another version of the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate that is required. Besides the Tax Record office in city hall, I went to my town’s official Tax Office. Requesting the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate from them shows them I’ve paid all debts and taxes across all government departments and agencies, as well as never missed any payment for any bills or loan. This document cost 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; to print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, to these tax documents, I had to include a photo of my bank book that proved I was getting paid the correct income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, for this section, I included the following documents:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt;- Kazei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - Nozei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書（未払いの税金がないことを証明するためのパート&lt;/span&gt;3&lt;span class='ja'&gt;）&lt;/span&gt;- Nozei Cert proving no upaid taxes&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;預貯金通帳（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo proving income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;8.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の公的年金及び公的医療保険の保険料の納付状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now that I had shown that I am legally employed, getting legally paid, and responsibly paying taxes on my legal income, I need to show that I’m paying into either my company’s pension or the government’s pension for at least two years. Also that I have health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section was somewhat difficult to follow. Initially, I just took a photo copy of my annual pension report that I had gotten in mail, but (&lt;I&gt;update!&lt;/I&gt;) apparently that wasn’t enough. A few days after I turned in my application, I got a letter in the mail requesting another form. The form they wanted detailed all of my pension payments, and each pension that I’ve contributed to. It was called the &lt;I&gt;Hihokenja Chousho Shoukai Kaitou-hyou&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt; or the “Insurance Record Inquiry Report,” I think? I’m not sure why it says insurance when its about pensions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get this form, I had to go to my town’s Pension office and request these forms. Prior to going to the office, I had some co-workers give them a call to make sure I was getting the right forms, and they were able to prepare everything for me before I arrived. It turned a possible 40-minute wait into 5 minutes. This document was also 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at this document, I’ve contributed into a government pension when I worked for the city as a teacher, and I’ve contributed to a private pension I have with my current job. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter wanted me to include receipts from any contributions to the government’s individual pension service, but I never did that, so I didn’t have any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the health insurance card, I just took a photo of it and blacked out the account number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, this is what I included from this section:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ねんきん定期便（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;健康保険被保険者証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;9.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人又は申請人を扶養する方の資産を証明する次のいずれかの資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the next part, I had to show all of Japanese financial assets. At minimum, I had to take photo copies of my bank statements to show how much money I have in Japan. I don’t have a house, so I didn’t have anything to show there. I do have a car, but I didn’t include any proof of that. Maybe I should have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Passport Photo and Residence Card Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人のパスポート（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の在留カード（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I included photo copies of my passport and residence card with my application, but this is not really necessary. When you turn in your application, you’ll need to also show them both of these, and they can take a photo copy themselves, at this time. I included these to save time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;12.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証に関する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A current Japanese citizen needs to vouch for who I am, what I stand for, and state that I would make a contribution to Japan by becoming a Japanese permanent resident. This person should be someone you know pretty well, and have a good relationship with. My principal at school has always sponsored my VISA, as well as other documents that required official clearance, so he was an easy choice as a guarantor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They need to fill in the guarantor form and prove who they are. For my guarantor, we included the following:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証書&lt;/span&gt; - the guarantor application&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証&lt;/span&gt; - a photo copy of their ID (driver’s license, in this case)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of employment, wherever they work.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of tax payments. (&lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt; - proof of residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the guarantor form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Japanese)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Contributions to Japan&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;13.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;我が国への貢献に係る資料（&lt;/span&gt;※&lt;span class='ja'&gt;ある場合のみで結構です。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is the last meaty section of the application. For this section, I included my letters of recommendation and other certificates and awards of accomplishments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I had 3 recommendation letters: one letter from the principal, one letter from the head of our English department, and one letter from head of the Kendo federation in my town. Each letter of recommendation talked about the contributions that I made to my school and kendo in town, and talked about why they think I should be awarded permanent residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional documents that I included were proof of things mentioned in either my Statement of Reason or their Letters of Recommendation. I included a photo of my kendo license showing participation for 10 years, my 3-dan diploma, and certificates of participation for 3 years in the international budo conference. I also included a photo of my driver’s license to show that not only do I have a license, but maintaining a perfect and safe driving record to be awarded a 5-year gold license.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, here were my documents for this section.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from principal)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from head of English)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from Kendo Federation)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo License Photo&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;段免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo 3-dan Diploma&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;国際武道文化セミナー&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;修了証&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;（&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt; - International Budo Conference particpation&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo of Gold Driver’s License&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;14.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分を証する文書等（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’m not Japanese, so I did not need to do this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if this one is proof of ancestry or identity, or what the difference is between part 4 above. For one of these, there is some kind of official family document Japanese people have that shows all of their registered family members, and you need to include a photo copy of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application Oath&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;15.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;了解書　&lt;/span&gt;１&lt;span class='ja'&gt;通&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The final document required is signing the application oath form. By signing this, you agree that if anything information within the application changes over the next 4 to 6 months, you must notify immigration about these changes and update your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Complete!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V0fGzq5K9UgM8KYY65wFZCzeLxUgBHG2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1UdKfVCrjEwz4vI2ehHJf79W6GI5FNPTO"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s everything. It doesn’t really seem like all that much once I finished making everything and putting it together. However, a lot of the time spent on the application is figuring out exactly what is required and where to go. The tax and pensions details are pretty tricky. I think my situation is pretty easy because I’ve only had the one job in the last 5 years, and the job is run by a professional organization. I also don’t have a house. Although, getting those documents probably aren’t too tough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 13th, I drove up north to Toyama and turned in my application at Toyama Branch Office of the Nagoya Regional Immigration Bureau. A long time ago, I figured out that very few people actually go to this branch office, so the wait time is never more than 5 minutes. In Gifu, wait times can be as long as 45 minutes. And in Nagoya, a friend of mine waited for an hour and a half once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the clerk instantly noticed one probably with my application (the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate not being 5 years), so I had to submit that afterward. I also got a letter in the mail on February 17th about the pension document. But, they accepted my application, and I’ve mailed those requested document as soon as I could. All documents were submitted as of February 21st, and I have not received any more letters about any more problems.  I think it’s all good!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically these application can take up to six months to be completely reviewed and responded to, but the clerk mentioned that it may only take three months to be complete. Over the last three years, thanks to Covid, the number of people moving to Japan has significantly decreased because the government shut down travel.  Previously, my VISA application would take 4 weeks to get approved, but it only took a week last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, by May, I’ll get the postcard in the mail to come back down and get my card. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/permanent-residence</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Extras</title><description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent release of Capcom CPS2 for the Analogue Pocket, there are a few more games that run on the current version of the core that don't have files included. This is true with a few others cores as well. I have collected all of the extra files and code edits in a single GitHub repository, available below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-extras"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-extras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 main collection of files, which are for (1) Capcom CPS2, (2) Donkey Kong (and Radar Scope), and (3) Pang. You can read the descriptions of each of the additions on Github. It'll have the most recent information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ehTMjJ08upTepDXLcBEVlfAKufQFi-k-"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ejyF7-Ru4pSS-5Shui3aS7XbR7_wIabA" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-extras</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Level 50</title><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2020, Pokemon Go announced that you’d finally be able to go beyond the level 40 cap all the way up to level 50. I started playing Pokemon Go in the beginning in 2016, but I didn’t really seriously start playing it until 2018, and I started a second account and played them both at the same time. My primary account was ahead of my secondary, but it didn’t take long for it to catch up and have pokemon teams just as powerful. After a few months, both accounts were essentially mirrors of each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2020, my primary account was able to hit level 40, but my secondary account still lagged behind.  In order to reach level 40, you need a total of 20 million XP in the game. I think my primary was at 25 million at that point? And my secondary may have been at 18 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the increased level caps set, you’ll now need a total of 176 million XP to reach level 50. In fact, the gap between level 49 and level 50 alone with 30 million XP. With these requirements and my current progress, I resigned myself that it would take years upon years to actually get there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it only took 2 years and a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - Jan 29th&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VHI1jhph0algC1xLoyPZt2Ra7PAclV0c" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - Jan 31st&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1V9rFX5ezXliylyOwbqlPFWtWHCVzXE7b" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both of my accounts hit level 50 last week after a long 7 months of being stuck on level 49.  In addition to needed XP to gain a level, you also have unique level requirements, like hatching some amount of eggs, or defeating some amount of rocket members. Level 49 requires you land 1000 excellent throws on Pokemon, which is very time consuming and annoying if you don’t manually play so often. I was able to grind them out with the most recent Electric event, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, if it took me more than two years prior to 2021 to gain 20 million XP, how was I able to get more than 150 million in just two years? Overall, 3 main factors contributed to my XP, but a few other things also changed how I played.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;XP Gains&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, as the level cap was raised, so was the XP you gain for doing various things in the game. Catching Pokemon gave you a little more. Spinning stops gave you a little bit. Defeating Raid bosses gave you a little more. And, most notably, excellent throws now gave you 1000xp.  Before, I think it was 200xp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, additionally, evolving Pokemon now gave you 1000xp, too. Throughout the weeks, as I caught a lot of Pokemon, if I could evolve them, I would put them into their own group. There are many Pokemon in the game, and many of these Pokemon are not useful in battles. Because of this, I’d just throw them away to make room to catch more. But, if I have a lot of candy for those Pokemon, may as well make them useful by evolving them for the XP. When you use a Lucky Egg, you’ll get double XP for the next 30 minutes. AND! I logged into a single account using both of my phones. I could evolve double the amount of Pokemon and get double the amount of XP. &lt;b&gt;In 30 minutes, I could get about 750 thousand XP&lt;/b&gt;. I caught enough Pokemon that I could do this every 2 or 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, the absolute best way to get XP in the game is through friendships. After 7 days, 30 days, and 90 days, you’ll increase your friendship level for 10 thousand, 50 thousand, and 100 thousand XP. Use a Lucky Egg to double it. Making friends in Pokemon go wasn’t easy to begin with, but it became very easy when they introduced Remote Raids. Other people built match making apps where you friend each other to do raids. After hosting MANY MANY raids, I continue to send gifts to people and increase friendships. Every 2 or 3 weeks when I did evolves, I would get the XP from friendships, too. After one of these sessions, I would routinely make around 1.5 million. One night, I made more than 5 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Play Style&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those were specific things I did to significantly increase my level, but overall, my play style is much different than it was prior to 2021 and the game has changed a lot, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main way my play style changed was using these two things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VcOUsbVitmCG5h7-XqQdmIgLNjbxsdKs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pokeball Plus was released in 2018 with the release of Let's Go Pikachu / Eevee, and meant to be used as a controller, but you could also connect it to Pokemon Go. When connected it will automatically spin stops for you. Also, when you're near a Pokemon you can click the button to try to catch it. Well, if you buy those rubber protectors above and shove a coin or two over the button, the button will automatically be pressed down and it will automatically catch a Pokemon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With these two Pokeballs, I can turn on Pokemon Go, turn on the Pokeballs, and it will automatically capture Pokemon as I drive around town. This is an amazing efficient way of getting a lot of Pokemon very quickly and catching a lot of Pokemon that I wouldn't have caught otherwise. It's not a 100% catch rate, but it's still doing a lot more work than I would have to do manually, and it frees me up to focus on driving and moving around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, the radius that allows you to spin stops was increased and the overall number of pokemon that spawn has increased, too. I'm catching far more Pokemon than I ever had before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Level History&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn't take too long for both of my accounts to go through level 41, 42, 43, etc. Once I hit the mid-40s, I would take about a month or two or three to make it to the next level before I finally hit level 49. Each time you gain a level past 40, you have the option of saving your stat sheet, so I saved all of these images when I could.  Here are my past few levels as a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - June 12th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VNaHorzlLzDei-it847JvhS39afS3PY0" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - June 16th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VaXEAKZCGqrDDc8ZO3d_1xdh837rQSHA" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - March 29th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VblL1QnPKPkDRJvdiLs595UE19YuE4u8" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - May 7th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VTbDouJYDUy__LrRPjQGfZh_re-kw1w9" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;DyreSchlock - Dec 25th 2021&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VOc6SyXPQCHr4k_8ed08Zf3KV4_VsUvj" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;DyreSchlock2 - Feb 26th 2022&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VLzclFc4dL8nR_5qmR0WQHN0yERDHUmu" /&gt;&lt;br class=“clr” /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;End Game&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe they'll increase the level cap again in the future, but I doubt it. There's no real benefit of having your character reach level 50 compared with level 40. Once you hit level 35, you can boost your individual Pokemon to level 50, so it doesn't matter what level you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been playing Pokemon Go more casually and only focusing on certain events. Part of the reason it took me 7 months to gain a level was because I was barely playing the game. It's always fun to explore around town playing Pokemon Go, but with one less goal overall, it is one less reason to play, and that's a good thing. I can focus on other stuff instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-level-50</link></item><item><title>Car Mileage</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Every 2 years in Japan, cars must go through a vehicle inspection called &lt;I&gt;Shaken&lt;/I&gt;. This is to ensure that the cars are still safe to drive and that they haven't been illegally modified. It's usually costs at least $1000, which is annoying, but it's even more annoying when you have a bunch of repair costs tacked on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in Japan, I had to buy a car because public transportation up in the mountains was not feasible. The car mechanic in town had a pretty good deal on a 2004 &lt;b&gt;Subaru R2&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1erFR1p3xXw8k8CQOJUng6l9bk-x2lnrS"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1envfK0XC8TeAg8IaA01gKtttqWWZOnSf" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Subaru R2 is a Kei car, denoted by its yellow plate. Kei cars are smaller and have smaller engines. This also means they get some pretty great gas mileage.  I bought the car in 2013, but as &lt;I&gt;Shaken&lt;/I&gt; loomed in 2021, the bottom plating had begun to erode away and it was no longer road-worthy. My mechanic information me that the repairs would be too much, and I should buy a new car. I had a bunch of money saved up from stimulus checks and not traveling due to lockdown, so it wasn't too bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My mechanic and I went through a bunch of cars on the open market, and I finally settled on a 2017 &lt;b&gt;Daihatsu Mira ES&lt;/b&gt;. I wanted to continue owning a Subaru, but they discontinued their line of Kei cars, and Daihatsu has purchased their designs. The Mira is a slight evolution of the R2 mixed with Daihatsu designs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1fBruTDAFL0ornQ5US3qLqFBrA7dJU904" &gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1f5SvxhZxkPXBytMXZckH1qW8Yn5Mobzi" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went with Red to try and set myself apart from the conformity of all the White, Off-White, and Grey cars of Japan. Nobody likes colors in their cars over here. It's still not completely unique, though, as the Mira ES is one of the most popular Kei cars on the road. I think that's good because it'll be easy to find replacement parts in the future if stuff breaks. Also the mechanic can easily figure out how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, and I've finally made the final payment on my car. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Car Mileage&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever I pay for gas, I've gotten in the habit of writing down the Odometer on the receipt in order to calculate my own gas mileage. These receipts pile up, and I eventually take all of the data and enter it into spreadsheets in Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1f5nGbrj7M9yLTBhxVxoseQA6fXMGQoeT"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1fazQp3xxHpVs75xFNf4bp5eYBMmgLb68" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1epYG1aZF74iWZ5kACd845uoKbhgEzWK7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1enbuEliaYpGFa44Oa95Xzc-s9v2iHflU" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those are both a year's worth of receipts. One pile is from 2020. The other pile is from 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the 8 years I owned my Subaru R2, I drove it 105,000 kilometers. I took some roadtrips to Hiroshima, Kyoto, and Chiba. Many times I drove to Tokyo, too. Throughout its life, it had an average of 32.93 or 33.67 mpg, after conversions from liters and km. Towards the end, it started losing some of its mpg, and after Covid started, I was really only driving around town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the full stats on my &lt;b&gt;Subaru R2&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1jEUeqESvioxxYmGwsYPkDsx453hCRjZDRJQlesGGBvI"&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/1jEUeqESvioxxYmGwsYPkDsx453hCRjZDRJQlesGGBvI &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have continued to do gas accounting with my &lt;b&gt;Daihatsu Mira ES&lt;/b&gt;. Here are its stats:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1FLFwmXzWKFbDLktdGgCvOMgRo9nMpoRom_beND6gmcE"&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/1FLFwmXzWKFbDLktdGgCvOMgRo9nMpoRom_beND6gmcE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Gas Cost&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March 2022, the war in Ukraine began and gas prices began to climb in the United States. People were paying as much as $70 for a tank of gas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not so much in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the whole year of 2021, I spent 97390&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on gasoline. In 2022, I spent 104654&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on gas. It did go up, but only by 7000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. In fact, if you wanted to go further with it, the exchange rate for Yen to Dollars tanked after the war started. If you convert this to dollars, I paid $881 in 2021 and only $792 in 2022. It's $90 less, in this case. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparatively, I bought 600 liters in 2021 and 603 liters in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/car-mileage</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Platform Images</title><description>&lt;p&gt;We're now up to 60 cores released for the Pocket from 9 different developers. The most visible front-facing part of these cores is the Platform information and image. This includes how cores are sorted in the openFPGA menu, the titles of the core in the menu, and the image that appears when selected. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some core information is slightly inconsistent with others, so I've been rewriting Platform information on my own and making new images as well. I made in initial release back in November covering some cores to make them consistent with others. But now I've finished making a complete image set that covers all currently released cores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1e66fWpTiiilZR6Kbe-TrqZa_97v40sOl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dsCs3jq-Y1d_uisPmQuC7UqBkhsxUKEV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Arcade Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For each of the Arcade core, I've tried to make an image like the original marquee for the Arcade cabinet. Usually these images are available, and it only takes 5 minutes to make the image. But, for some Arcade games, those images can be hard to find in good quality. Often too, if I do get a good image, the original artwork looks lame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been recreating many of these images using key art from officially marketing at the time. I put the image on the canvas and try to make it fit. Often I need to blend things around, move the title and other things in the background for a good composition. Now, I tend to spend around an hour of two making an image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are some Arcade cores that can run multiple noteworthy games since manufacturers often reused their boards for other games. Later still, some game companies made board that would specifically run multiple games. Images for those cores are different than just a simple marquee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view them all here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/blob/main/image_overview_arcade.md"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../image_overview_arcade.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are some of my favorites that I spent some time on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/xevious.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtcps1.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/radarscope.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtcps2.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/jtexed.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/arcade/tecmo.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Home Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;People had like my images, but some people complained that my image set wasn't complete. Thus, I created a "Home" image set to complement my Arcade images. Home would include cores for Consoles, Handhelds, and Computers. Technically, handhelds aren't specifically made for the home, but I think this monicker is pretty descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really liked &lt;a href="https://github.com/terminator2k2/Analogue-Pocket-Core-Art"&gt;Terminator2k2&lt;/a&gt;'s Image set which just had the logos of the systems, but I needed to do something else to distinguish my set. I got the idea when I started looking at old ads for consoles that showed off their game libraries. Also on Twitter, many people like to post a smattering or a pile of game boxes when they have a large haul from a shopping spree. I thought that I should try and do that. Games are the most important thing for any console or handheld after all. They should be displayed front and center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I already had a bunch of box art downloaded thanks to my &lt;a href="/pocket-utils"&gt;Pocket Utils&lt;/a&gt; project, so I made a collage of them in photoshop, added some perspective, shrunk down to the correct size, and color-corrected some things to make it look alright in grayscale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/snes.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/ng.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/nes.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/pics/home/genesis.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think they turned out pretty good. I think it gives a great sense of the number of options you have available for each platform. They may be a bit overwhelming and gaudy though since the Analogue Pocket prides itself on minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view them all here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/blob/main/image_overview_home.md"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../image_overview_home.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Unreleased Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is still lots to look forward for the Analogue Pocket in the future. The MiSTer is another FPGA device that has been around much longer than the Analogue Pocket, and there are hundreds of cores that have been created. All cores available for the Analogue Pocket today are ports of these cores. Because of this, it's easy to see a roadmap for future cores to be released on the Pocket. In particular, core developers &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/jotego/posts"&gt;Jotego&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengateware"&gt;Open Gateware&lt;/a&gt; (aka Boogerman) have a wealth of cores they plan to bring to the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've worked ahead quite a bit so when new cores are released, I don't have to spend that afternoon making the image. It's already done, and I can quickly make a new release of Platform Images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some images for possible future cores:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jthcastle.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/galaxian.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jtmx5k.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/tropicalangel.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/jtcps3.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/main/_unreleased/pics/druaga.png" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view all of these images here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/tree/main/_unreleased"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-platform-images/../_unreleased&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As these cores get released, these images are moved into their released folders, so hopefully this category will be zero someday.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-platform-images</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Utils</title><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month, the Analogue Pocket has continued to be an absolute monster. The Sega Genesis is now available. The Nintendo Entertainment System is now available. Sega GameGear is available, too. And there have been many cores of 1980s Arcade games released, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's starting to get unwieldily, so I've created a collection of programs to help me organize and process games so they can be played on the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-utils"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/pocket-utils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been working on this pretty solidly for the past three weeks, and I think it's finally feature finished. The GitHub repository has straight forward information of how each process is set up and what exactly each process does. But, overall…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pocket Utils is a collection of scripts and programs that do several things, including the following: (1) Process MRA files and Create Arcade Roms, (2) Create Library Images for sorted Games, and (3) Update Platform information for cores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Process MRA Files&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Multi-Arcade Machine Emulator, or MAME, on computer standardized how to emulate arcade games. When ripping games from their original boards, each component had their own file, and everything was put together in a zip file. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FPGA emulation of arcade games doesn't like this. The chip wants direct read access to the data it wants and unzipping a file in memory is extra useless overhead. Thus, the idea of a MRA file was introduced. A MRA file contains specific instructions on how each piece of the arcade board can be assembled into a single ROM file. This file is not compressed and allow free access to all the data the FPGA wants. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A separate program is required to process these MRA files, though. I use this &lt;a href="https://github.com/nullobject/mra-tools-c"&gt;MRA Tool&lt;/a&gt; found in NullObject's GitHub. When an arcade core is released for the Analogue Pocket, it'll come with MRA files to create ROMs from ZIP files of arcade components. You must get the arcade ROM zips, process the MRA file in the program giving it the zip files, and then place the generated ROM into the core's folder on the Analogue Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of steps to getting this to work, and many arcade cores released for the Analogue Pocket play multiple games. Some releases come with 10 or more games. In fact, arcade systems like Capcom CPS1 and CPS2 have as many as 300 variants of their games. Doing all of this manually is not feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This program solves this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put all of your MRA files in the to-be-processed directory. Run the program. It'll attempt to download any and all ZIP files required to make the arcade rom, and store them locally. If the Arcade ROM is successfully generated, it'll copy it to the correct directory on the Pocket, and also copy the MRA file to the Pocket, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it can't find the ZIP files online, you can manually search for them and put them in your local store. If a ROM was already generated, it'll copy over the MRA file anyway. If the MRA file is already there, it'll copy it to a duplicate directory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Standard games, everything works really well and there are almost never any problems. Problems usually only come up when trying to generate bootlegs or hacks of roms. Those often require extra steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Create Library Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most appealing features of the Analogue Pocket is the Library feature. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something I've never liked about using emulators is having to choose the games I want to play from a list. It's so sterile and clinical. The Super Nintendo Mini was so amazing because of its visual presentation. You had a line games presented with their box art. And you could visually choose the game you wanted to play by selecting that box art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Library feature of the Analogue Pocket was just that. It gave you a visual list of all your games to select from. Further still, you could organize all of your games in Playlists. This was promised in Analogue's Tweet about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/analogue/status/1449389698493861888"&gt;Analogue OS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, the Analogue Pocket has an internal list of game data but it doesn't have an images. Early on, you could download an image pack that gave you all the title screens for every game. But I don't want title screens. I want box arts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took a little while to figure out, but the Analogue Pocket uses a CRC hash of the file to reference which image is uses in the Library. If you have a correctly sized PNG file, you can run it through &lt;a href="https://github.com/DerTolleEmil/AnaloguePocketLibraryImageConverter"&gt;DerTolleEmil&lt;/a&gt;'s Image Converter and it'll give you a BIN file. Put this bin file in the correct folder named with the CRC hash, and it'll use this image in the Library.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, my program goes a bit further with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In each of the folders for Consoles and Handhelds on the Analogue Pocket, I have the ROMs that I like sorted into genre folders. My initial "CreatePocketEntries" program will collect all of these games in my database. "CreateLibraryImages" will look at every game in my database and attempt to download the box art image from &lt;a href="https://github.com/libretro-thumbnails/libretro-thumbnails"&gt;LibRetro&lt;/a&gt; on Github. With this image, my program will resize it to the correct dimensions for the Pocket, convert the PNG image to BIN, name it correctly, and copy the file to the System folder on the Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, when using the Library, the image matches the box art. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XjtzSnYUE8WPM1F5JxAdNGbXnHa1_kn2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xe26ZJlexUiRKTiZFE7ah1jpiXxXil4o" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Update Platform Information&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I collect in my database is Core information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a user chooses a core from the openFPGA menu on the Pocket, it lists certain information about itself, such as when the console or handheld was original released, who was the manufacture, and also the name and category of the core, too. All core developers are very particular about the accurate representation of the consoles, games, and their code, so this information is usually correct, but sometime it is not to avoid copyright and trademark violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the database, it's easy for me to edit this information and also collect all the information into categories. My program will rewrite all of the information in the Platforms directory with what I have in my database. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it'll create Platform Images using agg23's &lt;a href="https://github.com/agg23/Analogue-Pocket-Image-Process"&gt;Platform Image Creator&lt;/a&gt;. Any new images that I've made and placed in the processing directory will be converted and copied over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Run the Updater&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also a simple shell script that runs &lt;a href="https://github.com/mattpannella/pocket-updater-utility"&gt;Matt Pannella&lt;/a&gt;'s command line program with all of the settings that I like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Future&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this stuff pretty often when new cores and new features are released, so there continue to be more updates. When Playlists eventually come to the Pocket, I'll have a new program to make those. I'm also working on another program that will make a list of games I have in my "unsorted" directories for each core.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket continues to be one of the absolute best gaming devices made, and being able to make all this stuff to organize games has gotten back into programming on the side. It's been pretty great. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Analogue Pocket has become one of my favorite gaming consoles (or handheld) of all time. Initially announced as a modern device that plays games from the family of GameBoys, it has grown to become exactly what I wanted and has yet to reach its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1eU0wsOVi3CUMvS9SE25hIFdhSubmhtv_"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1eYbzXcMUneNFrvWBpga539Dc8ih-AjB-" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analogue is a company that specializes in creating retro gaming consoles. They are most widely known for making a $200 Nintendo and a $200 Super Nintendo. You can plug your original cartridges from these systems into these new ones, and everything still works. There have been several other machines that have done this in recent years, but Analogue’s edge is its use of the FPGA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internally, Analogue has reversed engineered and replicated the original chipsets of the Nintendo and Super Nintendo and have them running on a chip called an FPGA. This means that the games aren’t running in emulation on a PC or on Linux or something. It’s running the original processors EXACTLY the same way the original hardware did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By doing this, Analogue has replicated the exact original look and feel of the original console to near perfection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket Announcement&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;October 16th, 2019&lt;/b&gt;, Analogue announced its newest hardware recreation, the Analogue Pocket. The Analogue Pocket would be their first handheld device, and it would play GameBoy, GameBoy Color, and GameBoy Advanced games. Sold separately, you could also buy a Dock that would charge the device and hook up to a TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the biggest hint at its potential was the inclusion of a second FPGA chipset. A primary FPGA was included that would run a Game cartridge, but the second FPGA would be open to developers to do whatever they wanted with. This meant that it may be possible for people to play their own Game roms on the device. And this also meant that people could write code for other consoles to be played, like a Game Gear, or a Sega Genesis, or a Super Nintendo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I had been able to rediscover many amazing retro games thanks to the Super Nintendo Mini. But, the Mini was cumbersome and could only play certain games. If the Pocket could play Super Nintendo and other stuff, too, it would be like the Nintendo Switch for retro games. I could play Super Nintendo portably, or plug it into the TV and play them there. It would be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket Release&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost a year later on August 1st, a date and time was announced when you could buy one. For me, it would be Midnight on &lt;b&gt;August 4th 2020&lt;/b&gt;. Hype for the device began to buzz around the Internet with even Elijah Wood posting about it. Of course, this was the height of global lockdown from the Coronavirus, so any news on the Internet spread very quickly. I planned on staying up to secure my order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analogue’s Store page went live at Midnight, and I knew exactly what I wanted: Black Pocket, Dock, Case, Screen Protector, and Cable. Putting things into my cart was easy, but actually purchasing was a nightmare. The pages took a while to load, or didn’t load at all. I typed in all of my information and hit save, but international shipping took a while to appear. I kept hitting that Purchase button to conclude the sale, and eventually it went through. After waking up the next day, a purchase confirmation email was in my inbox. It was a success! My order was in the #54xxx range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket was expected to release in early or mid-2021. That was pushed to October, and then it was pushed again. Finally, orders began shipping in December, and on &lt;b&gt;December 24th, 2021&lt;/b&gt;, my Pocket arrived in the mail. Over 2 years after its announcement, and over 1 year after its purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y--KVgA2e9T-IucOVxT-UnrwVmod7Yt8" &gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xzk4Msel3UdUq_NGwgUEv5mmGQFpkG-J" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Analogue Pocket&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, the Analogue Pocket does exactly what it says it would do. You plug in a GameBoy game, it plays perfectly fine. You plug in a GameBoy Advance game, it plays perfectly fine. But that was all that it did. On release, the second FPGA chip was not yet available for other developers to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to &lt;b&gt;July 30th 2022&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/analogue/status/1553032922143330306"&gt;the first firmware update&lt;/a&gt; was released. The second FPGA was now available and the first core was released which recreated Spacewar, the first interactive game ever created on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Neo Geo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day later, something amazing showed up online. There was a &lt;a href="https://github.com/Mazamars312/Analogue_Pocket_Neogeo"&gt;core for the Neo Geo&lt;/a&gt;. The Neo Geo was a console released in the 90s which was identical to the company's Arcade hardware. It was the first time you could play perfect versions of Arcade games in your home. It was very expensive, so very few people actually bought it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Neo Geo is home to some of my favorite games of all time, now they were available on the Pocket. And they looked absolutely stunning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YCDvpBDAOG4lR3ovw-YF_yZzulgZQ76z"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y9zACZhlbQp4Gf5-a9JhChmsqq0KXAdq" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YTo9lMpQ7mNnmmnUfXbOLItPLWJhoJfI"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y7n3_eR0jC7QClpYfbAgw-8YcbQ_R8eV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all games played at first, but the ones that worked were perfect. They looked amazing, sounded amazing, and played amazing. As of today, &lt;b&gt;September 19th, 2022&lt;/b&gt; with its most recent update, all Neo Geo games are playable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Super Nintendo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, today-ish the dream has finally come true with the first release of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/agg23/openfpga-SNES"&gt;Super Nintendo core&lt;/a&gt; for the Analogue Pocket. 3 years after its initial announcement, preorder, release, update, the Analogue Pocket had reached the potential that many of us initially saw in the device, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ photos ]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actraiser looks and sounds absolutely stunning on the Pocket. Super Metroid looks and sounds amazing. It's all so beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;A Dream Device&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With both &lt;b&gt;Neo Geo&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Super Nintendo&lt;/b&gt; released, I'm able to play these games in the perfect environment without any of the problems of the Super Nintendo Mini. Adding and organizing games on the Pocket is FAR simpler than the Mini, and there is virtually no storage limit since everything is on an SD card. I'm able to play every game ever created on this device, and then organize the ones I want to play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For me, there are still a few more consoles needed to make the Analogue Pocket the perfect device for me. Obviously, the &lt;b&gt;Nintendo Entertainment System&lt;/b&gt; has an incredible number of classics, but I want to also play Sega Genesis with &lt;b&gt;Sega CD&lt;/b&gt;, in order to play Snatcher, and &lt;b&gt;Capcom CPS2&lt;/b&gt; for arcade perfect Street Fighter Alpha, Super Puzzle Fighter II, and some other amazing Shooters and Fighters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If all &lt;b&gt;five&lt;/b&gt; of these consoles were available on the Pocket, my Retro dreams would completely come true.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Raid Counters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Linked below is my collated list of all the best raid counters in Pokemon Go. These numbers of based on the calculations made by Gamepress’s &lt;a href="https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/comprehensive-dps-spreadsheet"&gt;Comprehensive DPS Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; but put together on a single page, rather than multiple ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VJA45l5CX2U3tQO7pKf3rFgu8PInZf1A" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not the prettiest page, but it shows everything I need in order to build my raid team. Each cell shows the following:&lt;br/&gt;- the name of the Pokemon&lt;br/&gt;- the level of the Pokemon used for the calculations&lt;br/&gt;- the fast move&lt;br/&gt;- the charge move&lt;br/&gt;- the DPS&lt;br/&gt;- the TDO&lt;br/&gt;- the final figure is DPS*4 x TDO / 100000. This is the number I used to sort each list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing more damage quickly is more important than staying alive, so I prioritize DPS. But, it’s not solely sorted by DPS because if you die immediately with no defense, it’s totally worthless.  Therefore, I’m using DPS*4 rather than DPS*3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m including level 40 for all Pokemon, but I’m also including level 50 for all non-legendary pokemon and level 45 for all legendaries. It’s not too difficult to boost Pokemon up to level 40, but even though you can boost them all the way up to 50, getting XL candies for legendaries is not so easy. Includes two levels for each Pokemon can show you how much more powerful one is compared to the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Purpose&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some quick background, in Pokemon Go, there are these Pokemon battles called raids that multiple people can join to defeat the boss. Once the boss is defeated, each player has a chance to catch that Pokemon for themselves. These Pokemon are strong enough that you cannot defeat them by yourself. Each boss is different, but you usually must have 3 or 4 players minimum to win, assuming they have the best Pokemon for the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what are the best Pokemon for the battle? A while ago, the Pokemon community on &lt;b&gt;Gamepress&lt;/b&gt; wrote a calculator that would tell you just how powerful a Pokemon was versus a raid boss. If you typed in the Pokemon you wanted to fight, it would give you a numbered list of all the best pokemon you’d need to defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was first doing raids, I found this calculator very useful to determine which Pokemon to catch and boost. However, for this calculator, you need to type in each individual Pokemon one by one to see each of the best counters.  I wanted a page that I could look at and see ALL of the best pokemon versus ALL of the raid pokemon in Pokemon Go. So, I made one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Raid Counter List&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The calculator will save a CSV will all the data for the raid counters.  So, back in 2019, I made this page to display all the information from these CSV files. Over time, this became unmanageable because the number of raid bosses continued to grow and the number of best Pokemon and best moves began to grow too. It would take me about an hour to download each individual sheet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gamepress Calculator does all of its calculations in JavaScript. So over summer, I went through that code and ported it to Java. Now, rather than compiling data from generated CSV files, I can generate that data myself. And, rather than downloading 30+ CSV files, I only need to download the raw data files and rerun the page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The General list says which are the best raid pokemon overall, but I also wrote a page that shows me which of my Pokemon are the best. I have to manually add every one of these, so my list is often out of date, but it gives me a general idea how much damage my team can do or how many people I’ll need to recruit to beat the boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/custom"&gt;Personal Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if any of this is readable to anyone else, but it helps me out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Cards</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my Twitch channel, and the overall general rise and demand for all things video games on the Internet during the pandemic, I had been getting into Pokemon Cards lately. Not spending too much money, but maybe spending more money than I had to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, it was announced that the Pokemon Card company would finally be doing a proper crossover with Pokemon Go. Generally, Pokemon card sets follow the main series of Pokemon games, such as X/Y, Sun/Moon, and Sword/Shield. Sometimes there would be novelty cards that would show up from other spin-off games, but no other spin-off game has been as popular as Pokemon Go.  In fact, the overall brand awareness of Pokemon increased significantly after the release of Pokemon Go in 2016, and it has stayed around the same ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new Pokemon Go set of Pokemon Cards would be an entire expansion of 72 cards, too. Previous novelty sets, like Detective Pikachu and the 25th Anniversary sets were only 20 or 25 cards, and these cards weren’t really all that useful passed their novelty. I don’t actually play the game, so I can’t say whether or not these Go cards are actually useful. But, it seems like they’ve put some actually work into them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was able to preorder a box of cards and the long box set from Pokemon Center online, so I got them in the mail as they released on Friday (June 17th). I was able to pick up a few more packs, plus the folder set from a convenience store on the way home after work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WqwNLNqqmI5BVfy6JlbHJ3UOmT8PuAMl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X15eG7WkkIGkZxnnXIQykfe8ArgyzpKZ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The long box came with a photo frame to hold a card, and a card box that looked like an egg incubator from Pokemon Go. It had some packs of cards, too. The folder pack came with that little folder to hold some cards. It also came with a Pikachu promo card. It also got 5 other promo cards from buying a booster box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each booster pack comes with seven cards: a special flashy energy card with the Pokemon Go logo, an item/sticker promo card with a code for Pokemon Go, 2 or 3 common cards, 1 or 2 uncommon cards, and a rare pull. The rare pull could be a simple rare, a V card, V-star card, V-max card, or any other rare card in the set.  There are a total of 72 cards in the base set, but an additional 12 or 15 secret rare cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z3RUjK4rx3RCnB5lla-MyL4w1z_I9UGF"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z2NO-VpbSiIJY8I6MuTnDbJCyHKxDzaU" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my first pack, I really didn't get anything special. In this case, my rare card was a Gyarados denoted by the &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt; next to the number at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The promo code in Pokemon Go can give one of eight different sets of items. There are six common sets and one uncommon set of items with stickers, and there is one rare set which gives clothing for your character.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update - 3 months later&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I streamed over the following weekends, I opened up some packs for my followers. Immediately, I started getting some good pulls, like the shiny Venusaur and Dragonite V-star card. As my streams continued, I started getting some other good stuff too, like the shiny Blastoise, Mewtwo V-star, and a full art Candela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XOsjzk3cJ5GK6IE9kseudlXsEnneyO6k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XJuAej3W4X2hbd6O7YINVpmwaRP-w57I" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XB4p6Zo5pwabYo7gf5hILYY5mo51GgWI"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XJnYVJNQWG1AXNMdiPWY8qBAp4niQ_YV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was getting very few duplicates of rare and uncommon cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, I had opened up all my packs of cards and was only missing 8 from the base set. Each pack of cards gave a chance to pull a rare card, and those were the 8 that I was missing. Obviously, I could buy more packs for more chances, but it is way more cost effective to just buy what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cards weren't too expensive, and I was able to quickly get most of them from Yahoo Auctions, except for one. Within the base set of 72 cards, the most expensive card was Shiny Charizard. My auctions were selling the card for $40, which was way too much for me to spend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;I&gt;Update 2&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward six more months and the Shiny Charizard was now only $10 on Yahoo Auctions. I am totally fine with spending $10 on a single Pokemon card as it was the ONE piece remaining from my collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now my collection is complete!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the photo below to see the whole set, or individual pages in the gallery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_5M9Giumlhh8JlVJhyU0GaUOJVe1l6cX"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_5aGVdZapAJgADDbW8gNciMptpcuN2G_" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-cards</link></item><item><title>Virtual Tokyo Marathon</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As the pandemic began, live events around the world were canceled and marathons were no exception. Luckily for them, the virus landed under their “acts of god” clause in their contracts, so they didn’t need to issue any refunds. But they had to adapt to the situation, just like everyone else and all other companies in order to stay in business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In lieu of being able to do physical marathons, many organizations began to host Virtual marathons, and many of these virtual marathons were free or significantly cheaper than doing them in person. To run them, you needed to download a GPS tracking running app, like Strava, and record a run with the same length as the race within the correct time period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These virtual marathons became so frequent and so cheap that throughout 2021 I was running one nearly every weekend. In 2018, I set a new personal record in distance having run a total of 367km in official races over the entire year. I spent nearly $1000 doing this, too. In 2021, I ran 365.6km in all of my races combined, only spending $200. This was an absolute godsend, even though my race times weren’t nearly as good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo Marathon was a race that had been on my bucket list ever since I started running in Japan. Every year I applied, but every year, I was unable to win the entry lottery for general entry. Much like all other marathons, it had been canceled in 2020 and pushed to 2021. Then canceled again and pushed to 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, this year, the Tokyo Marathon was finally held again, but only for the elite and career marathon runners. There was no general entry. To make up for this, they added an online component. Anyone who had general entry in the race could participate online for free. Additionally, the general entry became open to everyone for 5000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. This was finally my chance! Not only that, I only had to run a half marathon rather than a full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 5th, in the yet still snowy country-side, I ran my half marathon and completed the race. The app was very cumbersome, and I wasn’t really sure if my time actually registered. But today! I got my medal in the mail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WFK2LiSKRslFkOnRggPw-MT3b3-WqFP7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WH5CVBNVZcN6AqGW0ZENr9FOhTABlAUt" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WT5GGPTnPp1WLZGOb8FJIEEtAp2td3Kp"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WVFuH9Lk8ur_J9_OjUhsimAHevSDzwWE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WcD0ocPMMMZDLrEnHebByfBC_6MrwHAj"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W_6T2tOzZmOONHpWo3z5-tdQwuUaakiC" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is not a legitimate Tokyo Marathon medal, but it is good enough for me! Now it can join the club with all of my other marathon medals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WbHpagkMHM6vEFEzJ7qVlVIKvmrrlWmk"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1X4k5va9DnCjNz4qFznlKwIiMxhsqyah7" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Virtual marathoning, I could continue having motivation to run and exercise during lockdown. Running in the fields and the forests of the countryside have been an excellent break from being online 24/7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Tokyo Marathon medal, I've gotten a few more medals from Virtual races. Now I have so many that my medals have outgrown the box that I was keeping them in. It took some searching as I drove around to various antique stores, but I think I found the perfect box as my marathon medal collection's forever home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Ya-49VxMcrq_-4vEGBk9Xp2m6MZvWMIA"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YW7-9arYSd1urI6_kD-dZqMln1ScJxV3" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Z1eg6QTrv2e9LcAEs8WjMhT3ME4jqqJn"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Yui--bNTOPOVrzLG6fyX7_9eG04Rh62G" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1YcDvZ9fIA1zQ-GUg7ZHH2NfWmCYzJfWZ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Yf0N3R0QhpP_VbHaYVKr5F14EF6Pg5NV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/virtual-tokyo-marathon</link></item><item><title>Shiny Pokemon Inventory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the main goals of Pokemon is to catch every species of Pokemon available. I've talked about this before in my post about the &lt;a href="/completing-the-national-pokedex"&gt;National Pokedex&lt;/a&gt;. But, it's possible to take this a step further. These days, for every Pokemon, there is a 1 in 4096 chance that it will be &lt;b&gt;Shiny&lt;/b&gt;. A Shiny pokemon is a rare variant that appears in a different color. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent Pokemon Games have had methods of increasing the odds of getting a Shiny Pokemon. Since the beginning of the pandemic, I've been streaming video games on Twitch. And, in particular, I've been streaming hunts of Shiny Pokemon through these methods. When streaming on Twitch, I have HTML overlays in OBS that shows my progress of catching all Shiny Pokemon in the game, so I can keep track of what I have left to catch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been streaming Shiny Hunts in &lt;b&gt;Let's Go Eevee&lt;/b&gt;, and recently with the release of the excellent &lt;b&gt;Pokemon Legends Arceus&lt;/b&gt;. Additionally, &lt;b&gt;Pokemon Go&lt;/b&gt; makes it VERY easy to catch Shiny Pokemon. Not only is there is an increased base Shiny catch rate of 1 in 512, but often there are events that increase the odds as much as 1 in 20. So, I made a similar list to track my Shiny progress there, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view copies of these lists from the following links:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pokemon Let's Go Eevee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/letsgo"&gt;Shiny Completion List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pokemon Legends Arceus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/hisui/dex"&gt;Shiny Completion List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/hisui/order"&gt;Shiny Catches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/hisui/missing"&gt;Remaining Shiny Pokemon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pokemon Go&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/go"&gt;Shiny Completion List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all these lists keeping track of Shiny Pokemon, I was curious about my Shiny Progress across all Pokemon games. I have caught a few Shiny Pokemon in the main games, too, through events and randomly (though, rarely) in the wild. Combining all the counts from the above lists and the main games, I made an overall Shiny list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;b&gt;All Games Combined&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex"&gt;Overall Shiny Completion List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These lists are mostly up to date, but because I am manually entering data, it's really easy for them to get out of date. The index page for all of these lists has the date of when they were last updated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon"&gt;Shiny Pokemon Index Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, all of these lists are part of the schlock-bot project in git-hub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Let's Go Eevee&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I became interested in Shiny Hunting thanks to Let's Go. While watching various YouTube videos during the pandemic, one video showed that you could find a Shiny in about 20 minutes by catching the same Pokemon over and over again. I tried it out, and it worked! I caught my first Shiny Magikarp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Let's Go, you can increase your chances of getting a Shiny by doing three things. One, when you complete the Pokedex, you'll get a Shiny Charm. This will give you 2 extra chances for a Shiny. Two, when you use a Lure in the game, it'll give you 1 extra chance. And Three, the biggest one, when you catch the same Pokemon, you build a Catch Combo. When that combo reaches 31 and above, you'll get 11 extra chances for a Shiny. With all three combined, this gives 15 chances out of 4096, the equivalent to 1 in about 274.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was incredibly satisfying to start up a stream, and usually have a shiny appear once every hour. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XTQefvXRS6bfg2l9YBRaKLRplrIflxHv"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XTQefvXRS6bfg2l9YBRaKLRplrIflxHv" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XUYqmva5Wbu9bfF8g5N0pO7C30JG9K2v"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XUYqmva5Wbu9bfF8g5N0pO7C30JG9K2v" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While streaming, I would record my shiny catches using &lt;a href="/schlock-bot"&gt;schlock-bot&lt;/a&gt;, and use that &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pokemon/shinydex/letsgo"&gt;above overlay&lt;/a&gt; to display my progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Legends Arceus&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am in absolute love with Pokemon Legends Arceus. Since its release two months ago, I've been streaming the game, and shiny hunting has been pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like Let's Go, there are several methods of increasing chances for Shiny pokemon to appear. One, the Shiny Charm will give 3 extra chances this time. Two, the overall goal of the game is to complete the Pokedex. You do this by more than just catching Pokemon, though. If you complete an entry, you'll get 1 extra roll. But, if you perfect the entry, you'll get another 2 extra rolls. With all of these combined, you'll 7 chances out of 4096, the equivalent of 1 in about 586.  Just in the wild!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are Mass Outbreaks and Massive Mass Outbreaks of Pokemon. Including all of the above, Pokemon in mass outbreaks have a Shiny chance of 1 in about 128! In Massive Mass Outbreaks, chances are 1 in about 216. These chances are even better than Let's Go!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xcx3Mmca0ApBXx71mv4SWQ3PmtaTiEjc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Xcx3Mmca0ApBXx71mv4SWQ3PmtaTiEjc" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y1sIonXuugE0q1RDhpuH-jQHSMKQfn0Q"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Y1sIonXuugE0q1RDhpuH-jQHSMKQfn0Q" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pokemon Legends is my favorite Pokemon game of all time, it is incredibly satisfying to fly around and collect Shiny Pokemon. Much like Let's Go, I recorded my shiny catches using &lt;a href="/schlock-bot"&gt;schlock-bot&lt;/a&gt;, which updated the above display lists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Go and Others&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;People have been Shiny Hunting on Twitch and YouTube forever, but I don't think it became mainstream and accessible until Pokemon Go. As mentioned above, the overall base Shiny rate is increased to 1 in 512. I think this was their incentive to keep people playing because if you play for 3-4 hours straight in a day, you have a pretty high chance of finding a Shiny pokemon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Pokemon Go often has events that make Shiny hunting easier. One way is increasing the spawns of particular rare Pokemon, which gives you more to catch and more chance for a Shiny to appear. Another way is increasing the base odds of a Shiny appearing. The most common of these events is the Community Day, which boosts the odds up to 1 in 20! You are virtually guaranteed to catch several during the event!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of Pokemon Go, I think Game Freak has made Shiny hunting more accessible in the main games, too. Also with Pokemon spawning in the overworld (instead of random battles), you can easily see whether a Pokemon is Shiny. You can check WAY MORE pokemon these days than you could before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I still stream on Twitch, and usually I'm playing Pokemon. So, feel free to stop by and say hi!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/shiny-pokemon-inventory</link></item><item><title>Capsule Machine Capsule</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I had to escort a student to the Narita Airport in Tokyo so he could fly back to his country. We arrived very early before his flight so he could get a PCR test and be cleared to fly. We walked around while waiting for the results, and I found a pretty amazing sight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VrpiUz_LbELnfd2gXTFlROHcAHBi-M0c"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VlwX9N651H_hT4LqhvB-FfmgslUrphep" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a capsule machine that gave out miniature capsule machines! I absolutely had to have this thing. I got some change and turned the crank. My first pull gave me a pack of capsules! Pretty meta. I got a capsule ball full of tiny capsule balls. Well, now I needed to roll again to actually get a machine. My second pull was a success! I got the red version of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VxkuMtfQZo6pRKjQhFpu395Xe1bN6pJl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VxhKbu0jsAWJowxZk75e3VZQkl1PbAfz" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VtWYnAri_bT6JcMJv-Y_GRgqV237McYi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VsPe3KeqlntVnvNKWAKlE64S03U07I8h" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given all the moving parts of this little capsule machine, it was best to leave everything in its package for later. I said my goodbyes to my student as he got on his flight, and I returned home. At home, I assembled the machine together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WCVt6N6YrKQzHdydk795jq5pDIG4Kh8g"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W6pv6WK6LDvzFFsPq_p6JPk1vvkv5tAA" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Success! A miniature capsule machine for my shelf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I had one, I needed to have them all! I searched for the set on the Internet and learned what I could. This particular set was called &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ガチャガチャマシーン&lt;/span&gt;３ (or Gatcha Gatcha Machine 3), and it was released in December 2021. So, it was already out in the wild for 3 months. I learned that you can buy full distributions of some capsule times on Amazon.  For Gatcha Gatcha Machine 3 that consisted of 24 capsules, which was 3 complete sets of 8 items: 3 red machines, 3 white machines, 1 pack of capsules, and 1 set of metal shelves.  So, the Capsules I had gotten were a 1/8 rare pull. The red machine was a typical 3/8 pull.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continued searching on Yahoo Auctions to find someone selling the missing items in my set, but most people were selling a full set of 8 or selling the rare pulls for a lot of money. Eh. I gave up. One capsule machine is good enough. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Update - March 2023&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This has continued to nag at me over the last year. The other day, I was back on Yahoo Auctions looking around and I saw an auction for the two unique pieces of the set I was missing: the white capsule machine and a set of the shelving. It was only $10, so why not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not long after they arrived in the mail. The White capsule machine was in perfect condition, looking amazing and working well. The shelving was not. The piece had clearly been sitting in the sun for an extended period of time because the rods were warped. You can notice this in the photos below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1py4symgPw3B3oKxTUbPCTG_nIpFaS95F"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1pyBmYMHRllm2WNUUmGKglQ4mM1EU0AVx" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qGV6HdaBK3TXTL6zNy3F91vL7N50zH0f"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1q9ifYNYOip5Ga7y6jQUggswpCBr_0DQV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it sits on my shelf, you can't really notice. But I notice, and it annoys me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given this is the 3rd release of the Gacha Gacha Machine, the company had the foresight of expanding your collection of machines. If you happen to get two sets of shelving, you can combine into an expanded shelf that can hold four machines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I had a complete set, I could easily buy another complete set and combine them together. There was one on Yahoo Auctions for only $22.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qDdTq5zavdTQqeGzuAThq-CYLajrXfra"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qLPsR0i41aMfBRSoD22jKj1MzGfv2OHw" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qKOkjk_thQkMcKLsciKciNrHZWC9aQ0n"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qKNmFWLvxevMNv0VxDZaEzKwG6wygmpR" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It came in the mail pretty quickly, and the shelves were not bent whatsoever. The seller really took care of these compared to the last person. The shelves easily snapped together, and the machine easily snapped to the shelves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qc_Fsds3YQbbSAqr21enqkkNr1CJnQk_"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qVa-xFSRkh0rxBe63D8NsBhQGCUhtJpA" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qZt43vQYOVvkdx8nQND0LH6McM8hIWFF"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qkXAQAftbqt4aCnSN2GyPcR5y9aEapw3" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it looked pretty great. The shelves themselves are a bit flimsy, though. It's easy to understand how the sun could have warped them. If I were a real craftsmen, it might be worthwhile to try and make metal replacements. Or maybe 3D print slightly thicker ones. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But my collection is now complete, and I think it looks really nice on my shelf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qejAe_fhqykJEA6WCco-lf7Q-glm8x33"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qdOY_YgF9rC1n2FWLrQDgVYK86maUFzQ" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/capsule-machine-capsule</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Unown Availability</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Unown is a Pokemon from Gold/Silver that has 28 different forms. Each form is a letter of the alphabet, plus a question mark and exclamation point. Unown is special because it was originally only available at physical events. And at those events, only specific letters were available. Over time, it's become easier to catch at least one form of Unown, but certain letters have only been available a few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, which letters are the most common? Which ones are rare? And where have they been released?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been keeping track on this page: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/unown"&gt;/apps/pokemon/unown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This page shows the data in 4 ways:&lt;br/&gt;1. It shows which ones I'm missing and which events they were available at.&lt;br/&gt;2. It shows an ascending list of the rarest Unowns and their events from the last 3 years.&lt;br/&gt;3. It shows an ordered list of how many times each Letter has been available, and which events.&lt;br/&gt;4. And, it shows each individual event where Unown had been available, and which ones were there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this page to determine whether or not I should throw away some Unown after I catch them. If I go to an event in Japan, and a particular form appears that has not appeared back in the US, I'll hold on to more than usual so I can trade with people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Exclamation Point, for example, was available at Go Fest in 2019, but has not been available since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dp3JmY3OgR8oXqEAM--z7EuekCevrtlm"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dlPJ12eOjWXRP5rIJVmFnd8EWJNOPt76" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/unown-availability</link></item></channel></rss>