<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>One Schlock's Requiem is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher of English living in central Japan.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 04:09:24 +0900</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 04:09:24 +0900</lastBuildDate><link>https://theschlock.com/</link><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://theschlock.com/feed.xml"/><category>Japan / Games / Other Stuff</category><item><title>Sunset from the Tokyo Metro Building</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Tokyo is full of distinct buildings that make its skyline unique. The Tokyo Metro Building in west Shinjuku is one such building known for its twin towers. It was often depicted in classic anime series (particularly CLAMP series) as a source of power. In reality, it's a governmental building which administrates all the city affairs of Shinjuku and surrounding neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides that, the building serves another purpose which attracts quite a few tourists. Its observation deck is one of the best spots in Tokyo to view the whole city. And for free! I've been here several times before, and wrote about it too &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/tokyo-metropolitan-building" title="https://theschlock.com/tokyo-metropolitan-building"&gt;over 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was in Tokyo for school business, and as school business concluded, it was near sunset and I was near the Metro Building. I met up with another teacher and some of our students, and we walked to the building to catch the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only was our timing perfect, but because of the completely clear weather we had all weekend, Mt. Fuji was very visible right next to the sun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The clear weather also gave a perfect view of that beautiful Tokyo skyline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of people crowded around the west windows of the observation deck, but it wasn't as crowded as you'd think. I found a spot near a window and kept snapping photos of the sun slowly moving closer and closer to the horizon, until it finally went below the mountains left of Fuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had fun staring at the sun. It didn't sustain the interest of my students and the other teacher, though, as they were waiting for me on a couch nearby. They were hungry as their school business of the day was just as long as mine. Also, they were in a bit of hurry since they had tickets for an event at 7pm. We had dinner as fast as we could, then I saw them off in a taxi. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contemplating what to do with the rest of my evening, I decided to return to the observation deck and take some night photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last time I visited the Metro Building was in summer with some college friends in Japan on vacation. One night, we went to the Metro Building to watch the nightly &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5247.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5247.jpg"&gt;projected illumination event&lt;/a&gt;, which happens 3 times a day after nightfall. Visualizations were projected on the east side of the Metro building, which pulsed and moved to music. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visualizations matched the architecture of the building, and sometimes it felt like the building was transformed into a circuit board, or blocks which broke away in a fantasy landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, I was on the reverse side of the projection, looking down at the crowd and the projectors shooting up at me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looks like the projection is done using 28 projectors on the roof of the assembly building, opposite of the 45-story main building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, viewing the sunset from an observation point in Tokyo was one of the things on my bucket list (which I had forgotten), so I was glad to end the weekend and my business trip with such a beautiful site. Tomorrow, it's back to the blizzard up in the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/sunset-from-the-tokyo-metro-building</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/sunset-from-the-tokyo-metro-building</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Unicorn Gundam in Odaiba</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In Odaiba, Tokyo's manmade island in southeastern Tokyo, in front of the Diver City shopping mall and entertainment area, is one of Japan's full-scale, 1-to-1 life-sized Gundams. In fact, this is the premiere location of Japan's full-sized Gundams, of which there are 3 now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2017, the RX-0 Unicorn Gundam occupies this spot. This Gundam is from the anime series and novel, Mobile Suit Gundam Unicorn. As I understand it, Gundam Unicorn was a soft reboot or retelling of the original Gundam story. Or maybe a modern side story set during the time of the original. Made in 2010, it was a breath of fresh air and a return to roots for the franchise after countless spinoffs, sequels, and over-saturation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most iconic of gundams is the original RX-78 model, which occupied this space from 2009 to 2016. It was built to celebrate the Gundam franchise's 30th anniversary. People say that it was replaced with the Unicorn Gundam as a symbol of Japan moving into the future, with their bid for the 2020 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original RX-78 Gundam is still sometimes used for events. It was recently used in front of the Gundam Factory in Yokohama, which closed last year. Now, it might be in Osaka according to Wikipedia. Another full-sized Gundam is in Fukuoka, which was completed in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After arriving in Tokyo for a business trip, I went to Odaiba to see the Gundam during sunset. The timing ended out working perfectly. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 times a day, the Gundam performs its transformation sequence. I was able to catch the 5pm one, the last of the day. At night, there was a musical performance, but I wanted to get to my hotel and prepare for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/unicorn-gundam-in-odaiba</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/unicorn-gundam-in-odaiba</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Photo Collage Page</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 25 years, I've been taking photos and displaying them online, here. In fact, displaying my artwork was the original purpose for creating my website in the first place. Over time, the purpose of my website changed. Photography became more important to me than artwork. Then, writing more focused content became more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continue to take a lot of photos with my digital camera, but those photos are all attached to posts and only viewable at the bottoms of those pages. My writing is always put first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I've made a page that puts my photos first: the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo" title="https://theschlock.com/photo"&gt;Photo Collage Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo" title="https://theschlock.com/photo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From here, you can view all the photos I've marked as important or significant. You can click into them and view the corresponding post if it's available, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Diamond Grid Photos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The photos on the Photo page have been individually selected by me, after sifting through most of the over 20,000 images available on the site. While going through photos, I noticed there were many photo galleries in the directory that didn't have blog posts associated with them. Over time, I will add these posts to the site with the attached images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have already added a few of these posts. In particular, I added 2 major clusters of posts. The first cluster was my 2011 trip to Japan with my brother. We traveled around the Kansai region going to Osaka, Kyoto, Nara, and few other cities. The second cluster was my 2014 trip to Okinawa. I visited many war sites and met up with my friend Justin while he was stationed there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These posts are all back dated to when they took place. You can find them through the archive page from &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/archive/2011/6" title="https://theschlock.com/archive/2011/6"&gt;June 2011&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/archive/2014/7" title="https://theschlock.com/archive/2014/7"&gt;July 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of these past posts, I have now surpassed 1000 blog entries on the site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Single Photos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the pages I had on a previous version of my site showed off random photos of mine without any real context. These were singular photos that I thought looked nice, so I wanted to those photos on this page too. So, I added a new photo folder on the backend for single photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still continue to take random photos with my camera or my phone when I'm walking around, so I'll continue to add nice looking photos to the Photo page as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Updates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To match the diamond grid motif, image galleries on posts also have the diamond grid, replacing the original square grid. I might add more 45 degree angles in other places, too, to have more things match. We'll see, though. Keeping things simple around here is still important.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/photo-collage-page</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/photo-collage-page</link><category>Others</category><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Mt. Fuji 富士山 from Kofu 甲府</title><description>&lt;p&gt;From where I live, the fastest way to get to Tokyo is to drive. The second fastest way is by bus. Either way, after spending 2 hours driving up and down mountain roads, you reach the expressway onramp in Matsumoto, leading to the Chuo Expressway &lt;span class='ja'&gt;中央自動車道&lt;/span&gt;. It extends from south Nagano prefecture and goes directly to Tokyo in about 3 hours of driving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After traveling an hour on the highway and entering Yamanashi prefecture, Japan's most famous mountain comes into view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mt. Fuji &lt;span class='ja'&gt;富士山&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heading south on the Chuo Expressway gives you a clear view of Mt. Fuji. On a clear day, it is very visible coming in and out of view depending on the trees. The above photos were taken in November a while ago. (Taken on the iPhone while driving)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I escorted one of my students to Narita Airport, so we drove the whole way. Driving to Tokyo ends up being the cheapest way of travel when divided between multiple people not planning on staying multiple days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it was snow storming in my town of Takayama, the weather was pretty fair on the highway, and Mt. Fuji was clearly visible again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My student slept through the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We left around 8:30am and arrived at the Chiba Costco at 1:30pm. 5 hours is a pretty good time considering we stopped at a service area for about 20 minutes. After checking him into his flight and seeing him off, I went back westward and stayed the night in Kofu (cheaper than Tokyo).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kofu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;甲府&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kofu is a city directly north of Mt. Fuji in Yamanashi prefecture. If you plan on going to Mt. Fuji from the north, this is the highway exit you take, and then continue south. I've stayed here a few times before planning on going to Mt. Fuji the following day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This morning, Google Maps told me to go west to get on the highway to head back home. It brought me to the Futaba service area &lt;span class='ja'&gt;双葉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;サービスエリア&lt;/span&gt;. It was an absolutely beautiful clear bright morning, contrasting the snowy skies up in the mountains 3 hours away in Takayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Service Area has an observation tower giving a clear view of Mt. Fuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a higher resolution panoramic photo:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I had gone up here. The Futaba service area is also a scheduled stop on the Bus Route from Takayama to Shinjuku Bus Center, so I have been at the service area many times, just not to this side of the service area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have another business trip to Tokyo this coming weekend, so I'll go up there again and take more photos. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/mt-fuji-from-kofu</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/mt-fuji-from-kofu</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Site Design History</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It's weird to think, but this year marks 25 years of having some form of Internet home page. It all started with Geocities as a portfolio showcasing work from art school. Then, my site moved to Tripod where I tried making a web comic. And then to its home here at theschlock.com posting game reviews and photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I came across some of my old pages, and I wanted to find a way to surface them again. The actual content is too personal (or problematic), so I couldn't surface the pages in their original form, so I decided to reuse the old designs with all the posts currently available on the site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the current version of the site, I would count 8 distinct versions of my home pages over 4 clear eras of experimentation and learning. FYI, not all the links on these pages are available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Geocities Era&lt;/u&gt; / Microsoft Frontpage&lt;br/&gt;Version 0 - &lt;b&gt;Art Portfolio&lt;/b&gt; (2000, or 1999?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tripod Era&lt;/u&gt; / Microsoft Frontpage&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v1" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v1"&gt;Version 1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Original Version&lt;/b&gt; (June 12th 2000 - April 2002)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v2" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v2"&gt;Version 2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Updated Version&lt;/b&gt; (April 2002 - January 2003)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Domain Era&lt;/u&gt; / Macromedia Dreamweaver&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v3" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v3"&gt;Version 3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Experimental Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (January 2003 - February 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v4" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v4"&gt;Version 4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Clean Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (February 2003 - August 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v5" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v5"&gt;Version 5&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Framed Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - June 2005)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v6" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v6"&gt;Version 6&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Movable Type&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - August 2006)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wordpress Era&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v7" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v7"&gt;Version 7&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt; (August 2006 - March 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Current Era&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history" title="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history"&gt;Version 8&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Tapestry / Java&lt;/b&gt; (March 2014 - present)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Origins&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Internet was an absolute marvel to me. Everyone was spreading out on the net and carving their own corner of it for themselves. Everyone had their own website for their art, for their stupid movies, for their forums, for their ideas. I was in art school, so I wanted to be like all the other artists online, showcasing their stuff. Too bad I was a terrible artist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how to actual make a webpage. I don't remember the details, but it seems like I downloaded Microsoft Frontpage, which generated the code of my original pages, and put together a design based on other pages I liked. Geocities and Tripod offered free hosting, so I put it there and linked to other people's pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Version 0 - &lt;b&gt;Art Portfolio&lt;/b&gt; (Geocities, 2000)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v1" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v1"&gt;Version 1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Original Version&lt;/b&gt; (June 12th 2000 - April 2002)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v2" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v2"&gt;Version 2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Updated Version&lt;/b&gt; (April 2002 - January 2003)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Note: I am unable to retrieve any Geocities data at this time, so I'll try to revisit it later.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Domain&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After art school, I went to a real school and started learning programming. I started meeting more people who also cared about making an online presence for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;November 2002 was when I bought theschlock.com. Also, for that Christmas, I got my first digital camera, and starting taking tons of photos. I wanted to make a site that used my photography more in its design and showcased photos. I started going to more clubs, and wanted to put those photos online, too. I started thinking about having a multipage design, rather than a single landing page with links.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found Macromedia Dreamweaver online which was WAY more user friendly than Frontpage. I could actually edit things in a design view and move them around. It gave me more freedom. This really helped me develop a sense of web-design. I still had yet to fully understand HTML, but Dreamweaver had both design views and code views, so I could watch the code change as I moved things around. After a while, I could take off the training wheels and write the code myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v3" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v3"&gt;Version 3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Experimental Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (January 2003 - February 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v4" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v4"&gt;Version 4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Clean Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (February 2003 - August 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v5" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v5"&gt;Version 5&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Framed Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - June 2005)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I messed around with some designs and eventually landed on the last one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blogs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time I landed on that last design, I was living with friends and fellow students who were in web development at school. They also made their own websites, and quite knowledgable about all things Internet. Blogging software started becoming an actual business, and people had begun transitioning from completely custom hobbyist sites into Blogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology had changed too. Making website updates was no longer about directly editing HTML and uploading it. The underlying database would hold all the data, and software running on the server would generate the page. I didn't fully understand this. I had really only just grasped the top layer of web-dev.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my friends loved Movable Type, so I installed it on theschlock.com from his recommendation. I used it in tandem with the Framed version of the site. Moveable Type would handle all the long posts about games and whatever. The Framed version was updated with photos and pictorials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v6" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v6"&gt;Version 6&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Movable Type&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - August 2006)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used this site through the remainder of college.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearing the end of college, the Internet and blogging had matured. My site design was pretty "old" for the Internet and MovableType wasn't totally user-friendly to use. By then, Wordpress completely overtook all of independent blogging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to studying abroad in Japan, I downloaded my entire site locally and zipped it. I installed Wordpress on theschlock.com, which completely took over. Wordpress was WAY more user friendly than Movable Type, and I could easily write about everything I was doing in Japan, and show all my photos, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v7" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v7"&gt;Version 7&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt; (August 2006 - March 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I choose the design from a template, but then changed it slightly to be different. Not all that much, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After graduating, I still continued to use it. Working as a developer, I learned so much about using Java to manage and maintain websites, but I never had the headspace to use it on any personal projects. I had the time, but I already spent all day thinking about websites at work. I needed to decompress at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Version&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the current version of the site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Wordpress was far more user-friendly than my previous versions, it didn't feel special. It didn't feel like it was mine. Wordpress used PHP at the time, which I never liked. PHP feel far too loose and I couldn't understand it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to remake everything from scratch and have complete control over everything on the site in a more modern capacity. I had started laying some initial groundwork in 2012. But then, after moving to Japan and settling in, I finally had the headspace to execute on my ideas completely. I knew exactly what I wanted and exactly how to make what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote about all this in the first post on this version of the site on &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start" title="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start"&gt;March 4th, 2014&lt;/a&gt; as the site went live for the first time. Around 2 months later, the full design was complete. I wrote about that &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start-2" title="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start-2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history" title="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history"&gt;Version 8&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Current&lt;/b&gt; (March 2014 - now)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the site I had always wanted. I had complete control over everything on the site, and it was extensible enough to have new things over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running an active website isn't all that easy, though. It was always going down after a couple of days. I kept up with it for nearly 3 years. Then, one day, when I checked on it, the site was gone. Deleted from my host. My host had dropped support, so that was the end of that service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 years ago, with renewed programming interest, I finally brought the site back online, nearly 9 years after its initial launch. I posted about it on &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/website-revival" title="https://theschlock.com/website-revival"&gt;March 9th 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, the online version of my site is a generated mess of static HTML files. Because of this, there should no longer ever be any problems with hosting in the future. There's nothing running on the host, nor any database it's pulling from. It is free from any technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Future&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This design has changed and been refined a little bit over the years, but I doubt there will ever be another complete redesign of the site. The design still holds all the key values I want for written online content, and it's easy for me to add new things and change them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although...  Now that I have a framework for displaying my blogging content with different designs, I could experiment with new designs and see if anything sticks. Or, I could design terrible versions of my site in the same way that much of the blogging sites have turned into.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Revisiting many of these old pages has given me some new ideas, too, so stay tuned. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/site-design-history</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/site-design-history</link><category>Others</category><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Modded Console Game Inventory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I created a webpage that catalogues the library of games I have available on modded video game consoles. Last year, I set up a method of playing Playstation 2 games, and created a page that showed off that library of games. That was called the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory"&gt;Playstation 2 Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, my modded console collection is going to expand with the release of the Flippy Drive on the Gamecube. I also started looking at Dreamcast mods for fun, and decided to set up a Dreamcast with tons of games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With my modded console collection expanding, the Playstation 2 Game Inventory page has also expanded. I renamed it to the &lt;b&gt;Modded Console Game Inventory&lt;/b&gt; page, and it now displays Gamecube and Dreamcast games. It will probably expand even further in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modded Console Game Inventory Page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had thought about adding all these games into the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library" title="https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library"&gt;Digital Retro Game Library&lt;/a&gt;, which catalogues far more games and consoles available on the Analogue Pocket and Mister. But, those are more curated lists rather than a full inventory, like this list. As such, I decided to keep them separate.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory</link><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Projects</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Dreamcast GDemu Software Preparation</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I started thinking about the Dreamcast thanks to a recent playthrough of Crazy Taxi from ADGQ. While many of the games have been released and made available on other consoles and platforms throughout the years, there are still several games orphaned on the Dreamcast. Plus, the authentic feel of the playing the game, and hearing the original sounds and music is often not well replicated elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, and 8bitmods eventual release of their VMU Memcard Pro, I decided to look into Dreamcast mods to determine what it would take to put together a console capable of playing its vast library via hard drive or sd card, similar to the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/a&gt; set up I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Somewhat surprisingly, it does not seem difficult at all. Many moderns mods are parts replacement for internal components. You still need to open up the console and take things apart, but you aren't soldering any mod chips or replacing capacitors. You just unplug this component, remove it, and plug in this one instead. Very plug and play. Many of these parts are pretty cheap through AliExpress too!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I ordered a bunch of parts this week. My Dreamcast is back in the states, so even though the parts will arrive over the next two weeks, assembly will have to wait until after summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I can prepare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreamcast GDemu&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main mod used in the Dreamcast is the &lt;b&gt;GDemu&lt;/b&gt;. It is a PCB replacement for the entire GD-ROM reader assembly. To install, you need to take out the GD-ROM disc reader, and put this PCB in there instead. The GDemu board has an SD card reader attached to it, and this is where all of the games are stored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought a SanDisk Extreme 128gb card, Class 10. Game are around 1.2gb each, which I thought would be enough space. But, I'm already getting close to the upper limit of space. A 256gb cards would've been better. I might upgrade later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people online have complained about compatibility, but I think those complaints predate the current version of GDemu. More recent videos and posts have said similar SD cards work just fine for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Format SD Card&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDemu requires the SD card to be FAT-32 format. One person said that using 64k byte cluster sizes can help with readability, too, so I opted for that. (It probably doesn't matter.) Using Diskutil, Macs will format FAT-32 with a cluster size of 32k bytes. So, for the 64k byte cluster size, you can use the following terminal commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;diskutil unmount SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;br/&gt;sudo newfs_msdos -F 32 -c 128 -v VOLUMEID /dev/SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;br/&gt;diskutil mount SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive must be unmounted first before formatting it, then the &lt;code&gt;newfs_msdos&lt;/code&gt; command is used. &lt;code&gt;VOLUMEID&lt;/code&gt; is the new name of your SD card, and &lt;code&gt;SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;/code&gt; is the identifier used in disk utils.  Check &lt;code&gt;diskutil list&lt;/code&gt; for the correct identifier. &lt;code&gt;-F 32&lt;/code&gt; is for FAT-32. &lt;code&gt;-c 128&lt;/code&gt; is for the 64 byte cluster size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(The reasons for 128 with -c is a little complicated. Overall, we want a 64k byte size. In bytes, this is 64x1024 = 65,536 bytes. The SD card has a block size of 512 bytes, so we do 65,536/512, which is 128. This number describes the number of blocks in a cluster.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, our SD card is in the current format. Now, we need games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To combat piracy, Sega and Yamaha created a new disc format for the Dreamcast called the GD-ROM. GD-ROMs held up to 1gb of information, surpassing the 650mb limits of the CD-ROM. One unique feature of the GD-ROM was that information was "burned" into the CD from the outside in, rather than inside out, like CD-ROMs. Both of these together were expected to make the Dreamcast secure from people burning their own games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within one year after its North American release, this was circumvented. Even though games were on GD-ROMs, the Dreamcast could still read CD-ROMs, so hacker group Utopia created the infamous Utopia disc which forced the Dreamcast to boot in CD-ROM mode. Games could then be burned to CD-ROMs and run nearly identically to the GD-ROMs. Some stuff had to be cut from games to fit into the 650mb CD limit, but many GD-ROMs filled their discs with dummy information anyways.  Much of this dummy information was just pushing the data to the outer edge of the disc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Dreamcast games can be found online in two main formats: GDI and CDI files. GDI is usually preferred as the CDI version could have cut content to fit into 650mb. Although, the problem with GDI files is that they are always 1.1gb or 1.2gb to simulate the full size of the disc. It's possible to shrink these sizes, cutting out the extra content, but that can still cause some compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Game Management&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games are copied to the SD card, but the GDemu requires a specific file and folder structure. You also need files for the GD Menu, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found this amazing &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4"&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; from Derek Pascarella fully describing the software-wide of how to set up and manage games for your Dreamcast using the GDemu. Here's that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; again. The rest of this post is basically going to parrot this video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will need to download 2 things for Games and Menu management. And there's one more thing to download to edit Boxart and Metadata for games in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1) The &lt;a href="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager" title="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager"&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/a&gt; is how you will manage all your games&lt;br/&gt;2) &lt;a href="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu" title="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu"&gt;Open Menu&lt;/a&gt; is the most modern menu used in the Dreamcast to choose your games.&lt;br/&gt;3) The &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;OpenMenu DAT Tool&lt;/a&gt; for editing boxart and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Open Menu DAT Tool is available through the dreamcast-talk forum, which is member only and a little difficult to gain access. The video has a link to their personal Google Drive for the file. The link above connects to my Google Drive, where I also have a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager" title="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager"&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/a&gt; works for both Mac and PC. When you open the program, choose your SD card from the menu. You can choose whether to install GDmenu or Open Menu. Any game you want install, just drag into the window, rename to whatever you want, and hit Save Changes at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the GDemu wants each disc in its own folder, numbered starting from 01. The 01 folder is special and it must contain the GDemu menu (GDmenu or openMenu). The Card Manager will copy the correct files for you. From 02, each folder is for a game disc. Again, the Card Manager will manage all these folders for you. When adding new games, you can have them alphabetically sorted, and the Manager will rearrange everything for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some options are missing in the Mac version of the Card Manager. I'm not able to shrink the GDI files for some reason. This is probably using something only available on PC. However, as the video mentions, shrinking GDI files is not a one-size-fits-all hammer solution. For full compatibility, it's best not to shrink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Game Serial Numbers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like Playstation games, Dreamcast games each have a unique identifier. All retail games do this, but hacks, ports, and other self-published indie titles sometimes don't. For example, the Dreamcast port of Divi-Dead and Grand Theft Auto III share the same serial number when added to the card manager, T00001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the game title, you can freely edit serial numbers to whatever you like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I changed Grand Theft Auto III's serial number to TGTA3. The only thing this disrupts is the boxart and metadata used for Open Menu, and we can fix that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Menu&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Menu Card Manager saves changes to the SD card, it copies all the menu information it has locally to the SD card. On PC, all of its dlls and subfolders are clearly visible. The openMenu files are stored in the following location: &lt;code&gt;tools/openMenu/menu_data&lt;/code&gt;. This is true for the Mac version, too, but all the files are hidden inside of the app. Click on the GDMENUCardManager.app file and "Show Package Contents." From there, the openMenu files are located here: &lt;code&gt;Contents/MacOS/tools/openMenu/menu_data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, there's not much there, but that's where there &lt;a href="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu" title="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu"&gt;Open Menu&lt;/a&gt; download comes in. Unzip the latest release and copy all of the contents of &lt;code&gt;menu_data&lt;/code&gt; into the above location. Click on Save Changes in the Menu Manager, and your openMenu is completely up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Boxart and Metadata Changes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Open Menu files we copied to the GD Menu app were 3 DAT files, &lt;code&gt;BOX.DAT&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ICON.DAT&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;META.DAT&lt;/code&gt;. These are file databases which house boxart, game icon, and metadata for all the Dreamcast games. It has all retail games, indie games, and most other ports and hacks. But, it doesn't have everything. And if you changed any serial numbers, it definitely doesn't have those games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;OpenMenu DAT Tool&lt;/a&gt; will allow you to edit them. You can add new images (PNG format only) and create the menu icon from that. You can add and edit any metadata for games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save all the changes back to the DAT files for the Card Manager. And then "Save Changes" in the Card Manager to apply the changes to the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Preparation Complete&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the time being, my preparations are complete. I have loaded my SD card with over 100 discs. You can take a look at what I have available by viewing my &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory"&gt;Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll start getting the physical mods in the mail over the next few weeks. Then after summer vacation, I should have my Dreamcast available to install the mods.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation</link><category>Projects</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Lego Botanical - The Four Gentlemen</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Lego has released some new botanical sets to usher in the new year. These two new releases complement the releases from summer last year to create "The Four Gentlemen" of flowers, a classic staple of Chinese art representing ideal virtues and each of the four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These flowers (or plants) are the Chrysanthemum, the Plum Blossom, the Orchid, and the Bamboo, representing fall, winter, spring, and summer. I built each of these while streaming on Twitch, so take a look at the videos if you'd like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plum Blossom: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mini Orchid: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lucky Bamboo: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Chrysanthemum: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Four Gentlemen or Four Noble Ones originated in Chinese art over 1000 years ago. The Kanji for this is &lt;span class='ja'&gt;四君子&lt;/span&gt;, which reads &lt;i&gt;shikunshi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;しくんし&lt;/span&gt; in Japanese. Gentlemen, in this context, refers to an individual that exhibits virtues and morality that all people should aspire to. Each of the flowers represents different virtues stemming from their season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Lego release order, the Chrysanthemum &lt;span class='ja'&gt;菊&lt;/span&gt; represents fall. Despite the cooler weather, the flower blooms with bright energetic warm colors. It's generally considered a loner as its virtue is to share joy and shine proudly as yourself withstanding all adversities. It also symbolizes longevity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winter is represented by the Plum Blossom &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梅&lt;/span&gt;. Its petals bloom a sharp crimson contrasting the coldest whitest months of the year. Though, not the most beautiful flower, it continues the bloom its best in a time of the year when most other flowers can't survive. As such, the Plum represents inner beauty and humbleness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading into the new year, the Orchid &lt;span class='ja'&gt;蘭&lt;/span&gt; represents Spring. The orchid is a fragile flower, soft in a form and fragrance. It is often referred to as the most inoffensive flower. While Spring often represents new beginning, the orchid symbolizes nobility, friendship, and integrity, enduring life despite its frail form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blazing summer months are represented by the Bamboo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹&lt;/span&gt;. Physically, the bamboo is the absolute strongest of the Four Gentlemen, able to bend without breaking against harsh winds and rain. By yielding and not breaking, its virtues are cultivation, integrity, and loyalty. Bamboo is also hollow despite its strength, which also represents tolerance, humility, and open-mindedness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Altogether, the Four Gentlemen say you should be true to yourself, represent yourself with dignity and humility, and also stay true to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Lego sets, these look amazing and pair really well with the full-sized &lt;a href="lego-orchid" title="lego-orchid"&gt;Lego Orchid&lt;/a&gt;, released in the second wave of Botanical sets in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these sets have some form of repetition in their building, but it's really not bad considering each set only takes a full hour to build. The repetitious parts will only take about 5 minutes max. All sets have uncommon building techniques and parts usage that you probably hadn't thought of before. For example, the bulb of Chrysanthemum is created using over 30 lego bananas in different shades of yellow and orange. The flowers of the Mini Orchid use 3 handheld shield pieces, an interesting reference back to the Full Orchid, which uses 3 full-body shield pieces in its flowers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each are fun builds, look great, and are super cheap at only $30 each.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you were going to buy only one set out of them all, it's hard to recommend just one. My favorites are the Bamboo and the Chrysanthemum. Both of these sets look amazing at both a distance and up close. Originally, I skipped the Chrysanthemum because I thought the orange would outshine the others. It does quickly draw the eye, but the subtle perfection of the Bamboo can hold your eye just as long. Even though both are striking, I think they stay in their own lane as part of an ensemble. I think the Mini Orchid is the weakest. The bulbs on the full Orchid look more like flowers and less like Lego than the Mini-version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of them together create a very nice ensemble. There's still room on that shelf for more flowers, so I'm looking forward to the next Botanical sets Lego plans on releasing this year, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/lego-four-gentlemen</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/lego-four-gentlemen</link><category>Media</category><category>Toys</category></item><item><title>Okami</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Okami is a legendary game. I feel like everyone knows Okami and everyone loves Okami, but has everyone really played it? I don't think it really gets brought up in conversations past its art style. That's the camp I was in. I really liked the idea of Okami. I even bought it back in the day, but never really played it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Game Awards, an Okami Sequel was announced, which put the original game back on my immediate backlog. With revisiting a lot of classic games lately, I wanted to finally give Okami its shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, it's incredible. (I played through the PS4 version of Okami HD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly 20 years after its original release, its art style still looks fresh and stunning. The heavy thick black inked outlines create imagery invoking Japanese calligraphy and traditional painting matching the fairytale story it tells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story of the game starts like a fairytale, explaining a 100-year-old legend, a battle between the ultimate evil, the 8-headed serpent Orochi, being defeated by a hapless warrior, Nagi, and a wolf. The wolf was killed in battle, so the town erected a statue in her honor. Now, 100 years later, you emerge from the statue, a reincarnation of the wolf and the goddess of the sun, Okami Amaterasu. Someone broke the seal of Orochi, which has released you from the statue, so you now explore the land, cleanse the land of its curse, defeat his minions, and make your way to its layer reenacting the legend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okami is a very standard action adventure game which feels reminiscent of early 3D Legend of Zelda games. Through exploring, more areas of Japan are opened with more secrets and introducing more characters. Story sequences thrust you into exploring dungeons and defeating the monsters within. This results in giving you new weapons and abilities to expand your exploration in the world and also backtracking for previous secrets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The abilities you gain are executed using brush strokes. Hit the R1 button, and the whole scene pulls back to an inking canvas. Move the brush around to create strokes matching your abilities. Return to the scene, and the abilities execute by blooming trees, slashing enemies, and blowing wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like classic Zelda games, the story really opens up after completing the initial story sequence, the recreation of the 100-year legend. Evil still reigns in further areas of Japan, so you continue to chase after the shadows of the true evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up until this point, I had not really noticed how much of Okami was steeped in Japanese fairytales. I thought it was telling its own story. I did not know that the story of Orochi and Nagi was an actual Shinto tale until reaching the next section of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When reaching the major city, you meet Momotaro, try to locate Onigashima, also meet Urashimataro, and swim to the bottom of the sea to Ryuguujou (the Dragon Palace), and meet Otohime. You also meet Princes Sakuya, cut from Bamboo. These are all Japanese tales I'm quite familiar film. Momotaro and Onigashima is probably the most well known fairytale in Japan. All the kids here know it. The One-Inch Prince is another Japanese tale that I had read before and never made the connection to Issun, your companion throughout the whole game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not a Japanese fairytale or mythical expert, so many of these things went over my head on their first pass, but it never detracted from the experience for me. All of these stories felt natural within the story of Okami. There are fun references to real lore that really enhance the experience rather than use it as a crutch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was really surprised by Okami. The Japanese mythology, the overall structure and crafted nature of the gameplay and exploration, and the length of the game. I completed a full 100% playthrough in 52 hours. That's the same length as Twilight Princess, which came out a few months after Okami's original release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think a lot of people skipped Okami because the Playstation 2 was waning at that point. The Xbox 360 was released the year prior, and games looked FAR more incredible than the PS2. Okami released in September, and in just a few more months, the Playstation 3 and Nintendo Wii would be released. The future!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I was so busy finishing college in Spring and study abroad in Japan for my final semester in the Fall. When I came back in 2007, I immediately played Twilight Princess and then focused on other games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, as much as the art style is one of Okami's strongest points, cell shading was very divisive at the time. People hated Legend of Zelda Wind Waker because of its art style, and Twilight Princess was finally the realistic Zelda everyone wanted. I think this looked too "kiddy" for the PS2 crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm glad that I finally took the time to play through Okami, and I think more people really should do the same. Now that Okami finally has a second chance with this new sequel, I hope people actually buy into it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll be there.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/okami</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/okami</link><category>Game Specific</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Most Played Games in 2024</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This was another huge year in gaming for me, although my focus had somewhat shifted from the big platforms. I had begun moving away from Twitch and streaming, while focusing a lot on other gaming projects and other retro games. There were still some huge games this year, but I played a lot of games as more of a distraction from work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My year began with my continuation of playing through classic Zelda games. I had played through Zelda 1 and Zelda 2 at the end of the last year, and I started this year with Link's Awakening and the Oracle games on Gameboy. I finished up the Oracle games before the release of the biggest game this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Final Fantasy VII Rebirth&lt;/b&gt; was released in February, and it dominating my thoughts for the next two months. It's incredible that with such an expansive and huge game, all aspects felt hand-crafted and refined. Often huge open-world games use a lot of recycled quests or dungeons, using a script to manufacture its quantity. People argue there's too much stuff in Rebirth, but it's all there for the purpose of flushing out characters, lore, and story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both FF7 Remake and Rebirth are amazing examples of the lengths Nomura will go to retell the overall story of Final Fantasy 7 completely, which has been expanded upon over the 25 years since its original release. Everything feels like it's been completely thought out, even though the pacing is perhaps a bit much. I really hope the can stick the landing with the final game in the trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following Rebirth's story, once again, I went back to YouTube and watched a playthrough of the original Final Fantasy 7 to compare the story. It made me really nostalgic for the original playstation, especially Final Fantasy 8. I had always preferred FF8 because of its characters, but I've largely forgotten it all at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started looking into what it would take to play old Playstation and Playstation 2 games, and with several videos on YouTube showing how this was done, I put together a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;PlayStation 2 set-up&lt;/a&gt; to have access to all those games from my high school and college years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This became somewhat cyclical as I played a lot of Earth Defense Force 2 on PS2, then moved back to the PlayStation 5 for the recent release of &lt;b&gt;Earth Defense Force 6&lt;/b&gt;. Both excellent games of running around and shooting gigantic bugs and monsters. EDF6 is probably the best in the series at this point, combining modern graphics and frame rate with the highest variety of enemies in the whole series. I bought the Japanese version to save some money, which ended up being a mistake because I missed out on the campy English performances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the harsh Spring and Summer, I went back to story-driven games with &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/dead-space" title="https://theschlock.com/dead-space"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dead Space&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Callisto Protocol&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, actually taking photos in game and exploring their stories and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nintendo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Switch didn't see a lot of play this year as I took a break from Pokemon and Twitch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, in Spring, Nintendo announced a new Zelda was coming in September. We had just gotten Tears of the Kingdom last year, and already we're getting another game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Zelda: &lt;b&gt;Echoes of Wisdom&lt;/b&gt; was the first canon Zelda game where you actually played as Zelda. It featured a creative game mechanic of using objectives in the environment to climb, fight, and explore the world to eventually save Link. Its style immediately identified itself as being developed by Grezzo, who did the &lt;b&gt;Link's Awakening Remake&lt;/b&gt; from a few years ago. As such, I bought that and played through that as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading up to summer, I played through the remake of &lt;b&gt;Super Mario RPG&lt;/b&gt; on Switch. It was interesting playing through both remakes so close to each other along with FF7. Nintendo has an absolute vibrant history of games. Everyone has their own interpretations of those games and how they could best be adapted to today. Mario RPG does almost nothing to modernize itself beyond some quality of life changes to the gameplay. The story, the maps, and the pacing are all the same from the original. Link's Awakening is pretty much the same, too. It's the complete opposite of Final Fantasy 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's obviously no one best approach to remaking games. Would you rather have a gaming experience that reminds you of your childhood by playing a semi-modern version of the old game? Or would you rather have a new experience reliving the old story with the characters and lore you remember? For this year, Final Fantasy has had much more of an impact on me than these Nintendo remakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, with cheaper versions being release, I finally bought a Mister. This complements my Playstation 2 and Analogue Pocket for having access to decades of gaming history. Many of these older games still hold up quite well without the need of a remake or new version. I played through &lt;b&gt;Snatcher&lt;/b&gt; for the first time in decades and it's still an incredible experience, and one that I don't think would translate well to a modern remake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel incredible fortunate to have access to all these games from my past. And while I don't always have the time to play, I'm also grateful for the time I do have along with a platform to show them off.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/most-played-games-2024</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/most-played-games-2024</link><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Today's Posts</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have rearranged some of the categories for posts on the site to make way for a new feature. There are now 4 main categories of posts: Japan, Games, Media, and Others. Music has been a dormant category for a while, so I moved it into Media. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was to make room for a link to "Today's Posts." When you click on this, it will show all the posts made on this day in the past. You can further click to view all days and see a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/today" title="https://theschlock.com/today"&gt;full calendar&lt;/a&gt; of all the visible posts on the site and which days they were made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The archive is still the best way to view all posts available on the site, but the Today calendar offers a different perspective. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/todays-posts</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/todays-posts</link><category>Others</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Arrival &amp; Language</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Arrival tells a unique story about teaching and learning language while adapting to the culture of a complete foreign language. I instantly fell in love with this film when I saw it for the first time 7 years ago. I had been living in a foreign country for almost 5 years at that point teaching English, so I felt like it spoke to me directly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since I saw this film, I wanted to tell my students about it, and I had the chance the next week at my junior high school. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/arrival" title="https://theschlock.com/arrival"&gt;Here's that post&lt;/a&gt;. Since starting high school, I wanted to use it again in a much larger capacity. And I finally accomplished that this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the film, we discussed the overall story and ideas before focusing on the theory of "switching brains" when using different languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Story&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film begins with Louise (played by Amy Adams) narrating life to her daughter. The joy of her birth to the pain of her unexpected premature death. A person's life is often defined by moments outside of their control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h39m16s897.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h39m16s897.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h39m16s897_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h39m16s897_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h39m16s897_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Louise arrives at her university to teach a class about language, life is interrupted by alien spacecraft appearing in 12 locations in different countries throughout the world. There is no announcement from the spaceships, but every 18 hours, a chamber is opened allowing people to enter and have contact with the aliens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the chaos, Louise is contacted by U.S. Army Colonel Weber (Forrest Whitaker) asking for her help to translate a message from the aliens. Impossible from just a recording, she, Weber, and Physicist Ian Donnely (Jeremy Renner) travel to Montana to the spaceship. They meet the aliens, but ultimately have no physical commonality to bridge communication. The aliens sound more like animals to us rather than sentient beings. (End of Part 1 in class)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Louise hits a breakthrough when she uses a whiteboard to write our language and show it to the aliens. Having a visual representation of our language allows the aliens to understand and reciprocate with their written language. This also allows Louise to have a tangible and concrete connection from their language to ours, given her a starting point to begin a rough method of translation and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h57m09s565.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h57m09s565.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h57m09s565_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h57m09s565_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h57m09s565_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h58m14s439.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h58m14s439.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h58m14s439_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h58m14s439_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-10h58m14s439_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Louise and Ian live at the army camp and spend every waking minute working on a method of translating the alien language. Every time the alien craft opens, Louse and Ian enter, and do their best to communicate with the aliens. From the written sentences, they build vocabulary and grammar, and they also build a device that can replicate the alien sentences and show them to the aliens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weeks have passed. They are finally near the point of being able to ask them, "What is the purpose of your visit?" They ask the question and get a response which translates to "Offer Weapon." This response creates conflict between Louise's team and the military execs who never fully trusted the aliens. (End of Part 2 in class)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m56s259.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m56s259.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m56s259_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m56s259_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m56s259_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Language is Messy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming up with a 2-word response to such a large question is bound to have some errors, particularly in English. Looking through an English dictionary will give you plenty of words that roughly mean the same thing with small subtle differences. For anyone who has never thought about it before, these differences are often hard to identify, too. Like, what's the difference between &lt;i&gt;talk&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;speak&lt;/i&gt;, or &lt;i&gt;hear&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;listen&lt;/i&gt;? Any English speakers can tell you that these words have different meanings and uses, but can you clearly explain why they're different?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, these subtle differences are being translated into another language and back. The words of a language carry more than just their meaning. The meanings are often derived from the lineage of the country's culture, and their usage is determined from the society that came from that culture. When the society and culture of two languages are completely separate with completely separate pasts and values, you lose a lot in translation and need more context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This spoke to me directly being an American teaching English in Japan. English and Japanese are two of the most distant languages on Earth. At the base level, our writing, alphabet, grammar, and vocabulary are totally different. But, going up one level, our languages are also separated by different pasts and cultures which have created words used in completely different settings with different weights. To go from one language to the other requires more knowledge than just a dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, multiply this idea by another dimension to try and make contact with an alien species whose planet, biology, and even perception of reality are completely foreign to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m55s802.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m55s802.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m55s802_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m55s802_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h26m55s802_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Language from Culture&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's look at two specific sentences in Japanese and English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;I watch TV at home.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;私は家でテレビを見ます。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The order of English grammar has the subject, verb, and predicate of the sentence in that order. The Japanese sentence starts with the subject, but it ends with the verb. All the further details of the sentence are given before closing with the action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think English is a very &lt;b&gt;direct&lt;/b&gt; language. With any sentence, we immediately state the information of &lt;b&gt;who&lt;/b&gt; does &lt;b&gt;what&lt;/b&gt;. Any other information that builds context to that situation is given after. That information is of secondary importance. Most European languages follows this same pattern, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, European nations have focused on outward expansion and conquering. Greeks and Romans, then English, Spanish, and Portuguese through the world, then Americans in North America. Through our history of conflict and war, we have more aggressive and direct personalities, which is reflected in our direct language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Japanese language is the near opposite. Grammatically, the action is stated last. Their sentences care more about the details of the situation before deciding on the action. Because of this, Japanese is often described as an &lt;b&gt;indirect&lt;/b&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This also comes from history. Japan is a small island, and it didn't take long for all available space to be taken. Villages and settlements of people had nowhere to expand. If someone was exiled from a village, they couldn't make their own village. They would have to be accepted by another village, but that village would be suspicious of why they were exiled in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People needed a way to work together and not cause conflict. Direct language is often harsh, so their communication became soft and less direct, creating a more gentle and nice society. The Japanese language we have today came from these early ideals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In both cases, our histories and culture are reflected in the language we use today. This is also true with the alien's language in the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h21m38s941.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h21m38s941.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h21m38s941_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h21m38s941_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h21m38s941_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Immersion / "Switching Brains"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Louise is often able to read the alien sentences without using their translation device. Knowing about the small subtle differences in language, every small variation in the alien sentences brings up questions about why. Why is this different? What does this mean? How does this compare to a previous sentence with the same mark? Every day, she asks these questions to herself as she studies their language and refines their translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This immersion also brings about stress. She doesn't get a lot of sleep, so she often daydreams about her daughter. Ian notices this, and asks her about her dream. "When you dream, are you able to dream in their language?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This overall immersion is the center of Arrival's story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m23s049.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m23s049.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m23s049_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m23s049_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m23s049_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ian mentions that when you immerse yourself in a foreign language, you're able to rewire your brain to think in that language. People usually refer to this as "switching brains." When someone truly learns a language, they live it. They think in that language and can respond naturally in that language without ever using or thinking about their native language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, as people think and speak that foreign language, their personality can change to fit the culture of that language. As an example, I tend to speak softer when using Japanese and louder when using English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the film, as Louise uses the alien language, and thinks in the alien language, she has also slowly adapted to the culture of the aliens without realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h35m00s319.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h35m00s319.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h35m00s319_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h35m00s319_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h35m00s319_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h32m32s390.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h32m32s390.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h32m32s390_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h32m32s390_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h32m32s390_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Time&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;An alien sentence has no beginning and end, and it's written all at once without any order. This is completely different than any language on Earth. All of our sentences have a specific order. The components of the sentences might have a different order, but there's always a beginning and end, and language is also spoken in that same order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alien language becomes a visual representation for their perception of reality because their perception of time also has no beginning or end. An alien views their entire life all at once. As they live in their present, they also live in their past and their future. They know all of the events that will happen in their life as they live them simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Louise studied the language, she slowly gained this perception through the daydreams of her daughter, who is not born yet. Her daughter is born in the future, after Louise and Ian marry following the events of the film, after the aliens leave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her immersion and adaptation of the alien language allowed her to think like the aliens, who have no concept of linear time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-12h01m22s048.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-12h01m22s048.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-12h01m22s048_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-12h01m22s048_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-12h01m22s048_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Essay Topic 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first attempt at using Arrival for my writing class focused on this Immersion only. Students wrote an essay answering the question: &lt;b&gt;Is immersion necessary to completely understand a subject?&lt;/b&gt; Through Louise immersing herself in the alien language, she could completely understand it and adapt to their way of thinking. In general, was this really necessary?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was fine, but the result of that immersion is more important. I think it's a more interesting question to ask whether it is possible to "switch brains."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In more definitive terms, The Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis explains the idea of "switching brains." As a foundation, the hypothesis states that every language has a culture behind it, and this language and culture creates a thought process and view of the world for the people of that language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m27s359.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m27s359.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m27s359_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m27s359_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m27s359_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m35s958.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m35s958.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m35s958_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m35s958_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h22m35s958_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This idea is split into two opposing theories: &lt;b&gt;Linguistic Relativity&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Linguistic Determinism&lt;/b&gt;. Usually when people mention the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis, there are referring to Linguistic Relativity. This is what Ian Donnelly does in the film. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linguistic Relativity&lt;/b&gt; means that when you learn and immerse yourself in a new language, you can also learn and change to the thought process of that language. When people "switch brains" to use a foreign language, they're also thinking like the people from that country and can view the world and situations in the same way. A person's thinking can change &lt;u&gt;relative&lt;/u&gt; to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linguistic Determinism&lt;/b&gt; is the opposite. A person's thought process and view of the world is &lt;u&gt;determined&lt;/u&gt; by their native language, or primary language. They can still learn new languages, but their thoughts and actions will always be influenced by their native language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Essay Topic 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese students spend a long time learning English in school. Their first classes are in elementary school, and become more numerous through junior high and senior high school. Even so, there's still a gap between our languages that prevents general students from becoming totally fluent. Many of the students still stick to the fundamentals of Japanese culture. As such, students don't have a clear linguistic foundation to truly answer whether Linguistic Relativity or Linguistic Determinism is more correct because they've never been able to immerse themselves in a different language or culture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, school is an overwhelming part of their lives, especially at my school. Students who take my writing course have classes for 12 hours each weekday, and another 6 or 8 hours on Saturdays. All of their time is spent studying and doing work for school. So, instead of language, what about different school subjects? Students who are often good at math are often not good at humanities, such as English or Japanese. The reverse is true, too. So, students answer the following question for the current essay:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which is more correct: the idea of Cognitive Relativity or Cognitive Determinism?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, the Hypothesis states that different school subjects have different ways of thinking. For example, in math class, questions only have one answer and have a logically way of finding that answer. A student learns about formulas and methods of deriving that answer. For language class, the method of thinking is totally different. Language requires thinking that is far more fluid. There isn't a single way of answering a question, and answers can sometimes be long or short depending on the person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So for &lt;b&gt;Cognitive Relativity&lt;/b&gt;, when students focus and immerse themselves in various subjects, they are able to change their thinking to match the thought process of subject. And for &lt;b&gt;Cognitive Determinism&lt;/b&gt;, students have a best subject or a favorite subject, and because they feel most confident in that subject, it ultimately determines how they think. When studying their weak subjects, they want to use the thought process of their strong subjects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, is it possibly for people to "switch their brains" when studying?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h11m52s231.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h11m52s231.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h11m52s231_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h11m52s231_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h11m52s231_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Essay Writing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The essay follows the 4-paragraph structure of having an Introduction, Body, and Conclusion. The &lt;b&gt;Introduction&lt;/b&gt; introduces the film, its story, and the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis. It finishes by posing the above question &lt;u&gt;only&lt;/u&gt;. The question is not answered first; it's answered last, in the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two paragraphs in the &lt;b&gt;Body&lt;/b&gt;, which typically provide reasons for the answer, look at both sides of the argument. One paragraph focuses on &lt;b&gt;Cognitive Relatively&lt;/b&gt; and how the student can change their thinking when focusing on different subjects. The other paragraph focuses on &lt;b&gt;Cognitive Determinism&lt;/b&gt; and how it's difficult for students to focus on or understand subjects they aren't good at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;b&gt;Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;, having looked at both sides of the question, students make a decision on which is more correct. They show why their opinion is true and why the opposite is false. The essay is concluded with a positive statement about the future. What good things will happen in the future if people understood your idea?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the overall essay structure: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1f__nTSmGOkpSRFfPuwdenluPgW5GQXMR/view" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1f__nTSmGOkpSRFfPuwdenluPgW5GQXMR/view"&gt;gdrive/Arrival - Essay Structure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the class is taught once a week, the movie and explanation could take a month. Each paragraph also takes a month. There's also summer vacation, which is another month. Students write their paragraphs in their notebook and I check them for errors in their contents, like weak or missing explanations. Paragraphs are only finished when I've marked them with an "okay." With all paragraphs complete, students will type their paragraph in a Google Document and create an APA-style report, which follows &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fe0TK5KawBZIWQMZhKq836d0NekSl5h0/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fe0TK5KawBZIWQMZhKq836d0NekSl5h0/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;this format&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, class takes about 7 or 8 months. That seems like a long time to write a 3-4 page essay, but Japanese students have never written anything like this before. Many of them will never write something like this again because they'll focus on something else in university. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of all the work they put into this essay, I print them out and put them in rail files, just like an American University. I'm proud of all the work they've done, so I want them to be proud of it, too, and have something to keep and hold from their experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/IMG_8429.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/IMG_8429.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/IMG_8429_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/IMG_8429_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/IMG_8429_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of student work, with the cover page removed: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fewLzExX3HbqIFMPrzO6WbyAuTlS5bxn/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fewLzExX3HbqIFMPrzO6WbyAuTlS5bxn/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fkj5YhLVRNNmgCWkMP0S3_bHaRbCtWHJ/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fkj5YhLVRNNmgCWkMP0S3_bHaRbCtWHJ/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fks3eYxoHfL610cXayajQMmKpZqgd5UI/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fks3eYxoHfL610cXayajQMmKpZqgd5UI/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Debate&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With enough time remaining before finals, students can use their essays in a Japanese English debate style format. The class is divided into two teams based on how they're answered the question in their essay. Relativity v. Determinism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In teams, they discuss their essays and come up with the 3 best reasons for why their opinion is correct. These 3 reasons are spoken by group members as their &lt;b&gt;Opening Statement&lt;/b&gt;. Each team gives their opening statement, and the other team takes notes of the opening statement for the next part. (I also write them on the board and online for students to review.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the &lt;b&gt;Attack&lt;/b&gt;. After receiving the other team's 3 best points, teams come back together and discuss why the opposing team's reasons are not true. Each best point should have a team member attacking it. After discussion, each team will give their Attack speeches, and the other teams will take notes. (I write these down, too.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the &lt;b&gt;Defense&lt;/b&gt;, which works a lot like the Attack. After receiving the opposing team's attack, teams discuss why that attack was weak or incorrect and reinforce their best points. The Defense does not reinforce their own attacks. After discussion, once again, each team will have its members deliver the Defense speech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this debate format, there's a final speech called the &lt;b&gt;Summary Speech&lt;/b&gt;. Teams would give a speech stating their best points, why the best points of the opposing team were wrong, how the opposing team didn't correctly defend their points, and how their team correctly defending their own points. It's a bit much for students to do all of this for the first time, so I do the summary for them as a way of concluding the class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h58m07s723.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h58m07s723.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h58m07s723_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h58m07s723_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/arrival-2/vlcsnap-2023-03-24-11h58m07s723_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evaluation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, students are evaluated on their progress of writing the essay in their notebooks and meeting deadlines. The final report is harshly graded by any mistakes in print, and also being turned in on-time. By the end, everything should be perfect, so any mistakes are made through carelessness of typing of putting together their report. My class's overall grade this year was 95%, so it all worked out. Only one student got a B, which brought down the average.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I've had this film on my mind for 8 years since its release, but I think I can finally put it down after this last year of explaining it, reading about it, and writing about it again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/arrival-and-language</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/arrival-and-language</link><category>Teaching</category><category>Media</category><category>Film &amp; TV</category></item><item><title>Nintendo Controller Button Set</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive at Nintendo Stores in Japan are oversized Gatcha machines with a set of toys called the Controller Button Collection &lt;span class='ja'&gt;コントローラーボタンコレクション&lt;/span&gt;. Set 1 was released last year and focused on the original Famicom and NES. Over the summer, Nintendo released Set 2, which included Super Nintendo, Nintendo 64, and Gamecube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8397.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8397.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8397_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8397_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8397_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each pull costs 600&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. Because of the demand in summer, you would buy 1 or 2 tickets at a time, each for a pull. In July, I met some friends in Tokyo, and we went back and forth between buying tickets and hitting the button on the machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My main goal was getting both Super Nintendo and Super Famicom controllers. I did a total of 6 pulls, and got some duplicates. My friends were more fortunate with their duplicates, so after some trading, I was able to get most of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8414.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8414.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8414_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8414_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8414_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm only missing the c-stick from the Gamecube controller. (But, I ordered one from Yahoo Auctions to complete the set)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These things are pretty amazing. They are near-perfect replicas of classic Nintendo controllers, which seem to use the same molds as the originals? Actually, Nintendo is probably using the same molds and plastics for their recent releases of the classic controllers on the Switch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside are the same membranes used for the controllers too. There's a big plastic slab instead of a pcb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8427.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8427.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8427_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8427_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8427_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I posted this now because I was in Kanazawa over the weekend with a student, and we stumbled upon a pop-up Nintendo Store. Out front, they had 3 gatcha machines: Button Set 1, Button Set 2, and the Zonai Gear Magnet set, which was apparently an exclusive pre-release. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Zonai Gear are from Zelda Tears of the Kingdom, but they looked pretty crappy and low quality compared to the controllers. Typical gatcha garbage. Skip. I did one pull of the Button Set 2 for another chance at the one I was missing, or another Super Nintendo one. I pulled the Nintendo 64 buttons. Another whammy. They kids after me also pulled the same buttons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8387.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8387.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8387_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8387_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241201_nintendo/IMG_8387_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, these toys are really neat as a novelty. You could hang them from your bag, or maybe put them in your car. They aren't really useful otherwise, and don't necessarily display all that well either. But, it's fun to feel the buttons and control stick of the original controllers without having an original controller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitely worth a pull or two if you're able.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/nintendo-controller-button-set</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/nintendo-controller-button-set</link><category>Toys</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Takayama Photo Rogaining</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A month ago, a friend sent me a message about a Photo Rogaining &lt;span class='ja'&gt;フォトロゲイニング&lt;/span&gt; event in my town. Photo Rogaining is a somewhat new sport that combines photography and running. It's like a photo scavenger hunt, except you are giving specific locations where to take the photos. The challenge is, by having no prior knowledge of the locations, you must quickly determine a route to reach as many checkpoints as possible, each checkpoint having different point values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to his message, I had no idea what this was. &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ロゲイニング&lt;/span&gt;? I could not figure out the English word this was trying to be. Logging? Photo Logging? But, Photo Rogaining is the correct English. Rogaining as a sport began in Australia. Its first event was in the 70s. The name Rogaining comes from the 3 folks who invented it: Rod, Gail, and Neil. They just combined their names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8265.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8265.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8265_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8265_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8265_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The full title of the event was &lt;b&gt;Hida Takayama Photo Rogaining - Celebrating the 500th Birthday of Nagachika Kanamori&lt;/b&gt; -&lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森長近生誕&lt;/span&gt;500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年記念&lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span class='ja'&gt;飛騨高山フォトロゲイニング&lt;/span&gt;. Kanamori is a very special historical figure for the town. We have a statue of him in the Castle Park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Head of the Kanamori Clan, Nagachika led his troops as an arm of the Tokugawa Clan and conquered northern Gifu and eventually Toyama, Ishikawa, and Fukui. Becoming the daimyo of the area, Kanamori transformed Takayama into a small-sized castle town to encourage tourism of other rich lords. He established what would become modern day Takayama. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the event commemorates the 500th anniversary of his birth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8242.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8242.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8242_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8242_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8242_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Takayama event was advertised around town a little bit. The starting point as well as the main venue was the Takayama City Historical Museum downtown. The poster had a link to the website for more information: &lt;a href="https://photorogaining.com/event/3862/" title="https://photorogaining.com/event/3862/"&gt;https://photorogaining.com/event/3862/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were 6 different categories of participants: Family Team, Men's Team, Women's Team, Mixed Team, Men's Solo, and Women's Solo. The event had a limit of 100 entrees, but we only had around 40 people total? A few didn't show up, but overall I don't think the event was advertised all that well. I'm really glad my friend sent me the info.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friend joined a team with his daughter. There were 3 or 4 family teams. The biggest category was the Mixed Teams with 9 separate teams competing. The second biggest category was my category, Men's Solo. We had 6 individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The schedule was as follows:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;11:00&lt;/b&gt; - Reception&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;12:00&lt;/b&gt; - Start&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;15:00&lt;/b&gt; - Finish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;15:30&lt;/b&gt; - Awards Ceremony&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rules&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Japanese Photo Rogaining site, they listed some general rules. It was not exhaustive, so I didn't completely understand everything. Through the course of the event, I was able to understand the rules better, and now I have a much better grasp of what I could've done to place higher than I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reception for the event was 11am at the museum. At check-in, we got our bib, number, and a packet with our map, which we were not allowed to open yet. Around 11:30am, they began explaining all the rules for the event. Again, I would've preferred they had all the rules clearly listed, so I could've double checked everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 11:50am, 10 minutes prior to the start, we could open our maps and look at all of the objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1a6J5tz_b2LS9NelvnLodU58ywUpHdEAh/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1a6J5tz_b2LS9NelvnLodU58ywUpHdEAh/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-map.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-map.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-map.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1a1uPrhtQYvtJ0ZmL-YQqlo0IxkV5rkM9/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1a1uPrhtQYvtJ0ZmL-YQqlo0IxkV5rkM9/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-checkpoints.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-checkpoints.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/takayama-rogaining-checkpoints.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several points on the map were ones I had guessed earlier, but I had no idea it would push out as far as &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/matsukura-and-emaichi" title="https://theschlock.com/matsukura-and-emaichi"&gt;Matsukura Kanon and Matsukura Castle ruins&lt;/a&gt;. In reality, it's only 5 or 6km away. Normally isn't that far, but both of these are on the top of a mountain. Steep vertical ascents in a marathon are rough. On the other hand...  63 and 65 points are really high values, along with 43 and 47 on the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't have a lot of time to think or compare this to the other points. I know that I wanted to climb up Shiroyama (castle park) for those points. So, my plan was to get some nearby points, go up Shiroyama for those points, and then push off west for Hida no Sato at least. On my return, I would keep north to grab all of those points before the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the event began, one of the Solo guys immediately bolted to the stoplight and then west. I kept up with him to the stoplight, but I was going east. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I grabbed a photo of the rock wall leading up the hill, &lt;b&gt;Point 1&lt;/b&gt;, labeled as &lt;span class='ja'&gt;えび坂のお多福&lt;/span&gt;. Further east, I snapped a photo of this small park, &lt;b&gt;Point 14&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;川上別邸史跡公園&lt;/span&gt;, Kawakami's Historical Second Home park?, on the way to the Bell Tower at Soyu-ji Temple, &lt;b&gt;Point 31&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宗猷寺鐘堂&lt;/span&gt;. I snapped all of these in the first 7 minutes of the race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8250.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8250.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8250_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8250_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8250_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8253.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8253.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8253_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8253_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8253_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8255.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8255.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8255_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8255_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8255_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 → 14 → 31 // (46 points)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I wanted to climb Shiroyama &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城山&lt;/span&gt; and get those points. Looking back now, I really should've kept going west to grab Point 46, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;道分灯篭&lt;/span&gt;. It really wasn't that far away, and those 46 points would've been crucial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting my climb of Shiroyama, I grabbed a photo of an outer gate of the Kogane Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黄金神社&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 7&lt;/b&gt;. Behind the shrine is a hiking path that goes directly up to Shiroyama Park &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城山公園&lt;/span&gt;. I'm not sure too many people knew about that. Way faster than taking the road. In the center of Shiroyama Park is the bronze statue of Kanamori, &lt;b&gt;Point 24&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;長近銅像&lt;/span&gt;. This is also where I parked my car. I dumped all my extra packet stuff in my car, and continued.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before taking the path up to the Takayama Castle Ruins, I quickly ran over to the nearby Shoren-ji Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;照蓮寺&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 18&lt;/b&gt;. The path going up the mountain is pretty steep. Stair, after stair. It's not so bad if you're hiking normally, but in a race, it's rough. I reached the Takayama Castle Ruins &lt;span class='ja'&gt;高山城跡&lt;/span&gt;, main building &lt;span class='ja'&gt;本丸跡&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 23&lt;/b&gt;, at 12:25pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="fourColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8259.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8259.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8259_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8259_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8259_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8264.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8264.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8264_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8264_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8264_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8268.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8268.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8268_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8268_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8268_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column fourColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8272.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8272.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8272_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8272_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8272_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;7 → 24 → 18 → 23 // (+72 points / 118 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are hiking trails that spider-web themselves throughout Shiroyama. One trail leads directly down the mountain to Hie Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;日枝神社&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 32&lt;/b&gt;. It took me around 5 minutes to figure out the correct vantage point of the photo. (Later, I learned that getting an accurate photo didn't matter :/ )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Hie Shrine, I ran north along the river to grab &lt;b&gt;Point 44&lt;/b&gt; at Masugata Bridge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;枡形橋&lt;/span&gt;. Ippon-Sugi Hakusan Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;一本杉白山神社&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 29&lt;/b&gt; was a quick run away. Then, a little bit of backtracking to snap a photo of Yamaoka's statue, &lt;b&gt;Point 30&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山岡鉄舟像&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="fourColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8281.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8281.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8281_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8281_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8281_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8288.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8288.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8288_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8288_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8288_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8290.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8290.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8290_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8290_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8290_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column fourColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8295.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8295.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8295_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8295_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8295_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;32 → 44 → 29 → 30 // (+135 points / 253 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The time was almost 1pm. I grabbed quite a lot of points in a short amount of time, but now it was time to push out to the west towards Hida no Sato and Matsukura. It took about 15 minutes to run to Kinryu Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金龍神社&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;b&gt;Point 43&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the time around 1:20, I considered whether I would be able to make it to Hida no Sato and still have time to grab all the other points downtown. Eh, I pushed up the hill anyways, and reached Hida no Sato &lt;span class='ja'&gt;飛騨の里&lt;/span&gt; in about 13 minutes. &lt;b&gt;Point 47&lt;/b&gt;, easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8300.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8300.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8300_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8300_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8300_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8306.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8306.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8306_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8306_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8306_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;43 → 47 // (+90 points / 343 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being at the door step of Mt. Matsukura, I could've pushed further to reach points 63 and 65, but the climb up the mountain was a lot, and after already going up and down Shiroyama, I didn't really consider it possibly to get up there and back. Looking back now, it really didn't take much to get Hida no Sato from Kiyryu Shrine. Maybe I could've grabbed Matsukura, but there were closer points that I should've grabbed instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran down the direct road going North back to 472. I cut through some of the neighborhoods and reached the next location. Next to the Tsujigamorisan Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;辻ヶ森三神社&lt;/span&gt; are the ruins of a temple, the Kokubun Nunnery Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;国分尼寺金堂跡&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 26&lt;/b&gt;. From there, I continued straight downtown to the main Kokubun-ji Temple, &lt;b&gt;Point 13&lt;/b&gt;. Then, a little north towards Hachiman Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;櫻山八幡宮&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 28&lt;/b&gt;, but snapping a photo of the Ecchu Kaido Monument &lt;span class='ja'&gt;越中街道碑&lt;/span&gt;, on the street, &lt;b&gt;Point 35&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not on the list, but I also snapped a photo of the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8320.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8320.jpg"&gt;Pokemon Manhole Cover&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="fourColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8310.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8310.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8310_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8310_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8310_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8316.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8316.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8316_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8316_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8316_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8321.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8321.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8321_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8321_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8321_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column fourColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8326.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8326.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8326_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8326_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8326_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;26 → 13 → 35 → 28 // (+102 points / 445 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was now 2pm, only an hour left of the event. I was back near the finishing line and there were 7 locations around me. My plan was to grab those 7 locations and get back to the base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Hachiman, it was a quick run to Takayama Betsuin Shoren-ji Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;高山別院照蓮寺&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 10&lt;/b&gt;. Then a dash up the nearby hill to snap a photo of the Sakura Bell Gate for the Unryu-ji Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;雲龍寺鐘桜門&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 21&lt;/b&gt;. A rough stair climb up to Higashiyama Hakusan Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;東山白山神社&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 42&lt;/b&gt;. And then back down to the Bell Tower of Daiou-ji Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大雄寺鐘堂&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 20&lt;/b&gt;. Some time was wasted getting the photo to match correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="fourColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8330.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8330.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8330_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8330_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8330_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8333.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8333.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8333_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8333_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8333_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8337.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8337.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8337_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8337_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8337_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column fourColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8340.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8340.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8340_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8340_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8340_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10 → 21 → 42 → 20 // (+93 points / 538 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The time was 2:20pm with 2 quick close locations over the road, and then library real quick before finishing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought I had a pretty good idea where to find points 11 and 19, but as I marched up the hill, I found nothing. I ran around looking for the stone lantern in 19, and then looking for the wooden sign in 11. I probably wasted 5 minutes and some energy before finding some nearby signs and looking at where I was supposed to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Point 11&lt;/b&gt; is the grave site of Kanamori, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森家の墓跡&lt;/span&gt; and there were signs pointing to the location within the graveyard. I had finally found it. Then, taking this dirt path behind the Temple led me to the lantern I was looking for, the front of Sogen-ji Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;素玄寺本堂&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 19&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was 2:30pm, but it felt a lot later. After being tired from running around all afternoon, I felt like I was done. I hadn't planned on going anywhere else, anyway, so it was a quick stop at the library, Kanshoukan &lt;span class='ja'&gt;煥章館&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Point 5&lt;/b&gt;, and then back to the museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8344.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8344.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8344_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8344_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8344_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8347.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8347.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8347_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8347_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8347_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8351.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8351.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8351_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8351_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8351_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11 → 19 → 5 // (+35 points / 573 total)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived back to base with 17 minutes left, cold and tired. 17 minutes is a lot of time, but there wasn't anything near enough to make a 17-minute round trip. I was done. I thought I did pretty well, though. I captured a ton of checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8353.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8353.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8353.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8353.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8353.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scoring&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you returned, you are given a &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_xZehm1Ti1LwRKPeJt-5-aFzVQwINVHk/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_xZehm1Ti1LwRKPeJt-5-aFzVQwINVHk/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;Score Card&lt;/a&gt;, and you start tabulating your points. Some of the judges were watching me because I was one of the only ones back, but scoring was almost all done on an individual basis. People wrote down there own stuff, and posted their sheet on the wall without anyone double-checking anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, I noticed and began understanding a few additional rules. You could receive up 20 bonus points for each photo of the word Kanamori Nagachika &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森長近&lt;/span&gt; you took in addition to the checkpoints. Each photo would give 1 bonus point. Additionally, if you arrived late, you would be deducted 30 points every minute, up to 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I probably ran past a few places with the Kanamori Nagachika written somewhere. The statue in the park more than likely had his name written on it. The Castle Ruins and probably a few other places with a written description may have had his name, too. You may not think a few bonus points would be helpful, but it could've made a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Results&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, my total was &lt;b&gt;573 points&lt;/b&gt; from all the tabulations above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the race, this one guy bolted off west to Matsukura. I saw him later as I was coming back from Hida no Sato. He still had a ton of energy 2 hours into the event. After seeing his score card, not only did he grab both Matsukura locations, but he also ran north up the hill by the highway to grab those distant points, too. Absolutely incredible. His final score was &lt;b&gt;734 points&lt;/b&gt;. Far beyond mine. This is a pro score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other solos began posting their scores. &lt;b&gt;577 points&lt;/b&gt;. Damn! So close. Bumped down to third by only 4 points. Then, &lt;b&gt;531 points&lt;/b&gt;. Phew, not last. Then, &lt;b&gt;578 points&lt;/b&gt;. Ah dang. Now, I'm bumped out of the top 3, again by only a few points. Last, was &lt;b&gt;353 points&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8376.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8376.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8376_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8376_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8376_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8378.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8378.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8378_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8378_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241130_photo_rogaining/IMG_8378_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I missed second place by only 6 points! (Or 5 points for a tie)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those couple of bonus points really could've made a difference. Pushing out to Point 46 would've made a huge difference. Also, not trying to take the perfect picture would've made a difference, too. I spent about 5-10 minutes at some locations trying to get the best photo. That bit of extra time could've given me more confidence about running off to 46.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I could've skipped other places downtown in lieu of grabbing the really high-point locations. By hitting the far away, high-point totals first, once I returned downtown, I could've decided whether or not to sacrifice certain spots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having gone through the event, I've been thinking a lot about better strategies and how to improve my score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really want to try again. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rogaining Events&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of what made this event great was being able to compete on my home turf. I knew exactly where almost all the locations were by having native knowledge of the area. I've already been to all these places on my own by jogging, running other marathons, or playing Pokemon Go. Prior to the event, I had a good idea where a lot of these locations would be, so I had a good mental image of what I would do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the event, they gave out a &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_sYyvE3_Yx-m-Pv5A--1ou_Yqhfr-wPC/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_sYyvE3_Yx-m-Pv5A--1ou_Yqhfr-wPC/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;flyer&lt;/a&gt; with some more events. I have no idea if they'll be run the same way as this one, but I'm game to try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just need to find one that's (1) allows solo participants, (2) not too far away, and (3) not too long. Unless I start doing more training, I think 3 hours is my limit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I loved this event so much. This is my new favorite sport. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/takayama-photo-rogaining</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/takayama-photo-rogaining</link><category>Hida Takayama</category><category>Running</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Pokemon Snap</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Pokemon Snap is a game that everyone remember fondly. Originally released in 1999 for the Nintendo 64, it immediately became a fan favorite leveraging the rise of Pokemon fandom throughout the world, and having very unique gameplay that was very easy to learn and understand, and matched the franchise so well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/pokemon_snap/Screenshot_2024-11-16_12-38-22.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/pokemon_snap/Screenshot_2024-11-16_12-38-22.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/pokemon_snap/Screenshot_2024-11-16_12-38-22_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/pokemon_snap/Screenshot_2024-11-16_12-38-22_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/pokemon_snap/Screenshot_2024-11-16_12-38-22_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Pokemon Snap, you are positioned in an automated vehicle with a camera. Your goal is to take good-looking photos of all the various Pokemon in the environment. After you complete a level, you choose one photo to represent each Pokemon species you find. Photos are scored and after various goal posts, more levels and equipment are unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been a bit burnt out, so I wanted to spend some time with a game. Just like everyone else, I have fond memories of Pokemon Snap, too. As I started playing the game around 9am, I didn't think I would play through the entire game, completing the Photo-dex before Noon. Man, it is really short. Some games from 20 and 30 years ago felt so big and massive back then. Taking photos freely in an environment feels like something so expansive and never ending. Not even 3 hours is pretty crazy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the complete opposite of recent sequel, released in 2021. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/new-pokemon-snap" title="https://theschlock.com/new-pokemon-snap"&gt;New Pokemon Snap&lt;/a&gt; doesn't have a million levels, nor access to all 1000 pokemon, but the amount of replayability from altering course tracks, finding signature photo opportunities of each pokemon, and even secret Pokemon, pushes the game in the opposite direction where there is too much to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it was a fun Saturday morning game. While 3 hours is pretty short, it doesn't over stay its welcome. Below are all of my best photos from my play through. Unfortunately, the Mister N64 core doesn't allow screenshots, so these were done through OBS.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/pokemon-snap</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/pokemon-snap</link><category>Pokemon</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Ghibli Park</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly two years ago, Ghibli Park was first opened in the Aichi Commemorative Expo Park, northeast of Nagoya. Ghibli Park is an open-air museum of sorts, with replica houses, buildings, and environments from various works by Ghibli Film. In the center of it all, is the Ghibli Warehouse, which houses a museum, other exhibits, a theater, shops, and several other recreations of Ghibli works and history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four open-air areas of the Ghibli Park, each require an advanced ticket to enter. Each area is spread around the Expo Park. Here's a map:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Q-sL6TRDRArI8eX7x01ckPJoRvNpPZ-n/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Q-sL6TRDRArI8eX7x01ckPJoRvNpPZ-n/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/ghibli/oosanpo_map.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/ghibli/oosanpo_map.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/ghibli/oosanpo_map.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the &lt;span class="orange"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ghibli Warehouse &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ジブリの大倉庫&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in the middle, the &lt;span class="light_blue"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hill of Youth &lt;span class='ja'&gt;青春の丘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is near one of the main parking lots and the train station in the north. It's most likely the first area you'll come across. Near the other parking lot and to the south is &lt;span class="olive"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dondoko Forest &lt;span class='ja'&gt;どんどの森&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. These were the first areas available when Ghibli Park first opened on November 1st, 2022. Since then, in November 2023, the &lt;span class="purple"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mononoke Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;もののけの里&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in the northeast was completed. And most centralized and most recently opened in March 2024 is the &lt;span class="magenta"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Valley of Witches &lt;span class='ja'&gt;魔女の谷&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my friends visited the park a year or more ago, and said it wasn't all that special, but this is absolutely not the case. Seeing the scale of these areas in person is incredible. Climbing to the scenic lookout point, prior to the park's opening, and peering down at a life-size replica of Howl's Moving Castle brought up feelings that I didn't know I had.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5815.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5815.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5815_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5815_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5815_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DAMN. That's it. That's fricken it! The madmen did it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tickets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tickets for the Ghibli Park are all purchased in advance, online through Lawson. There are 4 different types of tickets available, with different levels of access to the park. The main tickets are purchases 2 months in advance, but there are last-minute tickets you can buy within 7 days prior to visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The standard ticket is the Grand Sanpo Pass, or Grand Walking Pass. This pass allows entrance to all four outdoor areas of Ghibli Park, and gives a specific entrance time to the Ghibli Warehouse. When you buy the ticket, the time you're choosing is when you can enter the Warehouse. You can enter any of the outside areas at anytime throughout the day. Tickets are 3500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second ticket is the Grand Sanpo Premium Pass. This also has a specific time for the Warehouse and allows entrance to all four outdoor areas. The Premium part allows entrance to specific buildings inside of the areas, including Mei &amp; Satsuki's Home, the Earth Antique Store, Okino's Residence, the Witch's Home, and Howl's Moving Castle. Without a premium pass, you cannot enter these buildings. This ticket is 7300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a third ticket which only includes access to Mononoke Village, The Valley of Witches, and all buildings in the Valley of Witches. Because these two areas are recent additions to the Ghibli Park, they created a new ticket just for people who had visited in the first year. This ticket is 3300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, and I think it will only be available temporarily for a little while longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final type of ticket is the last-minute Sanpo Pass. This ticket can only be purchased 7 days before your arrival, and it only includes the 4 outdoor areas of the park. There's no access to buildings, and no access to the Ghibli Warehouse. Also, you only have 3 hours to use your tickets to enter the areas. This ticket is only 1500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I purchased the 3500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; Grand Sanpo Pass for November 1st, the 2-year anniversary of the park's opening. The Premium Pass sold out too quickly for me to buy, but there seemed like a lot to do already. There were so many places to go and see. I wanted this trip to be more of a dry run rather than an exhaustive one. My warehouse entry time was Noon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open and Opening&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite Ghibli Park's website clearly stating that there is absolutely no parking, there was plenty of parking. I think they state this based on a technicality that Ghibli Park itself has no dedicated parking, but the Expo Park has plenty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Ghibli Park is the main draw (and often only draw) for the Expo Park, Ghibli Park still treats itself part of the area, rather than the whole thing. As such, the park is almost completely open. I arrived at around 8:30am, well before the 10am opening time. I was planning on sitting in my car, and going through photos. But, so many people were walking in after they parked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike a typical theme park or museum, there is no gate, and no perimeter closing the park off to people who didn't have tickets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5795.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5795.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5795_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5795_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5795_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bell tower elevator was completely open. Just hop in, and go down to the park area without showing a ticket or anything. I kept looking around for where I needed to scan my ticket or what I needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of the specific areas of Ghibli Park are ticketed, but the entire park itself is completely open. You don't need a ticket to walk around the park! Plus, there are a lot of things you can do and see without even having a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opening around 9am was the observation point. I walked up to the top, and it gave a full view of the Valley of Witches, the newest and largest addition to the park. Again, no ticket required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5806_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5806_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5806_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5806_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5806_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No one was yet around, but some of the buildings were being prepared for today's crowds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the observation point, I walked down through the other path which led to the Mononoke Village. I got yelled at for entering the area even though it was all open. So, I walked around the park for a while and got a good idea of the overall layout. I came back at 10am, and gained entry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="purple"&gt;Mononoke Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;もものけの里&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mononoke Village is an open area designed to look like the Emishi village at the beginning of the film. There is a path that cuts through rice fields, with the village's lookout tower, destroyed when the demon Nago attacks the village. Not far away is Nago itself covered and infested with the demon worms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5855.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5855.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5855_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5855_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5855_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5826.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5826.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5826_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5826_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5826_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5858.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5858.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5858_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5858_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5858_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearby is also Okkoto on the brink of being infested and corrupted. Children can climb through him, and slide down his back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the gift-shop, the main building in the Mononoke Village is an old-style hall with a grass roof. The roof has about 3 inches of dirt, wet to the touch, for the grass to grow from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5867.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5867.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5867_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5867_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5867_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an outer fence surrounding the perimeter of the hall. If the fence had grass covering, too, the hall would look like it blended into the scenery, completely camouflaged from anyone moving by, possibly explaining with the Emishi were so unknown and mythical in the film. Inside, you could spend 1200&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; to cook your own Goheimochi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Mononoke area was big, but there wasn't a whole lot to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gift Shops and Button Badges&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every area within Ghibli Park has its own gift shop with general and exclusive merchandise. The Mononoke Village had an Ashitaka hat, like the one in the film, some plushies, and some pins and buttons. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every area has a button badge that matches the art from the website. The buttons are only 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, so it's not too expensive to hunt down the full set by doing to each area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spoilers&lt;/i&gt;, but I was able to collect them all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6294.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6294.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6294_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6294_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6294_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collecting each of the buttons was a lot like a stamp rally. It was fun hunting them down, although the process certainly prays of my sense of consumerism. Many of the gift shops have lines, so while you wait to buy the buttons, you're also tempted to buy other stuff too. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of the exclusive merchandise, throughout all of Ghibli Park, I ended up buying things from 7 different gift shops. My main gets are pictured above: the buttons and the Ghibli Park Guide Book. I bought a bunch of other things as Christmas Presents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: Even though there are photo icons or badges of the premium areas on the website, there are no button badges for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cat Castle Playground &lt;span class='ja'&gt;猫の城遊具&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just outside of the Mononoke Village is a non-ticket area called the Cat Castle Playground. It has a separate entrance fee but it's free on weekdays. I just walked around and took some photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5891.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5891.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5891_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5891_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5891_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5923.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5923.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5923_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5923_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5923_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were small easter-eggs throughout the rooms and areas in the playground. Almost all of the references were things related to what cats would like. It was fine, but the playground was really not designed for me. Elementary school kids were the prime demographic, but I think even the older 5th and 6th graders would probably get bored pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Walking to Dondoko Forest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having only spent about 40 minutes in Mononoke Village and the Cat Castle Playground, I still had more than an hour before my Warehouse entry time. I went to the furthest area away, Dondoko Forest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5947.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5947.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5947_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5947_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5947_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a shortcut to the Forest by cutting through another forest. By walking through the gate and greeting the stone statue, you can take the steep, casual, or middle course going up the hill, and back down the other side. Alternatively, you could also take the cat bus from the station in front of Mononoke Village to the other side of the park. I didn't realize this at the time, but I'm more of a walker, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="olive"&gt;Dondoko Forest &lt;span class='ja'&gt;どんどこ森&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dondoko Forest is one of the more barebones areas in the park. Once you enter through the gate, you have the option of walking or taking the tram to the top of the hill. I walked. But, I also got a little lost in the forest. Signage is not so great. At the top, you're greeted by a Totoro statue, and the gift shop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5930.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5930.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5930_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5930_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5930_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Totoro statue acts like a shrine to commemorate your ascent of the hill. The gift shop sells netsuke, amulets, and charms similar to items you'd find at a shrine with various Ghibli characters. This is where I bought the area's button.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading down the hill are the wooden gates welcoming you to the Dondoko Forest. This leads to the exit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5940.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5940.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5940_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5940_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5940_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the foot of the hill near the exit is the oldest building of Ghibli Park. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Satsuki and Mei's Home &lt;span class='ja'&gt;サツキとメイの家&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the park's opening, the Satsuki and Mei home will built in 2005, and it's been available to visit on its own since then. I had visited the house in 2019 with my sister and niece. Now, it's part of the premium pass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5847_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5847_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5847_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5847_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_5847_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Satsuki Mei home is a replica house like the character's new country home in Totoro. There's the bath, well, attic, and atrium where their father wrote his book next to piles and piles of other books. Everything is created with specific attention to detail to recreate the scenes exactly as they appeared in the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was pretty crowded when we visited in 2019, but now, being part of the premium pass and how exclusive those tickets are, I'm sure it's much more relaxed and open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="orange"&gt;Ghibli Warehouse &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ジブリの大倉庫&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having finished the Dondoko area, I walked back to the center of the park and waited in line for the Warehouse. My entry time was Noon, and the time was 11:30am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241114_ghibli_warehouse/IMG_5952.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241114_ghibli_warehouse/IMG_5952.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241114_ghibli_warehouse/IMG_5952_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241114_ghibli_warehouse/IMG_5952_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241114_ghibli_warehouse/IMG_5952_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ghibli Warehouse is one of the key areas of the park. It's like an expanded version of the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/ghibli-museum" title="https://theschlock.com/ghibli-museum"&gt;Ghibli Museum&lt;/a&gt; near Tokyo. You get a ticket to watch an exclusive Ghibli Film. There are areas showcasing the creativity and history of Ghibli. And, much like the rest of the park, tons of areas that replicate scenes and characters from Ghibli Film's library of works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is so much here. I'm going to make a separate post about it. You can look at the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/ghibli-warehouse" title="https://theschlock.com/ghibli-warehouse"&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; now, though, if you'd like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I stayed in the warehouse for over 2 hours. 20 minutes of that was waiting in line at the gift shop. I got my button, plus other gifts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="magenta"&gt;Valley of Witches &lt;span class='ja'&gt;魔女の谷&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It began raining, but, next, it was finally time to visit the other key area of the park, the Valley of Witches. This area focuses on the works of Ghibli Film that specifically deal with magic, namely Kiki's Delivery Service, Earwig and the Witch, and Howl's Moving Castle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6191.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6191.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6191_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6191_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6191_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connected to the entrance, is The Flying Oven, a full service restaurant with many dishes and treats, like the ones you've seen in Ghibli Film. Maybe an oversight on my part, but I did not eat anything in the park, at all. I had a pizza in my car from visiting Costco the day before, so I already had more food than I needed. I'll do more of a food journey on my next trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road leading into the main area slowly reveals more and more buildings of the town. The first building is The Witch's Home, from Earwig and the Witch. This is the home where Bella Yaga and Mandarake live, and bring Earwig after they adopt her. This home is part of the premium pass, so I could not enter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road continues passed a fountain and some more buildings. There's a building with a confusing layout that is inspired by a boy who dreams of flying, like the puzzles in Laputa or Kiki. I didn't really notice any strong references. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next to this building is the valley's Clock Tower. The Clock Tower sits at the edge of ruins from a possibly city, leading to Howl's Moving Castle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6219.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6219.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6219_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6219_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6219_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6204.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6204.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6204_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6204_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6204_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6233.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6233.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6233_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6233_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6233_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howl's Moving Castle was magnificent. While it's not one of my favorites, it's still a film that I treasure and have fond memories of watching it with friends and family across different eras of my life. Seeing this one-to-one scale recreation of the mythical building was inspiring. Visiting the inside would probably bring up even more feelings. But, premium only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Howl's Moving Castle is the crown jewel of the park looking from the Outside, the Okino Residence is the other treasure, but more from the inside. Also, premium only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6238.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6238.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6238_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6238_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6238_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Okino Residence is Kiki's childhood home. This is where she lived before leaving on her journey and training to become a witch in the city of Koriko. Looking at photos online, there are beautiful rooms, like her mother's potion laboratory, the witch's shop, kitchen, and bedrooms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going back into the main town is the Guuchoki Bakery where Kiki lived with the Osono family. Connected to the bakery, is the Hatter's Hat Shop (from Howl), which sells hats and candy, the Witch's Bookshelf on the second floor, with various books about magic, and Sophie's workshop also on the second floor. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearby is a Hot Dog stand selling hot dogs with buns that look like cat's paws. They also sell beer, apparently. (Man, I need to back). On the way out of the Valley Witches is the main gift store, Thirteen Witches. This is where I bought the button.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="light_blue"&gt;Hill of Youth &lt;span class='ja'&gt;青春の丘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final area that I had yet to visit was the Hill of Youth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6253.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6253.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6253_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6253_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6253_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two buildings here. The main one is the antique shop from Whisper of the Heart. The ground floor is filled with antiques, and the second floor is filled with mechanical clocks and materials for creating violins. The inside of the building is premium only, and the gift shop is inside, too. In order to get my final button, I had to ask one of attendants and she escorted me inside to the store to quickly buy it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other building of the Hill of Youth is the Cat Office from The Cat Returns, the spin-off film to Whisper of the Heart. It's a small "cat-sized" building you can only view by peering through the windows. Inside, the Baron meets with Muta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6255.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6255.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6255_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6255_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6255_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6270.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6270.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6270_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6270_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241115_ghibli_park/IMG_6270_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without a premium pass, this area is pretty empty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ghibli Park&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, Ghibli Park is pretty incredible. With all the terrible shit in the world, it's amazing that there's a place you can visit that brings you back to those pure feelings of creativity and wonder that Ghibli Films so often inspire. I suppose this is how people felt when visiting Disney Land, 30 or 40 years ago, before it went bad. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the Premium Tickets are pretty expensive, exclusive, and also gate some of the best parts of the park, the other passes aren't all that expensive and relatively easy to buy. In fact, the outdoor-only pass at only 1500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; available 7 days before arrival is an excellent last minute purchase for your trip to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, after writing up this post and looking at the things I missed (like the food and beer), I may just buy one of those 1500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; passes and go back there over winter vacation on a day with really good weather. It's a really easy day trip for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would definitely recommend a visit, and I would also recommend this over the Ghibli Museum in Tokyo. There is way more to do in Ghibli Park and tickets are easier to get.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/ghibli-park</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/ghibli-park</link><category>Travel</category><category>Media</category><category>Anime</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Nintendo Museum</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, Nintendo announced the opening of a museum in Kyoto that showcased their rich history since their opening in the late 1800s. But, in Nintendo fashion, they didn't want to just make a boring museum. The museum has three main areas: a showcase of Nintendo history, an interactive play area with unique games, and a cafe and workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5729.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5729.jpg" &gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5729_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5729_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5729_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nintendo Museum has been open for a month now. Tickets are given by lottery, so you sign up for 3 available times and if you're selected, you can buy tickets. One of my choices was for Halloween, and I was selected. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since before its opening on October 1st, they had a press day and allowed several content creators to run amok in the place. The entire museum has been cataloged with tons of photos and videos online. Watching all that stuff can prepare you for the museum. But, in my case, it put my expectations too high on what I wanted.  Overall, &lt;b&gt;the museum was just okay.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is some advice for the museum, if you plan on visiting. Note: The museum hours are 10am to 5pm, and my entry time was 1pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pointers for the Store&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the store immediately when you arrive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those controller cushions only have a limited amount available each day. I saw people walking around having bought some, but I don't know if they had been there all day and got them at 11am or Noon or something. I don't know if you have to say some password to someone to get one. I entered the store around 2pm maybe, and I circled around quite a bit and saw nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controller cushions aren't as big as they look. The Wii one is the longest at maybe 3 feet. I was interested in the Super Famicom controller, but it was probably 2 feet wide. Pretty small.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controller cushions are also limited to one per person among all four types. Additionally, the tiny plastic controller replicas are also limited one per person. They had some of those left when I arrived, so I decided to get one and roll the dice. (I got a VB controller lol)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of other stuff was sold out in the store. Apparently, all those tiny controller keychains sold out around 3pm. They also didn't have any of the high end Hanafuda cards. They were missing some other stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stuff is expensive, too. Shirts are 5500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. They did have some Ultra Hands, but there were 7500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. Very few single items were under 2000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. Also, unlike the Nintendo Store, you couldn't get points with your Nintendo Account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I bought a lanyard for my Nintendo card, the cheap hanafuda set, and one controller keychain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5785.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5785.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5785_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5785_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5785_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5789.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5789.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5789_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5789_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5789_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pointers for Hanafuda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sign up for Hanafuda immediately when you arrive. Sign-ups are right next to the store by the entrance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can only sign up for the workshop and hanafuda sessions within 2-3 hours of your entry time. So, if you decide later that you might want to do it, all the times available to you will be sold out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was still able to do the Hanafuda painting session, but I couldn't do the learning/play session. It's fine, though. Like many of the amusement games, it looked like it was best played with 2 people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The painting and making hanafuda cards was pretty fun. I have some pointers on how I could probably make mine look better for next time, but I will refrain from mentioning them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Pointers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would say those are the two biggest things to pay attention to. The museum and amusement areas won't take you too long to go through, and they'll always be available for you. If you buy stuff first, it's not too difficult to lug around bags of stuff either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a smaller point: outside of the museum, there is nothing else around at all. This land must've been super cheap or the only thing available in the area because it's next to a Mazda dealership, a supermarket, and a bookstore. There's also a bicycle shop, and a couple other empty plots of land.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, if you're driving, there is scattered parking around the area. But driving in Kyoto is fucking terrible. Roads are narrower than most cities and there are too many cars. You could probably park at the Tsutaya? I think that's all paid parking, so why not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Museum&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the museum 2 hours early. Went to a Book Off down the road. Then walked around for a while. I eventually just sat in front of the museum with an hour left to kill. They let me in 15 minutes early. After going through the entrance, security screens, and baggage check, I was in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5726_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5726_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5726_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5726_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5726_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not really knowing what to do first, I followed the signs and went to the 2nd floor museum. No photos allowed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2nd floor showcased Nintendo prominent 40-year video game history with huge displays of each console generation and boxes from each of the 3 major regions of release: Japan, America, and Europe. They also had a sales ratio breakdown of each region, too. Nintendo 64 and Gamecube were huge in America making over half the overall total sales. The Nintendo DS had Japan take over half the total sales, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was neat, but...  It didn't really impress me or move me. So many people around me were going, "Oh wow, do you remember this?" "Oh man, this is so cool." But me... I guess I already had these waves of Nintendo nostalgia wash over me thanks to the Analogue Pocket and Mister FPGA consoles, and the Super Nintendo Mini. Also, I already saw a bunch of these games at Book Off a few hours ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not really nostalgia when this stuff is so ever present in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prototypes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This most interesting thing in the museum was off in the far corner. Behind a glass walled room were some haphazard displays of console prototypes. They had the original prototypes of Wii-motes, the gamecube, gameboy, Nintendo DS, Wii balance board, the Switch. This was actual lesser know or seen history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Behind them was a Donkey Kong arcade game, a few other arcade games, and shelves and shelves of other hardware or sales merchandise sitting in boxes. This led into an area that was roped off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once they go through this initial batch of ticket holders, maybe they'll collect all this stuff into an actual exhibition room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interactive Arcade&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All areas of the Nintendo Museum were open, so you can go downstairs whenever you wanted, play some games, and then return upstairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your Nintendo Museum ticket doubles as a play pass for all the games on the 1st floor. To play a game, you tap your pass and register to play the game. You have 10 coins total (cannot be refilled). Each game took certain amounts of coins. It is not possible to play everything, but you can still play a lot. The games go by pretty quickly, and Several games require two players.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Giant Controllers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5739.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5739.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5739_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5739_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5739_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I immediately noticed that Dr Mario was available on the giant Famicom controller, so that's where my first coins went. &lt;b&gt;Pointers?&lt;/b&gt; These controllers are actually giant. I have a pretty big arm span, but it was not possible to play with just one person. Also, it required two accounts to register, so you couldn't sign up yourself. I had one of the staff members help me out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They only give you 5 minutes, and they start you at level 1. Me and the dude made it to level 2, but it went by so fast. Oh well, it was fun. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It used 2 coins&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;ul class="museum-list"&gt;&lt;li class="museum-header"&gt;Use Date : 2024-October-31 (Thu)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_08.svg" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_08.svg" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_08.svg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13:12 (Asia/Tokyo)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big Controller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Controller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="title"&gt;Family Computer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Game&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="title"&gt;Dr. Mario&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level Reached&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;1,000 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item photos"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download1.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download1.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download1.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download1.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download2.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download2.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download2.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download2.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download2.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download3.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download3.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download3.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download3.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download3.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zapper &amp; Super Scoper SP&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I walked around and looked at other games. Nothing was super amazing. The Zapper game was the biggest and high production valued game there. It took 4 coins, the most of any game available. Expensive... but shit, was I really not going to play it? I'm not going to save these coins for anything else. I got in line and it didn't take too long for my turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5761_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5761_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5761_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5761_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5761_stitch_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Zapper game is a 12-player shooting gallery game where everyone chooses to use either a Zapper or a Super Scope. There are 3 rounds with various Mario enemy characters appearing, and you shoot down as many as you can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pointers?&lt;/b&gt; One key thing about learning how to play this is being able to watch the groups in front of you play their games. Everyone's score is tallied and there's an overall Gold, Silver, and Bronze winner of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it was my group's turn, I immediately noticed that you could shoot anywhere on the screen. You are not limited to the area in front of you. You could shoot way down to the other side of the screen if you wanted. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, as the enemies appeared, I shoot down everything that appeared in front of the people beside me first before turning my attention to stuff in front of me. I was in booth #5, so I could clear out lots of enemies from booths #1-#4 and still have stuff left going from #5 and up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, Blue turtles give you +3 points each.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I got first place with 215 points. :) I did not see what the second place score was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;ul class="museum-list"&gt;&lt;li class="museum-header"&gt;Use Date : 2024-October-31 (Thu)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_06.svg" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_06.svg" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_06.svg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13:32 (Asia/Tokyo)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zapper &amp; Score SP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Controller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;Zapper&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stage 1 Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;106 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stage 2 Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;59 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stage 3 Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;50 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;215 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trophies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/0_1.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/0_1.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/0_1.webp"/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ultra Hand&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I did the Ultra Hand game. It was only 1 coin. You use an Ultra Hand to grab poke balls moving along a suspended conveyer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5774.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5774.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5774_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5774_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5774_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pointers?&lt;/b&gt; The Ultra Hand feels kinda flimsy, but you need to strong-arm it a bit to get it working right. You close the arms together, like gardening sheers, to close the gripping hands on the end. Then you open the hand to bring it back. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hands will close and always stay closed. You need to clamp down hard (very hard) on the string so it doesn't move, which will pull open the hands on the end. You may feel like you're clamping down on the string hard enough, but it easily slips through the plastic. You need to crush down on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the staff member explained that to me completely, I was totally ready. The game was competitive in a group of 4 people. Once again, I got first in my group. Although, the lady next to me was a pretty close second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;ul class="museum-list"&gt;&lt;li class="museum-header"&gt;Use Date : 2024-October-31 (Thu)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_02.svg" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_02.svg" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_02.svg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13:44 (Asia/Tokyo)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultra Hand SP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fireworks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;8 launchs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/ultra-hand-fireworks.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/ultra-hand-fireworks.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/ultra-hand-fireworks.webp"/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item photos"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download4.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download4.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download4.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download4.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download4.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download5.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download5.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download5.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download5.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download5.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download6.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download6.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download6.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download6.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download6.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ultra Machine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next I played the Ultra Machine. It's an indoor batting game. It fires ping pong balls, and you swat them with a whiffle bat. You can hit various things in the makeshift room, and it'll make breaking sounds or do something, like fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was terrible at this. Maybe I should've played on my knees. I missed nearly every ball, and the ones I hit went straight up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was 2 coins. I should've played the Giant Nintendo 64.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;ul class="museum-list"&gt;&lt;li class="museum-header"&gt;Use Date : 2024-October-31 (Thu)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_03.svg" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_03.svg" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_03.svg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13:49 (Asia/Tokyo)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultra Machine SP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of Swings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bonus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item photos"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download7.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download7.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download7.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download7.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download7.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download8.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download8.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download8.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download8.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download8.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download9.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/download9.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download9.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download9.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/download9.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Classic Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For 1 coin, you could play a classic game for 5 minutes. They had emulated games for Nintendo, Super Nintendo, and Nintendo 64 available. Why would I spend my precious single remaining coin on something I'll just play at home later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5775.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5775.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5775_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5775_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_5775_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh wait, what's this? In the back, and completely open were stations with an NES challenge. Play NES versions of Donkey Kong, Pinball, Mario Bros, Balloon Fight, and Super Mario Bros, each for 1 minute and rack up as many points as possible. I used my remaining coin on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I completely biffed on Donkey Kong, but my scores were pretty good on the other games. After each game, they give you a 5-star ranking. I ended with a 4-star total ranking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;ul class="museum-list"&gt;&lt;li class="museum-header"&gt;Use Date : 2024-October-31 (Thu)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_01.svg" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_01.svg" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/icon_museum_01.svg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13:59 (Asia/Tokyo)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nintendo Classic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item column"&gt;&lt;p class="title"&gt;NES Challenge 5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item data"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Total&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="content"&gt;★★★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item game"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAEE.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAEE.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAEE.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;1,400 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item game"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAHJE.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAHJE.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAHJE.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;8,160 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;★★★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item game"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAWE.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAWE.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAWE.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;6,470 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item game"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAARE.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAARE.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAARE.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;14,750 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="item game"&gt;&lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAAE.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAAE.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/CLV-P-NAAAE.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;26,150 pts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hatena Burger and Hanafuda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After using all my coins, I went to the store and then reserved a time for hanafuda. With 40 minutes before hanafuda, I bought a burger at the cafe. All ordering is done on the phone. Scan the QR code, complete your order online, pay at the counter, and wait for the food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the menu:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bp5MSMud9DbecM46m-iZUHi74fS9qtrF/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bp5MSMud9DbecM46m-iZUHi74fS9qtrF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/hatena-burger-menu.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/hatena-burger-menu.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/nintendo-museum/hatena-burger-menu.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ordered a Wasabi burger, without any customization. The burger was small, but it was really good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After, I went upstairs to make some hanafuda cards. I think my overall crafting skills failed me. The light colors were too light, so I used more paint and it went everywhere. The dark colors were too dark, so those parts are completely blacked out. Glueing the paper on the back was pretty messy, and took quite a while. I was getting close to the one hour limit of the craft room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_1715.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_1715.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_1715_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_1715_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241101_nintendo/IMG_1715_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do I really care if they look professional though? Nah... Although, maybe I should've just torpedoed my project at the first sign of trouble to make something more unique. Eh, it's fine. I learned how traditional hanafuda cards were made, and learned a little bit more about what hanafuda is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expectations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I spent about 3 1/2 hours at the Nintendo Museum, which felt like stretching the most out of my time there. I left there somewhat disappointed in the experience. That's it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, writing about it is a bit cathartic. I actually did kinda do a lot there after all. How long do you usually stay at museums? 3 1/2 hours is pretty decent after all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, I think they'll add more to the museum. More games downstairs perhaps? A new exhibit upstairs to fill that empty back space?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More businesses might move to the area too, filling up those vacant nearby lots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd like to go back in a year or two with some friends. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/nintendo-museum</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/nintendo-museum</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Digital Retro Game Library</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My retro gaming hardware collection has grown recently. The Analogue Pocket introduced me into a gaming platform possible of playing decades of games across dozens of consoles, handhelds, and arcade boards. Recently, I got a Mister which expanded this reach even further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, I made a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games" title="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; that catalogued all of the notable games I had on my Analogue Pocket. And now I've revamped that curated list into an overall Digital Retro Game Library. This lists all the notable games I have available on both the Pocket and the Mister. More platforms may be added in the future, like PS2 and Gamecube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/pocket" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/pocket"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Digital Retro Game Library&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/pocket" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/pocket"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playlists&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally, these games were being collected to build Genre lists of games using the now-canceled Playlist feature for the Analogue Pocket. The idea was that I could scroll through a Genre of games and choose one to play without having to pay attention to the hardware platform it was designed for. I was collecting all this information using &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils" title="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils"&gt;Pocket Utils&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of Java programs that I wrote to manage games and stuff on my Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, after the Playlist feature was buried and gone, I decided to put all of this information into a webpage so I could at least see everything visually. This was the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games" title="https://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games"&gt;Pocket Curated Games&lt;/a&gt; page, the first iteration of this project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later again and recently, I got a Mister. The Mister is the premiere FPGA gaming platform, and the Analogue Pocket is a handheld FPGA device. FPGA cores are written for specific hardware, so there are advantages to both platforms, although the Mister can generally handle more complicated systems and it's open source. Because of this, people have built several features and accessories on top of the platform. One thing implemented a couple years ago was Shortcuts. Rather than turning on a core and choosing a game, you could choose a game directly from the main menu. This is exactly like how I wanted Playlists to work on the Analogue Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by updating the programs in Pocket Utils to look for Mister games, I could add all that information in the database. And writing a new program, I could automatically make shortcuts to all the games I have managed in my database, essentially creating all the Playlists I wanted from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket Curated Page being revamped into the Digital Retro Game Library now shows all those games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Launching Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's another really nice feature available on the Mister called TapTo. TapTo is a service that runs in the background on Mister and accepts game executing commands. The main idea for this feature was to bring back physicality to the Mister, which is a sole digital platform. Using a physical NFC reader you can "tap" a physical NFC card (or anything with an NFC signal) and it will automatically launch the game associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not interested in having a huge collection of cards for individual games. But, I was very interested in TapTo's feature of launching RANDOM games. By sorting all of my shortcuts to games in Genre folders, I could launch a random Shooter or random Fighter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the TapTo service was upgraded to accept network requests. Any device connected to the same Wifi network could send a command to TapTo and it'll execute it. They launched a phone app that took advantage of this, but the request service is wide open. Anything can send commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, combining yet another project with this, I added functionality in my chat bot, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/schlock-bot" title="https://theschlock.com/schlock-bot"&gt;Schlock Bot&lt;/a&gt;, to accept requests to launch random games from my Genres. With Pocket Utils updated to manage my Mister games, Schlock Bot can read this information too, and launch individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;!game Shooter&lt;br/&gt;!game Panzer Dragoon (Saturn)&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These commands can be typed in my Discord and read by Schlock Bot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Going Further&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One annoying thing about typing in games to launch in Discord is that you have to type them correctly. Dr. Mario has a period in it, so if you type Dr Mario, it won't find the game. Also, I have a Gameboy Color version of Dr. Mario, too, so which one do you want? You need to be annoyingly specific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, using the Digital Game Library, you can click on a game, it'll write that execution command in Discord, Schlock Bot will read the command (if it's running), and then launch the game on Mister (if that's running too).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As such, the Digital Retro Game Library not only shows all my available games, but it's also a method of selecting games to play on the Mister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of moving parts in between clicking a game and it launching on the Mister. It would be a lot better if the webpage sent the request to Schlock Bot directly. But, this janky thing works for the time being. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Future Additions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the Library, prior to getting a Mister, I set up a Playstation 2 with a game server to play all of those classic games. I made an &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory"&gt;inventory&lt;/a&gt; page that shows all of those games, but I'm thinking about adding them in this library, too. Also, I may mod a gamecube in the future to play a library of those games. I will want to have a library of those games listed somewhere, so adding them here or on the PS2 inventory page makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to more games, I was thinking of putting download links to my save files for each game, too. I'm already doing this on the PS2 Game Inventory page with memory cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll see. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library</link><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Projects</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>The Callisto Protocol</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You are a space trucker on your last mission before retirement. You're carrying some medical supplies from the prison on Callisto to Europa, both moons of Jupiter. But, shit goes wrong when terrorists responsible for a biological attack on Europa board your ship, attack you, and ultimately send your vessel back into Callisto's atmosphere, and crash on the surface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You survive the crash, but your copilot is dead. All members of the terror group are dead, except one. As the moon's guards discover the crash and find you, both of you are taken to the prison. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things get even worse when the pathogen from the biological attack spreads in the prison mutating many of the inmates into deranged violent abominations. The prison begins the fall apart allowing you to mount an escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how the story of Callisto Protocol begins. You are Jacob Lee, who's just a normal dude put into extreme circumstances. On the surface, it seems like a pretty standard action adventure game with an involved story and twists here and there. But, this game ends up living in the shadow of another, which dominates the conversation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Derivative&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as Callisto Protocol may want to stand on its own, it's hard to talk about it without talking about &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/dead-space" title="https://theschlock.com/dead-space"&gt;Dead Space&lt;/a&gt;. Callisto Protocol comes from one of the original creators of Dead Space, and has some members of the old team, too. Callisto tries its best to emulate what made Dead Space so great, but fails on almost every front. It takes some cues from &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/the-last-of-us-part-2" title="https://theschlock.com/the-last-of-us-part-2"&gt;Last of Us&lt;/a&gt; as well, but it feels like a rip-off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enemies and Combat&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, we be fighting zombies again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Dead Space and Last of Us have zombies and while the high points of both those games go far behind their enemy designs, the enemies are still interesting. The necromorphs in Dead Space had a very dynamic design that supported the combat. The infected in Last of Us were detailed enough that you could see how the fungal infection grew and mutated their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yep, that's a zombie. In Callisto, the biophages just look like dudes with skin problems. Later, you fight some others that look like Clickers from Last of Us. And then you fight deaf zombies EXACTLY like Clickers from Last of Us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One departure from Dead Space is that Callisto isn't a shooter first, but a brawler. You bob and weave incoming attacks and counter with a melee weapon, so it makes sense the zombies are more like crazed humans. But now we're doing Arkham Batman combat, and Arkham Batman combat was not this stiff. Batman combat was designed around fighting multiple enemies at once, and you could react to them working together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Callisto often struggles with this. Every attack has weight to it, but that weight often pushes you into a position you don't want. Other enemies then attack or you get stuck in a corner looking the wrong direction. It hard to tell where enemies are coming from if they aren't in front of you. Jacob isn't nimble enough to run around and take out enemies, so you always have to focus on them one-at-a-time, which slows down the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you're already moving pretty slow. In Dead Space, Isaac's slow movement made sense because you're moving around in a 200lbs suit meant for protection from environmental and occupational hazards. You're like a tank. In Callisto, you're only wearing a cloth prison jump suit. Jacob isn't some huge muscle dude, either. He looks like he could sprint down a hall way and slip past a group of people. Later, you get an EVA suit, but it looks flexible enough to move easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Environment and Immersion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key points of Dead Space was its immersive environment supported by the heavy futuristic machinery, dynamic lighting and color, and a sharp distinct and unique set of sounds that overwhelmed you. Incorporating all of the HUD and UI elements into the character and environment made you feel immersed in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last of Us had a similar approach. There were still some UI elements that assisted the player through exploration and combat, but the lack of music and use of silence matched with the vibrant lush overgrown environments which immersed me in the exploration of Seattle and listening for the subtle movements of enemies around blind corners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both games felt designed around the opportunity to give creative people a chance to make the most of their opportunities, and create dynamic and memorable experiences. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Callisto has some unique areas, but the first half of the game is moving through drab metal hallways and then the prison's sewer system. Lots of pipes and moving through vents. The arboretum is a nice area, but it's dark and muddy. Later, you visit an old mining area. The density of buildings and their layout is interesting, but the buildings themselves aren't very interesting. The environments are definitely detailed, but they don't really inspire creativity in me. It feels too restrictive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest flop of Callisto is its lack of dynamic sound. There's no unique sound of heavy machinery working. There's no sharp crack of gun fire or welding tools. There's no use of silence to accent the enemies movements. And overall, the music is pretty generic and used too frequently. There are no surprises or memorable experiences through sound, which dampens the overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the monotony is broken up by breaking out onto the surface of Callisto. You put on an EVA and are shot out into the environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836.webp"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow is pushed around by your foot steps and moving gates. While trying to find your way to the space depot, the blizzard often overwhelms your vision. At least now, Jacob's slow lumbering movements make sense. If Jacob could move faster or more dynamically, I would've loved to stay outside longer, but everything just seems to weigh down the experience that I want to move on to the next section as quick as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, we get another unique area, the clean living area of the administration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game could've used more unique areas like this. But, we're in a prison and we're climbing through sewers and mines. There aren't many opportunities to have fantastical elements while making the setting down-to-earth. Perhaps Callisto Protocol tries to bring too much reality to its setting. As a result, all of the edges feel sanded off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;What a Twist!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through attempting to escape, you journey into the depths of Callisto to an abandoned mining colony from 75 years ago, and discover the truth of the biophage outbreak. Can you guess?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, it turns out the government was behind the biophage attack on Europa, not the terrorists. And the terrorists were people caught up in the attack who blamed the government. The reason you were caught up in everything, too, was because the medical supplies you transported to Europa were hiding the viral agent that started the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;75 years ago, the first outbreak occurred in this mining colony as the scientists responsible for the biophage tested their progress. Once the outbreak was concealed, the prison was built on top of it to continue testing the biophage virus on inmates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was aliens all along. The miners had discovered the corpse of a massive alien and studied its secrets. The government agency funding this science believed the larvae of the alien could help human ascend to the next level of evolution allowing them to expand within the universe further. The biophage virus was the result of their research, and injecting humans was meant to make them impervious to the harsh environment of space. But, whatdya know, it just turned them into monsters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Callisto Protocol is the development of this biophage to push humanity to the next level of evolution, and its eventually release and conversion of all humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They got pretty close making an evolved human with this guy. But eventually he also turns into a mindless monster and you gotta shoot him in the face anyway. With their prime experiment defeated, the government (actually a crazed religious group) sets the prison to self-destruct. With only one escape pod available, you shove your friend into it and she escapes along with records of the event and a sample of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You are still stuck on the planet and the game ends as the monster jumps at you. No real ending, just a few words and cut to black.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continued in DLC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the $15 DLC, the story continues. You wake up with the doctor speaking to your through an earpiece. Get up! There are more secrets to be had! You travel to her lab and her hologram explains about the further experiments and atrocities. There was a competing experiment being held to push humans to the next stage of evolution. And you find out that the doctor led the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You stumble further down into her lab into far more interesting, detailed, and amazing looking areas than the main game. Areas use a lot of orange light to break away from the boring metal blue walls and floors. Bio-matter spreads and grows from the walls transforming it into an alien or infested looking environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is often difficult to tell whether something is going to come out of the wall to get you, or whether danger is just around the corner. The terrible "mood" music and jump scares are turned down and used in actual appropriate moments compared to the main game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sanity effects are now used, too, as it feels like Jacob is slowing falling apart mentally. You open up a treasure chest to receive nothing, and turn around to find the chest in front of you again, but unopened. You move down a hallway as enemies continuously attack you, not realizing the path forward is to turn around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;A New Enemy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something new appears in the depths of the labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prison bots from before have been infected and fused with bio-matter making them stronger and more aggressive than before. It's still not too difficult to dodge out of the way and slam them with your electrified police baton, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, as you enter the laboratory in the police bot factory, your baton is destroyed after beating a bot over and over again to its death. Your main weapon used throughout the entire game and a fundamental staple of how the game play works is removed from your arsenal. You can no longer easily dodge and counter enemies. The brawler has turned into a clumsy shooter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not long before you are chased into a test room with bots closing in on all of your sides when you obtain the best funnest weapon in the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hammer replaces your police baton and smashes through bots after a few hits. Zombies from before are cut through like butter. Up until this point, the whole game felt like you're fighting against the gameplay. Eventually you find a rhythm that works, but it ends up becoming a single use solution to every encounter. Now you feel incredible and powerful by slicing and smashing through everything that sucked about the game before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, the Callisto Protocol is the development of the biophage to push humanity into the next stage of evolution. Their main plan ended up turning people into zombie monsters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctor had a different idea and tried to compete with them. The doctor created these bio-bots as her solution to humanity's evolution. The bots were fused with human skin, muscles, and brain using the alien biophage material. Human consciousness was then uploaded into the bots for humanity to live on forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn't work. Just like the zombies, the bots became mindless machines of destruction and ripped apart anything that was human, relying too much on the prison's programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctor had been luring you further into the depths of the lab to reach an escape pod she had prepared for herself. As you arrive near the hatch, the doctor is grabbed by a robot. The bot infects and mutates the doctor into an abomination that you juke, jive, and smash until it's dead. With the doctor's voice still in your ear, you proceed to the escape pod.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The escape pod is your ship, though. It's your destroyed ship that crashed into Callisto in the beginning. The doctor directs you to hop on the controls and get out of there. You escape the prison, escape the moon. You continue to fly as far away as fast as you can. And space begins to light up. The light gets brighter and brighter to point where you can't see anything but white.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's done. You're done. You're dead. You've been dead this whole time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As your friend had escaped earlier with all the lab's data, you were killed as the enemies closed in. The doctor found your body, and ignited the few remaining sparks in your brain. The doctor used the implant in your head linked to your friend in order to send the remaining data she had exposing the government's horrific projects on Callisto, and her involvement in the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It felt like the DLC was going to give some full closure to the ending. And I suppose it did. Callisto Protocol no longer ends on a cliffhanger. But, it's not a happy ending and it completely closes the book on Jacob's story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Real Life Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people feel cheated by the ending, and further cheated by paying $15 to get an ending that punches them in the face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The publisher ultimately is to blame for the abrupt ending and pay-per-view ending. Krafton cut the development time towards the end of the project and forced the release date ahead of schedule. New enemy types were scrapped from the game, and the ending had to be reworked into what we got. It's pretty obvious that some of those scrapped ideas were remolded into the DLC ending.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's poetic and perhaps intentional that the final scene is of Jacob's horrific torn-apart corpse, a signal from the developer that there is no future for this game, and a metaphor of what the developers perhaps consider the result of their ideas and hard work after the publisher forced their hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It sucks even more that after the release of the DLC, the developer laid off employees as the publisher realigned the focus of the studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it's easy to say Callisto Protocol is kinda lame and not all that great, but I think the DLC shows that this game and its developer had the potential to make something better and more compelling than what we got. Not everyone gets a blank check, though. And very few publishers want to take a risk. Everything has to be a financial hit these days. There's no longer any room for mediocrity even if it has some kernels of something good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I'm glad I played it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol</link><category>Game Specific</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Dead Space</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Within the expanse of humanity's reach into space, the repair vessel, the Kellion, responds to a distress call sent by the USG Ishimura. The Ishimura is a massive mining starship in orbit above the planet Aegis VII, and the distress call was the last communication with anyone on board. Among the Kellion's sparse crew is Isaac Clarke, an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Clarke and the Kellion crew board the derelict malfunctioning ship, they are attacked by transformed mutated members of the crew, known as Necromorphs. The Kellion is destroyed, and Clarke and a few other members of the Kellion begin to explore and repair the Ishimura in order to escape and find out what happened to the crew. Isaac dons his heavy duty repair suit with iconic welding helmet, an overall staple of the Dead Space series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is a survival horror game with heavy inspirations from Resident Evil 4 and Event Horizon. Originally released in 2008, Dead Space become one of the genres best examples of survival horror done right, but eventually the series fizzled out as it became more action oriented, which was reason enough for Electronic Arts to shut down the developer's studio. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, EA Motive, the developers of this 2023 remake, insisted that this new game stick closely to its 2008 original, which I consider the best in the series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Immersion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space was unique upon release as one of its strict design ideas was using absolutely no HUD. All ammo, health, and menus are displayed within the universe of the characters, as if the character themselves are looking at and using those displays. All button prompts appear on the objects in the environment. If a menu appears, it comes from Isaac's computer Rig on his wrist, and he looks at it when you select menu items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, the true crown of Dead Space's immersion is the Audio. The Ishimura is a very dense, heavy, mining vessel. All the different areas have their thick heavy machines, and these machines are all distinct and loud. Often when you enter a new area, you become completely overwhelmed by the sounds of the machinery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite areas in the original was Engineering. As you kickstarted the engines, the overall sound was so loud you couldn't hear any enemies or footsteps or menu movements. It was a constant blast of sound until you exited the room. This area still exists in the remake, but they moved it into a corridor instead of the overall room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isaac is really just a repairman, and all of your weapons futuristic versions of welders, strippers, nail guns, and such. All of these guns have very powerful and electrical cracks and bursts that you may hear at a futuristic construction site. All these sounds feel like they split your ears as you rip apart the space zombies. With your heavy, 200lbs armored suit, you can also stomp them into the ground with a satisfying crunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything in the environment and everything you do comes with a heavy mechanical organic weight to it. It's criminal if you don't play this game with headphones turned up to 11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, one of the most impactful and immersive sequences is the first time you open a door, and all of the air and sound get blasted into space from a violent hull breach. Your suit's boots are magnetized so space walking is no problem, but the first time you get thrust into space feels like going over the top of a rollercoaster. It feels like part of your own breath was sucked into space, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Haunted House&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you continue to explore and repair the Ishimura, you move into new areas of the ship with new monsters. Often you'll reach a place of relatively quiet, only for a monster to SCREAM at you as it burst out of the ceiling or a nearby wall. This happens pretty often. As the game's sound fully immerses you in the environment, it tends to employ startling scare tactics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You get pretty powerful later on in the game, so when a standard zombie pops out of the wall, you can quick shoot it or bash it into the ground. Even when a bunch of zombies come at you at once, you can usually take them all at once with your arsenal. So, many of these sequences turn into a corner of a haunted house. Boo!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the first time you fight a Brute can make you feel powerless. A brute is a gigantic zombie about the size of a car. When it comes rushing towards me and my gunfire has absolutely no effect, my next instinct is to run! But then the heavy suit makes it feel like you're trying to run in water, and its huge stomping lumbering movements are right on your heels. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some genuine fearful movements as you try to evade death, but ultimately, you can overcome these moments by trying again after you die. Later on, you learn about the best ways of killing things by fighting the zombies over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;People generally define retro games as anything made over 10 years ago. This was an easy statement to make in the PS3/360 era of gaming, as each new console had some genuine easy-to-see graphical and design improvements over the previous generation. For example, Super Mario World and Super Mario Sunshine were 11 years apart, and the difference between those games of the same series is absolutely massive. The jump from 2D to 3D was huge, but so is the idea of having to explore the world to find levels, having a more involved story with characters having motivations, and talking with characters to find more things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The time difference between the original Dead Space and this remake is 15 years, and the overall game hasn't really changed at all. The graphics have been modernized, and load times reduced because of current generation hardware. A few quality of life features added for smoother gameplay. Isaac talks now and involves himself in the story, too. But it's still the exact same game that I remember from the Playstation 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are games from the PS3/360 era really retro if their game design still fits within the modern era of game design?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe some people consider games retro if they center on a single player experience. Most modern games today have some kind of social element, so you can share the experience with friends. Or they include some kind of open world experience, so it can feel like the game is endless and you can play for hours and hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is a pretty tight 12 hour game, and adding any of those modern engagement traps would ruin the experience. But, at the same time, once you finish the game (and finish it a second time), you're pretty much done with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Legacy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the original Dead Space, the studio became known as Visceral Games and made Dead Space 2 and Dead Space 3, as well as Dead Space Extraction (a light gun game), and some novels and comics. Dead Space 2 was another high for the series, but I think there was never enough lore and story to carry it to a full never-ending franchise. Dead Space 2 started the series into something more action-oriented to appeal to a general audience, and Dead Space 3 killed the franchise and the developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The creator of Dead Space had actually left Visceral before Dead Space 2, and recently he helmed the creation of a new game, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;Callisto Protocol&lt;/a&gt; released in 2022, which seems like an actual new Dead Space game in all but name. It's either ironic or malicious that EA came along with the Dead Space remake at the same time the original creator made a new one himself. However much of Visceral's former staff work at Motive and were key developers bringing this remake to life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dead Space remake does an absolutely excellent job of sticking to the original but adding a few new things and changing others to make it even better. This remake doesn't really feel like a cash-grab. It feels like the people working on it genuinely cared about Dead Space and wanted to bring it back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it really sucks that the remake did not meet the sales EA was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through killing space zombies and finding some survivors, Isaac uncovers the truth of what happened on the Ishimura. Members of the crew became obsessed and possessed by the religion of Unitology, which revolves around an artifact found of Aegis VII, known as The Marker. The Marker slowly morphed the colonists of Aegis VII into the Necromorphs, which attacked and infected the crew of the Ishimura.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the surface of Aegis VII is the Hive Mind, which controls all Necromorphs. In order to pacify and destroy it, Isaac brings the Marker back to the surface of Aegis VII. There are several other twists and turns along the way as Isaac is betrayed by his crew, and caught between the motives of Earth and the Church of Unitology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it turns out that his love interest that he's been chasing the whole game killed herself prior to the Kellion arriving at the Ishimura. He's essentially been chasing a ghost through manipulation of the Marker and an Ishimura survivor. With nothing left, Isaac continues to kill the Hive Mind, and escape the surface as the gravity tethers holding the Ishimura are severed, which sends the ship and its moon-sized payload into the planet, eradicating all remaining life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally Isaac gets to rest after a job well done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, except the Marker left its mark on Isaac. In the final moments of the game, the phantom of his girlfriend attacks him. Dead Space 2 picks up with Isaac awakening in an asylum above Saturn's moon of Titan, the doctors having extracted the remnants of the Marker from his brain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;New Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now there's a new, alternate ending. As Isaac runs through the Ishimura a second time, small Markers are scattered throughout the ship. Collecting all of these Markers and placing them on their alters in the Captain's quarters will unlock this ending. Now, after Isaac pacifying the Hive Mind and letting the megaton payload destroy the surface, he is no longer so solemn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a course set back to Earth, he mentions to the phantom of his girlfriend that he needs to build something first before they can return. Isaac has been fully corrupted and possessed by the Marker, it seems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Motive had plans to make a Dead Space 2, but as an alternate sequel rather than a remake of the original sequel. This sequel probably could've followed this new ending, and maybe implement some of the original ideas the creators had for Dead Space 2 back in the day, rather than some mandates EA imposed on Visceral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EA seemed keen on continuing the remake series, but plans were scrapped as sales were poor. Motive is off working on other projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is dead yet again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hope&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to check out &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;Callisto Protocol&lt;/a&gt; next and see if there's any life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/dead-space</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/dead-space</link><category>Game Specific</category><category>Games</category></item></channel></rss>