<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>One Schlock's Requiem is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher of English living in central Japan.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:47:56 +0900</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:47:56 +0900</lastBuildDate><link>https://theschlock.com/</link><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://theschlock.com/feed.xml"/><category>Japan / Games / Other Stuff</category><item><title>Assassin's Creed Shadows</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Assassin's Creed series finds its way to shove its story into fuedal Japan during Oda Nobunaga's conquest and unification. The long storied franchise which had always focused on Europe and the western expansion of the world spread itself to Japan via the attempted Catholic infiltration and invasion of the country. Like all AC games, you find yourself at a pivotal point in time, and carry out assassinations that shape the country's and world's history to create the world we live in today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20251005144213.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20251005144213.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20251005144213_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20251005144213_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20251005144213_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Act 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadows takes place around the year of 1579. Looking at real world history, the bulk of the story is set from 1581 through 1582, but also flashbacks to 1579, where those events serve at the catalyst for one of the protagonist's story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naoe is a young woman from Iga whose family and village are trained in ninjutsu. She was first tested in 1579 when Oda Nobukatsu (Nobunaga's son) launched an unsuccessful attack on their village. Clumsily, she killed her first man as the rest of the ninja repeled the attack. From that day, she continued her hard training to match the level of the others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1581 (real life), Oda Nobunaga returned to Iga with his army of over 40,000 men, and slaughtered as many ninja and families as he could find. In the chaos, Naoe's father gathers an important artifact and flees. Naoe follows, but they are both run down by a &lt;i&gt;mysterious&lt;/i&gt; group of 12 masked individuals who call themselves the Shinbakufu. They steal the artifact and brutally injure both Naoe and her father. Her father dies as she loses consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naoe wakes later in a monastery healed by a boy and an old man. After regaining her strength she vows revenge against Oda Nobunga for slaughtering her village and the Shinbakufu for killing her father.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825190741.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825190741.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825190741_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825190741_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825190741_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rewinding a little bit, we are introduced to our other protagonist first, Yasuke. Yasuke is Nobunaga's Black samurai. His main story also begins in 1579 as Jesuit Alessandro Valignano brings him to Osaka as he meets with Oda Nobunaga. Nobunaga is curious about the black man as almost no one in Japan had ever seen a black person before. They've only ever met white Catholics. Nobunaga is impressed that Yasuke understands the Japanese language, and invites (orders) him to train at his castle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Yasuka trains, he learns how a samurai should properly fight by balancing physical strength with mental strength. A duel between men is not just who is stronger, but how you can use your opponent's weaknesses against them. Through achieving this balance and showing his loyalty and honor in a fight, Nobunaga is so impressed that he "knights" him as a samurai. This is when Yasuke proclaims his name as "Yasuke."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years later in 1581, he is one of the samurai on the front lines attacking the Iga village, Naoe's village. The full game begins with you storming the village and killing ninja after ninja. You play about 15 minutes as him until the game switches to Naoe fleeing the village, and then you don't play him again until many hours later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824144138.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824144138.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824144138_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824144138_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824144138_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open World&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once Naoe leaves the temple fully healed from her attack, you have nearly free reign of the entire expansive map of pre-Edo Period Kansai. The distances are miniaturized, but the huge map goes from the Kii province in the south (modern day Wakayama) to Wakasa province in the north (modern day southern Fukui). You can travel to Omi province in the east (modern day Shiga, almost Gifu) to Harima and Tamba provinces in the west (modern day Hyogo).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can visit incredible recreations of Himeji, Osaka, and Niji castles and estates, as well as over a dozen more castles. Armored forts also dot the landscape and there are vibrant towns both large and rich, and small and poor. Outside of the villages, the forests and mountains look incredible. The overall attention to authentic details is amazing. It feels like I'm walking through the forests of Sekighara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These natural, beautiful, and authentic environments are the center piece of Assassin's Creed Shadows. If you see something interesting in a direction, just go in that direction and see what's there. Eventually you find vantage points (towers) that will reveal more points of interest and this curiosity and exploration will continue to push you to all areas of the map. Often at the top of a hill, you'll see a new castle or fort you haven't explored before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824205831.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824205831.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824205831_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824205831_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824205831_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point in gaming, the idea of "Do you see that building or mountain in the distance? You can go there." is pretty rote, but Assassin's Creed established and populaized this concept of open world exploration in its first game nearly 18 years ago. Actually, the first game is the only other AC game I've played of the whole series. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/assassins-creed-impressions" title="https://theschlock.com/assassins-creed-impressions"&gt;I wrote some impressions back then, too.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being able to go anywhere and having towers to organically push players into new areas was what made Assassin's Creed such an interesting game that it became a watershed moment, and nearly all other open world games have adopted this idea. Nintendo even took this idea with Zelda Breath of the Wild and it became one of their most highest selling and praised games of all time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824213807.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824213807.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824213807_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824213807_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824213807_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why so Special?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, why is Assassin's Creed Shadows so special? Why should you play it? There are really just 3 short reasons. It's a really good "one of those." The graphics looks incredible. And it's set in Japan. Those are really the 3 reasons why people have been so positive about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assassin's Creed has been plagued with mediocre games for years. Once they struck gold with the first games, they kept pumping them out each year. There have been 14 mainline AC games in the last 18 years. And so many of them have been boring, broken, overwhelming, and completely uninteresting according to people. But, it was able to break into the mainstream, so every release kept selling and selling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825132404.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825132404.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825132404_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825132404_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250825132404_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to play it because Ghosts of Tsushima was released a few years and seemed to do exactly what Assassin's Creed was doing. It was an open world set in feudal Japan where you run around and reach towers to unlock more points of interest on the map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/ghosts-of-tsushima-impressions" title="https://theschlock.com/ghosts-of-tsushima-impressions"&gt;I did and did not like Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;. From an exploration point of view, it was a bit derivative fully using the same formula as Assassin's Creed, but it was a good "one of those." You could climb almost everywhere and there were interesting hidden points as you explored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never wrote my full thoughts on the game, but there were three major things I ultimately really disliked about Ghosts that are (mostly) fixed in Shadows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824233554.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824233554.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824233554_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824233554_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250824233554_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest thing I hated about Ghosts was the overall tone of the story and sidequests. Everything was a fucking downer. Of course, the overall story of Ghosts was about the mongul invasion which is a serious subject, but Japanese cinema and story-telling like to add a bit of lightheartedness to their tales. Every sidequest in Ghosts ends with a family murdered, or a town murdered, or any shred of hope dashed in the end. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"My father has gone missing. Can you find him?" He's been robbed and murdered by bandits. "My wife is missing. Can you find her?" Murdered and ripped apart by bandits or monguls. "My children are missing. Can you find them?" Worked to death as slaves in a mongul camp. Why create such a beautiful lush environment only to dot it with the charred remains of villages and bodies of families and children? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, balance is important. Maybe they wanted to balance to beauty of the environment with death. But with the narrative so completely overwhelmed with negatives feelings and imagery, it dwarves the environment. You need some balance within your narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831103151.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831103151.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831103151_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831103151_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831103151_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadows has a few different side story threads that are pretty ridiculous, especially the Yokai quest line. Much of these goofy quests remind me a lot of the goofy kind of side quests you would find the Yakuza games, the premiere Japanese developed open world game series. Even though they are sometimes too goofy, they play well against the main character who tends to play the straight-man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadows never drags me down in the same way that Ghosts did. Although, eventually in the story, I think Naoe and Yasuke become a little too jokey with each other and other characters, so the tone ends up going in the wrong direction a little too far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I will say that Jin in Ghosts ends up being a much better developed character throughout the story. Naoe and Yasuke often become more of an avatar for the player, and you can often make choices that contradict the cutscenes and dont't make sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250828205305.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250828205305.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250828205305_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250828205305_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250828205305_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Repetitious Layouts&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadows hides its repitious buildings, foilage, and enemy layouts with a vast amount of variety. There really aren't all that many different models of trees in the game, but when placed in the environment along the sides of mountains and occasionally in towns, you really don't notice the repetition unless you really pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your base is a great example of this. In Shadows, you get a base and can put together the buildings, trees, and lots of other things anyway you like. I can create a pretty natural looking forest by rotating every tree I place. Combined together, you can't really tell which branches are the same on each tree. The photo below is from my base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831220644.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831220644.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831220644_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831220644_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250831220644_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some buildings in Shadows are obviously the same, but it doesn't really bother me too much. In real life, there are many houses that are the same because they all hired the same construction company. Also, many textures are reused in other castles and towns. But the layouts of all the castles and town are unique and are often historically accurately the layouts of the castles and towns they are meant to be. Towns and castles also have a lot of unique features that are not used anywhere in the game. Often, the developers tear down some walls or buildings to break up the repetition, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Ghosts, all the mongul tents and camp set ups looked identical. Again, it makes sense that they would all have the same tents, but every tent had the treasures and weapons laid out in the exact same position. Each tent also had a same flap exposed in the exact same position so you could sneak in. Tents were almost also laid out in the exact position in every camp, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadows also has various army and bandit camps with repeated layouts, but you have so many other castles, villages, estates, caves, mines, towers, and other places where you fight that there is so much variety among repeated elements. They don't hold back their layouts for story sequences only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250920153213.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250920153213.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250920153213_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250920153213_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250920153213_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Authenticity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ghosts prides itself on authenticity. Despite being an American game studio, they took multiple trips to Tsushima island to study the natural landscape, attended workshops focused on the island's culture and traditions, took tons of reference photos, and were also huge fans of classic Japanese samurai cinema, especially of Kurosawa. They used all of this knowledge to create beautiful environments that look like paintings and still images from their favorite films.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, it felt like a fairytale. Open areas of tall grass blowing like waves in the wind. Rocky mountainous hills with tall cedar trees. Vast marshlands filled with those white marshy flowers. And also snowy mountains to the north so cold that you can't survive away from a fire for a few moments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, Ghosts prisdes itself on authenticity, but are we supposed to believe this is an actual place? Tsushima is an island in the sea of Japan, which rarely gets snow. And those white marsh flowers only grow in marshes in the mountains, usually around May. Ghosts takes place in November. Also, there's a cherry blossom forest in November, what?!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They wanted to shove in too much imagery into a situation that doesn't make sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250919230937.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250919230937.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250919230937_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250919230937_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250919230937_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The environments in Shadows is much more consistent with reality. Also, seasons change over time. Every real-life hour (about) half a season in the year scrolls by. (This also allows for enemies to respawn and match your level.) Summer, Fall, Winter, Spring. Cherry blossoms only bloom in spring. In summer, all the forests are a deep green like normal. Rice fields are planted and flooded. In fall, the leaves begin to turn, but also, people are out in the fields harvesting the rice. In winter, snow becomes deep in the north, but it's pretty bare in the south near the ocean, just like real life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the seasons changing, it allows them to have all the imagery of Japan that Ghosts wanted to have in a more natural way. The attention to detail in each of the different regions depending on the season is incredible. It feels like the seasons changing in reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927230209.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927230209.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927230209_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927230209_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927230209_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shallow Story and Characters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I think Shadows excels best at exploring the environment, running through castles looting and killing, and naturally finding side story threads, it ultimately feels a bit shallow. Naoe and Yasuke are so stereotypical in their actions and dialogue. There's no weight behind anything they say or do. Everything in the story is telegraphed to the point where there are no real twists or turns. When you meet someone who seems remotely evil... Ah! I'll have to fight or kill this guy in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I've spent hours upon hours looting and killing everyone in the castles and forts that when the story says we "need to be careful" and "have a plan" to attack this specific character in a castle I've already been, it's laughable. Here's my plan: I'll just run in there and kill everyone just as I always do. And eventually that's what happens in the story. No build up needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story, dialogue, and character development of Ghosts had so much more weight behind it. Although, the story decisions in Ghosts also fell flat in the end when you just choose which ending to watch with your final action. All your actions throughout the game didn't mean anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Shadows, it was interesting to see how they weaved the overall Assassin's Creed story into Japanese history, but I could've easily just read a bullet point list on a wikipedia page and been just as satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927154422.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927154422.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927154422_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927154422_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250927154422_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;End of Act 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to the story, in Act 1, we were running around as Naoe searching for leads on Oda Nobunaga to exact our revenge. Through various story threads, we meet Akechi Mitsuhide (one of Nobunaga's trusted generals). He tells Naoe that Nobunaga is one of the Shinbakufu, and he sets us up with an opportunity to kill Nobunaga at Honnoji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The events happen in the same way they supposed did in real history in June 1582. Mitsuhide unsuspectingly lead his army into Kyoto and attacked Honnoji. You are able to use the chaos to fight your way through samurai into the temple where Oda Nobunaga stayed. The temple is set on fire, and you fight Nobunaga while the temple burns down around you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the final blow, Yasuke appears for the first time in hours to prevent your assassination. But the attack was successful either way. Nobunaga says that even if he were to flee, he reign as daimyo is over. He could never command his groups with authority again after this betrayal. He asks Yasuke to take his head as he commits seppuku due to his failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250902205314.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250902205314.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250902205314_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250902205314_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250902205314_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naoe flees the temple. Akechi revealed himself to be one of the Shinbakufu, not Nobunaga. With Nobunaga dead, unification of Japan stands still as the other generals and daimyo know fight for power. Akechi hopes to gain some power for himself, but there are so many rivals in his way. Naoe feels betrayed that she was only used as a pawn in his schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yasuke soon catches up with her. Naoe weilds a hidden spring-loaded palm knife that she had gotten from her father. She has used to assassinate all her targets so far and it's an iconic staple of all assassins through the AC franchise. Yasuke recognizes this blade. So, rather than fight Naoe out of loyalty for Nobunaga, he asks to join her. Akechi is their common enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The remaining story of Shadows happens in two acts, but the focus of each of these acts happen nearly concurrently. Act 2 story quests focus on elimating the remaining members of the Shinbakufu and eventually reaching Akechi to kill him. Act 3 quests focus on the pasts of Naoe and Yasuke. How did Naoe's father know about the league of assassins and how did they come to Japan? Also, how is Yasuke tangled up with the assassins by knowing about the hidden blade. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930213119.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930213119.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930213119_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930213119_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930213119_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Act 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After tracking down and killing all members of the Shinbakufu, you come to the final battle. Akechi is in Yamazaki castle, and you build your plans to attack with Toyotomi Hideyoshi. You meet a young Tokugawa Ieyasu (above) who takes his army away and doesn't join the battle, claiming that there will be more fighting in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's neat that you meet all three unifiers of Japan in the game. Oda Nobunaga began his campaigns to unify Japan, but was killed before he could complete it. Toyotomi is the second unifier, taking over for Oda in 1582 just after this battle where Akechi is rooted and killed. Nearly all areas of rebellion were quelled and brought under their power by 1592. Then, with Toyotomi's death in 1598, Tokugawa Ieyasu prevailed in &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/battle-of-sekigahara" title="https://theschlock.com/battle-of-sekigahara"&gt;the Battle of Sekighara&lt;/a&gt;, which allowed him to seize all power of Japan and usher in an era of peace (albeit under strict rule) for 250 years. It's funny how they protray him as a coward and schemer here as folks in Japan often have the same view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Toyotomi, Naoe and Yasuke lead the charge against Yamazaki Castle and eventually throw Akechi from the keep. Akechi flees on horseback, but Yasuke is able to keep up pace. He is eventually rundown in a small village down the river. Yasuke takes his revenge and cuts down Akechi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Real history plays out nearly the same way. Toyotomi attacks Yamazaki Castle and Akechi flees later to be killed in a village nearby by farmers wanting to collect a bounty set by Toyotomi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930215138.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930215138.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930215138_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930215138_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250930215138_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Act 3 - Assassin's Creed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overarching story of Assassin's Creed is the battle of assassins and templars throughout the course of human history. Templars are much like the illuminati who want to control the world and hold all the power to themselves, and the assassins are a brotherhood of warriors who aim to thwart their plans and keep the free will of history to the people. Throughout time, these events have always been centered in Europe, the genesis of most modern day societies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through investigating her family's past, Naoe learns that her mother met a Spanish assassin, who was an excommunicated member of the Assassin's Creed. He followed some templars to Nagasaki. Without the help of his brotherhood, he saught to recruit local people to form a Creed of his own to battle the templars. Naoe's mother was his first apprentice and they formed the Japanese brotherhood known as the Kakushiba Ikki.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As their brotherhood grew, they were able to have an audience with Emperor Go-Nara about the growing threat of templars in Japan. The emperor entrusted them with protecting the Imperial Regalia, 3 historical artifacts of extreme cultural significance (macguffins).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the Spanish assassin left Japan for some reason, and Naoe's mother continued leading the guild. The templars eventually found their guild. They attacked, killed all members of the guild (almost), and stole the regalia. In reality, Naoe's mother survived the attack and kept one of the artifacts, the jewel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Way back in the opening of the game, this is why the Shinbakufu singled out Naoe and her father. Her father carried this box. By killing Akechi, you were finally able to retrieve this box and learn of its importance. You return in back to its sacred vault underground with another one of the regalia that Hattori Hanzo was able to retrieve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907090527.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907090527.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907090527_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907090527_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907090527_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the coin is Yasuke. Yasuke came to Japan as a slave on a boat run by Duarte de Melo and Nuno Caro, both members of the Portuguese templar order. They find Yasuke (whose original name is Diogo) and his mother in their quarters trying to clean some papers that fell on the floor. In typical evil villain fashion, they bring them out on the deck to kill them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They shoot Yasuke's mother in the head and turn to him next. But, from above, an assassin appears and a fight ensues. Yasuke is kicked overboard away from danger. This is how he recognized the hidden palm blade held by Naoe. He knows that the assassins fight his enemies, so that's why he wanted to join her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yasuke tracks down Duarte and kills him. This leads him to Nuno Caro whom he also kills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their plans in Japan were to manipulate the Shinbakufu into stealing the Imperial Regalia and claim it for themselves. Their mission as templars were to bring the regalia back to their order and use it for some plot device bullshit. Ultimately, they wanted to keep the artifacts for themselves as they thought it would help them control Japan by shaping Japanese principles and beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907215726.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907215726.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907215726_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907215726_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ac_shadows/Assassins_Creed_Shadows_20250907215726_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I think the entire story of Assassin's Creed has become a complete mess, you really only get this tiny kernal of its overarching story here. Shadows feels like a small side story in the universe, even though the game is far from short. (I finished with 165 hours.) I think it's neat how they found a good point in history that made sense for their European order of assassins and templars to reach Japan. And it's neat how this idea of foreign invasion through manipulation was eventually the reason Tokugawa closed to the country to all foreigners in 1602 after he gained control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite its flat dialogue and characters, I felt like I had a better experience than I did with Ghosts. Ultimately, I think both games had different focuses and vibes, so it's perhaps not fair to compare them head-to-head. But, I think Shadows did a slightly better job achieving its goals than Ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am really excited to play the sequel to Ghosts, though: &lt;b&gt;Ghosts of Yotei&lt;/b&gt;. After watching some minutes of people playing story sequences, the dialogue and voice acting is world's beyond anything in AC Shadows. The location is up in Hokkaido now, so having mountainous terrain and snow make sense. In the differences of elevation, you can naturally have all the variations of environment. The story doesn't focus on a brutal invasion, so I think there is room for some lighthearted elements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't want to get my hopes up too high, but I think it has the opportunity to take the best things from both Ghosts of Tsuhima and Assassin's Creed Shadow to create something remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of time, I think playing through Assassin's Creed Shadows is worth it. Once you have full reign of the map, it's amazing to explore the mountains, forests, towns, and castles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sale&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games of this magnitude are so impressive that it seems almost a crime to buy it at a reduced price. I ended up getting it for $35 on ebay with a coupon. It should've included the newly released DLC, but they stiffed me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before too long, there will be a sale or some kind of bundle where it can be easily got for a cheap price. I'm sure over Thanksgiving and Christmas, you can find a deal. I plan on looking for deals on the $25 DLC at that time, too.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/assassins-creed-shadows</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/assassins-creed-shadows</link><category/><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Game Thoughts</category><category>Games</category><category/><category/></item><item><title>TapTo NFC Reader Enclosure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;After getting a Mister FPGA last year, I wanted to get ALL the accessories and try out everything the system had to offer (within reason). One of the accessories I bought into was TapTo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;TapTo (or Zaparoo)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TapTo (now renamed Zaparoo due to fear (or reality) of trademark infridgement) is a service that constantly runs in the background on Mister. With a connected NFC reader, any NFC signal it reads will automatically run instructions. The main use of this is having a physical set of cards or objects representing your favorite games. Tap the object and the game runs automatically without having to go through menus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a fun way of bringing physicality back to a digital platform, and people have let their creativity fly. There's a replica miniature C64 disk drive with an NFC reader inside, and you insert cards like floppies. Some folks have put NFC stickers on their physical game cartridges and use those to boot up games. People print their own NFC cards with various styles and images. People have also made figures with NFC buttons inside. The sky is the limit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For me, I thought this was all unnecessary. You're removing one of the advantages of having a digital platform which is reducing your amount of clutter. But, you can have TapTo (Zaparoo) do more than just execute games. You can have it execute button macros. And you can have it execute random games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was most interested in the random games. The standard randomization is to have it choose a console and execute a random games on that console. But, unlike the Analogue Pocket, you can build lists of favorites on the Mister using MGL files. So building lists of my favorite games in each genre, I can Tap a card, and have it run a random Shooter or Puzzle game or Fighting game. These are all single serving games, so it makes sense to randomly try one for 5 or 10 minutes and find a new one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, rather than use printed cards, Nintendo Amiibos use NFC, too. I could register the Pacman Amiibo to boot up a random arcade game, and use Ryu to boot up a Fighter. Dr. Mario for Puzzle games. And for Shooters? A Vic Viper would've been amazing. The closest is Star Fox, but those figures look terrible. I just went with Mega Man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;NFC Reader&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use any NFC reader with Mister, but all the official images used a particular one. It was only 764&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; on Aliexpress! So cheap! Why not buy it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1669.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1669.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1669_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1669_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1669_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so small! I was thinking that it would be the size of a trading card, but it's less than half that size. This is great because it has allowed creative folks to sneak it into their enclosures and even in their Mister cases. My Mister case is shoved into the shelf, though, so it's not practical for me to do that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a platform that could stick out of shelf for easy placement of Amiibo figures. Because the reader is like a tiny trading card, I thought I could use one of those hard plastic trading card protectors. Just screw the thing in there, and it would make for a pretty piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hard Plastic Card Protector&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon had a few different sizes of these sandwich plate style plastic card protectors available, so I bought a standard trading card size and a smaller size closer to the dimensions of the NFC reader. This one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0CQ3R5ZGX?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1" title="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0CQ3R5ZGX?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TheCase99-Chocolate-Seal-Size-R.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TheCase99-Chocolate-Seal-Size-R.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TheCase99-Chocolate-Seal-Size-R.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0CQ3R5ZGX?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1" title="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0CQ3R5ZGX?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&amp;th=1"&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;. Now, a year later, it's out of stock, but I bought it for only 660&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. Maybe that's expensive for a single card protector, but I think it's a good price for an NFC enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, with buying this protector, I wasn't really thinking about how the reader was going to slip between the two plastic plates. A card is as thin as paper. The PCB of the reader is thicker than that, plus it has a USB-C connector on it. The protector came with a thin plastic frame border for the card to hold it in place, but that would not work with the reader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1671.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1671.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1671_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1671_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1671_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the protector was a good size, but I did not think about the USB-C connector. I wanted the PCB more centered, but the USB-C plug on the cable is WAY thicker than the connector. The USB-C connector would have to be flush with the outer rim of the plastic for it to connect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The included screws weren't longer enough for added height, so I had to buy some new ones. My local hardware store was able to identify the guage of the screws at M4. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/image/tapto/IMG_2660.jpeg" title="https://theschlock.com/image/tapto/IMG_2660.jpeg"&gt;They sold these packs of screws, nuts, and washers.&lt;/a&gt; I had a few different lengths from some other projects, but I bought one of those packs with 15mm length screws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I ultimately used the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 Screws - M4 Size - 15mm Length&lt;br/&gt;4 Nuts - M4 Size&lt;br/&gt;8 Washers - M4 Size&lt;br/&gt;4 Thumb Nuts - Reusing the ones including with the protector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1676.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1676.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1676_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1676_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_1676_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a little tight, but it had to be to hold the USB-C connector in place. If it was too loose, the plates wouldn't hold it and you couldn't plug it in without pushing the PCB in further. Although, too tight and it could've cracked the plates or warped the connector. Adding the washers and screws gave it just enough height to hold it in place well enough. Although, it still slipped around and it could be pulled out easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The perfect solution would be to design a 3D printed bracket that could be flush with all edges of the plates and hold the NFC reader in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;3D Printed Bracket&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, after almost a year after putting the plates together, I finally designed a bracket. I didn't realize that my sister had a small 3D printer, so it was the perfect excuse to finally make this thing. Her model of printer was a ToyBox, a more accessible consumer level printer which allowed her kids to make little figurines and such. It also accepted custom STL files, so you could still print whatever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking online, &lt;a href="https://www.tinkercad.com/" title="https://www.tinkercad.com/"&gt;TinkerCad&lt;/a&gt; was recommended as an easy online program for creating STL files. And it was really easy to figure out how to move around the view, create objects, and also create negative objects which cut into the solid shapes ultimately creating and shaping your vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being very precise and measuring all lengths using a tape measure, I put together the model. The plates measured 74mm by 74mm, and I added 5mm height. The NFC reader measured 40mm by 61mm, so I added some grooves for the reader to rest into the model and stay in place. I added rounded corners and measured the screw holes. I also added some divots for the washers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It did not take long to create the model. I cut out more of the solid areas to use less material when printing. Also, I flipped the model upside down thinking that it would be better to have the flat areas printed first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TapTo-Bracket-Thin-Upside-Down.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TapTo-Bracket-Thin-Upside-Down.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/tapto/TapTo-Bracket-Thin-Upside-Down.webp" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the file: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/11UX3tfvHsffEDEHT3y7o3tb_nzsDfd-w/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/11UX3tfvHsffEDEHT3y7o3tb_nzsDfd-w/view?usp=sharing"&gt;Google Docs / TapTo Bracket Thin Upside-Down.stl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My sister had several failed attempts trying to print it for some reason. I've never owned a 3D printer, but it seems like there's so much variance in print quality depending on properly seeding the model to the bench, using quality materials, making sure the printer head is clean to allow clean material on the bench, the speed of building the model, and generally just the overall quality and precision of the printer itself. Seems like a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friend Jason was coming to visit, so I asked if he knew anyone with a decent printer setup. And he was able to get an clean print of my file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8751.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8751.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8751_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8751_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8751_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an exact clean print! It felt nice and sturdy compared to other 3D printed parts I've had before. It was SO exact that when I put the NFC reader into place &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8755.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8755.jpg"&gt;it perfectly snapped into position.&lt;/a&gt; There was absolutely no clearance. It was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8767.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8767.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8767_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8767_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8767_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took apart the base, and began assembling it with the bracket in the middle. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8769.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8769.jpg"&gt;The washers fit in the divots perfectly.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8771.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8771.jpg"&gt;The screw holes matched exactly with the screw holes on the plastic plates.&lt;/a&gt; Things were tight, but all the dimensions were exact enough that it fit together like a dream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The USB-C connector was a little recessed in the bracket, but the connector on the plug was long enough to compensate. And it fit in the connector perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8773.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8773.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8773_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8773_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8773_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8779.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8779.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8779_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8779_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8779_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After fitting everything together, I was so amazed at the results. I would expect there to be some problem with size or quailty or variance. Like the print would be slightly too large or small. Or maybe there was some piece of the PCB sticking out that I hadn't noticed before. Or the inlets weren't deep enough. Or I messed up my measurements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But no problems at all. It fit like a glove. Pac-Man agrees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8794.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8794.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8794_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8794_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251018_nfc/IMG_8794_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel to use the file and part list to create your own. The only thing I would add is a TapTo or Mister FPGA sticker.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/tapto-nfc-reader-enclosure</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/tapto-nfc-reader-enclosure</link><category/><category/><category/><category>Games</category><category/><category>Game-Related Projects</category></item><item><title>Modding a Sega Dreamcast</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I started thinking about the Dreamcast again. The recent ADGQ run of Crazy Taxi resparked some dormant brain cells and reminded me of all the arcade fun the console had to offer. Ultimately, back in the day, I would shelf the console in favor of the Playstation 2 and its library of much deeper story telling games. But, the console would occasionally get pulled out of storage when friends were around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this wave of nostalgia, I purchased several hardware mods to build an ultimate Dreamcast with all my favorite games available to play at a touch. I received all the packages, but my Dreamcast was half a world away in the United States. This summer, I returned home, and now I have all of my original Dreamcast hardware on hand, and finally took the weekend to put everything together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8103.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8103.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8103_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8103_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8103_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spoilers. It is excellent, and I am amazed how easy it was to install everything and how seemless everything worked on the first try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreamcast Hardware&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is all of my original hardware from back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7892.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7892.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7892_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7892_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7892_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a few surprises. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, I had completely forgotten that I bought a VGA box. After really crawling into my memory about when this happened, I do recall hooking it up to my LCD monitor a few times. But I never used it that way for long periods of time because it was a nuisance to my computer set up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, I had also forgotten about some other prior modding. 2007 was probably the last time I had used my Dreamcast. At that time, I had purchased some new Shmup releases and the discs would scrap along the shell inside of the disc tray. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/end-gen-dreamcast" title="https://theschlock.com/end-gen-dreamcast"&gt;I made a few modifications&lt;/a&gt;, and eventually &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7913.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7913.jpg"&gt;taped the lid sensor&lt;/a&gt; to always be closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreamcast Mods&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For modding and upgrading the Dreamcast, I purchased the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- &lt;b&gt;GDEmu Disc Emulator&lt;/b&gt; (8019&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $53.46)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;Noctua Fan Replacement&lt;/b&gt; (4924&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $32.82)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;DreamPSU Power Supply Replacement&lt;/b&gt; (3304&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $22.03)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;Console Shell Replacement&lt;/b&gt; (in Smoke Black) (4994&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $33.29)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;Bitfunk Dreamcast HDMI Adapter&lt;/b&gt; (2519&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $16.79)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;Retro Fighters D6 Controller&lt;/b&gt; (released in Feburary 2025) ($65.89)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;8BitMods VMU Pro&lt;/b&gt; (in Smoke Black) (released in November 2025) ($94.44)&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;b&gt;128gb SD Card&lt;/b&gt; (2865&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; / $18.77)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The top 5 hardware mods were purchased from AliExpress from various retailers. I bought the D6 Controller from Retro Fighters directly. The VMU Pro isn't out yet, but it's only available through the 8BitMods site. Those prices include shipping to Japan. Maybe it's a bit expensive, but I think it's a small price to have a dedicated machine that can easily play all of these great games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should note that understanding which mods to buy and what was required came from another one of Tito's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajGD-Ti7CFA" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajGD-Ti7CFA"&gt;Macho Nacho YouTube videos&lt;/a&gt;, similar to &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;my PS2 build&lt;/a&gt;. He put all of this stuff together a couple of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I decided to skip using the DreamPSU and the HDMI Adapter. Since its release, the DreamPSU has had &lt;a href="https://www.retrorgb.com/dreamcast-replacement-psu-design-analysed.html" title="https://www.retrorgb.com/dreamcast-replacement-psu-design-analysed.html"&gt;some criticism&lt;/a&gt;. It seems like the DreamPSU doesn't really offer anything new to the Dreamcast, and could potential cause harm. If there's nothing wrong with your current Dreamcast power supply, then there's no reason to get rid of it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I skipped the HDMI adapter because I am able to get crisp video through the VGA box. I can pass the VGA and audio signal into my OSSC, and use that to display on my TV through HDMI. Also, the HDMI adapter works with the VGA signal, so the few games that don't work with VGA won't work with it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Saturday afternoon was spent replacing the Dreamcast shell and installing the GDemu and the fan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7895.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7895.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7895_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7895_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7895_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's important to note that the GDemu only works on &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7901.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7901.jpg"&gt;version VA1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; consoles, denoted by the circled 1 on the bottom sticker. Revision VA1 consoles are the most common, so you most likely own that one. VA0 consoles were only produced through mid-1999, so perhaps only launch models in the US were VA0. The VA1 started production in mid-1999 and continued through late 2000. VA2 revision models began production around October and December 2000, but so they may have come to market in early 2001, a few months before Sega announced the Dreamcast was done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disassembly&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dreamcast can be completely taken apart using a Phillips head screwdriver. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The disassembly starts with the 4 screws keeping the outer shell in place. You'll need to remove the modem to get at the 4th corner screw. With the shell removed, nearly all the inner components are visible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7906.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7906.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7906_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7906_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7906_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GD reader is the large piece in the middle. We'll replace that with the GDemu unit later. The left component is the power supply. The on/off switch in the front left is plugged into it. The controller port assembly is the component in the front. It has a battery that manages the internal clock. It also gives power to the fan on the right. Everything sits on top of a metal shield. The Dreamcast motherboard is between this shield and another one on the very bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first component to remove is the GD reader. Mine was attached using 2 screws, even though there were holes for 3 screws. Maybe I lost one while I was messing around in 2007.  Be sure to pull it out as an entire unit with the metal plate on the bottom. You don't need to disassemble the reader itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7915.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7915.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7915_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7915_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7915_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7916.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7916.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7916_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7916_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7916_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the power supply. The power supply is held in place by 2 screws and its connection to the motherboard. First, unplug the on/off switch connected in the back and then remove the screws. The motherboard connection is really strong, so it can be difficult to pull it off with finesse. I rocked mine back and forth a bit, but be careful not too do this too much as it could dislodge the connector from the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power supply has a plastic shield that sits between it and the surrounding components, so don't lose that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next component to remove is the controller assembly in the front. You'll need to remove the power cable going to the fan and unplug the ribbon cable going to the motherboard. Both cables are removed pretty easily. Just gently rock them back and forth with a little bit of force and they'll come out. The component is held in place with 4 screws next to the controller ports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7918.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7918.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7918_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7918_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7918_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, there are only 3 more components to remove. The fan and the power button are only held in place with 2 screws each. Those are easy to remove. The direction they're installed is important, but it's easy to tell which was they go. We'll replace the fan later, so we don't need to worry about that one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final component is the motherboard, sandwiched between two metal shields, screwed to the bottom of the shell with 8 screws. After removing the screws, the upper metal shield is still attached to the motherboard with a few plastic pins. Removing them is unnecessary, so leave them alone. You can remove the upper shield and motherboard together as a single piece. The video plugs are set into the shell, so it takes a bit of movement to find the right angle, but eventually you can pull the motherboard out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All that remains is &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7919.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7919.jpg"&gt;the bottom shield&lt;/a&gt; with two termal pads. Nothing is holding this in place, so it's easy to pull out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7923.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7923.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7923_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7923_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7923_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gutted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reassembly&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I removed each component, I laid the screws next to them so I could remember which screws were used in which positions. Only a few components will be replaced, but these components rely on reusing the original screws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7925.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7925.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7925_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7925_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7925_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the new shell, first I placed the bottom thermal shield. Then, I screwed in the power button. It's important to note that the front plastic controller port panel must be set in place before putting the motherboard in. Also, VERY IMPORTANT, make sure the termal pads are in the correct position on the bottom plate before putting the motherboard in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One small problem with my reassembly was a single screw &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7928.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7928.jpg"&gt;being misaligned&lt;/a&gt;. All other points of the motherboard were perfect except for this small spot. I'm not sure why this happened, but I decided to proceed rather than remove everything and solve the problem. The screws only held the board in place and it was very secure without this screw.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7931.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7931.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7931_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7931_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7931_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the motherboard was secure, I put the power supply back into place, and made sure to put the plastic shield in the correct position. Make sure the power button cable moves underneath the component like it did before. Push the board into its connector, screw it in with the 2 screws, and connect the power button. The power plug in the back should be flush with the shell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the front, angle the controller port into the shell, then use the 4 screws to attach it to the build. Then plug in the ribbon cable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, everything should be pretty smooth, and we have only the fan and the GDemu left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7934.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7934.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7934_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7934_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7934_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreamcast GDemu Disc Emulator&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDemu is a PCB with an SD card slot and a button. It plugs into the motherboard in the exact position as the GD reader and acts as an emulator. Here's the GDemu board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7938.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7938.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7938_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7938_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7938_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just as the GD reader reads the discs and gives data to the motherboard, the GDemu also sends game data. You fill up the SD card with a bunch of games, and the GDemu reads the currently selected "disc" and sends the data to the board. The SD card needs to be in a specific format, but I did that &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation" title="https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation"&gt;preparation back in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the SD card, each disc is stored in a specific numbered position, so the GDemu ultimately acts like a disc changer. The first CD in the list is the default disc loaded when the Dreamcast is turned on. This is where the GDemu menu application is stored. From the menu, you can choose any game you installed. Additionally, you can switch games/discs using the button. Pushing the button loads the next disc in the list. This is really only useful for multi-disc games, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;GDemu Assembly and Installation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDemu package came with everything you see here: the GDemu PCB, SD card extender, an 8gb SD card, some plastic pieces, and some screws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7936.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7936.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7936_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7936_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7936_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It did not come with any instructions, so I was supposed to figure out how everything went together on my own. It's not too difficult to understand, but there are a few things that aren't so obvious. I found &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3EWUs-zDwcU" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3EWUs-zDwcU"&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; of a guy putting together nearly the same thing, which helped me out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technically, you don't need any of the plastic parts to connect the GDemu. You can plug the GDemu into the motherboard directly and be done with it. However, the purpose of the plastic pieces is to seel the internal components from the outside and allow the fan to do its job of efficiently venting hot air. Whether or not the fan actually does this is a different question, but its best to try and help the Dreamcast accomplish this original goal. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step in assembly is attaching the SD card extender to the large plastic cover. There are 2 tiny screws used to do this. (I had to use a smaller Phillips screwdriver to accomplish this.) &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7939.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7939.jpg"&gt;With the SD card extender in position&lt;/a&gt;, the tiny screws don't screw into it. They screw into the post beside it, and hold the extender in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7943.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7943.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7943_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7943_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7943_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That YouTube video was very helpful for understanding that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step is screwing the GDemu board into the same plastic assembly. Connect the SD card extender into the SD card on the GDemu board. The ribbon cable is too long, but it's okay to have the extra length spill out of the back. There's nothing behind it that is harmful. You may be able to fold the cable inside of the plastic piece, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The board attaches with two screws. Be sure to put the button into the plastic shell before screwing in the board. Also, be sure not to screw the board too tight. The bigger plastic button needs some clearance so it can click the board's button easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7945.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7945.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7945_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7945_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7945_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7948.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7948.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7948_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7948_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7948_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now there should be one long screw, one short screw, and one more plastic tube piece left. After plugging the GDemu into the motherboard, it becomes obvious where these pieces go. The back end of the plastic cover lines up perfectly with one of the GD reader screw holes. This is for the short screw. The front edge of the GDemu board hovers over another screw hole. The plastic tube props up the board and allows the screw to pass through into the base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With everything assembled and screwed into place, the GDemu board should be held above the metal shield. It looks pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7951.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7951.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7951_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7951_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7951_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Noctua Fan Mod&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final bit to install is the Noctua Fan. My order included the full fan kit, and a few extras. We only need the fan and a single screw from the full kit. The extras where some 3D printed brackets, and a conversion cable from the fan to the Dreamcast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7954.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7954.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7954_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7954_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7954_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 3D printed pieces were so cheap. I'm no 3D printing expert, by the overall quality looked like they used a 1st gen 3D printer to make them? What creates that rough unfinished imprecise surface? Is that from using poor materials? Or not properly calibrating your machine? Or not steadying the model on the surface pad while printing? They look so ugly, but they're internal components, so who cares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7960.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7960.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7960_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7960_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7960_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7969.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7969.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7969_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7969_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7969_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reusing the screws from the original Dreamcast fan, I attached the new fan hood to the shell. Then using one of the included screws in the kit, I attached the fan to the hood. Make sure the direction of the fan is going outward. There's a small arrow on the fan indicating its direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After plugging the fan cable into the controller port board, I scrinched the cables under the controller port ribbon cable to keep them secure in a position away from touching something else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7966.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7966.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7966_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7966_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7966_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's one final modification left. The Noctua fan takes up more space inside the Dreamcast and it interferes with the lid hatch. The mechanical component is a full squared piece and a section of it needs to be removed. Because of this, we've given those other two printed pieces as a lid hatch replacement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where the terrible print quailty of the components caused troubles. The inner peg is meant to be shoved through the larger peg and create the lid hatch. My inner peg was too fat, or the hole was too thin, so when pushing the peg through the hole it didn't go all the way. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7981.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7981.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7981_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7981_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7981_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The peg was about 2mm longer, which meant the whole piece couldn't fit into the lid flushly. I tried shoving the peg in further and wiggling it into place, but it was still too long. I used a nail file to make the piece a little thinner and that worked. Although, not really. Now the piece was too loose so when the Open Tray button was pressed, the lid latch wouldn't go back into its extended position, so the lid couldn't be closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7990.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7990.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7990_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7990_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7990_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lid latch component is very delicate. It needs to be loose enough to freely move back and forth between the two screw posts. When the button is pressed, it moves one way, then the spring brings it back to its original position. So, the two pieces also need to have a complete strong bond together so the spring doesn't pull the latch back on its own. Using the nail file, the middle piece was now too loose. Why did they print this as two pieces? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7988.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7988.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7988_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7988_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7988_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still had some epoxy from an earlier project, so I glued the two pieces together. The cheapness of the material probably helped fuse the two pieces together even better than usual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even so, the piece was still too rigid in the lid. I used my screwdriver head to widen the holes even more, and the piece finally moved smoothly. Much like the button component, these screws should not be too tight. They should be just tight enough to hold the piece into position and allow it to move freely back and forth. The lid finally opened and closed like it was supposed to after all this work. (This was the longest part of the physical build.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Complete&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the pieces of the puzzle finally put into place, I secured the top part of the shell on to the base, tightened the outer 4 screws, and the build was complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7992.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7992.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7992_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7992_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_7992_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I plugged the VGA box into my OSSC, plugged video and power in to the Dreamcast, turned it on, and it worked perfectly the first time. That beautiful Dreamcast opening filled the room with its ambience, and the GDemu menu popped up showing all the games &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation" title="https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation"&gt;that I had added back in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8012.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8012.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8012_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8012_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8012_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Video Conversion and OSSC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Dreamcast is using the VGA Box that I purchased decades ago to send its video signal into the OSSC. The OSSC translates that into an HDMI signal which I'm plugging into my TV. Even though I just bought a new TV, my TV doesn't really like 480p signals and it really doesn't like 960p signals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FirebrandX had created the "perfect" timings for the Dreamcast a couple years ago with the following settings:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Sync opt. &gt; &lt;br/&gt;    Analog sync LDF = Off&lt;br/&gt;Output opt. &gt; &lt;br/&gt;    480p/576p proc = Line2x&lt;br/&gt;Sampling opt. &gt;&lt;br/&gt;    Sampling phase = 45 deg&lt;br/&gt;    480p in sampler = DTV 480p&lt;br/&gt;    Allow upsample2x = off&lt;br/&gt;&lt; Adv. timing &gt; 480p:&lt;br/&gt;    H. samplerate = 858&lt;br/&gt;    H. Synclen = 62&lt;br/&gt;    H. backporch = 111&lt;br/&gt;    H. active = 640&lt;br/&gt;    V. synclen = 6&lt;br/&gt;    V. backporch = 34&lt;br/&gt;    V. active = 480&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This causes a black screen for me because my TV doesn't like 960p signals. Turning the output option back to PassThru also creates a black screen with these settings. If I leave all these values at default, I get a very beautiful image, but unfortunately it's stretched to the 16:9 ratio as shown above. My TV doesn't have a 4:3 option, so I would need another box that converts 480p or 960p to a 1080p signal and allows 4:3 to be forced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the Bitfunx HDMI converter does force 4:3 and gives a clean image, but there are no video options at all. You can't do scanlines or change the fuzziness of model edges. I dunno... it doesn't look right to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, between choosing an imperfect toolbox or a single use hammer, I think I'll stick with the toolbox. If I somehow can afford a RetroTink4k in the future, then that's probably the best path for me and my TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;RetroFighters D6 Controller&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I built my setup for the Playstation 2, I also bought an 8bitdo Retro Receiver so I could use a modern wireless controller with the old games. Wanting to do the same with the Dreamcast, I looked around for options. I decided to purchase the D6 controller from RetroFighters, which is unconventional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love this controller a lot, although I don't think it's for everyone. I wrote a review &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/retrofighters-d6-controller" title="https://theschlock.com/retrofighters-d6-controller"&gt;in a separate post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;8BitMods VMU Pro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet to be released, 8BitMods is in the final stages of completing its VMU Pro. The VMU Pro is a high-end game device that manages all of your Dreamcast save files, but goes further with a full color LCD screen and allows its own custom software to be run. In particular, they have shown video of running 8-bit emulators for GameBoy, GameBoy color, Master System, and the NES.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's being billed as the original ultimate vision of the Dreamcast VMU finally coming true. Preorders began back in May and it should finally ship in November. I will make a post about it after I've had long enough to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Dreamcast Lives on!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am very happy with how well this whole project came together. Installing all the mods was very simple. Managing games and details is also very simple. And there is still more to come with the VMU Pro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While playing pirated games on the Dreamcast has been available since its release, it's amazing how much the tech has matured over the years, and how much stuff is still being released for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a Dreamcast in storage, I would suggest giving these mods a try. You'll be able to relive all those old memories again, and make some new ones with unique games you never had a chance to try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8033.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8033.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8033_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8033_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251004_dreamcast/IMG_8033_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite games of all time, Rez, originated on the Dreamcast. These days, there are other modern ways of playing with a few more options. But, there's a debug version of Rez which allows you to mess with performance, enemies variance, and also have a free camera! (More on this in the future, maybe)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory"&gt;Modded Console Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt; page has been updated with all the games I plan on giving a try. Take a look and see if having a Dreamcast library immediately available to play on your TV sounds right for you. :)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/modding-a-sega-dreamcast</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/modding-a-sega-dreamcast</link><category/><category/><category/><category>Games</category><category/><category>Game-Related Projects</category></item><item><title>RetroFighters D6 Controller</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When modding and building a full modern day &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/modding-a-sega-dreamcast" title="https://theschlock.com/modding-a-sega-dreamcast"&gt;set up for my Dreamcast&lt;/a&gt;, I was in the market to look for a modern controller to use with it. The original Dreamcast controller was fine for it's day, but the controller is really big and clunky. Also, the D-pad is tiny and imprecise. I wanted something better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I built my &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;setup for the Playstation 2&lt;/a&gt;, I bought an 8bitdo Retro Receiver, so I could use a modern Playstation controller with the old games. Wanting to do the same with the Dreamcast, I looked around for options. However, Dreamcast controllers are very unique because you connect the memory card to them. There isn't a separate slot on the console like the Playstation and Gamecube. So, buying a Bluetooth receiver for the controller port isn't the best option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found RetroFighters, a vintage game controller manufacturer which created wireless Dreamcast controllers with the use of Memory Cards in mind. For their wireless controllers, the reciever plugged into the controller port is a large unit where you also plug in your memory card. Their most popular controller is the StrikerDC, but I decided to go with their most recent controller instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8122_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Released in late 2024, the D6 Controller looks more like a Saturn controller than a Dreamcast controller. It has 6 face buttons instead of 4 and it only has a D-Pad rather than both a D-Pad and a Stick. RetroFighters' goal for the D6 was to create the ultimate handheld controller for Dreamcast fighting games. The movement of the D-pad matches that of the Saturn, so you can get those perfect fireballs compared with the D-pad on the standard controller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the buttons are very clicky, which can turn people off, but I think the controller feels amazing. I think it's even better than the 8bitdo's M30. This is mainly because all of the buttons are the same size. Super Nintendo games feel terrible on the M30 because the top row of buttons are smaller and more concave. The D6 gives equal size and importance to all buttons, and the button presses feel great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I wanted this controller because it comes with a USB dongle. The StrikerDC only works with the Dreamcast so it's a single-use $55 controller. With the D6, I can use it with the Analogue Pocket, the Mister, and even the Switch for simple games. (It's excellent with Tetris.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8116.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8116.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8116_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8116_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8116_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the biggest question...  How does this controller work for games like Crazy Taxi, Sonic Adventure, or anything that uses the Stick for movement? On the bottom of the controller, there's a mode switch. All the way to the left, the D-pad operates as the D-pad. Switch the mode to the middle, and the D-pad operates as the Left stick. Switch the mode to the right, and it's the Right stick, which was the Dreamcast doesn't have, but other consoles do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's still limited in that you can't use both the Left stick and D-pad at the same time. Also, the D-pad focuses on digital input, so games that rely on Analog movement from the Left stick won't feel so great. In this case, the original controller would be the better option. But, for the niche this controller is trying to fill, I think it works perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, as another note, the receiver base only allows a single memory card as opposed to original controllers which have two slots for two memory cards. I think this is because the controller has vibration. So, it's using a fake second slot as a rumble pak. Ultimately, I think this is another con against the controller as you can't do any memory management with just the controller. You'll need a second controller, or do management directly from VMU to VMU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8124.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8124.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8124_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8124_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/251010_d6/IMG_8124_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think it's a great controller, although it's not the ultimate solution for playing all games on the Dreamcast. It feels great to pick up and hold, and cycling through menus is a breeze. It's worth the money in my opinion if you have a Dreamcast, enjoy playing fighting games on the Dreamcast and don't like arcade sticks, and also have several other devices or consoles with retro games.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/retrofighters-d6-controller</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/retrofighters-d6-controller</link><category/><category/><category>Games</category><category/></item><item><title>Doai Onsen 渡合温泉</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Doai Onsen &lt;span class='ja'&gt;度合温泉&lt;/span&gt; is a Ryokan deep in the forests and mountains of northern Nakatsuragawa, close enough to the southern border of Gero to consider it like Hida. Once you reach the turn-off from the main road, it takes over 30 minutes of driving on a narrow single lane road through the forest and along valley cliffs to reach the remote buildings. It's deep enough in the forest that cellphone reception is hard to come by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7419.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7419.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7419_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7419_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7419_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the inn is to relax with nature while shedding the modern conveniences of the Internet and electricity. To become less digital and more analogue. There are very few lights at Doai Onsen and after 10pm, the generator is turned off. The hallways and rooms are only illuminated by lantern at that point, of which there are more than 300 at the inn in various styles. The numerous amount of lanterns have become the mascot of Doai Onsen, so Doai is also known as the Lamp Inn &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ランプの宿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7292.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7292.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7292_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7292_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7292_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found this place while searching around on Google Maps looking for places to hike and explore, and with my friends Dirk and Zach coming to visit in September, we decided to give it a try and stay a night. They have a very modern website which made it easy to reserve a room and the prices were very good compared to other expensive onsens and ryokans. Only 15000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; (~$100) a night, which includes dinner and breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After an obnoxious lunch, we arrived around 4pm. There was a bit of confusion on when we were supposed to arrive, but it all worked out. Check-in official began at 3pm, but we could still arive by 5pm. We were sharing the inn with 2 other groups. One group was just a mother and son. The other group was a larger older family of about 6 people. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7313.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7313.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7313_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7313_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7313_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inn seemed like the perfect size for our 3 groups. I don't know if any of the rooms had names, but we were given the room nearest to the entrance. There were two connected tatami rooms that were opened up so we had a really large space, a total of 20 tatami mats!  The group of 6 had the whole lower wing to themselves, so they probably had probably double the space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While some others had already arrived, we were able to hop in the baths first and have them to ourselves before the other groups. Dinner was served around 6:15pm (later than usual), so there was a lot of time to soak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7329.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7329.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7329_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7329_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7329_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were separated baths for men and women which alternated in the night and morning. The men had the larger bath in the evening. The baths are kept warm from a wood burning stove underneath, known as the Goemon method. However, heated water from the tap is boiled using electricity from the generator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were two baths available. Both were filled with spring water from the mountain. One was full of water that was naturally heated by the thermals of the mountain. The other was from cool spring water that was manually heated. Both contain the natural minerals that onsen in the mountains are known for, such as sodium bicarbonate (baking soda, essentially). These baths repair and soothe rough skin and cuts by eating away at dead skin on the surface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7331.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7331.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7331_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7331_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7331_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love sitting in the warm baths. Natural onsens are my favorite. :) The open window looked out over the gorge with the Tsukechi river below. There were the 3 of us in the bath, so we were talking about things. But, it is always nice to just sit in the bath and listen the wind blow through the leaves and the water flow through the river. There were hot and cold taps for the baths, so I could douse myself with cold water when I felt I was getting too hot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was still pretty early out, but it would've been really nice to come back after the sunset and soak in the tub only lit by lantern light. The lanterns keep the insects away, so you could just relax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We stayed in the baths for about 40 minutes and were leaving just as the next group came in. We goofed around in the room for about an hour until the hostess notified everyone of dinner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7436.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7436.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7436_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7436_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7436_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dinner was incredible. Often when dinner is served at an enkai or ryokan, there is usually not enough (for me) to go around. I'm always leave feeling unsatisfied and that I could've had more. This was not the case at Doai. The meal began with mountain vegetables &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山菜&lt;/span&gt;, tofu, mochi, and some Iwana sashimi. Iwana is the most common and prevalent fish in the rivers of these moutanins, and local restaurants often serve it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7448.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7448.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7448_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7448_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7448_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7445.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7445.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7445_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7445_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7445_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more dishes kept coming out. We had baked Iwana, tempura, and a very large Gohei mochi. Gohei mochi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;五平餅&lt;/span&gt; is fried mochi on a stick with a sweet syrup sauce painted on the top. They are usually the size of a popsicle, but this beast was larger than most pancakes. It was so good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an amazing meal with so much delicious food. One of the best meals I've had in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With dinner finished, we had the lamp and safety demonstration at 7:30pm. I thought that this would take only a couple of minutes so I could be back in the onsen bath before they closed, but the lamp demonstration was only the beginning of the night's activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7466.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7466.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7466_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7466_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7466_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arriving in the common area, we were given a puzzle, a wooden needle threaded in a denim jacket. "Remove the needle from the jacket and get a prize!" It seemed pretty easy and I remember seeing a similar looking puzzle on YouTube a while ago where a person removed a bike lock from a lamp post. That was a different solve, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We fumbled around at the puzzle until everyone arrived and began the lamp demonstration. The host explained how to correctly light the lamp by achieving the correct flame size after lighting the wick with a match. The two sides of the flame should create an arch when holding the glass above the flame, creating an image that kinda looks like Batman. If the flame is too intense, there's too much wick. The reverse is true too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7468.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7468.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7468_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7468_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7468_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also mentioned that because the wick is completely soaked in oil, it never burns itself. The wick isn't like the wick of a candle. If the flame dies down, it's because of the oil running low, not because the wick is too low. As such, you should never push too much of the wick out of the base. In the short term, you might get the light you want, but after an hour there will be a massive flame burning out of the lantern. ALWAYS make sure the initial lighting creates the batman shape, and the lantern will be fine for the whole night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, when you want to extinguish the flame, don't mess with the wick. Simply blow over the top of the glass and the air circulation will put out the light.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were each given our own lantern to light the correct way. The wicks were already in the best position, so we didn't have to mess with it. After striking our match and lighting the wick, we just observed the flame's shape to verify it was correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7481.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7481.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7481_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7481_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7481_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, continuing with lighting lanterns, he had us lighting the lamps using the arcane method of flint and steel, the same way his Japanese ancestors like lanterns. We started off with a standard cut of steel against stones. But, if we couldn't handle it, we could use easier steel which guaranteed sparks. Every strike on the flint should try and knock the sparks into some padded cloth, and then attempt to transfer the spark into the lantern to light it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was not so easy. I could not get the right angle or I was holding it too hard. I moved on to the easy steel and sparks were flying immediately. Lighting the lantern was so much easier using the "starter" steel. Zach and Dirk were much better at using the true steel method.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving on from the lantern, there were many more activities. We continued with the wooden thread puzzle, and he continued to give us more and more hints until we understood how to solve it. Upon solving it, we could keep the wooden needle and as a prize, we were given an extra one to give to a friend. (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KfqqeREGeXUwXPGD_bJXkESB3_WP_0SB/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KfqqeREGeXUwXPGD_bJXkESB3_WP_0SB/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;Here's how to solve it&lt;/a&gt;) The host gave us some construction paper with lines to cut out and create a skeleton figure. He also taught us some ways of tying knots using rope, which could help us repel down a cliff or carrying something up. He gave us &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Cb8dXIbZxS9hLECKE573H-1SZ9L5MGFN/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Cb8dXIbZxS9hLECKE573H-1SZ9L5MGFN/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;more prints of the cutouts and rope instructions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7498.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7498.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7498_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7498_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7498_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7512.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7512.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7512_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7512_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7512_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The night kept moving with all the activities that it was nearly 10pm. The host said there were more games in the morning, and you can win a prize if you remember how to tie the ropes. But with the generator going off in about 10 minutes, we all retired to our rooms for the night. Each group could take a lantern back to the room to use after lights out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7528.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7528.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7528_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7528_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7528_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the generator off, the lanterns were dim, but being out in the pitch darkness of the forest boosted their glow considerably. The hallways filled with the warm light. Although, if we had to use the bathroom, we just used the light on our phones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I was alone, I would have loved to fall asleep to the wind in the trees and the water in the river. But, I put in my earphones to guarantee that I could actually sleep through the night without waking from the smallest of sounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7531.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7531.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7531_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7531_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7531_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The morning came and the light filled our room. It was around 6:30, I think? I heard some odd pinking sound, which I thought was water drops tinking into a thin metal gutter. It was not. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the other family members were in the common area with the host's BB rifle shooting at a tin target in the forest. I went to join them and shot a few rounds. If you called your shot and hit the target within 2 tries, you won a prize, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7549.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7549.jpg"&gt;a compact flint and steel set with some cloth to catch the spark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The baths were open at 7am, so I went back to the room to gather my things for the bath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7540.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7540.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7540_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7540_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7540_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were on the left side now. It was the same layout, except the baths were slightly smaller. It was totally fine though. You don't want to stay in the bath for very long in the morning, otherwise you'll waste all your strength for the day. I think I spent about 15 minutes in the water as others came and went.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in the common area, more of us gathered to shoot airguns and play with the wooden games he had laid out. Those host asked us if we remembered the knot tying from the previous night. By performing the knot successfully, the prize was a bear bell to use in the forest when hiking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7583.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7583.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7583_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7583_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7583_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 8 o'clock, our breakfast was served. More mountain vegetables, Iwana, Miso soup, and other staples of a Japanese breakfast. Plenty of rice, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After breakfast, we continued shooting guns and playing games in the common area and were given &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7626.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7626.jpg"&gt;our bill for our stay&lt;/a&gt;. It was 45900&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; divided between the 3 of us. 15300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for one person, which included an amazing dinner, a delicious breakfast, an onsen towel, portable flint/steel, the wooden needle puzzle, a bear bell, and a soak in their onsen is a damn steal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7600.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7600.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7600_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7600_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250914_doai_onsen/IMG_7600_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an incredible stay at a beautiful place that I will forever compare with all my subsequent ryokan stays. I think it would be even better paired with hiking in the area prior to staying the night. After we left, we visited the waterfall just down the road, and also visited the Tsukechi gorge which wasn't too far away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see more information on the &lt;a href="https://www.doaionsen.jp/" title="https://www.doaionsen.jp/"&gt;Doai Onsen website&lt;/a&gt;. I also scanned &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zc-zpPhvCMHx4SpnR9xGuJ5T2OVYmu4H/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zc-zpPhvCMHx4SpnR9xGuJ5T2OVYmu4H/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;their brochure&lt;/a&gt; which has some more information. You may notice on their brochure that they have increased prices in the past. Their website currently says that they plan on increasing prices again next year in 2026, but the experience is well worth it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/doai-onsen</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/doai-onsen</link><category/><category/><category>Hida Takayama</category><category/><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category><category/><category/></item><item><title>The Moon in America</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Since ancient times, when people looked at the moon, they thought they viewed some kind of image on its surface. In European cultures, handed down to America, we had always viewed this image as a face, dubbing it The Man in the Moon. However, in Japanese history (and also China and other Asian countries), they don't see a face. They see a rabbit. Since living here and looking at the moon, I see it, too. It always looks two ears flopped over a crouching body fit into a circle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I once read somewhere that claimed part of the difference of opinion was because the angle of moon when viewed in Japan was different when viewed in America. In Japan, the moon was rotated counter-clockwise which put the rabbit's ears up a bit higher, making the rabbit more distinguishable. This seemed like nonsense because Japan and America are on the same latitude. The moon doesn't spin that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One night while in America visiting family, there was a beautiful clear night. A few clouds, but the moon is full and illuminated the darkness. I wanted to photograph proof of this difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's the American moon shot in August 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250807_moon/IMG_5857.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250807_moon/IMG_5857.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250807_moon/IMG_5857_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250807_moon/IMG_5857_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250807_moon/IMG_5857_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here's the Japanese moon &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/super-moon" title="https://theschlock.com/super-moon"&gt;shot in November 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/161115_super_moon/IMG_0052.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/161115_super_moon/IMG_0052.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/161115_super_moon/IMG_0052_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/161115_super_moon/IMG_0052_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/161115_super_moon/IMG_0052_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is rotated by quite a bit! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But... this rotation could be because of a lot of things. This is August versus November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's another photo of the Japanese moon &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/september-moon" title="https://theschlock.com/september-moon"&gt;from September 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/140908_moon/IMG_6228.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/140908_moon/IMG_6228.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/140908_moon/IMG_6228.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/140908_moon/IMG_6228.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/140908_moon/IMG_6228.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's rotated even more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it's not the difference in time of the year, but the time of night? The September shots were from dusk. However, the 2016 and 2025 shots were both taken around 10pm at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is the moon really rotated slightly on the other side of Earth even though it's the same hemisphere?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This rotation clearly makes it easier to notice a Rabbit in the Moon compared to a Man in the Moon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/the-moon-in-america</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/the-moon-in-america</link><category/><category/><category>America</category><category>Others</category></item><item><title>Widen Enterprises Building</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When I was back in the US, I visited Madison for only a brief 8 hours before moving on. I visited State St and the Square and was shocked at how much the place had fallen apart, due to a combination of Covid and people working from home. Stores were boarded up and gone. They were in the process of tearing down some buildings. And homeless folks were everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were always homeless people in Madison, but they were among the many other people walking around, working, and living in the area. Now, it felt empty and ravaged. I don't think the downtown area of Madison was the only place in America that has fallen apart in recent years. (Visiting the city during a rainstorm probably also contributed to the gloomy atmosphere.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, one of my destinations in Madison was to visit where I used to work, Widen Enterprises. After graduating university, I worked for Widen Enterprises as a Software Developer for over 7 years and then worked abroad for them a litlte bit after coming to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Widen Enterprises had a history of print which began in the 40s. They first began detailing and manufacturing plates for newsprint and then broke into catalog printing in the 60s. In the 90s, they invested in developing a user interface and backend that would aid their customers and building these catalogs. This move was perfect syngery with their printing service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, with the Internet becoming more and more ubiquitous, print died and their software division grew considerably. During my years of working there, the printing division became smaller and smaller. The basement used to have huge printers for all their costumer's catalogs. As company's workflows moved online, less and less were printing and these printers just took up space. Just after I left, I think the entire print division was disbanded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Widen's Digital Asset Management system grew to become their main focus and now it had become their only focus. When I began work there, we occupied half of the top floor. After I left, the building was remodeled and development took over the entire ground floor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even before the Covid years, I think many developers and staff worked from home at least one day a week. And then during Covid, I think everyone switched to remote working. Not uncommon for companies in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, in September 2021, they sold the company to Acquia. Acquia's main product is a line of content management software for your enterprise website. Having a digital asset management system is powerful tool to allow your costumers to host all their product images and use their software to build their corporate website or commerical website around it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the 4 years of ownership and looking at some staff listsing at Acquia, it looks like much of the brilliant excellent folks at Widen have been moved into more senior roles within Acquia. From other rumors, it seems like much of Widen's staff has either been absorbed into other areas of Acquia or left the company altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4438.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4438.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4438_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4438_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4438_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the old Widen building is for sale. It is no longer used by any developers or staff still working on DAM, wherever they may be. I think Widen had been at this location since the late 60s or 70s? Some of the other print buildings in the area still look like they're in business. It seems like a blight to have one of the major businesses in the area gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone had recently mowed the lawn, so it doesn't look too bad. But there are still some overgrown plants around the parking lot. Nobody comes here. (The overgrowth is much more present on Google Street View.) I'm not sure when they sold the building. Maybe it was still being used in late 2023?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4430.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4430.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4430_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4430_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250731_02_widen/IMG_4430_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was in the US, I drove past many corporate buildings and businesses that were completely empty because of the workforce moving online. I'm not a fan of working from home, but my commute to work is only 5 minutes in this dense mountain town. If I had to drive 45 minutes to work every day in a dense metro traffic, I would probably prefer working from home, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While everything feels like it's falling apart in the states, I think it's a consequence of transitioning the next (or another) form of our society. And change hurts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It still &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/toys-r-us-is-dead" title="https://theschlock.com/toys-r-us-is-dead"&gt;sucks that another one of my former workplaces is gone.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/widen-enterprises-building</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/widen-enterprises-building</link><category>Madison</category><category/><category>Updates</category><category>America</category><category>Others</category></item><item><title>Kojima Ludens Capsule Figure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In June, Kitan Club released a series of figurines based on the Ludens mascot for Kojima Production. There are Deluxe Edition figures which have painted details released as blind boxes for 1650&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. And, there are "Simple" ones, released as a Capsule figure for 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; each. I found these while I was in Toyama to see Superman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2602.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2602.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2602_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2602_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2602_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The capsule machine will mostly full, but there were a few people around getting their coins ready for a pull, including one guy who excitedly got all 3 different figures in only 3 pulls!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I turned the crank and got the Fruit Roll-Up color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2610.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2610.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2610_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2610_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2610_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 3 colors available were translucent black, translucent red, and glow-in-the-dark. I think I would've prefered the glow-in-the-dark version for the novelty, but fruit snack red was a close second. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside the capsule there was an advertisment showing the different colors and some very obtuse instructions on how to assemble the figure. It wasn't difficult to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2632.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2632.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2632_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2632_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250712_08_ludens/IMG_2632_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Annoying that the flag is bent. The figure looks so chewable, but it's pretty solid and sturdy once put together. Not sturdy enough to withstand the Japanese summer heat sitting in a box somewhere for a few weeks, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it's fun for a 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; pull, but certainly not worth the 1650&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for the Deluxe figures.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/kojima-ludens-capsule-figure</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/kojima-ludens-capsule-figure</link><category/><category/><category/><category>Toys</category><category>Media</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Shimohara Winter Branch School 下原冬季分校</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Shimohara Village was a small village or settlement in the southwestern area of modern day Toyama Prefecture. It is one of the first villages along the Otani Valley, part of the five valleys of the area. After the village designations of the late 1800s, it became part of Toga Village, which is kinda weird, but maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole area of southwest Toyama is split into five major valleys. Toga Valley is the eastern-most one, with Otani Valley directly to the west. All of these valleys are very long and winding. Today, it takes about 30 minutes to reach the center of Toga Village from the valley base by car. It takes about 10 minutes from the same location to reach Shimohara going down the Otani valley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know how they expected these students to travel the distance back to the valley base and trek 3-times the distance up another valley to reach school each day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, the government must've thought the same way because in 1935 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;昭和&lt;/span&gt;10 they built a branch school in the center of this village, titles &lt;b&gt;Toga Element School - Shimohara Winter Branch School&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;利賀小学校下原冬季分校&lt;/span&gt;. Apparently, roads were established enough for students to make the trip outside of winter. When the school was built they were 16 students. Later in 1973 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;昭和&lt;/span&gt;48, it became an all-year branch school before closing in 1986 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;昭和&lt;/span&gt;61.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was according to research done by &lt;a href="http://heyaneko.web.fc2.com/zs14.html" title="http://heyaneko.web.fc2.com/zs14.html"&gt;Heyaneko&lt;/a&gt;. Much like other school buildings in the distant old villages of Toga Valley, some people began living in the building for a time. But, the building had been completely vacant for about 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1838_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1838_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1838_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1838_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1838_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, it's gone. Google Maps still shows the building being there, but it's using imagery from May 2024. So, it must've been demolished last year. Many of these old buildings used a lot of asbestos, so with no one maintaining them, they've become an incredible danger and must be removed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took some photos of the empty lot, and went up the hill to visit the village's shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1860_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1860_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1860_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1860_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1860_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Shimohara Hachiman Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;下原八幡宮&lt;/span&gt;. Hachiman Shrines are dedicated to the Shinto god Hachiman. He is apparently a god of archery and war, so he was a favorite god of many samurai. Many farmers and fisherman also pray to Hachiman for a bountiful harvest or a bountiful amount of fish in their nets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shrine was a bit unique as the Shishi Lion statues out front looked very stunted compared to ones I've seen at other shrines. Maybe these statues were the original ones from hundreds of years ago, never refreshed or reformed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shrine itself was protected by a wall of plexiglass surrounding the entire building. The front could be opened to enter, pray, and give your offering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1903_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1903_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1903_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1903_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_16_shimohara/IMG_1903_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This small pocket of civilization seems pretty representative of the many villages that dot these valleys. People often refer to them as islands because of how isolated they can be. Shimohara is pretty representative of this as the walls of the valley are so steep there's really nothing around except for the next pocket village down the road 10 minutes or back up the road for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's obviously easy to travel to all these village today with the roads and tunnels carved out of the mountains. But these roads have only been established since after the war in the 60s and 70s. 100 years ago, people were probably only traveling to these villages by boat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People still live in Shimohara today. There were four homes, and had their cars parked nearby. With the concrete school building gone, the area feels like its gotten closer to nature again.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/shimohara-winter-branch-school</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/shimohara-winter-branch-school</link><category/><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Abandoned Oshiba Settlement 押場集落</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Oshiba Village or Oshiba Settlement was one of the smaller villages in Toga Valley. It was small enough and close enough to another village that I don't think anyone considered in an actual village. Thus, it was given the designation of shuraku &lt;span class='ja'&gt;集落&lt;/span&gt; instead of mura &lt;span class='ja'&gt;村&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At its height, it seems like there were 10 homes clustered together with 100 people liviing there. This was during the Meiji period. In the year 2000, no one was registered as living here. Japanese Blogger Akirango visited &lt;a href="https://akiranngo.hateblo.jp/entry/2020/05/16/193121" title="https://akiranngo.hateblo.jp/entry/2020/05/16/193121"&gt;the area in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and did a lot of research on the old village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he visited in 2020, there were apparently several homes in the area. Most of them had been completely abandoned and several had collapsed or were on the brink of collapsing. He noted that one home looked like some folks still returned every now and then to check on it. &lt;a href="http://www.aikis.or.jp/~kage-kan/16.Toyama/Toga_Oshiba.html" title="http://www.aikis.or.jp/~kage-kan/16.Toyama/Toga_Oshiba.html"&gt;Mr. Murakage&lt;/a&gt; also visited the village in 2011. His page shows the population of the village since 1872 (Meiji 5).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1769.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1769.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1769_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1769_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1769_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days, anyone who still owned land in Oshiba must've died or sold it to the government because the construction companies have moved in and begun cutting down the forest surrounding the village. Google Maps doesn't show any of this, but it's using satellite images from May 2024. So all this deforestation happened last summer or this summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, looking on Google Map, the road leading to the village has had some changes in the last year, too. The village road branches off from Route 471 leading to the center of Toga Village. Near the crossing, the road had been taken out by a landslide, and construction crews have been building a new support bridge going from the main road down to the village area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, maybe they started cutting down trees last year, and the road was taken out over winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1726.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1726.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1726_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1726_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1726_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most important construction related projects in the area is the Toga Dam. Apparently, they've been working on this dam for almost 20 years. Looking looking at various old posts of people exploring the villages and schools in the area, looking through Google Maps, and also going there, it seems they area is full of construction from summer to fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open areas have temporary dorms set up for workers. The road-side stop &lt;span class='ja'&gt;道の駅&lt;/span&gt; further north on 471 had several billboards targetted at workers. It says how to avoid heatstroke while working in summer, and how it's okay to stop working if you feel too hot. The occasional truck or marked cars are parked along Route 471, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems like they could be clearing the forest for something related to the dam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1761.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1761.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1761_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1761_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1761_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While all the homes seemed to have been removed, the Shinmei Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;神明宮&lt;/span&gt; was still there, left untouched for now. Shinmei Shrines are Shinto shrines devoted to Amaterasu, the goddess of the sun. In Japanese mythology, Amaterasu was responsible for the origin of agriculture in Japan, so Amaterasu is widely worshipped in areas were agriculture was important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his post, Akirango wondered what the shrine would say about the history of its village, both the rise and the fall. I don't think anyone would have considered Oshiba a vibrant village. But even so, I suppose the shrine would have gotten lonely with its residents slowly moving away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nearby &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/kitamamedani-branch-school" title="https://theschlock.com/kitamamedani-branch-school"&gt;Kitamamedani Branch School&lt;/a&gt; used to have a winter branch school in Oshiba. It's full title was Toga Elementary Kitamamedani Branch School - Oshiba Winter Branch School &lt;span class='ja'&gt;利賀小学校北豆谷分校押場冬季分校&lt;/span&gt;. It opened in 1930 (Showa 2) and closed in 1968 (Showa 43), which is also when the Kitamamedani branch school closed. In 1943, it apparently had 11 students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would the shrine feel sad that children were no longer around? Or happy that they've found a more lucrative life elsewhere? Would the shrine feel sad that the remains of the town had been removed? Or happy that the area had become lively again with activity?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1744.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1744.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1744_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1744_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_15_oshiba/IMG_1744_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The outside of the shrine looked like it was pretty well intact. However, the inside didn't look so great. Much of the walls showed signs of termites. Ceiling boards looked like they were peeling and melting away. With absolutely no one in the area now returning, the shrine doesn't seem like it's going to survive many more winters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The was a painting of Nagoya Castle on the wall. There were also samurai horse paintings on the wall facing outwards. These are pretty similar to &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/ema-paintings" title="https://theschlock.com/ema-paintings"&gt;Ema Paintings&lt;/a&gt; in Hida. By facing outwards, the luck and protection is extended to the people and happenings outside of the building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually (probably in the not so distant future), the shrine will be gone and very little trace of the Oshiba settlement will remain. Only the photos and stories of those who've been here.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 05:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-oshiba-settlement</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-oshiba-settlement</link><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Kamimomose Branch School 上百瀬分校</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Kamimomose neighborhood is along the upper areas of the Momose River, the eastern river of the twin Toga Valleys. The single road in town follows the river up into the mountains, going around Mt. Kongodo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金剛堂山&lt;/span&gt;, and coming into Miyagawa, Gifu, on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current neighborhood on Kamimomose seems pretty vibrant enough these days, which several self-help facilities and performance arts camps. Many of the homes look pretty modern and maintained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up until a few years ago, the building of the former branch school was still standing in town. This was the Toga Elementary Kamimomose Branch School &lt;span class='ja'&gt;利賀小学校上百瀬分校&lt;/span&gt;. Like many of the other branch schools in the area, it was probably still in use until 1996, and then closed for good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The building still stood for 25 years, but no one maintained it, so it began falling apart and became a health hazard because of asbestos. Looking through Google Maps and Google Earth, it was demolished sometime between November 2021 and October 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_11_kamimomose/IMG_1569.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_11_kamimomose/IMG_1569.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_11_kamimomose/IMG_1569_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_11_kamimomose/IMG_1569_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_11_kamimomose/IMG_1569_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the gymansium still stands, but it has been completely gutted. Even before the main building was demolished, &lt;a href="https://ameblo.jp/hiho-haiko/entry-11934259064.html" title="https://ameblo.jp/hiho-haiko/entry-11934259064.html"&gt;Haiko Rider&lt;/a&gt; reported that a local construction company had been using the gym for storage. Now with the building gone, it has become the perfect open garage to store their larger equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the main building was demolished, it seems like they repaired and reenforced the roof. The old Google Maps show it is red. But, today, it's a reflective black surface. Sometimes it looks blue because of the sky's reflection.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 04:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/kamimomose-branch-school</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/kamimomose-branch-school</link><category/><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Tanoshima Shinmei Shrine 田ノ島神明宮</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Tanoshima Shinmei Shrine is all that remains of Tanoshima Village. The site of the village is along the Toga River going south up the mountain from Sakaue village. It's between the villages of Abetto and Taikanba.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A branch school was opened in the village for its children. In 1959, there were 16 students. But the school was closed 6 years later. Perhaps this was because many of the younger families moved away or because a bus service could be established between the village in Sakaue village nearby. The concrete branch schools in the area were built in the 1970s, so this building would've been made out of wood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, &lt;a href="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=134" title="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=134"&gt;Hayaneko&lt;/a&gt; visited the village and only 2 houses remained, with one of the houses actually being lived in. Today, all traces of those homes have been removed for some kind of fancy French restaurant and rental cabins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1353.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1353.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1353_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1353_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1353_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking in, it reminded me a lot of the restaurant from The Menu. Apparently meals are more than 10000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; a plate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The side road continues past the restaurant into the forest, and eventually ends with the forest engulfing the road. I wasn't paying attention to the map, so I didn't realize that I went past the shrine quite a while ago. Going back to the restaurant, the shrine is located up on the hill behind the area. You can see it from the road peering through the trees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1351.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1351.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1351_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1351_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_08_tanoshima/IMG_1351_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shinmei Shrines &lt;span class='ja'&gt;神明宮&lt;/span&gt; are Shinto shrines devoted to Amaterasu, the goddess of the sun. In Japanese mythology, Amaterasu was responsible for the origin of agriculture in Japan, so Amaterasu is widely worshipped in areas were agriculture is most important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout Toga Valley and many rural areas, it's pretty easy to find Shinmei Shrines, as their yearly festivals pray to the gods for an abundant harvest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With no one left in the village, I'm not really sure who maintains this shrine. Inside the shrine, a plaque showing the names of all the Shinto priests lies on its side, and hasn't been updated in years. Perhaps the folks running the restaurant keep up the old rituals.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/tanoshima-shinmei-shrine</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/tanoshima-shinmei-shrine</link><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Senzoku Branch School 千束分校</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Senzoku Branch School is a remote school further up the mountains in the Toga Valley. It was built in 1970 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;昭和&lt;/span&gt;45 to service the 54 students living in Taikanba Village. Originally, it was named Toga Elementary Taikanba Branch School &lt;span class='ja'&gt;利賀小学校大勘場分校&lt;/span&gt;. Later, after some school shuffling, it was renamed to Sakagami Elementary Senzoku Branch School &lt;span class='ja'&gt;坂上小学校千束分校&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By 1975, there were only 31 students. By 1984 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;昭和&lt;/span&gt;59, the school was no longer regularly used, and in 1996 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平成&lt;/span&gt;8, it was closed completely. According to &lt;a href="http://heyaneko.web.fc2.com/zs24.html" title="http://heyaneko.web.fc2.com/zs24.html"&gt;Heyaneko&lt;/a&gt;, who visited the location in 2011, there was a personalized mailbox, indicating that someone was living there. &lt;a href="https://ameblo.jp/hiho-haiko/entry-11934259064.html" title="https://ameblo.jp/hiho-haiko/entry-11934259064.html"&gt;Haiko Rider&lt;/a&gt; visited the location in 2014 and posts that a construction company was using the location for storage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_07_senzoku/IMG_1277.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_07_senzoku/IMG_1277.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_07_senzoku/IMG_1277_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_07_senzoku/IMG_1277_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_07_senzoku/IMG_1277_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the building is no longer there. Google Maps shows the building was still there in November 2021. But, by October 2023, it was demolished. All of these Toga branch schools were built in the same way using a lot of asbestos. With no one maintaining them, they became an incredible health risk, and had to be demolished.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/senzoku-branch-school</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/senzoku-branch-school</link><category/><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Taira Postal Corps Monument 郵送隊之碑</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When I explored Hosoo Pass &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠&lt;/span&gt; in early June this year, I learned about how the mountain pass was a pivotal connection point of the mountain villages of southwest Toyama to the urban areas of the north. One important part of this history was the postal service. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until 1970, especially in the winter, because of the large amounts of winter mountain snow, mail was still carried by hand. Carriers of Johana Town would bring the mail to the Hosoo Postal Exchange where they would meet carriers from Taira Village. Both teams left at 9am and met around 1pm. They would exchange their packages and letters. Then, they'd go back down the mountain to their post offices. These folks were known as the Postal Corps &lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins"&gt;Hosoo Pass Postal Exchange Office&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠郵便交換所&lt;/span&gt; was one of the places I visited when I explored Hosoo Pass. I went there on June 3rd. It turns out that just a days prior on May 31st, they held a dedication ceremony for the creation of a monument devoted to the Taira Postal Corps in Taira Village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0982.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0982.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0982_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0982_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0982_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monument details the history of the Postal Corps and includes 3 photos taken in the 1960s. There are a few individual credits on the back of the monument. The &lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊之碑&lt;/span&gt; calligraphy was done by Fumio Yamamoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山本文雄&lt;/span&gt;. And the 3 photos were taken by Toshio Takada &lt;span class='ja'&gt;高田&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;俊夫&lt;/span&gt;, Shinobu Soga &lt;span class='ja'&gt;曽我忍&lt;/span&gt;, and Tsutomu Takada &lt;span class='ja'&gt;高田勉&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The May 31st ceremoney was held by the mayor, the chairs of the commeration committee, and Shinobu Soga, one of the men who took a photo of the Postal Corps. The Yomiuri Newspaper wrote &lt;a href="https://www.yomiuri.co.jp/local/toyama/news/20250612-OYTNT50193/" title="https://www.yomiuri.co.jp/local/toyama/news/20250612-OYTNT50193/"&gt;an article about it&lt;/a&gt;. In the article, it mentions how Soga was a location scout for a film studio in Kyoto and came to Gokayama looking for locations. He learned of the Postal Corps and wanted to travel with them and learn more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, he could get some amazing unique photos of the team. Of the three photos on the monument, I think this one was his.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0987.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0987.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0987_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0987_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0987_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0988.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0988.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0988_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0988_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0988_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the other photos shows the Hosoo Pass Postal Exchange Office in the 60s in winter. Having been there a few weeks prior, they apparently made an addition to the building sometime in the 60s. The plaque in the Postal Exchange Office mentioned that mail increased significantly in the 60s because of economic reform. The Postal Corps chain would somtimes include up to 30 members. So, I suppose they needed the extra space for the package exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-postal-exchange-ruins-information" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-postal-exchange-ruins-information"&gt;transcription and translation&lt;/a&gt; of the plaque at the Postal Exchange office in the woods in the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8215.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8215.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8215_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8215_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8215_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plaque on the monument gives a brief history of the Postal Corps. Here's a transcription and translation of the contents:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;かって、冬期間積雪により交通機関が断され&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;陸の孤島と化していた越中五箇山の人々に&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;文化の火をもたらす役割を果たたのが&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵便遞送隊&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class='ja'&gt;通称&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;span class='ja'&gt;でした。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;当時、平・城端両郵便局では請負人を雇用隊を編成して標高七四〇&lt;/span&gt;m&lt;span class='ja'&gt;の細尾峠近くに設けられた郵便交換所まで背負って運び渡していました。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Postal Transport Corps (commonly known as the Postal Corps) played a role in bringing a firey culture to the people of Etchu Gokayama, who were once isolated village islands in the winter when transportation was cut off due to snowfall. At that time, the Taira and Johana Post Offices organized contractors into teams to carry mail on their backs to the postal exchange office located near Hosoo Pass, 740 meters above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;明治十五年下梨郵便局&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class='ja'&gt;現平局&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;span class='ja'&gt;開設されて以来、城端局と片道約二〇&lt;/span&gt;km&lt;span class='ja'&gt;の峠山道を徒歩で往復していました。昭和十年長い間続いた直送を廃し、両局の中程に位置する細尾峠で郵袋を交換する方法なりました。その後、バスの開通に伴い通常期はバス託送に改め、昭和三十年から請負による交換便は冬期に限られることになりました。深雪・吹雪の中隊員苦労は想像を絶するものでした。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Shimonashi Post Office (now Taira Post Office) was opened in 1882, mail was sent back and forth between Johana Post Office on foot along the mountain pass, about 20km one-way**. In 1935, the long-running direct delivery system was discontinued, as the method of mail exchange was changed to bus delivery at Hosoo Pass, located between the two offices. After that, the normal period was changed to bus delivery, and from 1955, the contracted exchange service was limited to winter. The hardships faced by the members of the Postal Corps in the deep snow and blizzards were unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(**note: The monument says one-way, but it's only 10 km one-way. It's 20 km round trip.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;時代と共に、請負人の雇用難・雪崩危険等に鑑み、昭和四十五年八十八年間に渡る郵送隊のの歴史を閉じました。その後冬期は庄川の船便等を利用する輸送となり昭和五十九年&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class='ja'&gt;国道三〇四号線に五箇山トンネルが開通したことにより、専用自動車便が通年運行され、現在に至っています。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As times changed, the Postal Corps came to an end after 88 years of operation in 1970, due to the difficulty of finding contractors and the risk of avalanches. After that, transportation in the winter was changed to ship services on the Shogawa River. In 1984, the Gokayama Tunnel was opened on National Route 304, and dedicated automobile services began to operate year-round, which continues to this day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊の大きな功績は&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Great Achievements of the Postal Corps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;・厳冬の雪深い峠道を人力で郵便物&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class='ja'&gt;生活必需品&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;span class='ja'&gt;を運び地域住民の暮らしを支えた。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- They carried mail (a daily necessity) by hand through snowy mountain passes in the harsh winter, supporting the lives of local residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;・隊員の大半は主婦で女性の忍耐と献身性が特筆される。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Most of the members were housewives, and the perserverance and dedication of women is particulary noteworthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;・郵便局では&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;地域への奉仕・貢献の原点として語り継がれている。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- At the post office, it is passed down as the origin of service and contribution to the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;ここにその功績を称え&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;史実を後世に伝えるものです。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here, we commemorate their achievements and pass on the historical facts to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;令和七年五月&lt;/span&gt; - May 2025&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊を称える会&lt;/span&gt; - The Postal Corps Commemoration Committee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0996.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0996.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0996_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0996_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_0996_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monument is a great way of commemorating such a unique service in the area. But, the monument is a little sad. They placed the monument at the location of the original Shimonashi Post Office from 50 years ago, but that building has moved since then. Now, there's only houses and an open field next to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current Taira Post Office is just down the street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_1031.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_1031.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_1031_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_1031_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_04_postal/IMG_1031_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it's a pretty amazing coincidence that I started exploring and researching about this stuff at the same time this monument was created. Many of these remote rural areas of Japan have their own unique stories, and many of those stories have been immortalized on monuments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 03:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/postal-corps-monument</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/postal-corps-monument</link><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category><category/></item><item><title>Miune Branch School 三嶺分校</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This school's full name was the Taira Village Municipal Shimonashi Elementary Miune Branch School, or &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平村立下梨小学校三嶺分校&lt;/span&gt;. At the time of its construction, there were two major elementary schools in the municipality of Taira Village, Shimonashi Elementary and Higashi Nakae Elementary. However, each one had plenty of branch schools that served as the students' actual day-to-day school. Students probably only went to the main school for the entrance ceremony and graduation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure when it opened, but it was closed in 1962 and all students went to Shimonashi Elementary. The branch school is located in the Kogurusu neighborhood &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小来栖&lt;/span&gt; directly north of downtown Shimonashi Village where Shimonashi Elementary was located. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days its only a 5 minute drive, so it seems somewhat frivolous to have created a school so close. However, travel in Japan prior to the 60s was not so easy. The neighborhood is a somewhat decent climb from Shimonashi, and far too dangerous for a child to make the hike in winter. The village probably didn't have busses until the 1960s, so building a small school was easier. Even in Kogurusu, neighboring houses are at a pretty steep incline, so walking to school was still a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0890.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0890.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0890_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0890_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0890_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The school was featured in Toyama Prefecture's series showcasing the &lt;a href="https://www.tkc.pref.toyama.jp/video/eizou/detail.aspx?record_id=1801" title="https://www.tkc.pref.toyama.jp/video/eizou/detail.aspx?record_id=1801"&gt;wooden schools&lt;/a&gt; of the past, and the old wooden building still exists today. It has been used pretty frequently as a community center for those living in the neighborhood since its closure as a school. Inside, in the entrance, are some commerative photos taken at neighborhood events. The most recent one was from 2016 for the Kogurusu Summer Festival &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小来栖の夏祭り&lt;/span&gt;. The was the most recent thing I found inside the building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The building is pretty small with only a few rooms on the first and second floors. The first room on the first floor was an open room with some tables and some other equipment. The room further back on the ground floor was also used for storage, however the floor had been eroded away leaving the dirt exposed. Going inside, bats started flying around the ceiling, so I didn't stay inside for long. I think this may have been the living quarters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0952.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0952.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0952_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0952_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0952_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upstairs was a much larger open room. Half of the room had Tatami, and the other half had the equipment used for their summer festival. On the wall near the doors, were some awards. In 1990 (Heisei 2), Taira Village apparently held a competition for morning exercises among the farming community. The Hanahikara (?) group &lt;span class='ja'&gt;はなひからの部&lt;/span&gt; got first place, and their award was on the wall. The Koshihikari group &lt;span class='ja'&gt;コシヒカリの部&lt;/span&gt; (koshihikari is a kind of rice) got second place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0946_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0946_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0946_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0946_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_0946_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the wall facing the tatami mats was the Taira Village Town Charter &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平村民憲章&lt;/span&gt;. It reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;わたくしにちは、五筒の美しい自然と香り高い文化遺産の伝承に誇りと責任ともち活力ある平村をめざしてこの憲章と定新ます。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We take pride in and responsibility for the beautiful nature of Gokayama, the fragrant cultural heritage of our village, and set out to create a vibrant village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;一、おたがいに信じあい励ましあって、住みよい村とつくります。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;First, we will trust and encourage each other to create a pleasant village to live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;二、きびしい自然にうちから生産につとめて、豊かな村をつくります&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Second, we will endevor to continue production in the harsh natural environment to create a rich village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;三、伝統を生かし文化と育てて、うるわしい村とつくります。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Third, we will make use of traditions and foster culture to create a beautiful village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;四、感謝の心をもち家族助けあって、むつまじい家とつくります&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fourth, we will be grateful and help each other as family members to create a harmonious community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;五、からだときにえ教養と高めて、たくましい人になります。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Five, we will improve our physical and cultural abilities to become strong people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of the outer areas of Taira have been vacated from depopulation, the downtown area of Taira and the communities along the river still feel very vibrant. While driving around, I saw several tourists visiting the old Gasshou homes and going in and out of local stores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, times continue to change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_1015.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_1015.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_1015_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_1015_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_03_kogurusu/IMG_1015_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As transportation became stronger, and as more people moved away to cities, more and more branch schools closed and the students could join the main elementaries. By the 1990s, Taira village only had two elementary schools: Higashi Nakae Elementary School and Shimonashi Elementary School. In 1999, Higashi Nakae ES closed and students now attended Shimonashi, but it with the combination, the school was renamed to Taira Elementary School.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2004, Japan issued widespread municipal mergers across all the rurals areas of the country. The three separate Gokayama municipalities of Taira, Toga, and Kamitaira combined with five other villages to the west and north to create Nanto City. In 2006, Taira Elementary was closed and students traveled further down the road to Kamitaira Elementary. Perhaps as a trade-off, students of Kamitaira came to Taira for junior high school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The old Taira Elementary School was turned into government offices, many of which focused on research for ground water and hydro electricity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, the building has been completely demolished. Now it serves as an emergency port for helicopter landings if any citizens need to extremely fast transport to a hospital in the city up north. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/miune-branch-school</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/miune-branch-school</link><category/><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Abandoned Nashitani Village 梨谷村</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Located in a small valley between the two major mountain passes of travel connecting the urban areas of Tonami &lt;span class='ja'&gt;砺波町&lt;/span&gt; and Johana Town &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城端町&lt;/span&gt; to the large village of Shimonashi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;下梨村&lt;/span&gt; (modern day Taira &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平村&lt;/span&gt;), was the village of Nashitani &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷村&lt;/span&gt;. Today, what remains of the village is slightly hidden behind the Taira Ski Resort and Restaurant Maple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several houses in the village still standing, and some of the homes seem like they've had some recently maintenance work done of them. According to some online research done by &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-nashitani.html" title="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-nashitani.html"&gt;Mr. Murakage&lt;/a&gt;, there were people living in some homes until 1982. Although, even though it doesn't seem like anyone is living here today, the families still come back to check on the houses. He and &lt;a href="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=123" title="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=123"&gt;Hayaneko&lt;/a&gt; visited in 2011 and found no one there, and neither did I during my visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0539.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0539.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0539_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0539_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0539_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When parking at the Taira Ski Resort, you can see the village poking through the area behind Restaurant Maple. The restaurant seems like its open every day to cater to the construction workers up in the mountains doing whatever work they do. I arrived before the opening time, and the people working at the restaurant were preparing for the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road to the village loops behind the restaurant and goes up the hill. You walk past a grave and some monuments. The monuments were too withered away to fully understand them. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0551.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0551.jpg"&gt;The grave&lt;/a&gt; was marked as Hotouge Family &lt;span class='ja'&gt;朴峠家&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-nashitani.html" title="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-nashitani.html"&gt;Murakage-san&lt;/a&gt; was able to research the names of the 28 homes that used to be in the village, and he listed them on his page. The Hotouge Family apparently moved to Osaka in the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0554.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0554.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0554_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0554_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0554_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still standing in the main area of the village were three homes, and a few sheds and garages. The first home was owned by the Yamazaki Family &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山崎家&lt;/span&gt;. The next home was owned by the Higashi Family &lt;span class='ja'&gt;東家&lt;/span&gt;. The Higashi Family had &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0742.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0742.jpg"&gt;a grave&lt;/a&gt; behind their house, but there was no Yamazaki grave. There was a foundation for a small building behind there, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the homes in the area had their windows boarded up, and occasionally some extra supports along the outsides. This was mainly to prevent any structural or internal damage happening from excessive snow and snow melt in the winter. As such, the only access to the homes were the front doors, which were all locked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was one more home in this small neighborhood cluster. Rather than wooden supports and protection, it was covered in aluminum siding, which was probably installed in the last 20 years. The whole home seemed like it was perfectly preserved inside its metal shell. Out back, there was a family grave, but I don't remember the name. Guessing, but it was probably for the Tsujimoto Family &lt;span class='ja'&gt;辻本家&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0763_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0763_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0763_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0763_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0763_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the middle of this neighborhood cluster was the village's temple. The door was open, so I went. It seemed like it was pretty well taken care of for a building that was over 100 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The temple included a shrine behind the folding walls, but covering the inside walls of the temple were names and names and names of everyone who was a member of the shrine. Every little bit of upper wall space was covered in thin wooden planks, each denoting a single person's membership. The planks didn't have any dates, but according to Murakage's page, the history of the village went back further than the  Meiji period. Many of the names matched Murakage's listing of famliies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0775.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0775.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0775_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0775_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0775_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking through my photos, this white plaque was the most recent, dated Heisei 10 or 1997 &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平成十年吉日&lt;/span&gt;. The title says &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷村道場修繕工事一式&lt;/span&gt;, which seems to translate as Nashitani Village Dojo Repair Work All Members. And then it lists 66 members, and an additional 3 executive members &lt;span class='ja'&gt;実行委員&lt;/span&gt;. The 3 executive members are Nakai &lt;span class='ja'&gt;中井&lt;/span&gt;, Yamazaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山崎&lt;/span&gt;, and Arai &lt;span class='ja'&gt;荒井&lt;/span&gt;. In fact, there are many planks throughout the temple (or dojo?) of the Yamazaki family. Maybe their family were the mayors of the village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, so far, we've seen the Yamazaki Home, Higashi Home, village Temple or Dojo, and Tsujimoto Home. Behind the Tsujimoto home were storage building that were half torn apart and perhaps a few more winters away from complete collapse. The road continued past this cluster, which revealed the Nakai Home &lt;span class='ja'&gt;中井家&lt;/span&gt;  on the bend of the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0839.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0839.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0839_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0839_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0839_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a walkway going past the Nakai Home into some farm fields and a storage shed was some equipment that was probably still used 10 years ago. Next to the storage shed was the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0858.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0858.jpg"&gt;family grave&lt;/a&gt; for the Uji Family &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宇治家&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This small area felt very classic country, like the Shire in Lord of the Rings. A wavy stone path with a stone wall connecting homes to homes with circular plots of fields for whatever they grew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0860.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0860.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0860_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0860_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0860_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning to the Nakai Home, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0846.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0846.jpg"&gt;their family grave&lt;/a&gt; was out front, too. It's important to note that all of these graves were very clean, recognizable, and had recent flowers placed on them. It would seem like these families, whether the original residents are still alive living elsewhere or their descendants, still return here after winter to maintain the houses and the graves. Actually, a whole field of grass near the Nakai home showed signs of it being mowed in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nashitani Village is abandoned in that no one lives here, but it's not so abandoned that people haven't forgotten about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0874.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0874.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0874_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0874_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0874_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, the final home in the area, the Kuribayashi Home &lt;span class='ja'&gt;栗林&lt;/span&gt;, had quite a lot of recent repair work done on the front, including a new door with its &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0876.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0876.jpg"&gt;wrapping&lt;/a&gt; still on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murakage's page again lists all the families living in the village since the Meiji period, and only 5 families were still living in Nashitani by 1982 (Showa 57). Those 5 families were Yamazaki, Higashi, Tsujimoto, Arai, and Nakai. The Arai family married into the Yamazaki family. There was also the maintained grave for the Uji family. They apparently only moved to Johana, a mere 10km away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Kuribayashi family, though... Murakage lists them as having moved to either Kyoto or Hokkaido in the 60s. I wonder who fixed up their home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0743.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0743.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0743_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0743_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0743_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those 5 main homes and the temple, plus a garage and a few other storage buildings were all that I could find in the area. Apparently, there's another home further up the Nashitani river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murakage-san visited Nashitani with another abandoned village researcher named &lt;a href="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=123" title="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=123"&gt;Hayaneko&lt;/a&gt;. He does a lot of research on these villages by looking up old schools, specifically branch schools. Branch schools are extensions of the main school in the area that cater specifically to the residents of remote villages. It's often too far and too dangerous to have the kids travel to school each day, so a local school would be built and a teacher would live at the school during the week or sometimes for the whole winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Out here, the school was named Taira Village Shimonashi Elementary School - Nashitani Branch School &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平村立下梨小学校梨谷分校&lt;/span&gt;. According to his research, the school was classified as a Grade 3 Remote School and had 24 students in 1959 (Showa 34). It was apparently built in 1902 (Meiji 35). According ot Wikipedia, the branch school was officially closed in 1971. Apparently it was turned into a community center after it closed, but there doesn't seem to be any trace of it left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any elementary students left in the area went to Shimonashi Elementary School directly after the branch school closed, which became much easier with the completion of the Nashitani Tunnel in 1973. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later in 1999, the two elementary schools in the area, Shimonashi Elementary and Higashi Nakae Elementary both closed when Taira Elementary School was established. Not much later, in 2004 during the phase of rural municipal mergers across Japan, the whole southwestern area of Toyama became Nanto City. In 2006, elementary school students now went to Kamitaira Elementary School,  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0797.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0797.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0797_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0797_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0797_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel like the graves and the temple are the most interesting part of this village. According to Google Maps, the name of the temple of the Nashitani Nembutsu Dojo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷念仏道場&lt;/span&gt;. Apparently, Nembutsu is a specific sect of Buddhist spread a priest named Rennyo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;蓮如上人&lt;/span&gt; who lived in the Gokayama mountains. He began preaching about Joho Shinshu during the Muromachi period and gained many followers in the mountains and in Nanto and Johana Towns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Edo Period, he was able to build temples in many of the small mountain villages for the locals to practice the religion. The temples were apparently unique in that they were as large as a normal homes, and priests could live in them. Looking back through some names, the priest of Nashitani may have been named Anchi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;安地&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each one of the graves are nearly identical with the exception of the famliy's name. The top reads &lt;span class='ja'&gt;南無阿弥陀佛&lt;/span&gt; or Namuamida Hotoke. Namuamida is Buddha. Hotoke, I think, means statue or monument. Maybe it doesn't mean grave after all...  But, I think these monuments were still erected to pay respects to the families of the past 200 years. Weird that I never saw the Yamazaki one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0548.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0548.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0548_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0548_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_02_nashitani/IMG_0548_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it does feel like the many pockets of society dotted throughout the Gokayama mountains have been slowly reclaimed by nature, I'm actually surprised how much information I could find out about this one. If I did more research, I wonder if I could find out more about the people who lived here, and what their modern-age descendants might be doing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village</link><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Abandoned Ueda Village 上田村</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Old Ueda Village used to be a key destination on the old Gokayama Highway, leaving the urban area of Tonami City &lt;span class='ja'&gt;砺波町&lt;/span&gt; and Johana Town &lt;span class='ja'&gt;城端町&lt;/span&gt; and going up into the southwestern mountains of Toyama prefecture. After Ueda Village, there was nothing but the road, the trees, and the climb. Many of the residents made their living catering to these travelers, or by working as porters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the first mountain was &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins"&gt;Hosoo Pass &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which I wrote about before. The Hosoo Pass and the area is well known for its Postal Corps, a group of housewives and local people employed by the postal service who would cross the mountain every day during winter to deliver the mail. When descending from the pass from the other side, you'd reach &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village" title="https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village"&gt;Nashitani Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷村&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and then after going over Ose Pass, you'd reach Taira Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平村&lt;/span&gt; and Shinonashi Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;下梨村&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the war, Japan began to rebuild and became an economic icon. They invested a lot of money into infrastructure, making many of the remote areas more accessible. The Gokayama Highway became Route 304, and as transportation also became stronger, fewer and fewer people were stopping at Ueda before going up the mountain. In 1970, a new Route 304 was established, and now no one traveled through Ueda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1973, the remaining residents of the Ueda Village all moved away together to the Rikyu area of Johana Town, leaving what was left of their homes to be reclaimed by the forest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2009, a monument was erected in remembrance of the old village. I put a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/ueda-village-translation" title="https://theschlock.com/ueda-village-translation"&gt;transcription and translation&lt;/a&gt; of that monument in another post, so you can view the information directly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0425.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0425.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0425_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0425_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0425_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monument details the history of the village with its credits listed on the back of the monument. On the larger stone monument, a town map has been enshrined. It lists 35 households from 1945 (Showa 20). From research done &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-ueda.html" title="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-ueda.html"&gt;Mr. Murakage on his site&lt;/a&gt;, Ueda village had 30 homes with 174 people in 1872. The number of homes may have peaked in 1930 with 42 homes. As mentioned above, it was 35 homes in 1945. Murakage says 22 homes in 1946. And only 8 homes in 1948.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently when Murakage and Hayaneko visited the area in 2011, there were still some wooden remains of a few houses. Today, I couldn't any trace of homes other than some stone foundations and a few bridges that crossed the steam and went no where.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0418.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0418.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0418_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0418_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0418_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at the town map again, there are a lot of side roads branching off of old Route 304. The map shows a shrine off in a direction, so I wondered if there were still any traces of that left. Usually people still attend to shrines long after the area is desserted. (Of course, I wasn't able to sight-read the monument, so I didn't know the shrine had folded and its diety moved into town.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Across the street from the monument, it did look like there was a path leading into the forest. It was heavily overgrown, but my legs were completely wrapped up and I had my work gloves. I could power through it if the path continued to be noticeable enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0476.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0476.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0476_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0476_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0476_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tearing through vines and overgrowth wasn't that bad, and the path continued to lead to a raised clearing which must've been a foundation for a home. So, I figured that I must have been going the right way. Although, looking at the map, it was clearly not. The path to the shrine went up a bit, so I continued up, but the ground was too muddy and unstable. I stepped on the ground, and my foot sunk into a mud hole. Meh, I'm going back. It's probably better to try and run through the woods in fall after the growth has died down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got back in my car and continued driving south going up the mountain. Along the road were several dumping pits for concrete rubble. Further up the road was a construction site for machinery milling out parts of the mountain to create concrete and concrete blocks used for road construction and such.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road twisted back on itself and sharply shot up the mountain to reach the current Route 304.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0526_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0526_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0526_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0526_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0526_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the junction, you could look back down and see just how thick the forests were after so much rain and sun in May and June. Way up in the left corner of that photo, you can see &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins"&gt;Hosoo Pass &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the ultimate destination of all the porters who lived in Ueda Village when they transported things to Gokayama. By continuing up the new Route 304 (new as of 1970), you'll reach the destination of the porters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0378.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0378.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0378_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0378_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0378_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, finding the Ueda (Futatsuya) Village monument took a little bit of research. I had found those webpages of &lt;a href="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=122" title="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=122"&gt;Hayaneko&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-ueda.html" title="https://theschlock.com/pages/murakage-ueda.html"&gt;Mr. Murakage&lt;/a&gt; going to the village in 2011, but it's not marked on the map, and both reports don't actually say where it is. I had a general idea where it was, though, given the location of Hosoo Pass. And just north of Hosoo Pass was Futatsuya River following north into Johana. It had to be along there, but I didn't really have confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I was really looking for was the first image in &lt;a href="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=122" title="https://heyaneko.jugem.jp/?eid=122"&gt;Hayaneko's Post&lt;/a&gt;. There was an old road sign pointing to Ueda two kilometers ahead. This had to be somewhere in southern Johana. I poked around a lot Google Map Street View, and I finally found it. This is at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@36.4842751,136.8923234,20z" title="https://www.google.com/maps/@36.4842751,136.8923234,20z"&gt;36°29'03.5"N 136°53'32.4"E&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/google-maps-2025-06-05.png" title="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/google-maps-2025-06-05.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosoo/google-maps-2025-06-05.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosoo/google-maps-2025-06-05.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosoo/google-maps-2025-06-05.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Street View had an entry for 2021 and 2012, both of which had the sign removed from its posts. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0388.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0388.jpg"/&gt;When I arrived at the location&lt;/a&gt;, the posts were no longer in the ground. There was some debris nearby, some piles of loose lumber, possibly from a demolished shed. I found &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0369.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0369.jpg"&gt;an old bus stop sign&lt;/a&gt; partially buried in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the way back to my car, I looked over at the shed with metal siding and saw the sign, continuing to rust and decay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0385.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0385.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0385_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0385_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250628_01_ueda/IMG_0385_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gifu was still visible, but both towns of Ueda &lt;span class='ja'&gt;上田&lt;/span&gt; and Shimonashi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;下梨&lt;/span&gt; had decayed. Interesting that those two of the three had been abandoned and decayed themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After going through Ueda village and back up the mountain, my next location was another abandoned village, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village" title="https://theschlock.com/abandoned-nashitani-village"&gt;Nashitani Village &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷村&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Shimonashi was the main village along river, and Nashitani was futher up the mountain between Ose Pass and Hosoo Pass.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-ueda-village</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/abandoned-ueda-village</link><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Iiyama Temple 飯山寺</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Iiyama Temple is a small yet somewhat fabled temple on the outskirts of the downtown area of Takayama. It's now all that remains of the Iiyama family and castle, which was said to be a psuedonymn of Asahina Saburou &lt;span class='ja'&gt;朝比奈三郎&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to the area because I was looking around at locations of castle ruins in Takayama. I had never noticed this before, nor really knew anything about it. Also, Google Maps didn't even have a road going to it, so it seems like an interesting place to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To reach the temple, there's an unremarkable unpaved side road that goes up a hill through some farms. The farmland is still being used, so some rice planting equipment was on the side of the road. The narrow roads winds up the hill as most side roads do, and the forest opens up to reveal the temple and a rather large garden with some old folks doing their various gardening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0213.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0213.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0213_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0213_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0213_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being the height of June, all the plants and grass have grown to take over much of the area. There were several historical plaques posted near the temple with each more recent plaque having more detailed information of the history and significance of the temple. I made a separate post with full &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/iiyama-temple-translations" title="https://theschlock.com/iiyama-temple-translations"&gt;transcriptions and translations&lt;/a&gt; of those plaques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legend of the temple begins with Asahina Saburou, a legend of Japanese folklore. After his defeat in the Heiji Rebellion, he apparently fled to Hida and lived in hiding by changing his name to Iiyama. At this location, at the foot of the mountain, he built his castle and estate. Although, the plaque says that the rebellion was in 1159, but Wikipedia says Asahina was born in 1176, so who knows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After building his estate, he ultimately came into possession of a statue of the eleven-headed Kannon. He built a hall within his estate to house and display the statue. This hall was named Reishoin &lt;span class='ja'&gt;霊松院&lt;/span&gt;. The hall was later refashioned into a temple in 1339 for the statue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, Miki Yoritsuna (1540-1587) invaded Hida and burned down Iiyama's castle and estate, along with the temple. Miki built &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/matsukura-castle-harayama" title="https://theschlock.com/matsukura-castle-harayama"&gt;Matsukura Castle&lt;/a&gt; on the top of that mountain to defend the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0257_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0257_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0257_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0257_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0257_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the Kanamori Clan swept through Hida and conquered it, Kanamori &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森長近&lt;/span&gt; ordered a Shingon monk to rebuild the temple at its current location, which was said to be where Iiyama Castle and estate once stood. The temple was renamed Toukouzan Iiyama Temple &lt;span class='ja'&gt;東向山飯山寺&lt;/span&gt;. This was in 1604.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Edo Period, with Tokugawa Shogunate in full control of Japan, a priest named Genkai &lt;span class='ja'&gt;玄海&lt;/span&gt; began the revival of state sanctioned Buddhism. He moved to Takayama and lived in Iiyama Temple as he helped rebuild and shape Kokubunji Temple downtown. He also rebuilt Ichinomiya Shrine to the south. The Buddhism revival attracted many lords and people, so the temple flourished again. The current worship hall at Iiyama Temple was part of Ichinomiya Temple reconstruction, and later moved here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside the temple, the wooden statue of the eleven-headed Kannon is still there, according to the plaque. All of the doors were closed, and the entrances were covered in screens for protection against animals. For a time, the temple was home to two works by the Japanese Monk, Enku &lt;span class='ja'&gt;円空&lt;/span&gt;, both of which are designated as cultural properties of Gifu prefecture. Those works are now on display in the Takayama City Museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the Temple having been largely abandoned, every seven years the temple opens again for the public to view the priceless statues inside. Although, apparently, this practice may have stopped in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0289.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0289.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0289_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0289_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0289_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Near the exit to the forest was a small collection of Ojizosama. It seemed like it had been several years since they've been tended to. One of the Jizos didn't even have a face anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ojizosama statues offer two kinds of protection. One of these protections are for children who have died too early in life. As a child's soul passes into the afterlife, it doesn't have its parents to guide them. So, the Jizo-sama protect them like a parent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days, I think the more common protection of these statues is for travelers, which is why you see these statues everywhere when driving around in the mountains. The Jizo-sama protect people traveling long distances and help them reach their destination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0331.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0331.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0331_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0331_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0331_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the hill, there are a few more statues and monuments, but many of them had been knocked over by snow melt. Now, they've become buried again from the high grass. Up on the hill behind the temple and behind the monuments was a cellphone tower. The cellphone tower seems like it gets more attention these days than the temple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon entering and leaving the area, you pass by a small shrine on the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0342.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0342.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0342_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0342_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250622_iiyama/IMG_0342_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The stone sign next to it says it's the Iiyama Temple Children's Area &lt;span class='ja'&gt;飯山寺子供地域&lt;/span&gt;. Back in the day, this might make sense as an area for the Temple's children to use while the adults perform the festival at the main temple. Nowadays, the road to the temple goes directly passed it, so it's only still here for preservation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the road leading to the temple is a fairly unremarkable side road off of Route 41. The side road used to be masked by a construction company and their large building, but I feel like they had been slowly going out of business over the last several years. Now, this main building has been completely demolished. Looking through Google, it must've happen in the last 6 months, which is really recent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's remarkable to go around Japan and find pockets of rich history. But, it's also almost just as remarkable how fast they can tear down their modern buildings when their business moves or changes. Living in Takayama for over 12 years, there have been so many changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/iiyama-temple</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/iiyama-temple</link><category/><category>Hida Takayama</category><category/><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category></item><item><title>Hosoo Pass 細尾峠 &amp; Postal Station Ruins 郵便交換所</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hosoo Pass was a crucial route for the people living in the valley villages of southwestern Toyama and Johana Town, the closest major city. People living in these villages were largely cut off from the main Japanese society. One of the main transportation routes was along the Sho River &lt;span class='ja'&gt;庄川&lt;/span&gt;, but the river only went through mountains in the north. A whole range of mountains encircled the southern end of Johana shielding the town from the valley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the old Hosoo Pass route was established in 1887 (Meiji 20). It was fairly direct ascent up the mountains, but the road twisted enough that it was smooth travel for people and easy for horses, too. This 10 kilometer route was far more convenient than the 40 kilometer detour north following the river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7758_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7758_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7758_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7758_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7758_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the road, at the top of Hosoo Pass, you can clearly see Johana Town and the rest of the Takaoka and Tonami area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days that old route is no longer used. In 1927 (Showa 2), the Yahata Road &lt;span class='ja'&gt;八幡道路&lt;/span&gt; was completed. It was a paved road that went directly from Johana Town, through Hosoo Pass, and continued to the Taira and Kamitaira villages before ending in Shimonashi village on Sho River. Part of this new road was the Hosoo Pass tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7665.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7665.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7665_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7665_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7665_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the southern end of Hosoo Pass, continuing to Taira and Shimonashi villages, the old route went over Kakuma Pass &lt;span class='ja'&gt;鹿熊峠&lt;/span&gt;, but in 1973, the Nashitani Tunnel &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梨谷トンネル&lt;/span&gt; was completed which decommisioned that part of the route. In 1979, construction on the Gokayama Tunnel &lt;span class='ja'&gt;五箇山トンネル&lt;/span&gt; began and finished in 1981. The tunnel went directly through the mountains and connected with the Nashitani Tunnel. Yahata Road going through Hosoo Pass was no longer necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road is still usable today despite the occasional fallen rocks and branches from the cliffs above. Old folks still drive along the road and clear the debris. Enough preventions have been set to prevent landslides, but eventually there could be a large enough landslide to knock out the road, rendering Hosoo Pass no longer travelable from the north.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adventure&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I traveled to Hosoo Pass. At the time, I knew nothing about the area, so I followed Google Map's suggestions, which lead me to several closed roads, taking too much time, and forcing me to return a few days later. That's the day that I went to that &lt;a href="donohara-winter-branch-school" title="donohara-winter-branch-school"&gt;Donohara Winter Branch School&lt;/a&gt;. That branch school was along the Sho River to the north of Shimonashi village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my second trip, I left my house early at 6:30am and arrived at Hosoo Pass around 8am, an hour by highway and 30 minutes on mountain roads. Before exploring the rest of Hosoo Pass and Yahata Road, I took the side path next to Hosoo Tunnel to climb Hakamagoshiyama. I detailed that hike in a &lt;a href="hakamagoshiyama" title="hakamagoshiyama"&gt;different post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hosoo Pass Tea House Ruins &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠の茶屋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today it's no longer a spectacle, but next to Hosoo Tunnel was a two story Tea House.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7714.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7714.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7714_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7714_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7714_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now all that remains are 7 metal posts sticking out of the ground and a bunch of metal garbage behind them. Much of that metal garbage is the old aluminum roof of the building. There was also a refrigerator back there, and a few other things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have no idea when the tea house was built, but it apparently had no running water, nor any electricity of its own. For those people who traveled along the old route in the Meiji and early Showa periods, this had to have been used as a rest stop in the middle of the journey from Johana to Taira or Shimonashi. Later, after it closed, construction companies used it as an office and warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking around the Internet, I found a webpage that had a photo of the tea house in the year 2001. I copied the page and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/pages/hosoo1.html" title="https://theschlock.com/pages/hosoo1.html"&gt;hosted it here&lt;/a&gt; as a backup. You could clearly see the 7 white metal posts holding up the front of the building, but many of the windows have been broken out, and the building doesn't look very safe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found some other photos other sites, too. &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/IMG_60171.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/IMG_60171.jpg"&gt;Here's a photo&lt;/a&gt; of less than half of the building remaining from around 2005, I think. And then another &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/20190906133106.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/image/hosoo/20190906133106.jpg"&gt;photo from 2019&lt;/a&gt; of a more distinct pile of rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8049.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8049.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8049_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8049_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8049_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, there is so little left. I think, year after year, snow melt continued to push and move the garbage away from the site and down the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hosoo Postal Exchange Ruins &lt;span class='ja'&gt;細尾峠郵便交換所&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few hundred meters away from the tunnel and tea house is the ruins of the Hosoo Pass Postal Exchange office. Finding this building is not very easy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8059.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8059.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8059_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8059_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8059_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Yahata Road curves along the rim of the mountain and has a steep drop off. There's a 3-meter drop to the ground from the road, and the ground is angled at 45 degrees. But apparently there's a trail down there which was the old Hosoo Pass route. Google Maps doesn't mark any kind of entry, but the OSM maps had a trail. And at those coordinates, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7690.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_7690.jpg"&gt;I found a rope&lt;/a&gt;. The rope trails trials off into the brush going nearly straight down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my first trip, I did not believe that was the entry point, but I confirmed it later at home. When I came back on the weekend, I put on my worker gloves and scaled down to ground. The trail apparently hugs the road and then shoots off along the ridge of the mountain. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When there's no clear indication of a trail and you're cutting through brush, it's hard to tell if you're going the right way. I naturally followed the downward slope of the mountain, but then remembered this was not the way. I climbed up a bit, using the plants as handles and found a flattened spot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8062.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8062.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8062_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8062_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8062_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I headed in the direction that seemed correct, I noticed a red flag on a tree. Okay, I am actually going the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the trail was completely covered in brush, but there were the occasional stone and cement bricks along the path. The trail did hug the road for a little bit before heading off in the direction of the mountain ridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And after 10 or 15 minutes, the ruins poked through the brush in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8068.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8068.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8068_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8068_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8068_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8070.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8070.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8070_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8070_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8070_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside the ruins was a large painted board that detailed the history of Hosoo Pass and the Post Office. I transcribed the board and put a translation &lt;a href="hosoo-postal-exchange-ruins-information" title="hosoo-postal-exchange-ruins-information"&gt;on this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Taira Post Office was established in Shimonashi in 1872 (Meiji 5), the Postal Corps &lt;span class='ja'&gt;郵送隊&lt;/span&gt; was also established. The Postal Corps was a group of people who lived in the villages of Taira and Shimonashi. This group of people would gather all the mail for the day and physically hike up to Hosoo Pass and down to Johana. They would collect the mail at Johana, and then return to Taira Post Office. Each person carried a maximum of 18 kilograms of mail and packages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They did this 20 kilometer round trip every day, even in winter. When the traveled the formed a line of people. Sometimes in winter, blizzards would be so strong that it was difficult for the mail carriers to see the next person in front of them. They constantly had to sound off to make sure no one was left behind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years later in 1887, the old Hosoo Pass route opened which made this travel must easier and faster. Again, in 1927 the paved road, Yahata Road, was opened which made travel more convenient in summer, and now mail could be transported by trucks. But the Postal Corps still transported the mail by foot in winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8181.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8181.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8181_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8181_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8181_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1945, ths Hosoo Pass Postal Exchange Office was built. Now, the Postal Corps had two teams. Both teams who would leave Taira and Johana post offices at 9am and meet here. Parcels and Mail would be exchanged between both teams. And then, they'd return to their towns. This cut travel time in half, but required more workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1955, as Japan experienced significant economic growth, many temporary workers were hired to match the workload. However, by 1971, the villages of Taira, Ueda, and all the areas around Shimonashi experienced significant depopulation. The current members of the corps were aging, and young people moved away to live in larger cities. The postal corps was abolished that year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And again, the Nashitani and Gokayama tunnels were completed in 1973 and 1981, which made the road obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8120.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8120.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8120_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8120_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8120_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brickwork and cement structure is still holding after 80 years, but all of the metalwork has rusted, and the roof of the office building has collapsed. Part of the roof still protects the signboard from the weather, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a few more pictures and then returned to the road. Out of the entrance to the Postal Exchange, the old route branches up and down the mountain. I wasn't paying close attention, but I managed to go the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving along the ridge of the mountain, I came to the area underneath the paved road. The old route snaked along with the road until it came to that 3-meter drop off with the rope. But, I figured that I could just ascend anywhere that seemed easy enough to reach the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8228.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8228.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8228_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8228_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8228_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, this looked like a good spot. I grabbed the trees and climbed up. With each step, I grabbed the next bit of plants coming out of the ground. Often I would lose my footing and slip down, but I was able to keep advancing and pulling myself up. Inch by inch, I finally saw the outline of the road and had my exit in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I moved along the 3-meter drop off until some plants were high enough to vault me up to a guardrail pipe and then I yanked myself up onto the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8234.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8234.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8234_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8234_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8234_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should have shimmied along the road back to the rope, but I was back to civilization, and back on easy street. I returned to my car and continued down towards Johana to meet the Gokayama Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road continued to snake along the edge of the mountain. Occassionally I would have to squeak my car to the side to let another car pass. Lots of people were using the road today. I'm not sure why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8269.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8269.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8269_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8269_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8269_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gokayama Tunnel Emergency Exit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually around a corner of the mountain road, this structure came into view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8304.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8304.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8304_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8304_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8304_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first, I had no idea what this was. A small stream was flowing over part of it, so I thought it was a hydroelectric plant, using the natural spring of the mountain for power. There was an occasional whirring sound, too, which I thought it was a turbine or some kind of internal machinery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The northern side of the structure had plastic windows, several of which were broken. I took a look inside, and a car whizzed by! Ah... I checked the map. This was part of the Gokayama tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back at the large square garage-looking door, one of the emergency exits was not locked, and I could go inside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8338.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8338.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8338_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8338_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8338_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was about a kilometer into the 3km tunnel. The road wasn't super busy, but cars whizzed by every minute or so. Next to the emergency exit was an SOS phone. Wikipedia mentions that the Gokayama tunnel was built in two parts, so maybe this was the half point of its construction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took some photos, and then returned to my car. I continued to the end of Yahata Road, next to the mouth of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8394.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8394.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8394_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8394_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8394_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was some weird art structure nearby, but this was the end of Yahata Road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sakaide &lt;span class='ja'&gt;坂出&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 6 hours of hiking and driving around the old road, I went to Shimonashi for lunch. Sakaide was a small family owned restaurant in the center of Shimonashi village. They had the standard dishes of Udon, Soba, and Rice Bowls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the menu, I noticed that they served bear meat in their dishes, so I ordered the Bear Meat Soba, or &lt;span class='ja'&gt;くま肉そば&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The soba was great, although soba is always great. I don't know how it stood apart from other soba I've had before. In the soba were chunks of cooked bear meat. It also wasn't really remarkable. They tasted like cuts of beef. It was good, but I think buying the mountain vegetable soba &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山菜そば&lt;/span&gt; would've probably been better. Either way, it was exactly the meal I wanted for lunch. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8437.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8437.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8437_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8437_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hosoo/IMG_8437_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When driving down the highways and motorways of Japan, there are so many side roads that go off along mountains or continue into forests. I have driven past hundreds of these roads and barely given a thought to where they lead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like this case, they are often the original old roads that snaked around the mountain before tunnels were built. Also, these roads traveled to villages that once were and are no longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Timeline of the Adventure&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;6:30ish&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Left Home&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:00am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Arrived at Hosoo Pass Tunnel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4474912,136.8967591" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4474912,136.8967591"&gt;36°26'51.0"N 136°53'48.4"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:25am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hakamagoshiyama" title="https://theschlock.com/hakamagoshiyama"&gt;Hiking Hakamagoshiyama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4317188,136.8799013" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4317188,136.8799013"&gt;36°25'54.3"N 136°52'47.7"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:00am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to Car&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4323459,136.880427" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4323459,136.880427"&gt;36°25'56.6"N 136°52'49.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:15am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tea House Ruins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.448049,136.8977035" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.448049,136.8977035"&gt;36°26'53.1"N 136°53'51.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:30am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;(Jumping down the cliff)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4489325,136.9003997" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4489325,136.9003997"&gt;36°26'56.2"N 136°54'01.4"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:45am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Finding the Post Office&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4510614,136.9000417" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4510614,136.9000417"&gt;36°27'03.9"N 136°54'00.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:05am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Leaving the Post Office&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:15am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Climbing to the Road&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4498593,136.9010224" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4498593,136.9010224"&gt;36°26'59.7"N 136°54'03.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:25am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to Car&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.448049,136.8977035" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.448049,136.8977035"&gt;36°26'53.1"N 136°53'51.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:50am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Highway Emergency Exit&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4604666,136.910906" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4604666,136.910906"&gt;36°27'37.7"N 136°54'39.3"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12:15pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to the Main Highway&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4649974,136.9032231" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4649974,136.9032231"&gt;36°27'54.0"N 136°54'11.7"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12:30pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sakaide &lt;span class='ja'&gt;坂出&lt;/span&gt; (for lunch)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4331262,136.9485503" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4331262,136.9485503"&gt;36°25'59.3"N 136°56'54.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins</link><category/><category>Urban Exploration</category><category/><category>Mountains</category><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Hakamagoshiyama 袴腰山</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hakamagoshiyama is a mountain in southwestern Toyama. It's a pretty short climb, and more seasoned hikers use it as the first stop of a much longer hike going to the peaks bordering Toyama and Ishikawa prefectures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I planned to explore &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins"&gt;Hosoo Pass&lt;/a&gt; and the various ruins along that road. The trailhead for Hakamagoshiyama was in the opposite direction after reaching the Hosoo Pass Tunnel. The entirity of the road for Hosoo Pass was paved, but after turning off for the mountain, it was all rock and dirt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7785.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7785.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7785_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7785_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7785_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stopped a few times to clear some rocks from the road. I also had to move to the side to let a car go through. I guess some other folks just drive over the rocks in the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trailhead for the hike was clearly marked, but I parked about 100 meters away from the entrance because of a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7792.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7792.jpg"&gt;crack in the road&lt;/a&gt;. It was probably safe to drive over, but a few other cars were parked away from the fissure, so I parked back there, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hiking to the peak of Hakamagoshiyama was pretty rough. Immediately from the start, the path went nearly straight up. This first part of the hike wasn't too bad, as steps were carved and placed into the ground. The trees gave way to a clear sky above and when reaching the top of the stairs, a rest hut was at the top of the first peak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7802_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7802_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7802_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7802_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7802_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was pretty early in the hike for a rest, but the hut was meant more for hikers in the winter starting from the villages at the base of the mountains. There is too much snow in the winter to be plowed, so anyone hiking these mountains would spend more than a day doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving further to the edge of this peak, you could see most of the distance someone would have to travel from below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7820_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7820_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7820_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7820_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7820_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was about 300 or 400 meters into the hike so far. There was still another 800 meters to go. This first bit was tough, but the stairs made it pretty easy. The rest of the hike had no stairs and most of the hike was far steeper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7851.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7851.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7851_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7851_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7851_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the hike was pull up to a wall of dirt and roots with some ropes attached to trees above. I can usually pull up steep ascents on hikes by myself, but these were far steeper than usual. I actually had to use the ropes. (And the ropes were absolutely necessary going back down.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trail went straight up in parts, and then snaked around some small ridges of the mountain. Occassionally, the trees would open up giving &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7854_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7854_stitch.jpg"&gt;a beautiful view&lt;/a&gt; of all the mountains to the east along with a reminder of how far you've gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It felt like the hike took a while. But, in reality, it only took about 30 minutes from the rest hut to reach the peak. The peak forked into two separate observation points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7891_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7891_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7891_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7891_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7891_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning left at the fork and going south, you could see everything to the southwest of Hakamagoshiyama. There was the highway exit for Suganuma Gokayama Village, the exit I initially took to get here. Above the village, the highest peak was Hakusan &lt;span class='ja'&gt;白山&lt;/span&gt;, which bordered Gifu and Fukui prefectures. Closer to me were the mountains Ogasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大笠&lt;/span&gt; and Oizuru &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笈ヶ岳&lt;/span&gt;. Mt. Oizuru was the border of three prefectures: Gifu, Fukui, and Toyama. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The observation point had a lot of bees and large flies buzzing around. Apparently two weeks ago, all of the magenta flowers on the mountain were in full bloom. The insects could have been flying around trying to find any remaining ones still open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took my photos and moved to the northern observation point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7973_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7973_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7973_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7973_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7973_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After climbing the ladder to the top of the tower, you had a full 360-degree view of the surrounding mountains. You couldn't see Gokayama anymore, but all the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7957.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7957.jpg"&gt;mountains to the south&lt;/a&gt; were visible. You could also see all &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7930_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7930_stitch.jpg"&gt;mountains further to the east,&lt;/a&gt; too. Mt. Norikura wasn't in view, but I could see Shirakimine, which I hiked &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/shirakimine" title="https://theschlock.com/shirakimine"&gt;2 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I approached the observation tower, someone else was already at the top. A woman who was more than happy to talk to me. I was surprised that I hadn't met anyone yet considering the two other cars at the trailhead. Apparently, for seasoned hikers, Hakamagoshiyama is just the first stop on the hike of these mountains. Past the observation tower, you continue down the opposite side of the mountain and go up the western mountains to eventually arrive at the peak of Mt. Ogasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大笠&lt;/span&gt;. That was too much for what I had planned for today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mountain views were great, but the view to the south was pretty special.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7939_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7939_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7939_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7939_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7939_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole Nanto, Tonami, and Takaoka areas were visible. It wasn't too hot, but the humidity did limit some of the visibility. Apparently, you could also see over the western mountains and view Kanazawa, but I didn't notice it. Maybe I'll come back some day and continue along the western mountain ridges to see that view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I snapped my photos and moved on. There was more adventure scheduled for today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descending mountains is usually the easiest part of the hike, but that wasn't the case when the paths are so steep. I had to constantly hold on to ropes and branches to catch myself from slipping, and I often still slipped anyways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8002.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8002.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8002_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8002_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8002_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halfway down, I had some kind of cracking sound and then some guys shouting something. I stopped to listen, but the noise stopped. A few minutes later, I heard it again, but had no idea what it was. I reached an observation point and noticed &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7996.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_7996.jpg"&gt;a few more cars next to mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further down the mountain, I heard some more shouting. Eventually, I got close enough to it to understand the situation. In the brush, away from the trail and invisible to me, were two guys cutting through a separate trail. They were yelling out to each other as a safety measure. If one of them yelled out and there wasn't a reply, they would know the other person was in danger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A worker van was parked at the beginning of the trail, so they must've been construction workers making their way to an electrical tower, or something. The descent took almost the same amount of time as the ascent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8009.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8009.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8009_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8009_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250607_hakamagoshiyama/IMG_8009_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At my car, I took a look back at the mountain, but I couldn't see any trace of the observation tower or points along the trail. Everything was pretty well covered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hakamagoshiyama was a really nice and semi-challenging hike that did seem like only the first step of a much longer adventure. It was only a side adventure for me, as I was really up there exploring &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins" title="https://theschlock.com/hosoo-pass-postal-station-ruins"&gt;Hosoo Pass&lt;/a&gt;. It would be nice to return and continue along the ridges to view Ishigawa and Kanazawa on the west side. Being able to see the Sea of Japan from the mountains would be great, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Timeline of the Hike&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:25am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trailhead for Hakamagoshiyama&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4317188,136.8799013" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4317188,136.8799013"&gt;36°25'54.3"N 136°52'47.7"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:35am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rest Hut&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4294422,136.8788346" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4294422,136.8788346"&gt;36°25'46.0"N 136°52'43.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:05am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Plateau Trail Fork&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4279707,136.8728114" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4279707,136.8728114"&gt;36°25'40.7"N 136°52'22.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:10am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;South Observation point&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4261869,136.8724235" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4261869,136.8724235"&gt;36°25'34.3"N 136°52'20.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:20am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;North Observation point&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4284536,136.8720321" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4284536,136.8720321"&gt;36°25'42.4"N 136°52'19.4"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:30am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to Trail Fork&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4279707,136.8728114" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4279707,136.8728114"&gt;36°25'40.7"N 136°52'22.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:55am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to Rest Hut&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4294422,136.8788346" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4294422,136.8788346"&gt;36°25'46.0"N 136°52'43.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:00am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to Car&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4323459,136.880427" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.4323459,136.880427"&gt;36°25'56.6"N 136°52'49.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/hakamagoshiyama</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/hakamagoshiyama</link><category/><category/><category>Mountains</category><category/><category/><category/><category/><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category></item></channel></rss>