<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>&lt;b&gt;One Schlock's Requiem&lt;/b&gt; is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher on English living in central Japan.</description><link>http://theschlock.com/</link><item><title>Vivillion Shiny Hunt</title><description/><link>http://theschlock.com/vivillion-shiny-hunt</link></item><item><title>Website Revival</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/website-revival</link></item><item><title>Application for Permanent Residence</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years ago, I moved to Japan. I didn’t necessarily intend to stay for more than a year or two, but I loved living here and loved teaching students. Teaching had become the most rewarding job I’ve done in my life, so I didn’t want to leave, and it never felt like my time in Japan was complete. Now, this is where I live. A town full of students or parents of students that I’ve helped teach for more than 10 years. And full of friends and connections that I’ve made over the years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that 10 years has passed, I can apply for Permanent Residence in Japan. In simple terms, Permanent Residence means that I no longer have to renew a work VISA after 3 years and I can buy or build a house. But to me, it means that I’m further established as a part of Japan and don’t intend to leave. It’s the near-equivalent to a Green Card in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying for Permanent Residence is not a simple process of filling out a couple of forms. There are many parts to prove your legal employment, payment of taxes, and contribution to Japan. I spent about a month working on the application back in October, only to have it rejected because I hadn’t lived here a complete 10 years yet. Now, 4 months later, my application is complete and it ended up being 47 pages long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VKDo29AZMTz6NCGxvFXU_efaE_egb_tR"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VKhKluWm_6qOqFGcGBfjZFrvs6FRlj6m"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so long that I wrote a Table of Contents describing everything that I included, and sectioned everything into different folders to make it as easy as possible for them to see what I’ve included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;b&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1.      &lt;b&gt;Application for Permanent Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;b&gt;Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3.      &lt;b&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;6.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;7.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;8.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.      &lt;b&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10.    &lt;b&gt;Passport Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.    &lt;b&gt;Residence Card Photo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;12.    &lt;b&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;13.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Contributions to Japan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;14.    &lt;b&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;15.    &lt;b&gt;Application Oath&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The instructions for how to apply for permanent residence can be found on the government Immigration website. They are written in &lt;a href="https://www.isa.go.jp/en/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/applications/procedures/zairyu_eijyu03.html"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;. My table of contents follows the list of required materials from that page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though, they have an English version that doesn’t necessarily mean it’s easy to figure out what to do. These instructions are machine translated, and you still need to understand what they’re saying in Japanese because of the specific names for forms, and the specific departments and locations you need to visit. There’s a lot of running around involved getting all the correct documents, so I have detailed everything I did to build my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Payment of Fee&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;手数料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is not required when you submit your application, but it will be required after your application is successful. You must fill out the Payment form and attach an 8000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; revenue stamp to it. Revenue stamps can be purchased from the post office. Obviously, if you’ve been in Japan long enough, you already know how to do this from renewing your VISA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the payment form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002847.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application for Permanent Residence &amp; Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;永住許可申請書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;写真&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The first document is the application itself. Again, from renewing a VISA, all the same information is here with the addition of a short version of why you want permanent residence, work history, and guarantor information. For my reason, I wrote "I wish to obtain permanent residence to continue teaching in Japan indefinitely and continue my study of kendo and Japanese culture to further enrich myself." It sounds like a lofty reason, but I have fully explained it in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the application form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002835.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll need a 40mm x 30mm photo attached to your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Statement of Reason&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;理由書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perhaps the part of this application that will take the longest is writing about why you want permanent residence in Japan. My short version stated that I wish to teach in Japan indefinitely and continue to learn about Japan, but those ideas are weak unless there is proof. In total, I wrote 3 pages about my time over the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started with detailing my current responsibilities and accomplishments working at my high school: supporting English teachers in class, leading English writing classes, being an assistant Homeroom teacher, leading classes to prepare students for studying abroad, training students for speech contests and winning them, and teaching foreign exchange students Japanese language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I detailed my accomplishments and responsibilities working in public elementary and junior high schools as part of the JET Programme, such as supporting English classes and training students for speech contests, but also volunteering in town for English conversations classes supporting the hospital and library, developing summer English camp and other events for students, and developing a full English curriculum for elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I detailed my responsibilities as a Regional Prefectural Advisory supporting other ALTs in my region and the prefecture by developing our biannual skills conferences and leading lectures and discussions about lesson planning and ideas, as well as lead monthly meeting for the ALTs in my town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I closed my statement of reason with my contributions to the kendo federation in my town. I wrote about how I joined students in their club activities and practiced kendo, what I learned from doing kendo both personally and professionally, and eventually reaching the rank of 3-dan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 pages might have been too much for a statement of reason, but I wanted to completely show everything noteworthy that I’ve done in Japan. It was very direct and unemotional, focusing on the facts. My approach to writing the statement was very similar to writing a resume for an application. Overall, I don’t think the statement has to be completely emotionless, but I don’t think it should be the main focus of the argument. Show, don’t tell, as I say to my students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though I wrote all this information in English, I had to rewrite everything in Japanese, too. I had some help with that. I included both English and Japanese versions of my statement in my application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Identity&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分関係を証明する次のいずれかの資料（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I am not Japanese, so this was not required for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Residence&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Whenever you move somewhere in Japan, you must register at the town hall so it has a complete and up-to-date record of all of its residents. The application for permanent residence requires a print of this record. It was easy to get from my town’s registrar by filling out a request document and paying 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for them to print the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has information, such as when you moved to town, current address, previous addresses, nationality, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Employment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In addition to proving that you live somewhere, you also need to prove that you work somewhere. This was pretty easy for me to get since my school is private and not that big. For a larger organization or a government organization, it might take some time for your request to go open the chain and for the document to come back down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just went to the office and they created a document that proved my employment. Depending on whichever company you work for, it may be an official document or it may not. I think it just needs to include a statement saying you work there as well as information that can be contacted later. My school/company just made up an official looking document with all the correct information on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Income and Tax Payment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;直近（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）の申請人及び申請人を扶養する方の所得及び納税状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Things start to get more complicated, as a single piece of paper proving your employment isn’t enough. Of course, you need to show that you’ve been paying taxes on the income that you’ve earned. And also show that you’ve been doing it for at least five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These documents include the &lt;I&gt;Kazei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;I&gt;Nozei shoumeisho&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt;. Both documents translate as either Tax Certificate or Taxation Certificate, so looking at the English information about this section may not be helpful. Overall, the &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details how much taxes you had to pay and what taxes you had to pay on your income within a given year. The &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate details the amount of taxes you still owe for a given year. Essentially, &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; is like an itemized bill, and &lt;I&gt;Zozei&lt;/I&gt; is the receipt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each document you’ll need for 5 years. For my town, I had a single &lt;I&gt;Kazei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate for each year. For the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate, each year could be written on the same document. For each document, for each year, it cost 300&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;. So for all the documents, my bill would’ve been 3000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;I&gt;update&lt;/I&gt;, when I initially turned in my application, I forgot to get 5 years for the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Certificate. I was able to turn in my application, but I needed to mail in the correct form within two weeks. They gave me an envelope and a sheet that described the document I was missing. Another problem, though: my town only keeps the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate up to 4 years, instead of the 5 years they wanted. I called them, and they said 4 years was fine. So, my bill was actually 2700&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for these documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally! There’s another version of the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate that is required. Besides the Tax Record office in city hall, I went to my town’s official Tax Office. Requesting the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate from them shows them I’ve paid all debts and taxes across all government departments and agencies, as well as never missed any payment for any bills or loan. This document cost 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; to print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, to these tax documents, I had to include a photo of my bank book that proved I was getting paid the correct income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, for this section, I included the following documents:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;課税証明書（過去&lt;/span&gt;５&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt;- Kazei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - Nozei Tax Certificate (5 years)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書（未払いの税金がないことを証明するためのパート&lt;/span&gt;3&lt;span class='ja'&gt;）&lt;/span&gt;- Nozei Cert proving no upaid taxes&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;預貯金通帳（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo proving income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Pension Payments and Health Insurance&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;8.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の公的年金及び公的医療保険の保険料の納付状況を証明する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now that I had shown that I am legally employed, getting legally paid, and responsibly paying taxes on my legal income, I need to show that I’m paying into either my company’s pension or the government’s pension for at least two years. Also that I have health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section was somewhat difficult to follow. Initially, I just took a photo copy of my annual pension report that I had gotten in mail, but (&lt;I&gt;update!&lt;/I&gt;) apparently that wasn’t enough. A few days after I turned in my application, I got a letter in the mail requesting another form. The form they wanted detailed all of my pension payments, and each pension that I’ve contributed to. It was called the &lt;I&gt;Hihokenja Chousho Shoukai Kaitou-hyou&lt;/I&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt; or the “Insurance Record Inquiry Report,” I think? I’m not sure why it says insurance when its about pensions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get this form, I had to go to my town’s Pension office and request these forms. Prior to going to the office, I had some co-workers give them a call to make sure I was getting the right forms, and they were able to prepare everything for me before I arrived. It turned a possible 40-minute wait into 5 minutes. This document was also 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at this document, I’ve contributed into a government pension when I worked for the city as a teacher, and I’ve contributed to a private pension I have with my current job. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter wanted me to include receipts from any contributions to the government’s individual pension service, but I never did that, so I didn’t have any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the health insurance card, I just took a photo of it and blacked out the account number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, this is what I included from this section:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ねんきん定期便（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;被保険者調書照会回答票&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;健康保険被保険者証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Financial Assets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;9.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人又は申請人を扶養する方の資産を証明する次のいずれかの資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the next part, I had to show all of Japanese financial assets. At minimum, I had to take photo copies of my bank statements to show how much money I have in Japan. I don’t have a house, so I didn’t have anything to show there. I do have a car, but I didn’t include any proof of that. Maybe I should have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Passport Photo and Residence Card Photo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人のパスポート（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;申請人の在留カード（写し）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I included photo copies of my passport and residence card with my application, but this is not really necessary. When you turn in your application, you’ll need to also show them both of these, and they can take a photo copy themselves, at this time. I included these to save time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Guarantor Information and References&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;12.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証に関する資料&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A current Japanese citizen needs to vouch for who I am, what I stand for, and state that I would make a contribution to Japan by becoming a Japanese permanent resident. This person should be someone you know pretty well, and have a good relationship with. My principal at school has always sponsored my VISA, as well as other documents that required official clearance, so he was an easy choice as a guarantor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They need to fill in the guarantor form and prove who they are. For my guarantor, we included the following:&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身元保証書&lt;/span&gt; - the guarantor application&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証&lt;/span&gt; - a photo copy of their ID (driver’s license, in this case)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;在職証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of employment, wherever they work.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;納税証明書&lt;/span&gt; - proof of tax payments. (&lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;住民票&lt;/span&gt; - proof of residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the guarantor form:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002536.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Japanese)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/930002537.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Contributions to Japan&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;13.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;我が国への貢献に係る資料（&lt;/span&gt;※&lt;span class='ja'&gt;ある場合のみで結構です。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is the last meaty section of the application. For this section, I included my letters of recommendation and other certificates and awards of accomplishments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I had 3 recommendation letters: one letter from the principal, one letter from the head of our English department, and one letter from head of the Kendo federation in my town. Each letter of recommendation talked about the contributions that I made to my school and kendo in town, and talked about why they think I should be awarded permanent residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional documents that I included were proof of things mentioned in either my Statement of Reason or their Letters of Recommendation. I included a photo of my kendo license showing participation for 10 years, my 3-dan diploma, and certificates of participation for 3 years in the international budo conference. I also included a photo of my driver’s license to show that not only do I have a license, but maintaining a perfect and safe driving record to be awarded a 5-year gold license.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, here were my documents for this section.&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from principal)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from head of English)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;推薦状&lt;/span&gt; – Letter of Recommendation (from Kendo Federation)&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo License Photo&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;段免許（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Kendo 3-dan Diploma&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;国際武道文化セミナー&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;修了証&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;（&lt;/span&gt;３&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年分）&lt;/span&gt; - International Budo Conference particpation&lt;br/&gt;·        &lt;span class='ja'&gt;運転免許証（写し）&lt;/span&gt;- Photo of Gold Driver’s License&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Proof of Japanese Ancestry&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;14.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;身分を証する文書等（該当しません）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’m not Japanese, so I did not need to do this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if this one is proof of ancestry or identity, or what the difference is between part 4 above. For one of these, there is some kind of official family document Japanese people have that shows all of their registered family members, and you need to include a photo copy of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Application Oath&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;15.      &lt;span class='ja'&gt;了解書　&lt;/span&gt;１&lt;span class='ja'&gt;通&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The final document required is signing the application oath form. By signing this, you agree that if anything information within the application changes over the next 4 to 6 months, you must notify immigration about these changes and update your application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf"&gt;https://www.moj.go.jp/isa/content/001356126.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Complete!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VNEi30qT4tesov-EG7rpGUiiCti8nXDi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VNXzqzhPUCLQLOmmK2tMM4R-Qry6Xyye"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s everything. It doesn’t really seem like all that much once I finished making everything and putting it together. However, a lot of the time spent on the application is figuring out exactly what is required and where to go. The tax and pensions details are pretty tricky. I think my situation is pretty easy because I’ve only had the one job in the last 5 years, and the job is run by a professional organization. I also don’t have a house. Although, getting those documents probably aren’t too tough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 13th, I drove up north to Toyama and turned in my application at Toyama Branch Office of the Nagoya Regional Immigration Bureau. A long time ago, I figured out that very few people actually go to this branch office, so the wait time is never more than 5 minutes. In Gifu, wait times can be as long as 45 minutes. And in Nagoya, a friend of mine waited for an hour and a half once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the clerk instantly noticed one probably with my application (the &lt;I&gt;Nozei&lt;/I&gt; Tax Certificate not being 5 years), so I had to submit that afterward. I also got a letter in the mail on February 17th about the pension document. But, they accepted my application, and I’ve mailed those requested document as soon as I could. All documents were submitted as of February 21st, and I have not received any more letters about any more problems.  I think it’s all good!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically these application can take up to six months to be completely reviewed and responded to, but the clerk mentioned that it may only take three months to be complete. Over the last three years, thanks to Covid, the number of people moving to Japan has significantly decreased because the government shut down travel.  Previously, my VISA application would take 4 weeks to get approved, but it only took a week last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, by May, I’ll get the postcard in the mail to come back down and get my card. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/permanent-residence</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Extras</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-extras</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Level 50</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Asdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src=“/photo/230131_pokemon/dyreschlock_50_230129.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1W-bgKltUU-xFPCa-UyamC4kuzZs945lY" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-level-50</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Platform Images</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/pocket-platform-images</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket Utils</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils</link></item><item><title>Analogue Pocket</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Raid Counters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Linked below is my collated list of all the best raid counters in Pokemon Go. These numbers of based on the calculations made by Gamepress’s &lt;a href="https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/comprehensive-dps-spreadsheet"&gt;Comprehensive DPS Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; but put together on a single page, rather than multiple ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VY-8qOf09VGMlhyHcAXL02w97P_914oA" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not the prettiest page, but it shows everything I need in order to build my raid team. Each cell shows the following:&lt;br/&gt;- the name of the Pokemon&lt;br/&gt;- the level of the Pokemon used for the calculations&lt;br/&gt;- the fast move&lt;br/&gt;- the charge move&lt;br/&gt;- the DPS&lt;br/&gt;- the TDO&lt;br/&gt;- the final figure is DPS*4 x TDO / 100000. This is the number I used to sort each list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing more damage quickly is more important than staying alive, so I prioritize DPS. But, it’s not solely sorted by DPS because if you die immediately with no defense, it’s totally worthless.  Therefore, I’m using DPS*4 rather than DPS*3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m including level 40 for all Pokemon, but I’m also including level 50 for all non-legendary pokemon and level 45 for all legendaries. It’s not too difficult to boost Pokemon up to level 40, but even though you can boost them all the way up to 50, getting XL candies for legendaries is not so easy. Includes two levels for each Pokemon can show you how much more powerful one is compared to the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Purpose&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some quick background, in Pokemon Go, there are these Pokemon battles called raids that multiple people can join to defeat the boss. Once the boss is defeated, each player has a chance to catch that Pokemon for themselves. These Pokemon are strong enough that you cannot defeat them by yourself. Each boss is different, but you usually must have 3 or 4 players minimum to win, assuming they have the best Pokemon for the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what are the best Pokemon for the battle? A while ago, the Pokemon community on &lt;b&gt;Gamepress&lt;/b&gt; wrote a calculator that would tell you just how powerful a Pokemon was versus a raid boss. If you typed in the Pokemon you wanted to fight, it would give you a numbered list of all the best pokemon you’d need to defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was first doing raids, I found this calculator very useful to determine which Pokemon to catch and boost. However, for this calculator, you need to type in each individual Pokemon one by one to see each of the best counters.  I wanted a page that I could look at and see ALL of the best pokemon versus ALL of the raid pokemon in Pokemon Go. So, I made one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Pokemon Raid Counter List&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The calculator will save a CSV will all the data for the raid counters.  So, back in 2019, I made this page to display all the information from these CSV files. Over time, this became unmanageable because the number of raid bosses continued to grow and the number of best Pokemon and best moves began to grow too. It would take me about an hour to download each individual sheet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gamepress Calculator does all of its calculations in JavaScript. So over summer, I went through that code and ported it to Java. Now, rather than compiling data from generated CSV files, I can generate that data myself. And, rather than downloading 30+ CSV files, I only need to download the raw data files and rerun the page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/general"&gt;General Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The General list says which are the best raid pokemon overall, but I also wrote a page that shows me which of my Pokemon are the best. I have to manually add every one of these, so my list is often out of date, but it gives me a general idea how much damage my team can do or how many people I’ll need to recruit to beat the boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/custom"&gt;Personal Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if any of this is readable to anyone else, but it helps me out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters</link></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Cards</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-cards</link></item><item><title>Virtual Tokyo Marathon</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/virtual-tokyo-marathon</link></item><item><title>Capsule Machine Capsule</title><description></description><link>http://theschlock.com/capsule-machine-capsule</link></item><item><title>New Pokemon Snap</title><description/><link>http://theschlock.com/new-pokemon-snap</link></item><item><title>The Features and Potential of Japanese Budo Culture</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I attended the 30th Annual International Seminar of Budo Culture, which coincided with the 150th anniversary of the start of the Meiji era in Japan.  This year’s main lecture was &lt;b&gt;The Features and Potential of Japanese Budo Culture&lt;/b&gt; given by Seiichi Takeuchi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹内&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;整一&lt;/span&gt;.  He is currently a professor at Kamakura Women’s University, and former professor of the University of Tokyo.  His field is the study of ethics and Japanese thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lecture was given in Japanese and translated into English by Alex Bennett, who is currently a professor at Kansai University and has written and translated many books on the Japanese Budo arts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qkz7Dr0LdIt_c1uUzVlLqe0Un5KgBCNV"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14si24DDGrQOgoATrPpZQr5yQqXh0iIHK" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was my 3rd time attending the seminar.  Every year I’m able to get amazing insights into budo martial arts and learn about their connection to Japanese psychology and culture.  I previously wrote about the main lecture from the first seminar I attended two years ago: &lt;a href="/the-cardinal-virtues-of-japan"&gt;March 4th, 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I felt the contents of the lecture did not match the title, but the main idea expressed in the lecture was another fascinating look at an explanation for Japanese culture.  The theme carried through the explanations and examples was that of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「おのずから」と「みずから」&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; explained the cooperative duality of these two forces behind the decisions and actions of people in Japanese culture and society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;おのずから&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class='ja'&gt;自然の働く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;みずから&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class='ja'&gt;自分の能力&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s do &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;, first.  &lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; is the effect from oneself.  It’s the idea that an action or decision you made came as a result of your own willpower.  &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the workings of nature, the idea that there is an overwhelming force behind a decision or action that made or allowed it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt; is pretty easy to understand, but &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is much more ambiguous.  In western countries, &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; could be similar to the will of god.  God is an outside influence, and people often thank God for giving them fortunes, or blame God for misfortunes.  This was brought up in a question after the lecture had finished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But for Japanese people, the idea of God is not a singular entity.  Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; mentioned if you asked a Japanese person who they pray to when they pray, they would not have an answer.  They wouldn’t know.  The will of nature is a result of many different factors and moving parts within the world and society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As another example, another question was asked, "Did you decide to do this lecture? Or was it the will of nature?"  He replied that he did want to do lecture, but he was also asked by many people to do it.  The people he knew and the connections he’s made throughout his life knew his expertise that made him qualified to give a lecture on this subject.  In that way, there was a force that created the opportunity for him to accept.  So, this lecture was a result of the actions of both nature and self.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the idea of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the force of everything around us.  It’s the connections we’ve made with people in our lives, the opportunities society gives us, and nature itself.  It is not, directly, "the will of God."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Example within Japanese Language&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two concepts aren’t something that is thought of on the surface level.  People aren’t consciously thinking about the will of themselves or nature when making decisions.  But there are examples within the Japanese language that build on this idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main example given was &lt;b&gt;I am to be married&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;結婚することになった&lt;/span&gt;.  When people get married in Japan and they announce it to their family and friends, they use this phrase.  It’s very passive and reflects the idea of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.  Getting married is simply a matter of course.  It’s natural.  Additionally, the effect of getting married wasn’t just decided or caused between the two involved.  It was the culmination of the people around them and their families’ blessings and good intentions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He did mention later in the lecture that a lot of young people these days use a more affirmative phrase when speaking informally about marriage, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;結婚することにした&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;we’ve decided to get married&lt;/b&gt;.  The two getting married take responsibility for their marriage as opposed to passively excepting it as a matter of nature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There could be any number of reasons for why this is becoming more popular.  Perhaps young people aren’t being taught more tradition methods of speaking than they were before.  Maybe people aren’t getting married as often as before, so they don’t hear the phrase enough.  Or perhaps, as English and the western world becomes more prevalent in Japan, people are becoming more direct and affirmative when expressing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Connections to Budo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a practitioner of a budo martial arts, we also seek for our movements to become natural.  In the beginning, we chose to study a martial art of our own free will (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;).  We all have our reasons for wanting to do it, whether it be for health, for friends, for fun, or because it looks cool.  We start from ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There Japanese word &lt;span class='ja'&gt;習う&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;narau&lt;/i&gt; means "to learn", but literally, it means "to continually repeat things" and becoming accustomed to it.  As a result, over time, these actions become natural.  You no longer need to think to do them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Budo, we strive for this level of movement where the thought process is no longer a factor, and to become part of nature, the natural flow of life (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  When movements and actions are not performed naturally, they are not seen as being complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Kyudo (archery), for example, when one reaches the level of complete mastery, the practitioner feels that the bow no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;The 3 points of Japanese Thought&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the balance of &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; is the concept of Japanese thought and 3 points that define it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;自然&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;shizen&lt;/i&gt; - nature&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;意気&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt; - will power&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;諦念&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt; - resignation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of &lt;b&gt;nature&lt;/b&gt; leads to accidental fury that was must put up with.  It’s something that we must endure and grow from.  &lt;b&gt;Will power&lt;/b&gt; is the willingness to put your body on line for what may happen.  And if something goes wrong, it’s your responsibility to &lt;b&gt;resign&lt;/b&gt; yourself to the outcome, and not make excuses for the result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though, resignation does not mean to simply give up.  It’s about reconciling the efforts of one’s will with the movement of nature, and to be able to see something clearly for what it is.  And in some cases, recognize your powerlessness to deal with whatever comes.  We take for granted our power over nature and often think that we can overcome it, but in reality we cannot.  Nature is a much greater force.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;申し訳ない&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;moushi wakenai&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This phrase literally translates to "there were no reasons behind my actions" or "there is no verbal excuse for what I have done."  This is used as a strong apology in Japanese, but an actual apology means to explain your actions and why you were wrong.  This goes one step further by saying there can be no excuse for the action I’ve done.  In this way, you’ve accepted the outcome (resigned) and take full responsibility (will power).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;すみません&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;sumimasen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is used as a light apology and basically means &lt;b&gt;excuse me&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;sorry&lt;/b&gt;, but the direct and complete translation is something closer to "my actions were not clear or clean or complete," or "I wasn’t able to completely do this action myself."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Other Japanese Words&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like the lecture on the cardinal virtues of Japan, speaker Seiichi Takeuchi wrote several books on the subject of &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.  He wrote 4 books, actually.  3 of which are out-of-print and expensive!  On Amazon, they are being sold for nearly 7000&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.  But, there was one book I could buy for only 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1QxsUo-FzLcdJABzLKDwiUVNpwp_yaZs5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1tGlVlvR5HrQPmrJ7ZLMIuOIi5RwR-5aq" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「おのずから」と「みずから」のあわいで&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;やまと言葉で&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;哲学する&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;i&gt;onozukara to mizukara no awai de yamato-kotoba de tetsugaku-suru&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;i&gt;Awai&lt;/i&gt; isn’t so easy to translate, but I was told, in this context, that it basically means between.  Takeuchi&lt;span class='ja'&gt;先生&lt;/span&gt; talked about this balance between both &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt; in his lecture, so I think it makes sense.  &lt;i&gt;Yamato-kotoba&lt;/i&gt; basically means words (&lt;i&gt;kotoba&lt;/i&gt;) that encompass the spirit of Japan (&lt;i&gt;yamato&lt;/i&gt;).  And lastly, &lt;i&gt;tetsugaku&lt;/i&gt; is philosophy.  So, the title is basically &lt;b&gt;The Philosophy of Japanese Words and Their Existence Between the Balance of &lt;i&gt;Onozukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mizukara&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book starts off with a quick summary and definition for &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;, and then has chapter on specific Japanese words, phrases, or expressions, their history, and their connection to &lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=15O--vfjvvxTUILT3ud41EMwJL4zKpuTD"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nviBkuSfALzyaI8H-lfMf_MTc3U862kR" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;span class='ja'&gt;ありがたい&lt;/span&gt; (thanks), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;めでたい&lt;/span&gt; (congratulations), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;あう&lt;/span&gt; (when meeting someone), &lt;span class='ja'&gt;あいする&lt;/span&gt; (loving someone), and so forth.  Maybe in the future, I’ll try and go through some of these chapters and write something about them.  For many people, though, Japanese philosophy is an incredibly dense topic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Relation to Myself&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1vatrNiCsgOmRwnn3vtQTS-EC-BD_hQD0"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14f_ebtjeh6vlsqM3467R6HhCVaV8BCGC" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Lecture Abstract&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese will often say things like &lt;i&gt;kekkon suru koto ni natta&lt;/i&gt; (I am to be married) or &lt;i&gt;shuushoku suru koto ni natta&lt;/i&gt; (I am to start work).  It should be expressed as "I decided to …"  Even if something is decided by the will of the individual (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;), it is expressed as something that has been predetermined for him or her as a matter of course (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  This in turn indicates a tendency to accept things in one’s life and the world as being naturally preordained and to be accepted passively.  The Japanese philosophers Kuki Shuuzou identified three elements in the features of Japanese thought: "nature" (&lt;i&gt;shizen&lt;/i&gt;), "chic" (&lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt;), and "resignation" (&lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt;).  This means that based on "natural" (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) conduct, when something occurs the individual decides from one’s self (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;) to confront the situation putting their own body on the line (for example, seppuku) in the spirit of "chicness" (&lt;i&gt;iki&lt;/i&gt;), while also resigning (&lt;i&gt;teinen&lt;/i&gt;) the self to go with the natural flow (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  The culture of Japanese thought is considered within the encounter between the movement of nature (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) and exertion of the self (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese budo culture is the same.  According to Kuki, "The ideas of Japanese morality maintain a significant meaning in universal nature (of &lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;)…  Morality which must reach the stage of becoming 'natural' cannot be seen as complete."  The term "morality" (&lt;i&gt;doutoku&lt;/i&gt;) can be replaced by the word "budo" here.  In bud, first engaging in rigorous training or study from your own volition (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;), if it does not ultimately become an inevitably natural (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;) activity then it "cannot be seen as complete."  To "&lt;i&gt;narau&lt;/i&gt;" (learn) means "to continually repeat things" thereby gradually becoming accustomed (&lt;i&gt;nare&lt;/i&gt;) to it, and "reaching the stage where it is natural."  In the culture of Japanese bud, there are correlations with moral, religious, and artistic thought in that one’s own efforts (&lt;i&gt;mizukara&lt;/i&gt;) will finally proliferate into and connect with natural expansiveness and depth (&lt;i&gt;onozukara&lt;/i&gt;).  Seen in this way, the features and potential become apparent.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/the-features-and-potential-of-japanese-budo-culture</link></item><item><title>Funayama 船山 in Winter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in a while, I had a day off with no plans at all.  I woke up around 6:15am, as usual, and looked out the window to see a beautiful site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1i74fuBKlhEyfQOVWS_PaMLjQUAfUdGjY"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ONvLmAOR1FTiy2NRGtXhRbc2yg-uw5fk" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mt. Norikura looked gorgeous.  The sky was quite clear.  And the sun was just below the true horizon about the rise.  I decided to grab my coat, put on my shoes, get in my car, and drive south to Funayama to catch one of the most fantastic views in Takayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went to Funayama about a year and a half ago (&lt;a href="/funayama"&gt;November 5th, 2016&lt;/a&gt;) and it was incredibly easy.  Because of the cell reception station and towers at the top of the mountain, there’s a paved road that goes all the way up.  And because of those buildings, I assumed the entire way would be plowed for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I was half right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1usla0Qm7sv5a9A0bXLSkSHScDuPs8Mxi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1SlMRgK40Z8Y560lgaM368Xgmu0TEpzQj" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XXSu9RqxNPIB0glThPMafO_CIqelRglH"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1EoxWtymi4fnU1CEfQmf_2W5AJGQzwhmn" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road leading to the top was plowed up to the cabins.  The sign near the fork of the road said it was another 2 km before reaching the top.  I thought, "that’s not that far.  I can run that in about 15 minutes."  Though, that would be on a flat course with no snow and ice.  I parked my car and started going up the path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow had hardened since it had fallen over a month ago.  With each step, I had to dig my boot into the snow to keep traction and move forward.  It wasn’t hard.  Just annoying.  If I had remembered to bring my snowshoes, I could have doubled my pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1HLgSuhP8w9o8N5DkWEkubFFD90oj8rD9"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1olreQTKrAiaUHVdAIZNFxDrJQwN-Tulb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=11f6gg-VJHw4UMy179lrE8noyCVe8Qzu7"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1z7jDrA1OST8XvSEiUg-7YZ6AHNeW2UgR" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me about 15 minutes to travel half a kilometer, and that’s when I reached a fork in the road.  The road was in the process of being plowed, but it was still too slippery for my car.  It was still too slippery for my boots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road curved around back and forth to make up the vertical distance without being too steep.  With each turn, a small building through the trees became more and more visible.  When I moved around the last turn, it was in clear site, as was the edge of the hill it sat on top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1PLGirsYoHGZ2AoHvljrFRoBjZdLeQsr5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=15xM9t0LWWeHfO3CrqDoCTDbHip8eCUME" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast" &gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LCcMNUnMwCe_N7bnwL-uyz7qrNdMLdHl"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qukXS57m2PqnlmInrjXuStHcyKkORZzE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1RT1wh7JfQvwox1uskvGwQS5roYZbYQ0p"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1GiGbgocWPtdhBp_hWi2T4gMqnDuVw3_5" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the top of the Arkopia ski hill on the Takayama-facing side of Funayama.  From the top of the hill, Mt. Ontake, Mr. Norikura, and the Mt. Hotaka range were all in clear view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1RIO0TYGaWjht4bSzNcTZmHp2RqNvnOAF"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1rJ-yLXG5qk6CTDj2Lq-nYP74qL_IFvZd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dQC-UESaYNtfctIvl42HcGbdxPXyKiJu"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aX3KiFPKF_hQmnxH9q46iYMMId5joP37" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a beautiful site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still had another kilometer left to climb, but having been up there before, the view was basically identical.  It would’ve taken me another hour to drudge up through the snow and take more photos of the view I already had in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took several pictures from where I was, but then headed back down to my car.  Most of the trip was sliding down the road using the flat trends of my boots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=14gKN4BsnYoUo5c4JKHr-r1gqgO4p4V2q"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LD4ouWIYM2vSdvSNuAaKUD7bVd7tdePt" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ever get the chance, whether it be summer or winter, Funayama offers one of the best views in the whole region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Timeline&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:09am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Camp Site &lt;span class='ja'&gt;キャンプ場所&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026147, 137.253332"&gt;36°01'34.1"N 137°15'12.0"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:22am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Road Fork &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026979, 137.249255"&gt;36°01'37.1"N 137°14'57.3"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:36am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Arkopia Peak &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.027811, 137.246809"&gt;36°01'40.1"N 137°14'48.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7:49am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Left Arkopia Peak &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.027811, 137.246809"&gt;36°01'40.1"N 137°14'48.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:01am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Road Fork &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026979, 137.249255"&gt;36°01'37.1"N 137°14'57.3"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8:13am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Camp Site &lt;span class='ja'&gt;キャンプ場所&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.026147, 137.253332"&gt;36°01'34.1"N 137°15'12.0"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/funayama-in-winter</link></item><item><title>Blade Runner 2049</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Blade Runner 2049 was a very overwhelming film when I saw it the first time.  A lot of that came from the sound, music, and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sound and music are very loud and unnerving.  It helps describe the enormity of the future and density of the city.  Much of the music drips of wet industry.  Loud sprawling flanges in wide shots.  Silence and subtle tones in movement.  The technology of the future feels organic and grown out of past that incorporated the technology into itself, rather than began anew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The art design compliments the music well.  The future iterates on the future shown 30 years ago in the original Blade Runner.  Displays are blocky monitors rather than flashy holograms.  Communication is done through these displays, rather than a smartphone-like device that keeps constant communication between people.  The future also feels organic and lived-in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Replicants in Blade Runner&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The premise of Blade Runner is that a corporation has developed technology to essentially manufacture people.  Replicants are not mechanical robots or cyborgs or something like that.  They are a completely organic manufactured person.  Designed to be less emotional and strong, they are mainly used off-world as a physical workforce or soldiers or whatever dirty-work humans don’t want to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first film, replicants are Nexus-6 models made by the Tyrell Corporation and are illegal to bring to earth.  Blade Runners are a section of the police force to capture or take out rogue replicants that somehow get to earth.  The main plot of Blade Runner follows Deckard, a blade runner, as he tracks down 4 rogue Nexus-6 models that have come to Los Angeles.  One significant aspect of the Nexus-6 model is their 4 year lifespan, which was used as a security deterrent if they were ever lost or escaped.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The secondary plot of Blade Runner follows Deckard’s relationship with Rachael, who is a prototype Nexus-7 model.  She was given memories and believes herself to be human.  The memories define her as a person, and as such cannot be easily detected as a replicant.  They’ve removed the lifespan limit as well.  The film also famously toys with the idea of whether or not Deckard himself is a Nexus-7 model, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result of the events of Blade Runner, the Nexus-6 models were deemed too unstable or uncontrollable for continued use, and Nexus-7 models never went to manufacturing and their designs lost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Replicants in Blade Runner 2049&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nexus-8 models were quickly developed by the Tyrell Corporation and sent to market.  Models had registration numbers imprinted on their eyes, and records of all models were kept in a central database.  Replicants were easy to tell apart from humans.  But the public rejected them because of how violent and problematic the Nexus-6 models were.  Many models were hunted down and killed in the streets on Earth.  This led to the events described in the short film, Blackout 2022.  Two replicants successfully destroy the database and detonate an EMP above Los Angeles to erase all records of Nexus-8 models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From that point on, replicants became strictly illegal.  All surviving Nexus-6 models died naturally.  Nexus-8 models went into hiding.  The Tyrell Corporation went out of business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the next decade, the infrastructure of Earth begins to deteriorate with the loss of the replicant workforce.  There are not enough people to sustain the ecosystem.  Niander Wallace of the Wallace Corporation buys the Tyrell Corporation and begins developing the Nexus-9 model of replicants.  These models are have the same feature of the Nexus-8 models, but designed to be absolutely loyal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the short film, Nexus Dawn 2036, Niander Wallace brings his new Nexus-9 model before congress, states his claim that humanity needs replicants and that the replicant-ban be revoked, and then demonstrates their obedience.  Congress moves to revoke the ban, allowing Wallace to mass-produce Nexus-9 replicants and help rebuild the Earth’s environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Blade Runner 2049, the main character is a Nexus-9 replicant, KD6-3.7, or "K" for short, played by Ryan Gosling.  He works for the LAPD as a Blade Runner tracking down remaining Nexus-8 models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Cells Interlinked&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To verify K’s operational stability, he is subject to a baseline recalibration test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1SLovz2o5Phetg0pJQauOJMJ0t1tKz4uC" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The test asks him a series of questions followed by a word of phrase he is meant to repeat.  The replicant is not meant to think or respond to the question, only the subsequent phrase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite parts of the film is how K’s obedience gradually and subtly erodes over time.  Much like the test, within his police work, he is meant to avoid or deflect questions while getting answers.  Within his investigation and daily life, every question is a test.  In the beginning, he doesn’t waver.  Sapper asks him questions.  He ignored them.  Luv asks him questions.  He deflects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides answering to his boss, played by Robin Wright, it’s only when Mackenzie Davis asks him a question, "What’s this?"  "A tree," that he responds directly to someone else’s question.  The first failure of the baseline test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WdYSwpyXeLnYcV051SB0DVjZNe29MdeE" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, he speaks with Robin Wright about the case and she asks him a direct question of the case, "What do these numbers mean?" or "Do these numbers mean anything to you?"  He replies, "No."  A lie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As K continues to investigate the whereabouts of a replicant born into this world, rather than manufactured, and as he starts to believe that he is that child, he starts to question his obedience and loyalty.  In following scenes, his stern emotionless face begins to crack under the weight of his feelings.  Through his blank face, we can feel his sadness, frustration, and confusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blade Runner 2049 follows K’s transformation from a mindless "robot" into someone fighting for himself and others and what he believes is the right course of action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Imagery&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the movie centers on K and his lack of emotion, so many scenes feel sterile and emotionally distant even though they are gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went through the film and picked out many images that shows the beauty of Blade Runner 2049’s art direction in set design, costume design, and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1EQ-pChFng9QoNMOrl92WDrpdoG8Nfo-Y" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-SiRkjHUCsZQCRiTyxYmm3WDtIBfHIRs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1KaT6VnJ9BqzKn7hsWQkUE838w-_1ny75" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19-ThonNp_znjBEivB3tVFjpfDTYPyNMO" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Denis Villeneuve&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, Blade Runner 2049 was definitely my favorite film of 2017.  It was directed by Denis Villeneuve, who directed my favorite film of 2016, too, &lt;a href="/arrival"&gt;Arrival&lt;/a&gt;.  Both movies were continuations and adaptations of previous works, but had a voice of their own, presented with a tense atmospheric soundtrack and beautiful visuals that engaged me completely.  I haven’t really seen any of his other films, but I’m definitely going to pay attention to whatever he does next.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/blade-runner-2049</link></item><item><title>January Total Lunar Eclipse</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, the US had a rare chance to observe a total solar eclipse.  During the day, the moon moved in front of the sun and cast parts of America in darkness for a short time.  Total lunar eclipses are not so rare and seem to happen fairly regularly.  The website &lt;a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/"&gt;https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/&lt;/a&gt; has a list of all their occurrences past and present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Living in Japan, I’ve already seen one total lunar eclipse in &lt;a href="/october-moon"&gt;October 2014&lt;/a&gt;.  It was a beautiful and clear night, so the red, blood moon cast in the Earth’s shadow was in clear clear view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This January, there was another total eclipse, which began around 8:30pm.  The weather was cloudy, but it was light with many breaks.  The moon was clearly visible in the sky.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was also cold cold cold.  It was definitely below zero.  Maybe -4?  I thought about driving to somewhere beautiful and open to view the eclipse, but it was just too cold for me to sit outside.  The moon was clearly visible from my apartment, so I simply set up my tripod in my kitchen, opened the window, and shot the moon from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1jDfNPVesxYtYdvaAZDt3_RioOraibZCU"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1LklZx-6FqOslkf04fKilg7nGpuorDnfh" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the lack of indoor heating in Japan, the cold temperature indoors really made no difference.  My apartment usually feels like it’s colder inside than outside anyway.  It only lacks the wind.  Besides, sitting under a pile of blankets (as I usually do at home) would be warmer than sitting around outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here was the schedule for the eclipse:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Penumbral begins - 7:50pm&lt;br/&gt;Partial begins - 8:50pm&lt;br/&gt;Full begins - 9:50pm&lt;br/&gt;Maximum - 10:30pm&lt;br/&gt;Full ends - 11:10pm&lt;br/&gt;Partial ends - 12:10pm&lt;br/&gt;Penumbral ends - 1:10pm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The penumbral is a partial shading or dimming of the moon as the Earth begins to eclipse the sun.  The partial is when the full shadow begins to engulf the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=193mfID3WaJl_xypufQm2IpBVwXp0MDAL"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1kkjZMYGTdY-axWksBiHBgo7fMhFXGNC0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the moon well into the penumbral and minutes before the partial began to creep.  I don’t really see much difference.  I guess maybe the moon dimmed a little bit more than normal, but it’s still in full view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But as the partial began, the moon definitely started to show a noticeable difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1IS2CLPtwTbxMo8LS6oEHBo3tWpt1cldr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dYufZiQWv__FAQHc3N2y2m_DBlaNFyhE" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shadow started to form in the lower left and, steadily over the next hour, it would move the completely cover the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as the moon continued to rise higher in the sky, it was met with more and more clouds.  The moon still showed through the clouds, but became dimmer and more obscured.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Bjv9nP6AwlqR0eGs2dMgj3bu1UDRTMdf"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_zlYpfmn9PQxt-b1KrJVV8NL6uuQ7ckV" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was still able to stretch the focal length of my camera and extend the exposure to capture the moon, but with time passing, the details and of the moon blurred more and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1pO9NIV14HMHF8-GYLfUTwhRsWjH_PBrB"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1d9hXDvSZhSEccD5WKSQliY-G-p3ZtcRO" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As 9:50pm approached and the total eclipse should have been visible, the cloud cover became too great, and I lost any visual of the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=18iZIiKkVehPvmj04LViQsqcXj-8sSKjM"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1CnMWkALOpGeMJ3EgYF1BcDCzSJktywv3" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s unfortunate, but I was glad to be able to see as much of the eclipse as I did.  I went outside a few times after to try and see it, but the clouds completely cover the sky.  I couldn’t even remotely tell where the moon would be behind the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not everywhere in Japan was covered up, though.  Down in Gifu City, it was a completely clear night.  Same with Nagoya and Tokyo.  There were some photographs that came out of Tokyo that are quite stunning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made a few animated gifs with the several photos of the eclipse I was able to take. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16cZui5H65p_Lr1_qrKxHeKPXsuYmIgtX" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1xL5qLt72UUJncXQkSWmmb-CKybdsvzWE" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next total lunar eclipse visible in Japan will be in July, but it’ll be an early morning eclipse rather than one at night.  It will be visible for a little while before the moon sets over the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/january-total-lunar-eclipse</link></item><item><title>Horizon Zero Dawn</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn was a game for the Playstation 4 released in March of 2017.  It’s an absolutely beautiful game set in the far future after current society had already collapsed.  Roaming the lands are robotic animals that human civilizations hunt and harvest for parts to build and protect their villages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the moment it was first shown at E3 in 2015, everyone wanted to know more about it.  The concept looked interesting and unique.  Unfortunately, it’s release in early 2017 was completely blown away by The Legend of Zelda Breath of the Wild.  On the surface, both games were an open world that lent itself towards exploration.  But Zelda had many aspects that innovated and expanded the genre compared to Horizon’s iterative approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, unlike Zelda’s pure sense of exploration, Horizon’s strong sense of story fueled my exploration of the game’s world.  How did the world turn out like this?  Why are their robotic animals running around?  What is going on?  Underneath the lush beauty of nature are several metallic facilities of a futuristic society long dead.  Why?  And by the end, there are satisfactory answers to these questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Combat feels great.  Every beast you encounter has a weakness to exploit, or some specialized parts to harvest.  After a while, you are given enough equipment to take on these enemies in a variety of ways.  You can set traps, or blow off body parts.  Fire down arrows from safety, stealthily melee enemies from bushes, or just run in and attack directly.  It’s fun, and certainly challenging on higher difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout my play through of the game, I stopped several times to use the photo mode and take a picture of the environment around me.  So many shots and scenes in this game is incredibly gorgeous, and the photo mode made everything come out great.  Every game should have a photo mode at this point.  Below are all the shots that I kept.  They include areas and scenes from the DLC, as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/horizon-zero-dawn</link></item><item><title>Final Fantasy XV</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite it’s many flaws, I like Final Fantasy XV quite a bit.  The story was quite clumsy.  It’s representation of women was poor.  And some sequences in the game required some patching and reworking from the developers.  But, I loved the music, setting, and, most of all, the main cast of characters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of the game, all the way through until the end, you play as Noctis and have your three friends, Gladiolus, Prompto, and Ignis, by your side at all times.  At the beginning, as a player, I didn’t really care for them.  In previous Final Fantasy games, the other cast members are just kinda there.  They have their one or two story moments, and for the rest of the game, they don’t talk or add anything to the experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Final Fantasy XV, your three friends, the other party members, constantly talk about pretty much everything that’s going on.  Noctis doesn’t really say a whole lot unless it’s a pivotal story point.  I think most people get annoyed about this.  But after a while, it’s just the norm.  And their character shows through all of the interactions they have.  The friendship between the four characters isn’t really explained.  It’s felt.  It’s atmospheric.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first half of the game, none of this really has an impact.  You basically take your party members, your friends, for granted.  Then, at a certain point in the game, things change that impact your friendship.  They become quiet and sometimes scornful.  I was able to feel the magnitude of the decisions and consequences of the previous events through the change in atmosphere.  I had come to care for these characters, and now that things had changed.  It felt tense and sad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it wasn’t just getting passed what had happened or about trying to get things back to the way they were.  It was about living with the decisions that were made, and moving forward.  And moving forward together as a group, rather than breaking apart forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being able to feel this connection to the characters and being able to relate to this kind of conflict through my own life was really powerful.  The localizers did an excellent job conveying this dynamic between the characters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Photos&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, one of the other great things about the game is the photographer of the group, Prompto.  Throughout play, he passively takes photos at somewhat random points.  When you take a rest at the end of the day, you can go through these photos and keep the ones you like.  Sometimes these photos even capture some glitches or bugs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are all the ones I’ve kept.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/final-fantasy-xv</link></item><item><title>Kendo San-dan 三段</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;剣道三段に合格しました&lt;/span&gt;！&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right on track.  After passing the ni-dan test two years ago, I’ve been able to continue practicing and learning more about the Japanese martial art of kendo.  And last weekend, I was able to pass the 3rd level of dan, san-dan, in kendo.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the sensei giving the test, I am the first foreigner to pass this test in Gifu.  Breakin’ boundaries!  Though, that title obviously comes with some caveats.  There are plenty of other foreigners living in Japan that have passed this test, and are way higher rank than me.  They just don’t live in Gifu.  If Gifu had a higher foreign population, someone would’ve passed this test long ago.  It’s more a sign of foreign folk living in more remote areas of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was certainly nervous going into the test.  I understood everything that was required of me, but I wasn’t sure if I could do everything perfectly and correctly.  I don’t think I would’ve been able to pass if it wasn’t for my new job working at Takayama Nishi High School, and practicing kendo with the students, especially the 3rd year students, nearly every day for the last two months.  It was really rewarding taking the same test with those students, and all of us passing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passing the test with my 3rd year high school students is also very apt because I feel like san-dan level is analogous to high school level proficiency and knowledge in kendo.  Passing san-dan is like graduating high school in kendo.  And, in a few months, the 3rd year students will actually graduate high school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;Dan Levels&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I previously remarked that passing ni-dan just felt like a stepping stone.  San-dan was the true next test.  But, after talking with some people about it, I don’t think that’s exactly true.  In fact, I think the high school analogy works pretty well.  The 1st grade kyu, or ikkyu, is equivalent to elementary school proficiency.  1st grade dan is like the beginning of junior high school, and 2nd grade dan is completing junior high school.  3rd grade dan is completing high school.  After completing high school, you’re an adult in kendo.  Fully proficient in kendo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next level is 4th grade dan, which could be thought of as completing college.  You are now a full professional in kendo.  Kendo is no longer just something you did, it is something you do.  You have proven that you are kendo.  With the next grade, 5th dan, it’s like completing a masters or a phd program.  You are not only a professional kendo practitioner, but also a specialist in kendo.  Typically, 4th and 5th grade dan are the lowest levels where one leads their own dojo or has a sensei status within their own dojo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond that are 6th, 7th, and 8th dan.  These levels are only awarded on a national level.  A practitioner is now nationally recognized as a master in kendo.  Even though kendo is a life of continued study of the art, most lessons are learned through teaching others, and contributing to the martial art as a whole.  You are now a master that others look up to.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I think this is a pretty good comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having passed the test of adulthood in kendo (3rd grade), the next step is becoming a professional in the martial art (4th grade).  Apparently, people consider this the next big step.  Probably because of the age requirements.  4th grade dan is the first level only adults can take.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Gifu, 4th and 5th grade dan tests are only done twice a year and with everyone in the prefecture.  Up through 3rd dan, the proctors travel around to different regions several times throughout the year.  It’s a much bigger deal with much fewer practitioners taking the test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, for me, that’s in 3 years.  It’s not enough to simply "cram" for the test starting 2 months in advance.  I need to continue practicing throughout these next 3 years and retain the ideals of my current grade so I’m able to reach beyond it.  Thankfully, I work at the perfect school and live in a great town to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update: March 1st&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, all of the 3rd year students graduated from high school.  We also received everyone’s certificate for completion of 3rd grade dan back in November, so they were able to get them before they left officially left school.  It’s very fitting (though also convenient) to get them today as I consider passing san-dan as the equivalent of completing high school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got my certificate, too. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1MLzrWoOE3DeHRW31_3HkHlNMq5nyC1UO"&gt;&lt;img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1JDf13RAWnnYusdMvEtjIrFDstchJVyBH" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having now mastered the basics of doing kendo for myself, 4th grade dan and up is the study of being able to instructor others on the best ways to do kendo and guide them on the right path while sharpening your own skills.  And as high school students graduate, they continue to university and college and do exactly that with either kendo or their own profession.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://theschlock.com/kendo-sandan</link></item></channel></rss>