<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>One Schlock's Requiem is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher of English living in central Japan.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:53:38 +0900</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:53:38 +0900</lastBuildDate><link>http://theschlock.com/</link><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://theschlock.com/feed.xml"/><category>Japan / Games / Other Stuff</category><item><title>Digital Retro Game Library</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My retro gaming hardware collection has grown recently. The Analogue Pocket introduced me into a gaming platform possible of playing decades of games across dozens of consoles, handhelds, and arcade boards. Recently, I got a Mister which expanded this reach even further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, I made a &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games" title="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; that catalogued all of the notable games I had on my Analogue Pocket. And now I've revamped that curated list into an overall Digital Retro Game Library. This lists all the notable games I have available on both the Pocket and the Mister. More platforms may be added in the future, like PS2 and Gamecube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/pocket" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/pocket"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Digital Retro Game Library&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/pocket" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/pocket"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/241030_gamelibrary/IMG_5723_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playlists&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally, these games were being collected to build Genre lists of games using the now-canceled Playlist feature for the Analogue Pocket. The idea was that I could scroll through a Genre of games and choose one to play without having to pay attention to the hardware platform it was designed for. I was collecting all this information using &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils" title="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-utils"&gt;Pocket Utils&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of Java programs that I wrote to manage games and stuff on my Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, after the Playlist feature was buried and gone, I decided to put all of this information into a webpage so I could at least see everything visually. This was the &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games" title="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket-curated-games"&gt;Pocket Curated Games&lt;/a&gt; page, the first iteration of this project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later again and recently, I got a Mister. The Mister is the premiere FPGA gaming platform, and the Analogue Pocket is a handheld FPGA device. FPGA cores are written for specific hardware, so there are advantages to both platforms, although the Mister can generally handle more complicated systems and it's open source. Because of this, people have built several features and accessories on top of the platform. One thing implemented a couple years ago was Shortcuts. Rather than turning on a core and choosing a game, you could choose a game directly from the main menu. This is exactly like how I wanted Playlists to work on the Analogue Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by updating the programs in Pocket Utils to look for Mister games, I could add all that information in the database. And writing a new program, I could automatically make shortcuts to all the games I have managed in my database, essentially creating all the Playlists I wanted from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pocket Curated Page being revamped into the Digital Retro Game Library now shows all those games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Launching Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's another really nice feature available on the Mister called TapTo. TapTo is a service that runs in the background on Mister and accepts game executing commands. The main idea for this feature was to bring back physicality to the Mister, which is a sole digital platform. Using a physical NFC reader you can "tap" a physical NFC card (or anything with an NFC signal) and it will automatically launch the game associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not interested in having a huge collection of cards for individual games. But, I was very interested in TapTo's feature of launching RANDOM games. By sorting all of my shortcuts to games in Genre folders, I could launch a random Shooter or random Fighter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the TapTo service was upgraded to accept network requests. Any device connected to the same Wifi network could send a command to TapTo and it'll execute it. They launched a phone app that took advantage of this, but the request service is wide open. Anything can send commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, combining yet another project with this, I added functionality in my chat bot, &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/schlock-bot" title="http://theschlock.com/schlock-bot"&gt;Schlock Bot&lt;/a&gt;, to accept requests to launch random games from my Genres. With Pocket Utils updated to manage my Mister games, Schlock Bot can read this information too, and launch individual games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;!game Shooter&lt;br/&gt;!game Panzer Dragoon (Saturn)&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These commands can be typed in my Discord and read by Schlock Bot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Going Further&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One annoying thing about typing in games to launch in Discord is that you have to type them correctly. Dr. Mario has a period in it, so if you type Dr Mario, it won't find the game. Also, I have a Gameboy Color version of Dr. Mario, too, so which one do you want? You need to be annoyingly specific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, using the Digital Game Library, you can click on a game, it'll write that execution command in Discord, Schlock Bot will read the command (if it's running), and then launch the game on Mister (if that's running too).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As such, the Digital Retro Game Library not only shows all my available games, but it's also a method of selecting games to play on the Mister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of moving parts in between clicking a game and it launching on the Mister. It would be a lot better if the webpage sent the request to Schlock Bot directly. But, this janky thing works for the time being. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Future Additions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the Library, prior to getting a Mister, I set up a Playstation 2 with a game server to play all of those classic games. I made an &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory" title="http://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory"&gt;inventory&lt;/a&gt; page that shows all of those games, but I'm thinking about adding them in this library, too. Also, I may mod a gamecube in the future to play a library of those games. I will want to have a library of those games listed somewhere, so adding them here or on the PS2 inventory page makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to more games, I was thinking of putting download links to my save files for each game, too. I'm already doing this on the PS2 Game Inventory page with memory cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll see. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category><category>Internet</category><category>Programming</category><category>Local</category></item><item><title>The Callisto Protocol</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You are a space trucker on your last mission before retirement. You're carrying some medical supplies from the prison on Callisto to Europa, both moons of Jupiter. But, shit goes wrong when terrorists responsible for a biological attack on Europa board your ship, attack you, and ultimately send your vessel back into Callisto's atmosphere, and crash on the surface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You survive the crash, but your copilot is dead. All members of the terror group are dead, except one. As the moon's guards discover the crash and find you, both of you are taken to the prison. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things get even worse when the pathogen from the biological attack spreads in the prison mutating many of the inmates into deranged violent abominations. The prison begins the fall apart allowing you to mount an escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825192638_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how the story of Callisto Protocol begins. You are Jacob Lee, who's just a normal dude put into extreme circumstances. On the surface, it seems like a pretty standard action adventure game with an involved story and twists here and there. But, this game ends up living in the shadow of another, which dominates the conversation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Derivative&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as Callisto Protocol may want to stand on its own, it's hard to talk about it without talking about &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/dead-space" title="http://theschlock.com/dead-space"&gt;Dead Space&lt;/a&gt;. Callisto Protocol comes from one of the original creators of Dead Space, and has some members of the old team, too. Callisto tries its best to emulate what made Dead Space so great, but fails on almost every front. It takes some cues from &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/the-last-of-us-part-2" title="http://theschlock.com/the-last-of-us-part-2"&gt;Last of Us&lt;/a&gt; as well, but it feels like a rip-off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enemies and Combat&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, we be fighting zombies again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Dead Space and Last of Us have zombies and while the high points of both those games go far behind their enemy designs, the enemies are still interesting. The necromorphs in Dead Space had a very dynamic design that supported the combat. The infected in Last of Us were detailed enough that you could see how the fungal infection grew and mutated their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240825203241_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yep, that's a zombie. In Callisto, the biophages just look like dudes with skin problems. Later, you fight some others that look like Clickers from Last of Us. And then you fight deaf zombies EXACTLY like Clickers from Last of Us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One departure from Dead Space is that Callisto isn't a shooter first, but a brawler. You bob and weave incoming attacks and counter with a melee weapon, so it makes sense the zombies are more like crazed humans. But now we're doing Arkham Batman combat, and Arkham Batman combat was not this stiff. Batman combat was designed around fighting multiple enemies at once, and you could react to them working together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Callisto often struggles with this. Every attack has weight to it, but that weight often pushes you into a position you don't want. Other enemies then attack or you get stuck in a corner looking the wrong direction. It hard to tell where enemies are coming from if they aren't in front of you. Jacob isn't nimble enough to run around and take out enemies, so you always have to focus on them one-at-a-time, which slows down the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you're already moving pretty slow. In Dead Space, Isaac's slow movement made sense because you're moving around in a 200lbs suit meant for protection from environmental and occupational hazards. You're like a tank. In Callisto, you're only wearing a cloth prison jump suit. Jacob isn't some huge muscle dude, either. He looks like he could sprint down a hall way and slip past a group of people. Later, you get an EVA suit, but it looks flexible enough to move easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Environment and Immersion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key points of Dead Space was its immersive environment supported by the heavy futuristic machinery, dynamic lighting and color, and a sharp distinct and unique set of sounds that overwhelmed you. Incorporating all of the HUD and UI elements into the character and environment made you feel immersed in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last of Us had a similar approach. There were still some UI elements that assisted the player through exploration and combat, but the lack of music and use of silence matched with the vibrant lush overgrown environments which immersed me in the exploration of Seattle and listening for the subtle movements of enemies around blind corners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both games felt designed around the opportunity to give creative people a chance to make the most of their opportunities, and create dynamic and memorable experiences. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212920_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Callisto has some unique areas, but the first half of the game is moving through drab metal hallways and then the prison's sewer system. Lots of pipes and moving through vents. The arboretum is a nice area, but it's dark and muddy. Later, you visit an old mining area. The density of buildings and their layout is interesting, but the buildings themselves aren't very interesting. The environments are definitely detailed, but they don't really inspire creativity in me. It feels too restrictive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest flop of Callisto is its lack of dynamic sound. There's no unique sound of heavy machinery working. There's no sharp crack of gun fire or welding tools. There's no use of silence to accent the enemies movements. And overall, the music is pretty generic and used too frequently. There are no surprises or memorable experiences through sound, which dampens the overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the monotony is broken up by breaking out onto the surface of Callisto. You put on an EVA and are shot out into the environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836.webp"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240827212836_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow is pushed around by your foot steps and moving gates. While trying to find your way to the space depot, the blizzard often overwhelms your vision. At least now, Jacob's slow lumbering movements make sense. If Jacob could move faster or more dynamically, I would've loved to stay outside longer, but everything just seems to weigh down the experience that I want to move on to the next section as quick as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, we get another unique area, the clean living area of the administration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901192951_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game could've used more unique areas like this. But, we're in a prison and we're climbing through sewers and mines. There aren't many opportunities to have fantastical elements while making the setting down-to-earth. Perhaps Callisto Protocol tries to bring too much reality to its setting. As a result, all of the edges feel sanded off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;What a Twist!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through attempting to escape, you journey into the depths of Callisto to an abandoned mining colony from 75 years ago, and discover the truth of the biophage outbreak. Can you guess?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, it turns out the government was behind the biophage attack on Europa, not the terrorists. And the terrorists were people caught up in the attack who blamed the government. The reason you were caught up in everything, too, was because the medical supplies you transported to Europa were hiding the viral agent that started the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;75 years ago, the first outbreak occurred in this mining colony as the scientists responsible for the biophage tested their progress. Once the outbreak was concealed, the prison was built on top of it to continue testing the biophage virus on inmates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901142817_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was aliens all along. The miners had discovered the corpse of a massive alien and studied its secrets. The government agency funding this science believed the larvae of the alien could help human ascend to the next level of evolution allowing them to expand within the universe further. The biophage virus was the result of their research, and injecting humans was meant to make them impervious to the harsh environment of space. But, whatdya know, it just turned them into monsters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Callisto Protocol is the development of this biophage to push humanity to the next level of evolution, and its eventually release and conversion of all humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240901194403_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They got pretty close making an evolved human with this guy. But eventually he also turns into a mindless monster and you gotta shoot him in the face anyway. With their prime experiment defeated, the government (actually a crazed religious group) sets the prison to self-destruct. With only one escape pod available, you shove your friend into it and she escapes along with records of the event and a sample of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You are still stuck on the planet and the game ends as the monster jumps at you. No real ending, just a few words and cut to black.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continued in DLC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the $15 DLC, the story continues. You wake up with the doctor speaking to your through an earpiece. Get up! There are more secrets to be had! You travel to her lab and her hologram explains about the further experiments and atrocities. There was a competing experiment being held to push humans to the next stage of evolution. And you find out that the doctor led the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You stumble further down into her lab into far more interesting, detailed, and amazing looking areas than the main game. Areas use a lot of orange light to break away from the boring metal blue walls and floors. Bio-matter spreads and grows from the walls transforming it into an alien or infested looking environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906214812_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is often difficult to tell whether something is going to come out of the wall to get you, or whether danger is just around the corner. The terrible "mood" music and jump scares are turned down and used in actual appropriate moments compared to the main game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sanity effects are now used, too, as it feels like Jacob is slowing falling apart mentally. You open up a treasure chest to receive nothing, and turn around to find the chest in front of you again, but unopened. You move down a hallway as enemies continuously attack you, not realizing the path forward is to turn around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;A New Enemy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something new appears in the depths of the labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907143246_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prison bots from before have been infected and fused with bio-matter making them stronger and more aggressive than before. It's still not too difficult to dodge out of the way and slam them with your electrified police baton, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, as you enter the laboratory in the police bot factory, your baton is destroyed after beating a bot over and over again to its death. Your main weapon used throughout the entire game and a fundamental staple of how the game play works is removed from your arsenal. You can no longer easily dodge and counter enemies. The brawler has turned into a clumsy shooter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not long before you are chased into a test room with bots closing in on all of your sides when you obtain the best funnest weapon in the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240906233036_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hammer replaces your police baton and smashes through bots after a few hits. Zombies from before are cut through like butter. Up until this point, the whole game felt like you're fighting against the gameplay. Eventually you find a rhythm that works, but it ends up becoming a single use solution to every encounter. Now you feel incredible and powerful by slicing and smashing through everything that sucked about the game before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, the Callisto Protocol is the development of the biophage to push humanity into the next stage of evolution. Their main plan ended up turning people into zombie monsters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctor had a different idea and tried to compete with them. The doctor created these bio-bots as her solution to humanity's evolution. The bots were fused with human skin, muscles, and brain using the alien biophage material. Human consciousness was then uploaded into the bots for humanity to live on forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn't work. Just like the zombies, the bots became mindless machines of destruction and ripped apart anything that was human, relying too much on the prison's programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctor had been luring you further into the depths of the lab to reach an escape pod she had prepared for herself. As you arrive near the hatch, the doctor is grabbed by a robot. The bot infects and mutates the doctor into an abomination that you juke, jive, and smash until it's dead. With the doctor's voice still in your ear, you proceed to the escape pod.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The escape pod is your ship, though. It's your destroyed ship that crashed into Callisto in the beginning. The doctor directs you to hop on the controls and get out of there. You escape the prison, escape the moon. You continue to fly as far away as fast as you can. And space begins to light up. The light gets brighter and brighter to point where you can't see anything but white.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/callisto_protocol/The_Callisto_Protocol_20240907145107_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's done. You're done. You're dead. You've been dead this whole time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As your friend had escaped earlier with all the lab's data, you were killed as the enemies closed in. The doctor found your body, and ignited the few remaining sparks in your brain. The doctor used the implant in your head linked to your friend in order to send the remaining data she had exposing the government's horrific projects on Callisto, and her involvement in the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It felt like the DLC was going to give some full closure to the ending. And I suppose it did. Callisto Protocol no longer ends on a cliffhanger. But, it's not a happy ending and it completely closes the book on Jacob's story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Real Life Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people feel cheated by the ending, and further cheated by paying $15 to get an ending that punches them in the face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The publisher ultimately is to blame for the abrupt ending and pay-per-view ending. Krafton cut the development time towards the end of the project and forced the release date ahead of schedule. New enemy types were scrapped from the game, and the ending had to be reworked into what we got. It's pretty obvious that some of those scrapped ideas were remolded into the DLC ending.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's poetic and perhaps intentional that the final scene is of Jacob's horrific torn-apart corpse, a signal from the developer that there is no future for this game, and a metaphor of what the developers perhaps consider the result of their ideas and hard work after the publisher forced their hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It sucks even more that after the release of the DLC, the developer laid off employees as the publisher realigned the focus of the studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it's easy to say Callisto Protocol is kinda lame and not all that great, but I think the DLC shows that this game and its developer had the potential to make something better and more compelling than what we got. Not everyone gets a blank check, though. And very few publishers want to take a risk. Everything has to be a financial hit these days. There's no longer any room for mediocrity even if it has some kernels of something good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I'm glad I played it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol</link><category>Games</category><category>Game Specific</category></item><item><title>Dead Space</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Within the expanse of humanity's reach into space, the repair vessel, the Kellion, responds to a distress call sent by the USG Ishimura. The Ishimura is a massive mining starship in orbit above the planet Aegis VII, and the distress call was the last communication with anyone on board. Among the Kellion's sparse crew is Isaac Clarke, an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Clarke and the Kellion crew board the derelict malfunctioning ship, they are attacked by transformed mutated members of the crew, known as Necromorphs. The Kellion is destroyed, and Clarke and a few other members of the Kellion begin to explore and repair the Ishimura in order to escape and find out what happened to the crew. Isaac dons his heavy duty repair suit with iconic welding helmet, an overall staple of the Dead Space series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817190714_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is a survival horror game with heavy inspirations from Resident Evil 4 and Event Horizon. Originally released in 2008, Dead Space become one of the genres best examples of survival horror done right, but eventually the series fizzled out as it became more action oriented, which was reason enough for Electronic Arts to shut down the developer's studio. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, EA Motive, the developers of this 2023 remake, insisted that this new game stick closely to its 2008 original, which I consider the best in the series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Immersion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space was unique upon release as one of its strict design ideas was using absolutely no HUD. All ammo, health, and menus are displayed within the universe of the characters, as if the character themselves are looking at and using those displays. All button prompts appear on the objects in the environment. If a menu appears, it comes from Isaac's computer Rig on his wrist, and he looks at it when you select menu items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, the true crown of Dead Space's immersion is the Audio. The Ishimura is a very dense, heavy, mining vessel. All the different areas have their thick heavy machines, and these machines are all distinct and loud. Often when you enter a new area, you become completely overwhelmed by the sounds of the machinery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite areas in the original was Engineering. As you kickstarted the engines, the overall sound was so loud you couldn't hear any enemies or footsteps or menu movements. It was a constant blast of sound until you exited the room. This area still exists in the remake, but they moved it into a corridor instead of the overall room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240818204204_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isaac is really just a repairman, and all of your weapons futuristic versions of welders, strippers, nail guns, and such. All of these guns have very powerful and electrical cracks and bursts that you may hear at a futuristic construction site. All these sounds feel like they split your ears as you rip apart the space zombies. With your heavy, 200lbs armored suit, you can also stomp them into the ground with a satisfying crunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything in the environment and everything you do comes with a heavy mechanical organic weight to it. It's criminal if you don't play this game with headphones turned up to 11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240817203233_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, one of the most impactful and immersive sequences is the first time you open a door, and all of the air and sound get blasted into space from a violent hull breach. Your suit's boots are magnetized so space walking is no problem, but the first time you get thrust into space feels like going over the top of a rollercoaster. It feels like part of your own breath was sucked into space, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Haunted House&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you continue to explore and repair the Ishimura, you move into new areas of the ship with new monsters. Often you'll reach a place of relatively quiet, only for a monster to SCREAM at you as it burst out of the ceiling or a nearby wall. This happens pretty often. As the game's sound fully immerses you in the environment, it tends to employ startling scare tactics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You get pretty powerful later on in the game, so when a standard zombie pops out of the wall, you can quick shoot it or bash it into the ground. Even when a bunch of zombies come at you at once, you can usually take them all at once with your arsenal. So, many of these sequences turn into a corner of a haunted house. Boo!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the first time you fight a Brute can make you feel powerless. A brute is a gigantic zombie about the size of a car. When it comes rushing towards me and my gunfire has absolutely no effect, my next instinct is to run! But then the heavy suit makes it feel like you're trying to run in water, and its huge stomping lumbering movements are right on your heels. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822085322_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some genuine fearful movements as you try to evade death, but ultimately, you can overcome these moments by trying again after you die. Later on, you learn about the best ways of killing things by fighting the zombies over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;People generally define retro games as anything made over 10 years ago. This was an easy statement to make in the PS3/360 era of gaming, as each new console had some genuine easy-to-see graphical and design improvements over the previous generation. For example, Super Mario World and Super Mario Sunshine were 11 years apart, and the difference between those games of the same series is absolutely massive. The jump from 2D to 3D was huge, but so is the idea of having to explore the world to find levels, having a more involved story with characters having motivations, and talking with characters to find more things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The time difference between the original Dead Space and this remake is 15 years, and the overall game hasn't really changed at all. The graphics have been modernized, and load times reduced because of current generation hardware. A few quality of life features added for smoother gameplay. Isaac talks now and involves himself in the story, too. But it's still the exact same game that I remember from the Playstation 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are games from the PS3/360 era really retro if their game design still fits within the modern era of game design?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240822090323_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe some people consider games retro if they center on a single player experience. Most modern games today have some kind of social element, so you can share the experience with friends. Or they include some kind of open world experience, so it can feel like the game is endless and you can play for hours and hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is a pretty tight 12 hour game, and adding any of those modern engagement traps would ruin the experience. But, at the same time, once you finish the game (and finish it a second time), you're pretty much done with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Legacy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the original Dead Space, the studio became known as Visceral Games and made Dead Space 2 and Dead Space 3, as well as Dead Space Extraction (a light gun game), and some novels and comics. Dead Space 2 was another high for the series, but I think there was never enough lore and story to carry it to a full never-ending franchise. Dead Space 2 started the series into something more action-oriented to appeal to a general audience, and Dead Space 3 killed the franchise and the developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The creator of Dead Space had actually left Visceral before Dead Space 2, and recently he helmed the creation of a new game, &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;Callisto Protocol&lt;/a&gt; released in 2022, which seems like an actual new Dead Space game in all but name. It's either ironic or malicious that EA came along with the Dead Space remake at the same time the original creator made a new one himself. However much of Visceral's former staff work at Motive and were key developers bringing this remake to life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dead Space remake does an absolutely excellent job of sticking to the original but adding a few new things and changing others to make it even better. This remake doesn't really feel like a cash-grab. It feels like the people working on it genuinely cared about Dead Space and wanted to bring it back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it really sucks that the remake did not meet the sales EA was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through killing space zombies and finding some survivors, Isaac uncovers the truth of what happened on the Ishimura. Members of the crew became obsessed and possessed by the religion of Unitology, which revolves around an artifact found of Aegis VII, known as The Marker. The Marker slowly morphed the colonists of Aegis VII into the Necromorphs, which attacked and infected the crew of the Ishimura.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the surface of Aegis VII is the Hive Mind, which controls all Necromorphs. In order to pacify and destroy it, Isaac brings the Marker back to the surface of Aegis VII. There are several other twists and turns along the way as Isaac is betrayed by his crew, and caught between the motives of Earth and the Church of Unitology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it turns out that his love interest that he's been chasing the whole game killed herself prior to the Kellion arriving at the Ishimura. He's essentially been chasing a ghost through manipulation of the Marker and an Ishimura survivor. With nothing left, Isaac continues to kill the Hive Mind, and escape the surface as the gravity tethers holding the Ishimura are severed, which sends the ship and its moon-sized payload into the planet, eradicating all remaining life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally Isaac gets to rest after a job well done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240823111503_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, except the Marker left its mark on Isaac. In the final moments of the game, the phantom of his girlfriend attacks him. Dead Space 2 picks up with Isaac awakening in an asylum above Saturn's moon of Titan, the doctors having extracted the remnants of the Marker from his brain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;New Ending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now there's a new, alternate ending. As Isaac runs through the Ishimura a second time, small Markers are scattered throughout the ship. Collecting all of these Markers and placing them on their alters in the Captain's quarters will unlock this ending. Now, after Isaac pacifying the Hive Mind and letting the megaton payload destroy the surface, he is no longer so solemn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/dead_space/Dead_Space_20240825121558_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a course set back to Earth, he mentions to the phantom of his girlfriend that he needs to build something first before they can return. Isaac has been fully corrupted and possessed by the Marker, it seems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Motive had plans to make a Dead Space 2, but as an alternate sequel rather than a remake of the original sequel. This sequel probably could've followed this new ending, and maybe implement some of the original ideas the creators had for Dead Space 2 back in the day, rather than some mandates EA imposed on Visceral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EA seemed keen on continuing the remake series, but plans were scrapped as sales were poor. Motive is off working on other projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dead Space is dead yet again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hope&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to check out &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="http://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;Callisto Protocol&lt;/a&gt; next and see if there's any life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/dead-space</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/dead-space</link><category>Games</category><category>Game Specific</category></item><item><title>Emperor and The Imperial Palace 皇居</title><description>&lt;p&gt;After the United States dropped the atomic bombs on Japan, they surrendered to the United States. This was announced to the nation on August 15th, 1945, seventy-nine years ago. In the following days, officers of the United States military came to Japan, and oversaw the occupation which would rebuild Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In these first few days, the American public wanted immediately and swift revenge for Pearl Harbor and Japan's involvement in the war. It was easy to place a target on the figurehead of Japan, Emperor Hirohito. To the typical American, the Emperor was like a king, and a king commands its armies to attack. So, surely Emperor Hirohito commanded Japan's army and navy to attack Pearl Harbor and enter the war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Supreme Commander Douglas MacArthur arrived in Japan to lead the occupation, one of his first assignments was given to General Bonner Fellers. This assignment was to determine the extent of the Emperor's involvement in the war. Did he give the command to attack? Did he give the command to invade?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the overall plot of the 2012 film, Emperor, starring Tommy Lee Jones as Douglas MacArthur and Matthew Fox as Bonner Fellers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster-2.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster-2_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster-2_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/emperor-poster-2_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;General Bonner Fellers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film focuses on Bonner Fellers. MacArthur entrusts Fellers with this mission of determining the Emperor's guilt because of Fellers close relation and expertise of Japan. After arriving in Tokyo, various members of the Japanese military are arrested, and Fellers oversees the operation understanding how these officers value sacrifice in the wake of defeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The arrested officers are interrogated and seemingly uncooperative. Fellers understands the ambiguity of their answers, but is still frustrated with the lack of substantial proof and direct answers required for making a clear decision to MacArthur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h58m49s738.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h58m49s738.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h58m49s738_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h58m49s738_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h58m49s738_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my initial favorite things about Emperor was Feller's frustration. Fellers (and Matthew Fox's acting) clearly shows a love and respect for Japan, but he is constantly beat down, turned away, and disrespected by its people. He understands the damned future Japan would have without an Emperor, so he continues to fight for the answers despite the constant problems. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This feeling of frustration is the initial reason why this film stayed with me. I immediately identified with these feelings having lived here for a few years when seeing it for the first time. This feeling of working towards the same goal as others, but being pushed aside because I'm a perceived outsider, thus being perceived as an opponent or someone that wouldn't understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Honne and Tatemae &lt;span class='ja'&gt;本音と建前&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the film recently with my Japanese language students, I had forgotten that it spent some time explaining Japanese culture. One of the key points of the film was a flashback between Fellers and his fictional girlfriend's uncle, General Kajima. The uncle explains &lt;b&gt;Honne&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Tatemae&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h59m19s716.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h59m19s716.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h59m19s716_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h59m19s716_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h59m19s716_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tatemae&lt;/b&gt; is the way that things appear. The uncle explains to Fellers that when you look at Japan (in 1930s/40s), you see the most advanced and westernized country in all of Asia. &lt;b&gt;Honne&lt;/b&gt; is the way they really are. Underneath this westernized surface is the true heartbeat of Japan, which runs on the ancient warrior code of loyalty and obedience. From this explanation that Fellers learned before the war, he understands that without the Emperor as a symbol to guide the public, Japan would fall into chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This concept of Honne and Tatemae is ever present in modern Japan. They consider and cherish group harmony over everything else. They do this because on the surface conflict will create rifts between individuals and eventually break that harmony. So, they often contribute and conform to the group to avoid social strife. This is why everyone perceives Japanese people as super nice and accommodating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's not to say Japanese don't complain. When they do complain, they complain to their own social circles about something outside of it. It's often a way to bring people in their circle together. And if they complain more outwardly (like on Twitter), it's as an individual completely detached from their circles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe this sounds obvious and not really foreign to America, but it's something that foreign people who come to Japan often struggle with, especially when a Japanese person says one thing, but then does the opposite. The classic example is being invited to someone's home. They'll say, "You should come over to my house." They'll often do this as way to be nice and create harmony, but usually they expect you to decline, something like, "Oh, I'd love to some day." They don't want you to say, "Ok, when?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Group Harmony formed from Ancient History&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't remember if the subject was Honne and Tatemae, but one of my college professors once mentioned that the culture of group harmony and being nice was born from being such a small country with limited resources. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japan has very clear natural outer borders, and plenty of mountains creating internal borders, too. Space for creating towns with agriculture was limited to few areas. Self-sustaining communities didn't have a lot of extra food, so if you stole from your neighbors or created problems, you would be banished from the town. Other towns and settlements also had limited resources, so they wouldn't just accept an outsider. And even if you proved your worth, they would still be wary of accepting you completely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As such, this created the culture of group harmony above self interests. And, this is perhaps how the idea of Honne and Tatemae was formed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compare this to Western Europe and modern-day Americans. Our civilizations have always been formed from expanding our borders into uncharted areas. Greeks and Romans established their cities and expanded to conquer new ones. Americans broke away from Europe and expanded and "conquered" North America. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In America in the Wild West, if we stole from our neighbor and pissed off people, it wouldn't matter if we were banished. We could easily pick a direction and find new fertile land to start a new farm. People were constantly traveling to new places, so there was always new work available, and people dealt with problems head on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Direct and Indirect Language&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could also say that the insular culture of Japan and expansive culture of America and Europe influenced both Japanese and English languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In general, English is a very direct language compared to Japanese, which is built into our grammar. Our sentences always begin with the subject followed by the verb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;I walk to school everyday.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We always want to know &lt;code&gt;who&lt;/code&gt; is doing &lt;code&gt;what&lt;/code&gt; when we talk. All the other details of the sentence follow afterwards, when, why, where, how often, with whom, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japanese starts with the subject, too, although it's often not needed if the subject of conversation is clear. All the other details are expressed first before concluding the sentence with the verb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;私は&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毎日&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;学校に&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩いて行きます。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could say that a speaker wants to create a full picture of a situation first before completing and ending their thought. Comparing to English, we get the most important information said immediately, and the listener can then decide on the importance of the later details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going back to the earlier example of inviting someone...  In English, if you wanted to refuse someone's invitation, it's perfectly fine to just say no. "Hey, would you like to come over this weekend?" "Sorry, I can't." You wouldn't necessarily need to provide any context. In Japanese, though, outright refusing an invitation with such a direct response could be considered rude. "&lt;span class='ja'&gt;すみません、ちょっと。。&lt;/span&gt;" "This weekend is not good for me." "I'm sorry, but I have a prior engagement." You want to make a nice soft rejection sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of culture or cognition influencing language or language influencing culture or cognition is the central focus in another one of my favorite movies: &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/arrival" title="http://theschlock.com/arrival"&gt;Arrival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways... back to Emperor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dai-Ichi Life Building &lt;span class='ja'&gt;第一生命&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Douglas MacArthur and Bonner Fellers arrived in Tokyo, their offices were set up in the Dai-Ichi Life building, across the moat from the Imperial Palace grounds. From a story perspective, the location is perfectly fine, but the imagery and location are factual incorrect, and the location sometimes seems to move depending on what's happening in the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We see the Dai-Ichi Life building in the first sequence of the film as MacArthur and Fellers arrive. It's made to look more oriental and aged compared to how it actual looked. On the left is a composite image from the film, compared to the image on the right, which is apparently a photo of the building from 1945, taken from &lt;a href="https://www.oldtokyo.com/dai-ichi-seimei-sogo-building-marunouchi-c-1949/" title="https://www.oldtokyo.com/dai-ichi-seimei-sogo-building-marunouchi-c-1949/"&gt;oldtokyo.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h56m05s892_stitch.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h56m05s892_stitch.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h56m05s892_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h56m05s892_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h56m05s892_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/dai-ichi-1945.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/dai-ichi-1945.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/dai-ichi-1945_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/dai-ichi-1945_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/dai-ichi-1945_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess they didn't want the building looking modern for the film? Or, the real building looked too western or too Washington? My composite image is a little goofy, but much of the perspective of the building is off, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dai-Ichi Life building is still standing today in Tokyo in the same spot it has been since it was built in 1933. There have been some additions to the roof. Also, the original building acts as a front to a 21-story office building, which was completed in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5307.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5307.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5307_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5307_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5307_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside the Dai-Ichi Building, MacArthur's office is still preserved as it was 80 years ago. It is not open to the public, but maybe someday they'll figure out a decent way to have a tour of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dai-Ichi Life Building Location&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The actual location of the Dai-Ichi Building is outside the south-eastern corner of the Imperial Palace grounds. This is at the orange circle on a nearby guide map near where the above picture was taken. The yellow circle is the location of where it appears in the film because of its near proximity to the Sei-mon gate &lt;span class='ja'&gt;正門&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5314_map.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5314_map.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5314_map_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5314_map_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5314_map_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h57m20s136.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h57m20s136.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h57m20s136_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h57m20s136_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-14h57m20s136_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even the above shot from the film is doctored because the Sei-mon Gate bridge is removed and it looks like you could just walk up to Fushimi-yagura &lt;span class='ja'&gt;伏見櫓&lt;/span&gt; without crossing any bridges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading Emperor's IMDB page, they only spent 2 days filming on location in Tokyo. All other filming was done in New Zealand. So, it makes sense that the Dai-Ichi Life building doesn't look correct, and some other things are weird.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, the shots filmed in Tokyo were at a single location used slightly in the background here, but substantial used in two other pivotal scenes in the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sei-mon Gate &lt;span class='ja'&gt;正門&lt;/span&gt; / Nijubashi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;二重橋&lt;/span&gt; / Fushimi-yagura &lt;span class='ja'&gt;伏見櫓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Angered by the constant failed attempts the get answers from high ranking politicians and military commanders, Fellers gets approval from MacArthur to interview Vice Minister Sekiya. Fellers takes this written approval, and approaches the Sei-mon gate to enter the palace for his interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h02m29s594.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h02m29s594.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h02m29s594_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h02m29s594_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h02m29s594_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the film makes it look like they just went out of the Dai-Ichi Life building and approached the gate immediately. When in reality, this distance is about one kilometer. But, this is the one location where they actually filmed Emperor on site. They reused this location later towards the end of the film when Emperor Hirohito agrees to meet and talk with MacArthur out in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over summer, I met up with some friends from college, and we explored some areas in Tokyo, including the Imperial Palace. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5512_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5512_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5512_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5512_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5512_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having just watched Emperor with my students, I wanted to visit the actual locations from the film to give some further context when we finish the film after summer. I should have studied these shots much closer before visiting Tokyo, but I was able to take some photos that were pretty close to the actual scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m33s053.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m33s053.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m33s053_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m33s053_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m33s053_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_2_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_2_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_2_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m22s443.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m22s443.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m22s443_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m22s443_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h03m22s443_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5489.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5489.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5489_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5489_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5489_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h01m54s258.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h01m54s258.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h01m54s258_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h01m54s258_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h01m54s258_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5320.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5320.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5320_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5320_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5320_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That final reverse shot I should've studied more, but I was able to get a photo of that tree. That same tree shows up in the same location behind Fellers (Matthew Fox), although the depth of field is pulled WAY in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In reality, I couldn't find any information that said Fellers actually entered the Palace grounds for an interview. Also, would it have been appropriate to have entered through this gate? A &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5326.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5326.jpg"&gt;nearby plaque&lt;/a&gt; states the the Sei-mon gate is only used for official diplomatic use by the Emperor, State guests, and ambassadors. Crossing through it is part of ceremony. The other two northern gates are for workers and guests. But, this was 80 years ago, post-war, and technically he had official approval from MacArthur making Fellers and extension of MacArthur whom the Japanese government viewed as the highest order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Accuracy v. Story Telling&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, Emperor takes a lot of liberties with history in order to tell its story. Some of the smaller ones have been covered already, but the biggest inaccuracy is the love story between Fellers and Shimada Aya. Their story is completely fictional as Fellers was already married to Dorothy Dysart in 1925. They stayed married with 3 children until Feller's death in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall love story was most likely added to make the story relatable to general audience. Do people really want another boring historical drama based on facts? If Fellers has "love" for Japan, we gotta show that love somehow. Love for a woman is the easiest way to do this. Plus, people like a good tragic love story. Let's do that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h06m06s785.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h06m06s785.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h06m06s785_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h06m06s785_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/vlcsnap-2024-08-04-15h06m06s785_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics hated this part of the story because it was so cliche. They also felt that the film focused on their love story too much when they had a wealth of history to draw story from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, for someone that knows nothing of the subject matter, I think the movie does well portraying the events in the film and introducing the audience to these events that were pivotal in created modern Japan. It also does well introducing people to some parts of Japanese culture they probably aren't familiar with. So many war movies focus on heroes in battle and show the horror of war. Very very few films focus on creating peace through reconciliation rather than fighting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emperor is a fantastic under appreciated film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Imperial Palace &lt;span class='ja'&gt;皇居&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After showing the palace guards MacArthur's approval, Fellers enters the Palace and interviews Sekiya. Through researching these locations, I noticed that the Imperial Palace offered tours. Unfortunately, these tours are only outside the palace buildings. But, they're still within the palace grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could make reservations, but the majority of people just show up. They allow the first 300 people who show up an hour before the tour to join. Information for the tour is available here: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://sankan.kunaicho.go.jp/english/about/koukyo.html" title="https://sankan.kunaicho.go.jp/english/about/koukyo.html"&gt;Imperial Palace Tours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I suggested this as an activity with my friends, and they all agreed it would be a great idea. The tour began at 10:00am, but required some preparation prior to starting. You needed to fill out an application or registration for any security problems. And they began handing out numbers and applications at 9:00am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5351.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5351.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5351_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5351_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5351_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5352.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5352.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5352_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5352_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5352_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to miss the chance of taking a tour of the palace grounds, I showed up around 7:20am to take photos of the Dai-Ichi Life building, walk to the Sei-mon Gate as Fellers did in the film, take more photos, and then walk to the Kikyo-mon Gate where the line-up began. I was the second person in line starting at 8:00am. The other dude said he arrived around 7:30am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friends showed up around 8:45am with around 120 people in the line? So, ultimately, I didn't have to be so afraid of missing this chance. But, it was alright. Around 9:30am, they allowed tour members to enter the Kikyo-mon Gate and wait at the visitor center for orientation. They explained the route of the tour, and had pamphlets available. Tour guides were available in 5 different languages: English, Spanish, Japanese, Chinese, and Korean. Although, you could also scan a QR code to listen to all the details yourself. A small gift shop was also located in the visitor center, so you can buy random stuff with the imperial seal on it. I bought a small guidebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are scan of pamphlets and that guidebook:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TqPKGJJ9Hq8Pqxe2jRnIrjD9fPvh5TO6/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TqPKGJJ9Hq8Pqxe2jRnIrjD9fPvh5TO6/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-english.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-english.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-english.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TuxcHMRh9Sb4yatSh7M0MIhu9cnnNKqs/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TuxcHMRh9Sb4yatSh7M0MIhu9cnnNKqs/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-japanese.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-japanese.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-pamphlet-japanese.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Ttu2vJrrXWi6_sLzSJbsBhbTTk8AwTVX/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Ttu2vJrrXWi6_sLzSJbsBhbTTk8AwTVX/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-book.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-book.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/imperial-palace-book.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shortened Tour&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the summer heat, tours were only offered in the morning, and the tour today was cut short. The normal tour of 75 minutes was cut down to 45 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall tour starts from the visitor center, travels down the road passed the Fujimi-yagura &lt;span class='ja'&gt;富士見櫓&lt;/span&gt;, passed the Imperial Household building, the main Imperial Palace, and over the Nijuu-bashi bridge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;二重橋&lt;/span&gt;. From the bridge, the tour goes back to the Imperial Palace, behind the Imperial Household building, along the Lotus moat, and back to the Visitor center. Our cut tour just skipped the walk behind the Household building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Niju-bashi Bridge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;二重橋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being able to walk over the Niju-bashi and viewing the Sei-mon Gate and Bridge from the reverse was neat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5439.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5439.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5439_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5439_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5439_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5433.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5433.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5433_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5433_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5433_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, a really great photo would be from someone standing outside of the Imperial Palace with their camera focused on the Niju-bashi Bridge. Perhaps both a semi-wide shot and a zoomed-in close up. You might need a camera with a strong zoom lens. Then, put your friend or partner on the tour. Have them wait around until the tour clears the bridge so they're the last person off the bridge. As they exit, face the camera for a couple good shots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would take a bit of preparation and patience, but it could be worth it. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tour&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the tour was fine. Sharing the tour with 300+ people means barely being able to hear the tour guide over constant talking. Everyone was taking the same photos, too, so not particularly unique. Occasionally, someone would step on something forbidden and get yelled at. Once or twice, it seemed like someone important was in a car that drove by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Imperial Palace reminds me a lot of the Imperial Palace in Kyoto. Both are the center pieces of ancient government in their cities, but they aren't represented by a massive multi-storied castle like Himeiji or Matsumoto. Though, I suppose the Emperor would want to be shown as modest. The Emperor of Japan isn't known for flaunting wealth and status over the citizens of their country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I suppose the East Palace Gardens are meant to show off the beauty of the palace. Those are also within the palace grounds, but are freely open to the public most days. We skipped that, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240802_imperial/IMG_5323_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I think the view of Fushimi-yagura with the Sei-mon Gate and bridges together ends up the most scenic area of the palace, which is probably why the used it for the film. If you have time, I think the tour is worthwhile, but if you only have a few days in Tokyo and time is short, you could take a look around the outside and be satisfied enough. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/emperor-and-the-imperial-palace</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/emperor-and-the-imperial-palace</link><category>Media</category><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category><category>Film &amp; TV</category></item><item><title>Ema Market at Yamazakura 山桜神社</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Ema &lt;span class='ja'&gt;絵馬&lt;/span&gt; are horse paintings created at the height of summer in Takayama. People have these paintings created to bring luck and protection to a person's family or business through the upcoming year. This tradition began several hundred years ago, when farmers would bring their horses to the &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/matsukura-and-emaichi" title="http://theschlock.com/matsukura-and-emaichi"&gt;Matsukura Kannon Temple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松倉観音&lt;/span&gt; on nearby Matsukura mountain to pray to Kannon for their protection. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230801_harayama/IMG_5960_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230801_harayama/IMG_5960_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230801_harayama/IMG_5960_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Matsukura Kannon Temple was first established in the 1690s by a Buddhist Monk named Tenden Koutou &lt;span class='ja'&gt;天電高幢&lt;/span&gt;. Kannon is a Buddhist with six transformations, and the Matsukura Temple specifically worships Bato Kannon  &lt;span class='ja'&gt;馬頭観音&lt;/span&gt;, the horse-headed transformation of Kannon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, the Hida region has been populated by farmers, so horses were a very important part of their lives. They were used in their farm work for cultivating their fields and transporting food to town. They were also needed to travel the long distance up north or down south. People considered them part of their family. As such, their stables were connected to their houses at the front door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each year on July 9th, people would bring their horses to the Matsukura Temple to have their horse blessed by the monks of Bato Kannon. 400 years ago, traveling up the Matsukura mountain to reach the temple was difficult, and horses were often injured. As the custom grew in popularity, it became even more troublesome to bring horses up the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Emas &lt;span class='ja'&gt;絵馬&lt;/span&gt; were created. Rather than bringing your physical horse up the mountain, you could buy a painting of your horse, have the monks bless the painting, and receive the same protection and fortune. People would hang the painting near their front door, near their horse's stable. Over time, these paintings have come to represent general good luck. As the horse faces inwards, it would bring you good luck to your home or business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/ema-paintings" title="http://theschlock.com/ema-paintings"&gt;previous years&lt;/a&gt;, I've gone up the Matsukura mountain to visit the Kannon Temple and get a horse painting. But, that's not the only place that makes these paintings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yamazakura Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山桜神社&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yamazakura Shrine is a small shrine on Honmachi street, one of the main streets in Takayama. It is squished between two restaurants. Despite being centrally located, it's perhaps more annoying to reach than the Kannon Temple on the mountain because there's no parking (for free) around the area. Although old people just park in the middle of the street anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5713.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5713.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5713_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5713_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5713_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yamazakura Shrine is named after a local horse that became a legend. Yamazakura &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山桜&lt;/span&gt; was born in the town of Nyukawa (NE town of Takayama) and became the horse of Kanamori Yorinao &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森頼直&lt;/span&gt;, the reigning ruler of Takayama at the time, great grandson of Kanamori Nagachika &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森長近&lt;/span&gt;, who established modern Takayama. Yorinao was in Edo when the Great Fire of Edo happened in 1657. Yorinao was completely engulfed in flames in his guest house. The story goes that Yamazakura burst through the door allowing Yorinao to get on his back. The horse rushed out of the building and leaped into the river extinguishing the flames saving his life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yorinao was so grateful to his horse. He established the horse's stable in downtown Takayama on Honmachi street so the people of Takayama would look after him and treat him with respect. After Yamazakura's death, he was cremated and ashes spread at the foot of Mt. Matsukura on the path to the Kannon Temple. At the location of the stable, Yamazakura Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山桜神社&lt;/span&gt; was established. Besides praying to Bato Kannon for protection and prosperity, the shrine specializes in protection from fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ema Market &lt;span class='ja'&gt;絵馬市&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Yamazakura Shrine advertises in the town newsletter and I often see these advertisements around the shrine when I drive by. Rather than go to Matsukura Kannon, I wanted to visit a different Ema distributer this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="img"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1VoPxwlgiZ61dJUmk5nqaHJUmoVaAEdvI/view?usp=drive_link" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1VoPxwlgiZ61dJUmk5nqaHJUmoVaAEdvI/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;&lt;img style="height: 724px; width: 512; text-align: center;" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/240807_emaichi.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/240807_emaichi.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/240807_emaichi.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yamazakura and Bato Kannon are celebrated on August 8th, 9th, and 10th each year at the Yamazakura shrine, but the shrine is open from August 1st to 10th at 10am to 3pm each day. I had time to visit on August 7th before class in the evening. You're able to make an order &lt;a href="https://honmachi-2chome.jp/bato-ema/index.html" title="https://honmachi-2chome.jp/bato-ema/index.html"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; prior to visiting. But, if you just show up, they don't have a standard order form, like the Kannon temple. You just tell them your name, the Ema size, what color (black/white), and which way it should face (left/right). The small painting was 1800yen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the shrine is so small, they only let a few people in at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5720.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5720.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5720_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5720_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5720_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5721.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5721.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5721_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5721_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5721_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a few different designs beyond just the color of the horse, I think for different luck. I just went with the green one because it looked pretty and unconventional. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, because the shrine is so narrow and demand is somewhat high, I had to wait outside for them to finish painting my name, blessing, and stamping all the protections on the painting. I didn't have to wait too long, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5727.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5727.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5727_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5727_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240807_emaichi/IMG_5727_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They didn't write the date on the painting, which was common with the Ema from Matsukura Kannon. But! My luck has been renewed for yet another year. This time with extra fire protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/ema-market-at-yamazakura</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/ema-market-at-yamazakura</link><category>Hida Takayama</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>MemCard Pro2 for Playstation 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year, English gaming company 8bitmods released a device called the &lt;b&gt;MemCard Pro 2&lt;/b&gt;. It is advertised as "the last memory card you'll ever need." It works for both Playstation 1 and Playstation 2, and it stores all of its data for memory on an SD card. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5034.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5034.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5034_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5034_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5034_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After putting together my &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;Playstation 2 set up&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted some way of being able to backup all of my save data from my decade of playing the Playstation 1 and 2. Having a memory card that uses an SD card was what I wanted, and I found this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, it does MUCH more than just store save files on an SD card. It has a paging system, so you can easily create a new card with the press of a button. It identifies games with Game Id, so it can create unique memory cards for each game. And the card has Wifi, so all of its functions can be controlled by a web interface!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Updating&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything, you need an SD card. Each PS2 memory card is 8mb so even having an SD card with 128gb of space is massive over kill. I bought a 64gb Samsung card for around $10 since it seemed to be the cheapest option. 32gb cards were available, but they were around the same price. May as well get a slightly large one. The SD card must be formatted either FAT32 or ExFat. I went with ExFat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the card ready to go, the next necessary step is firmware. You should update to the most recent version for access to all of the current features. Here's the link to the firmware:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://install.appcenter.ms/orgs/beta-ucu9/apps/memcard-pro2/distribution_groups/public" title="https://install.appcenter.ms/orgs/beta-ucu9/apps/memcard-pro2/distribution_groups/public"&gt;Latest Firmware Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the SD card in the MemCard and put the MemCard in the PS2. Power it on, and it'll start updating. When finished, it is ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wi-Fi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may think that Wi-Fi is unnecessary for a memory card, but you have so many more methods of control than being limited to the 2-button, small screen interface attached to the PS2. When you want to change card, you can easily do it with a scroll and a click in a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the Wi-Fi has a few steps that are pretty easy. First, you need to hold down the Left button and release to enter the Menu. Click down to Wi-Fi and select it. You'll be given an IP address. Now, the memcard pro is broadcasting as an access point. It wants you to connect to the access point and visit the webpage at that IP address. Going to that IP address will open a webpage to complete the Wi-Fi set up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5040.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5040.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5040_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5040_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5040_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5041.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5041.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5041_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5041_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5041_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5043.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5043.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5043_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5043_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5043_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5045.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5045.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5045_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5045_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5045_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Setup Wizard, you'll choose a Wi-Fi network to connect to. From there, the Memcard will connect to the network, and have another IP address. Any device that is on your network can navigate to that IP address in a browser and be able to manage the data and settings on the Memcard Pro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5050.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5050.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5050_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5050_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5050_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5052.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5052.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5052_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5052_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5052_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the Browser you can easily select which memory card should be used and quickly change cards, too. You can further set up which memory card should be selected by default when the console powers up. And, you can set up cloud backup with Google Drive. You can also update the firmware from here, too, rather than doing it manually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Save Management&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the best features of the Memcard is identifying games using Game_Id. Every disc printed and created for a Playstation 1 and 2 has a unique Game_Id associated with it and the Memcard can identify this ID and automatically create or switch to a virtual memory card used only for that game. It does this by default, but you can change this behavior in the settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That means that you don't need to worry about trying to find which cards have which saves. You also don't have to worry about space on a card because other games won't be there to fill the space. And, even if you do save a lot in one game and use up all of the space, you can create a new page and have up to 8 memory cards for each game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All memory cards are stored as virtual drives in the &lt;code&gt;mcd&lt;/code&gt; format on the SD card. Unfortunately, you can't modify the contents of the card directly on a PC. So, if you want to add stuff on the card directly, you still need to use uLaunchELF on the PS2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There might be something out there that will mount of the drive and give you access because people have written scripts and programs that access the contents of the cards for Save Splitting. But, I haven't found anything yet. Save Splitting is useful when moving the contents of your current memory card stash into the Memcard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Transferring Old Memory Cards&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an old plastic bag full of memory cards from the late 90s and 2000s. The bulk of these are Playstation 1 cards, but there are some Playstation 2 cards, too. As well as Dreamcast, N64, and Gamecube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_1516.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_1516.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_1516_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_1516_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_1516_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5059.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5059.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5059_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5059_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5059_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5054.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5054.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5054_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5054_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5054_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total, I have eleven Playstation 1 cards, a Pocketstation, and six Playstation 2 cards. I want to move all of this data onto my SD card. It'd be nice if the Memcard Pro2 had an option to copy a Memory Card directly, but we have to copy over everything manually. From there, we have to use Save Splitting programs to separate and sort all of the saves into their own memory cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a 2-step process for both Playstation 1 and 2, and the first step is identical for both: we need to manually transfer all Memory Card saves from one memory card to another. This is normally done using the Playstation browser, and I think it's the fastest method for Playstation 1. But for Playstation 2, it's much faster to use uLaunchELF and move all of the file contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5078.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5078.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5078_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5078_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5078_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5080.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5080.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5080_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5080_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5080_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With uLaunchELF, &lt;code&gt;mc0&lt;/code&gt; is the memory card is slot 1, and &lt;code&gt;mc1&lt;/code&gt; is slot 2. Mark everything you want to copy with the X button, hit R1 for the menu, and select copy. Navigate to the other memory card location, hit R1 for the menu again, and select paste. Everything you selected will be copied. uLaunchELF didn't refresh when I unplugged and changed memory cards, so I had to restart uLaunchELF each time.  It's still MUCH faster than loading PS2 saves in the Browser, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the cards copied as Virtual memory cards, we want to break out all the saves into all of their unique cards for each game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the save splitting stuff I learned from &lt;b&gt;Archades Games&lt;/b&gt; on YouTube. He has a ton of tutorials for retro gaming setups, and I followed his videos quite closely whenever I had problems.&lt;br/&gt;For PS2 saves: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RAmtPF_0ij0" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RAmtPF_0ij0"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RAmtPF_0ij0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For PS1 saves: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAYrCiQEBr0" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAYrCiQEBr0"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAYrCiQEBr0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 2 Save Splitting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For PS2 saves, Archades' video pointed to a dev named K3zter. He has created a save splitter script, and it's available here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/K3zter/mcp2-save-splitter" title="https://github.com/K3zter/mcp2-save-splitter"&gt;https://github.com/K3zter/mcp2-save-splitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are instructions on the page, but in order to use this, you want to download the entire contents of this repository and place them into a folder on your computer.  The script relies on program called &lt;code&gt;mymc&lt;/code&gt; created by another developer, gastroman. As the description says, you can download that program here: &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/mymc-opl/files/" title="https://sourceforge.net/projects/mymc-opl/files/"&gt;sourceforget/mymc&lt;/a&gt;. All contents of mymc distribution should be placed in the &lt;code&gt;mymc&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The save-splitter distribution has an &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; folder. Pretty self-explanatory. Put all your saves in the import folder, run the script, and all of the split saves will be in the export folder. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The script is run from a PowerShell instance and you need to Run it as an Administrator, since it'll be moving and editing files. Once opened, navigate to the script's location, and execute the script by typing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.\split.ps1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The script may not run at first because Windows doesn't want you to run scripts that change the contents of your computer without you understanding what you're actually doing. Archades' video points to a &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10635/why-are-my-powershell-scripts-not-running" title="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10635/why-are-my-powershell-scripts-not-running"&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; question asking how to get around this. I typed in the following to get this script working:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted&lt;br/&gt;Set-ExecutionPolicy AllSigned&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5091.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5091.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5091_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5091_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5091_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5097.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5097.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5097_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5097_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5097_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all restrictions removed, the script was run and it processed all memory cards and save files in the import directory, and spit out individual cards for each game in the export directory. With all the saves split, all folders in the export directory should be moved into the &lt;code&gt;PS2&lt;/code&gt; folder on the MemCard's SD card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 1 Save Splitting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;PS1 saves have a similar process. Archades' video pointed to the save splitter program was written by Bodgit, and it's available here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/bodgit/memcardpro" title="https://github.com/bodgit/memcardpro"&gt;https://github.com/bodgit/memcardpro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have to do a little more work compared with the PS2 save splitter, but we don't have to deal with PowerShell and any of its restrictions. Also, this has linux and darwin versions, so I could run it on my MacBook. But, the PC is already open, so I'll just use the Windows version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time, we're executing the script from the Command Line (or Command Prompt). Because of this, we need to add a bunch of arguments to the execution code. You also need to make your own export folder. In the same folder with the program, I made a folder called &lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt;. I also made an &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; folder, but it's not necessary. For the command line, you'll need to type in this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;memcardpro split export import/MemoryCard?-?.mcd&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to change the question marks in that command to the actual filename. They do not act as wild cards. Although, there is probably something you could use as a wild card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5082.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5082.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5082_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5082_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5082_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5084.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5084.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5084_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5084_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5084_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the execution is complete, the export folder will be filled with split memory card images. Copy all of these into the &lt;code&gt;PS1&lt;/code&gt; folder of the MemCard's SD card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Saves&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, I have saves for 53 Playstation 1 games and 89 Playstation 2 games. I thought it'd be more, but it makes sense looking at my &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/games/" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/games/"&gt;Video Game Collection&lt;/a&gt;. I own 65 ps1 games and 84 ps2 games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've uploaded all of my saves to my GitHub page for my &lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout/tree/master/mcp2" title="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout/tree/master/mcp2"&gt;OPL load out&lt;/a&gt;, but it's not particularly reader friendly. So, I added Save Icons to my &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;Playstation 2 Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt; and to the &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/games/" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/games/"&gt;Video Game Collection&lt;/a&gt;, so as you browse all of the games I put on my PS2, you can see which games have saves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, the Memcard saves each card as a virtual memory card in the &lt;code&gt;mc2&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;mcd&lt;/code&gt; formats, so you'll need to do some processing to extract the individual saves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the Memcard works! All of my saves from 20 years ago or more are all in tact, including my Final Fantasy X saves that I put over 200 combined hours into.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5149.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5149.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5149_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5149_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5149_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5101.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5101.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5101_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5101_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5101_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Free McBoot&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While cataloging all of my game saves is great, we need Free McBoot on this thing to launch Open PS2 Loader is play games on our hard drive or network server. Again, the Memcard Pro acts like any PS2 Memory Card, so moving stuff on an empty card using uLaunchELF works the same as any other memory card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a bit of a chicken/egg scenario because you need to use uLaunchELF to install Free McBoot on a memory card. But, you can't run uLaunchELF unless you already have a memory card with Free McBoot. (Or you have a DVD with uLaunchELF burned on it) One of Archades' videos had a link to a Memcard image with everything already installed. I made a few updates, and you can download my FreeMcBoot memory card image here: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JqGUIB73w_NrLc7JKU3fX0a0TVXIgKQ3/view" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JqGUIB73w_NrLc7JKU3fX0a0TVXIgKQ3/view"&gt;googleDrive/MemoryCard1-1.mc2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5172.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5172.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5172_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5172_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240801_memcard/IMG_5172_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Archades' image, there is wLaunchELF (updated uLaunchELF), and OPL with Game ID code enabled, plus Grimdoomer's OPL fork. I added two more programs: OPL Anniversary edition, which supports old Playstation 1 games, and the "latest" version of OPL 1.2 beta rom Github.  The Game ID OPL and Latest OPL are basically the same, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because that Memory Card image is the one that I actually use, it has all of my configuration details included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Overall&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love the Memcard Pro2. It is the perfect way of preserving all of your saves from the past and managing them today, as long as you're running them on original hardware. That's really the one downside. If you're emulating games on PC or some other device, the Memcard Pro2 is good for extracting the saves, but you won't need it beyond that. For continued support, it works best when actually using a Playstation 2. My set up has a Playstation 2 at its heart, so it's perfect for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you're still playing games on an actual Playstation 2, I would recommend the Memcard as a must buy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/memcard-pro2-for-ps2</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/memcard-pro2-for-ps2</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category></item><item><title>Using the OSSC with the PS2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The OSSC stands for Open Source Scan Converter. It's a device created from a community standard that converts analog video signals into digital signals, primarily for retro video game consoles. It has 3 inputs, SCART, component, and VGA, and will output HDMI. I'm primary using this with a Playstation 2, but the Analogue Pocket's Analogizer is also hooked up to it. I recently got mine from AliExpress for $90. Then I bought an acrylic outer case for $20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The era of the Playstation 2 was the last video game generation to use analog video signals as a standard. Starting with the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360, consoles natively supported HDMI, and now its standard on absolutely everything. Prior to HDMI, RCA composite cables were standard in North America and Japan, while SCART was standard in Europe. But, for North America, the highest quality video you could get used RGB composite cables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 2 Component Cables&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Playstation 2, the official component cables are one of the best options. But the actual official ones are hard to find and usually expensive. Also, there are many bootlegs cables being sold as official. Signal integrity is very important to analog video, so cheap cables can eat away at the quality. So, the actual best PS2 video cables on the market are the cables from Retrovision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5676.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5676.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5676_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5676_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5676_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think they look cheap on the outside, but the internals are not. The inner components are perfectly shielded and expertly crafted to ensure the highest quality, strongest signal possible from source to destination. They were $30 on Amazon, not too much more expensive than others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Signals and Resolutions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the most part, by default, the Playstation 2 outputs a 480i resolution. In general, this is a 640x480 resolution drawn with interlacing. I'm not an expert, but I have come to understand that interlacing draws the video with overlapping alternating lines. A complete single frame is split into two images alternatingly drawn on top of each other, which creates two frames instead one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern TVs with HDMI use progressive scan to draw the image on a TV. A single frame is drawn from top to bottom in order without alternating lines. Some Playstation 2 games have the option of output 480p, where p stands for progressive. The OSSC loves a 480p signal because, even though it is being passed as an analog signal, it's in a digital format, and that's what modern TVs want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 480i signal is more annoying. The OSSC needs to convert the interlaced signals into progressive, and it uses bob deinterlacing to do this. Bob deinterlacing takes the half-drawn image from the first frame and treats it as progressive. It's only 240 tall, so it doubles the height. Then it does the same with the next frame, the other half of the image. Another name for this technique is line doubling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, we want to set up the OSSC to handle &lt;b&gt;480p&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;480i&lt;/b&gt; signals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People have made a list of all Playstation 2 games that support 480p (and other resolutions) and how to enable it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.everybodywiki.com/List_of_PlayStation_2_games_with_alternative_display_modes" title="https://en.everybodywiki.com/List_of_PlayStation_2_games_with_alternative_display_modes"&gt;https://en.everybodywiki.com/List_of_PlayStation_2_games_with_alternative_display_modes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;480p Signals&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, if a game supports 480p (or any progressive scan format), we want to use it. Using OPL, there's a way to force this. GSM, or &lt;b&gt;Graphics Synthesizer Mode Selector&lt;/b&gt;, is another unofficial PS2 app that works with OPL. When choosing a game in OPL, you can hit &lt;code&gt;triangle&lt;/code&gt; to enter the Game Settings menu. Then enter the GSM Settings menu. For 480p available games, enable GSM and switch the "Mode" to 480p.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1509.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1509.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1509_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1509_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1509_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to save the Game Settings! Now, when you launch the game, it will automatically run in 480p.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;OSSC Settings&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; I'm still trying to find the best settings. Please check back later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/using-ossc-with-ps2</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/using-ossc-with-ps2</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category></item><item><title>Playstation 1 Games on PS2 OPL</title><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best features of the Playstation 2 on its release was backwards compatibility with Playstation 1 games. In those recent years, no home console had been backwards compatible with its predecessor, mainly because of cartridges. So having a new console being able to play your current game library was a massive boost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was accomplished by including the original Playstation hardware inside of the Playstation 2. Over time, this extra hardware was shrunk, and eventually relegated to software emulation, which wasn't perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, with getting OPL and a Games server working for the Playstation 2, I wanted Playstation 1 working in the same way. The overall process for Playstation 1 games is similar to Playstation 2 games, but the steps are different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is my set up for the Playstation 2 with OPL, the file server, and everything else:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;/returning-to-the-playstation-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;POPStarter&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though the Playstation 2 has the Playstation 1 hardware for games, the games will be run in software. Unfortunately, there's no way around this. &lt;b&gt;POPS&lt;/b&gt; is Sony's Playstation 1 emulator that runs on the ps2, and OPL's method of using this is called POPStarter. It stands for Playstation One Portable Station, probably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: There are two ways of setting up Playstation 1 games and POPstarter using OPL and I'm using the old way. This way is only compatible using OPL Anniversary Edition. The latest versions of OPL have removed this method of execution for a newer method which has a slightly better success rate for compatibility. I'm not sure if it works through SMB, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, my Playstation 2 setup is streaming games through the ethernet port using an SMB server hosted on a Raspberry Pi 3. I need to add POPStarter configuration on my memory card with Free McBoot. And then, there are some additional files required for the file server along with the games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;POPSTARTER Configuration for the Memory Card&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because I'm running Playstation 1 games from the SMB File Share, I needed to download a specific POPStarter setup for the memory card. I downloaded &lt;b&gt;POPSTARTER.zip&lt;/b&gt; found on the following page: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.psx-place.com/resources/popstarter.683/" title="https://www.psx-place.com/resources/popstarter.683/"&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/resources/popstarter.683/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When unzipped it will give a &lt;code&gt;POPSTARTER&lt;/code&gt; folder. This entire folder will be copied to the Free McBoot memory card, but we need to change two things first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we need to change the &lt;code&gt;IPCONFIG.DAT&lt;/code&gt; file. This contains the ip details of the PS2. By default, here are the file contents:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;PS2-IP-ADDRESS NETMASK GATEWAY&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These details are all found in the Network Settings of OPL. The PS2-IP-ADDRESS is the IP address of the PS2 on the network. The Netmask is the same one in OPL. And the Gateway is the IP address of the File server. All of these are listed in OPL's Network Config menu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Originally, my Playstation 2 IP address was &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.10&lt;/code&gt;. POPS does not like it when the IPs of the Playstation 2 and the File Server are on different subnets, so I changed the PS2's IP address in OPL to &lt;code&gt;192.168.2.10&lt;/code&gt;. This solved my problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is my completed file:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;192.168.2.10 255.255.255.0 192.168.2.1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to change &lt;code&gt;SMBCONFIG.DAT&lt;/code&gt;. This tells popstarter where the files are located on the network. OPL knows where the files are, but it doesn't tell POPS this information when it launches, so we need to add this information here. By default, here are the file contents:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;PC-IP-ADDRESS PS2SMB&lt;br/&gt;username&lt;br/&gt;password&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's the server's IP address, the server's folder name, and the login details. I'm using the SMB Share setup on the Raspberry Pi, so here are my details:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;192.168.2.1 share&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no login details, so those lines are omitted. The share on the Pi is just &lt;code&gt;share&lt;/code&gt;, and it's running on that IP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Memory Card Installation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;POPSTARTER&lt;/code&gt; folder and all of its contents will be copied to the Memory Card with Free McBoot. To do this, we'll need to put all these files on a simple USB Drive and plug that directly into a USB slot of the PS2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After turning on the PS2 with Free McBoot, you'll need to open uLaunchELF, which is a file browser for the Playstation 2. The drive marked &lt;code&gt;mass&lt;/code&gt; is your USB drive, &lt;code&gt;mc0&lt;/code&gt; is the memory card in the first slot, and &lt;code&gt;mc1&lt;/code&gt; is the memory card in the second slot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1510.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1510.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1510_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1510_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1510_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;mass&lt;/code&gt;, select (mark) your &lt;code&gt;POPSTARTER&lt;/code&gt; folder, hit &lt;code&gt;R1&lt;/code&gt; to pull up the menu, and select copy. Navigate to &lt;code&gt;mc0&lt;/code&gt; for your Free McBoot card, hit &lt;code&gt;R1&lt;/code&gt; again, and select paste. This will copy your &lt;code&gt;POPSTARTER&lt;/code&gt; folder to the memory card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your memory card setup is complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;File Server Files&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the file server, Playstation 1 games are put in the &lt;code&gt;POPS&lt;/code&gt; folder, but we need another file for the emulator to work, the emulator itself! The file for the actual emulator is named &lt;code&gt;POPS_IOX.PAK&lt;/code&gt;. It's not too difficult to find through a Google search, but this file contains copyrighted information by Sony, so search at your own risk. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last file we're going to need is &lt;code&gt;POPSTARTER.ELF&lt;/code&gt;. ELF files are applications that run on the Playstation 2, and this is POPStarter application that runs the emulator. When you select a game in OPL, it will open that game with this application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With everything set up, now we need some games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;POPStarter and OPL requires Playstation 1 Games in the VCD format and using the same filename format as PS2 games. When you illegally download any Playstation 1 game, it'll most likely be in the bin/cue format. So, you'll need to convert them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best program to do this with is called &lt;b&gt;PFS BatchKit Manager&lt;/b&gt;. It can be found on GitHub here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/GDX-X/PFS-BatchKit-Manager" title="https://github.com/GDX-X/PFS-BatchKit-Manager"&gt;https://github.com/GDX-X/PFS-BatchKit-Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PFS BatchKit Manager is a command line program for Windows, so Windows might complain when you try to open it. It should run within your OPL folder on your File server. Conversions are found under the Advanced Menu. Follow this route:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt; -&gt; 10. Advanced Menu&lt;br/&gt; -&gt; 1. Conversion&lt;br/&gt; -&gt; 1. Convert .bin to .vcd&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1495.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1495.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1495_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1495_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1495_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will search the &lt;code&gt;POPS&lt;/code&gt; folder for any bin/cue files, and process them. First, it'll combine all the bin files into a single bin file. Then it will convert to vcd. PFS BatchKit Manager will also rename your files with the Disc ID in the front and with the correct game name from their database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've had the process fail once or twice on large batches of files, so I always convert a few at a time. It can sometimes take a while, too, so I prefer going bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will complete the process for single disc games. You can open OPL Manager to double check the file names are correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Multi-Disc Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For games with multiple discs, there is one more step to complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;POPStarter doesn't read the PS2's memory card, so it will create a virtual memory card for saving. Memory card files are stored/indexed by Game Id, and this is problem with multi-disc games because each CD has its own Game Id.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configuration files must be set up to tell POPStarter you are running a multi-disc game. This will allow memory card sharing among each disc AND it will allow you to swap game discs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a script you can download called &lt;b&gt;DISCS_POOPER.cmd&lt;/b&gt;, also Windows only. Place this script in the same folder with all the discs of a multi-disc game, run the script, and it will create the necessary sub folders and the configuration files needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1499.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1499.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1499_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1499_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1499_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find this by searching around, but I have a copy of it on my GitHub:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout/blob/03bb3180655a99fb3962c2f889c88d85d5d1404f/POPS/DISCS_POOPER.cmd" title="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout/blob/03bb3180655a99fb3962c2f889c88d85d5d1404f/POPS/DISCS_POOPER.cmd"&gt;github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout/DISCS_POOPER.cmd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put these folders and games in the &lt;code&gt;POPS&lt;/code&gt; folder of your file server, and you're good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Multi-Disc Controls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are button commands used for multi-disc games to simulate opening the disc tray, inserting a different disc, and closing the tray. These commands are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;·    To open the lid: Select + L2 + R2 + Triangle&lt;br/&gt;·    To insert Disc 1: Select + L2 + R2 + Up&lt;br/&gt;·    To insert Disc 2: Select + L2 + R2 + Right&lt;br/&gt;·    To insert Disc 3: Select + L2 + R2 + Down&lt;br/&gt;·    To insert Disc 4: Select + L2 + R2 + Left&lt;br/&gt;·    To close the lid: Select + L2 + R2 + Square&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These commands were found on this page: &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/ShaolinAssassin/popstarter-documentation-stuff/wiki/multi-disc" title="https://bitbucket.org/ShaolinAssassin/popstarter-documentation-stuff/wiki/multi-disc"&gt;bitbucket.org/popstarter/multi-disc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Execution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the Playstation 1 games put in the &lt;code&gt;POPS&lt;/code&gt; folder, they will show up in OPL under the Playstation menu. Selecting them will run POPStarter. Unfortunately, even with everything set up correctly, not all games work with POPS. Some games won't open. Some games will open, but then lock up after the game starts. Other games will run with audio stuttering or graphics stuttering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a Google Doc where people have submitted their compatibility issues with POPS, so prior to trying, you can check whether or not a game works.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ERB4SIXTTgsUCqOcoRPIseh2jnRfZWnGITOd_qz7s8E/edit?pli=1&amp;pli=1&amp;gid=1#gid=1" title="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ERB4SIXTTgsUCqOcoRPIseh2jnRfZWnGITOd_qz7s8E/edit?pli=1&amp;pli=1&amp;gid=1#gid=1"&gt;POPStarter Playstation Compatibility Chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Final Fantasy VIII crashes at the beginning when trying to load the second cutscene in the game. :(   But other games, such as Super Puzzle Fighter II, work perfectly for POPS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1442.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1442.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1442_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1442_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1442_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Almost Perfect&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, it's not the perfect solution to playing Playstation 1 games that I want. But, it works for many games, and they can live alongside the Playstation 2 games on my file server. I don't need another process for them to work. Most of the incompatible games that I want to play, I have physical copies of anyways.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category></item><item><title>Returning to the Playstation 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have revisited the Playstation 2, my favorite console of all time. I played the PS2 for hours and hours during college, made some amazing friends through playing games, and have amazing memories of those times. So, I wanted to relive those memories as well as return to a time when video games began evolving into something with more complexity, both for story and gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to return to the PS2 in the same way I've come back to other retro consoles thanks to the &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket" title="http://theschlock.com/analogue-pocket"&gt;Analogue Pocket&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to have a significant library of games that could easily be stored and sifted through digitally, as well as having them look their best on a modern TV. The PS2 is also backwards compatible with Playstation 1 games, so I wanted to be able to play those too. After messing around with things for about a month, I finally have everything set up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5687_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall set up isn't too complicated, but it has a bunch of parts required for everything to work together. To quickly explain, I'm using a memory card with Free McBoot on an original Playstation 2 slim to run Open PS2 Loader. I have a Raspberry Pi acting a network file server that OPL is connecting to in order to load games. I have a 4tb hard drive connected to the Raspberry Pi where all of the games are stored. And, the PS2 is using component video cables connected to an OSSC to digitize the video and send it to my modern TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of this was inspired by another one of Tito's YouTube videos: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVCFbJCPtO8" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVCFbJCPtO8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVCFbJCPtO8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the center of the entire set up is an actual Playstation 2. None of this entire process modifies the original console whatsoever. Everything extra can be unplugged from the Playstation 2, and it'll be the same as it was 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My original Playstation 2 Slim is 10,000km away back in the United States, so I bought a Japanese Slim from Yahoo Auctions. For the best possible compatibility, people had recommended the original Slim release, so I bought a SCPH-70000 model. It was really cheap at only 3000yen, and it came with the vertical stand and a few games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5708.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5708.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5708_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5708_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5708_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In later revisions of the Playstation Slim, they moved Playstation 1 processing into software rather than hardware. They also removed legacy hard drive support, which isn't even available for the Slim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Free McBoot Memory Card&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order for any of this to work, we need access to the Playstation 2's file system and be able to run unofficial applications. In particular, we need to be able to run &lt;b&gt;Open PS2 Loader&lt;/b&gt;. Creating your own Free McBoot memory card from complete scratch has a lot of steps, but these days, you can easily buy a pre-built Free McBoot memory card from Amazon. I bought one from Amazon JP for only 1500yen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5131.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5131.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5131_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5131_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_5131_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Official Playstation 2 memory cards have the Magic Gate branding on them, which acts like a Seal of Approval ensuring that all games are compatible with it. This card doesn't have such approval and it's also 64mb compared to the official 8mb limit. Because of this, some games don't like it. We Love Katamari in particular has some saving problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One really nice thing about this card is that it came with absolutely everything installed on it. It already had OPL, all of the retro game emulators, and other necessary applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;MemCard Pro2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going one step further, 8bitmods released a device called the MemCard Pro2, which they restocked a month or two after my initial setup was complete. It is advertised as the "the last memory card you'll ever need," and with this, I no longer need a dedicated memory card with Free McBoot. Although, having an extra card with Free McBoot is handy when moving files around from Memory Card to Memory Card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the details for the Memcard Pro2 are discussed in another post: &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/memcard-pro2-for-ps2" title="http://theschlock.com/memcard-pro2-for-ps2"&gt;/memcard-pro2-for-ps2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Raspberry Pi 3 w/ SMB Share&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the hardware center is the Playstation 2 itself, the software center is the Raspberry Pi. The Raspberry Pi acts as a File Server and it is directly connected to the PS2 using an ethernet cable. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't own a Raspberry Pi, so I went to Yahoo Auctions again to find a cheap one. I found a Raspberry Pi 3 with heatsinks installed and an AC adapter for 4000yen. Good deal!  Later, I bought an acrylic case with a fan for only $4 from AliExpress. Also, I had an extra LCD Monitor and a extra keyboard, so I'm using those with it, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1444.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1444.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1444_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1444_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1444_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1452.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1452.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1452_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1452_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1452_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to set up the SMB Share, you need to flash an SD card with the Playstation SMB Share. This image is found here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/toolboc/psx-pi-smbshare" title="https://github.com/toolboc/psx-pi-smbshare"&gt;https://github.com/toolboc/psx-pi-smbshare&lt;/a&gt;. I used a program called balenaEtcher to put this image on one of my extra micro SD cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the initial power-up, it takes a little time to do some set-up, but eventually you'll be given a log in prompt. This happens every time the Raspberry Pi boots up. The default username is &lt;code&gt;pi&lt;/code&gt; and the default password is &lt;code&gt;raspberry&lt;/code&gt;. With everything set up, you'll need IP information for OPL's connection. Type in &lt;code&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt; and you'll be given the network data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1433.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1433.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1433_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1433_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1433_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;inet 192.168.2.1  netmask 255.255.255.0  broadcast 192.168.2.255&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the line that we care about. The Pi's IP address is &lt;code&gt;192.168.2.1&lt;/code&gt;. To turn off the Raspberry Pi, type &lt;code&gt;sudo shutdown -h now&lt;/code&gt;. It will shutdown, but then you'll need to unplug it. There's no actual on/off switch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; the Raspberry Pi doesn't like to plug and play. Anything you have plugged in on start up, it will auto mount, but if you plug in something after it has already been turned on, you need to manually mount the device, whether it's a keyboard, a monitor, or a usb drive. Plug in everything before you give it power for best results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;USB Drive&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SMB Server expects a USB device plugged in the Raspberry Pi to serve files from, and the device must be formatted exFat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every one recommends to use a USB Flash Drive, but standard USB Flash Drives aren't able to scale. They're fine if you want to have a couple of games, but I want to have a large library of games. Modern USB hard drives are pretty big. In fact, I have a few 5tb SSD drives for backing up files. But these are powered through USB. The Raspberry Pi uses a measly amount of power so it can't power anything through USB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had an older 4tb Western Digital hard drive with an actual hard disk, not a solid state or a flash drive. This drive has its own power connection separate from USB. By plugging this in and turning it on before powering on the Raspberry Pi, it works just like any other USB storage device. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Games and OPL Manager&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The physical chain between the Playstation 2 and the games is complete, but there are two more steps. First off, we need some games. You can illegally download games for several different places online. These files come in two different flavors: ISOs and bin/cue files. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open PS2 Loader&lt;/b&gt; is the UI application used on the Playstation 2 to select and run these files, so they need to be in a particular format and have a particular file naming scheme. The USB Drive also needs to be in a particular file structure for OPL to find the games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPL Manager&lt;/b&gt; is a PC program that will do all of this for us. You can download it &lt;a href="https://oplmanager.com/site/" title="https://oplmanager.com/site/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or just search on Google if the location changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When OPL Manager first starts, it will ask for a base location. For me, I use a temp location on my USB drive for a few reasons. (One) OPL Manager can take a while to load if there are a lot of games at the location. So, when using a temp location it only needs to load the few games I'm working with at the time. Likewise, these games take up a LOT of space, so (Two) I don't want to process them locally and copy them later. This takes up a lot of space on my local computer, and takes time copying to the hard drive later. I want to work with everything on the drive, and move files around on the drive after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once a base location is selected, it will create all of the folders OPL requires. PS2 games will primarily go in the &lt;code&gt;DVD&lt;/code&gt; folder. The &lt;code&gt;CD&lt;/code&gt; folder is also for PS2 games that use CD format rather than DVD. This only matters when a game uses other tracks on the disk for audio. I don't think any PS2 game does this. All notable and modern games have their music baked into the game code, so the &lt;code&gt;CD&lt;/code&gt; folder can be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a few other interesting folders, particular &lt;code&gt;THM&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ART&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;CFG&lt;/code&gt;. For a further description of these folders, please read my full OPL load out post: &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout" title="http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout"&gt;/opl-theme-and-loadout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OPL only wants games in the ISO format, so you need to convert CD/Bin games to ISO. OPL Manager can do this. Choose &lt;code&gt;Disc/Convert to ISO&lt;/code&gt; under Tools, and select files from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, OPL wants a particular file format. OPL Manager will mark all the illegal filenames for you and ask you to change them. File names should start with the game's disc id, should not contain certain invalid characters, and should also not be longer than 31 characters. OPL Manager will help you make sure all of this stuff is correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once all of the games are converted, I copy them into the main location and they are ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open PS2 Loader&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the games ready, it's time for the Playstation 2 to find them. The USB Drive is plugged into the Raspberry Pi. The Raspberry Pi is turned on and the server is running. Now, the Playstation 2 can be turned on. With the Free McBoot memory card also plugged in, Open PS2 Loader, or OPL is available from the menu. Select it, and OPL will open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it first boots up, there will be no games. There's a few things OPL does by default that we'll change later, but the first thing we'll need to do is configure the Network Settings so OPL can find the file server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hit &lt;code&gt;start&lt;/code&gt; to bring up OPL settings, go to Network Config, and here is where we will enter the IP information from the Raspberry Pi we received from several steps before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1507_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the SMB Server, the PI's IP address was &lt;code&gt;192.168.2.1&lt;/code&gt;, and the "Share" folder's name is &lt;code&gt;share&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; Originally, my PS2's IP address was &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.10&lt;/code&gt;, but I changed it to &lt;code&gt;192.168.2.10&lt;/code&gt; to have the same LAN address as the Raspberry Pi. It's not necessary for OPL to work, but it is necessary for POPS to work with Playstation 1 games. Please read the &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl" title="http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl"&gt;POPS&lt;/a&gt; post for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, OPL will serve PS2 games from 3 locations: the USB drive, the hard drive, and the ethernet port. By default, it won't automatically connect to these locations. You need to hit the Circle button to connect manually. Also, the hard drive is selected by default. All of this can be changed in the OPL Setting menu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1508.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1508.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1508_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1508_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1508_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, I am displaying the Ethernet games on Start Up. Since we're not using the USB Drive and Hard Drive for games, nor are we using any Applications, I disable all 3 of these options in the menu. And for both Ethernet games and Playstation games, I have OPL connecting to these sources automatically on start up.  Now, when OPL opens all of my Playstation 2 games will be shown immediately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; I'm using OPL Anniversary Edition which has Playstation as a menu display. The latest versions of OPL have removed the Playstation menu and force everything to be run from the Applications menu for better compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1506.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1506.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1506_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1506_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1506_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 1 Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can also run Playstation 1 games using OPL. As mentioned above, this is only available through OPL Anniversary Edition as a separate menu. I have detailed that process in a different post:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl" title="http://theschlock.com/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl"&gt;/playstation-games-on-ps2-opl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPL Themes and Metadata&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;OPL allows you to customize its appearance with an overall theme. You can also have artwork and metadata for all of the games. I put all of these details in a different post:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout" title="http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout"&gt;/opl-theme-and-loadout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Video Conversion and the OSSC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is one final link in this entire PS2 chain, and that is the video output. The video game generation of the Playstation 2 was the final generation to output analog video by default. HDMI became the standard for the PS3 and Xbox 360, and now everything is HDMI. Without any additional modification, Component video is the highest quality available for the PS2. I'm using the Retrovision Component cables for the PS2, which are apparently the absolute best.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analog video must be converted to digital, and that's where I'm using the OSSC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1348_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1439_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The OSSC isn't too difficult to get working, but it can send you down a rabbit hole of optimization headaches. I made another post about making Playstation 2 games looking their best using the OSSC in other post:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/using-ossc-with-ps2" title="http://theschlock.com/using-ossc-with-ps2"&gt;/using-ossc-with-ps2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retro Receiver and PlayStation 4 Controller&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final icing on this cake is using a Playstation 4 controller on the Playstation 2. With the 8bitdo Retro Receiver controller dongle for the Playstation, you can connect almost any bluetooth controller through the controller port of the Playstation or Playstation 2, and use that to control the games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1440.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1440.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1440_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1440_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1440_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm using my &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/fixing-and-modding-ps4-controller" title="http://theschlock.com/fixing-and-modding-ps4-controller"&gt;Playstation 4 controller&lt;/a&gt; that I fixed and slightly modified not all that long ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is my entire chain that serves my Playstation 2 library on my modern TV. The Raspberry Pi 3 is running a local network server serving files from a 4tb hard drive across a wired LAN connection to the Playstation 2. The Playstation 2 is running OPL from the Memory Card which finds these games and will play them. The video signal is being converted by the OSSC to a modern TV. And I'm controlling it all with a bluetooth Playstation 4 controller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a lot of moving parts, and each part in the chain is using its own power outlet, but it works. I can play my favorite games from 20 years ago, and plenty of others that I skipped at the time. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category></item><item><title>OPL Theme and Loadout</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Open PS2 Loader is an application that runs on a PS2 and allows the user to choose games with a hard drive, usb drive, or network share. Setting up games takes a bit of work, but it's overall not too difficult. I wrote about the process in another post: &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="http://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;/returning-to-the-playstation-2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In that post, I mentioned how to set up games on the file server using OPL and OPL Manager, but there's more that can be done! With games available on the backend, we want a beautiful frontend to choose our games from. This is our OPL Theme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An OPL Theme is an overall graphical layout and presentation showing off the games available. It also pulls artwork and metadata for each game. There's a default theme, but I wanted more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a quick link, here's the GitHub repo with my theme, and all artwork and metadata for my games. I've uploaded my game saves for the Memcard Pro2 here, as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout" title="https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout"&gt;https://github.com/dyreschlock/ps2-opl-loadout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Theme&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a sub-forum on PSX-Place where people have posted all of their themes. There are 72 posts with a couple of different variations of the themes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.psx-place.com/forums/themes-for-opl.229/" title="https://www.psx-place.com/forums/themes-for-opl.229/"&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/forums/themes-for-opl.229/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally, I wanted to make a theme that mirrored the Analogue Pocket's interface, but I went through a bunch of these themes to see what was available. I prefer themes that are as simple as possible, and I found one that I really liked: Jonepo's N-Glass Remix, the Blur version&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-theme-n-glass-remix-supports-all-opl.43565/" title="https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-theme-n-glass-remix-supports-all-opl.43565/"&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-theme-n-glass-remix-supports-all-opl.43565/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240601_ps2/IMG_1503_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has a nice colored backdrop and simply displays the game list, cover art, and other menu options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;More to Come&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; I'm still working on customizing the theme and layout. Please come back later.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/opl-theme-and-loadout</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category><category>Programming</category><category>Local</category></item><item><title>Playstation 2 Game Inventory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Playstation 2 is my favorite console of all time, and recently I've been setting up a way to play all of my favorite games from 20+ years ago. Using original hardware, the best way to do this is using  OPL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open PS2 Loader&lt;/b&gt;, or OPL, is an interface installed on a PS2 memory card using Free McBoot OS. Through OPL, you can view all games you have installed on a USB drive, hard drive, or on a network share. After a bit of trial and error, I have a tons of a games on a 4tb hard drive hosted on a network share from a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have loaded this hard drive with every or any game I've ever remotely wanted to play, and the list has grown far greater than I imaged it would. To keep track of everything, I put all the entries in a database. And because OPL uses box art and metadata, I wanted an easy way to view it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I made another Game Inventory page, and this shows all of the Playstation 1 and Playstation 2 games currently stored on my hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation 2 Game Inventory&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240609_ps2_inv/IMG_2524_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240609_ps2_inv/IMG_2524_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/240609_ps2_inv/IMG_2524_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category><category>Internet</category><category>Programming</category><category>Local</category></item><item><title>Twin Arch 138</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Twin Arch is one of the most recognizable landmarks from the highway leading out of Gifu in the south. It was one of the first things I noticed after arriving in Gifu for the first time eleven years ago, and after all this time, I finally went there to see it in person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5110.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5110.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5110_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5110_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5110_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I always associate the arches with South Gifu, but technically, they're in northern Aichi, just on the other side of the Kiso river that separates the two prefectures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I brought my Gameboy Camera along with to take some photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5150.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5150.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5150_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5150_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5150_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_204930_stitch.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_204930_stitch.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_204930_stitch.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Twin Arch is at the front of a long beautiful park with flower fields and walking trails through the forest. In January, they have a marathons that runs through the trails of the park. There's an auditorium, too, which was being used for a musical festival when I arrived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the true treasure of the park is the 360 degree view from the observation deck nearly 100 meters above ground. You have a clear view of southern Gifu to the north and northern Aichi to the south.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5177_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5177_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5177_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5177_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5177_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5212_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5212_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5212_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5212_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5212_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5168_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5168_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5168_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5168_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5168_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weather was absolutely perfect when I visited. Absolutely clear skies all around. You could see an incredible distance unobstructed by clouds or water vapor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nagoya was in clear view to the south. The lens on my Gameboy Camera was able to capture it nearly perfectly, too. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5254_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5254_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5254_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5254_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5254_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205155_stitch.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205155_stitch.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205155_stitch.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205155_stitch.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205155_stitch.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The camera sensor has about a 1-second refresh rate, so it's very difficult to get a significant amount of detail. There are only 4 colors, too, so that's also a problem.  But, as long as I'm able to prop the camera up against the glass or some solid surface, it's stable enough to take a photo without blur. Above is a stitched together image from 4 shots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mt. Ontake and Mt. Norikura to the north were clearly visible, too. It's pretty amazing how far you're able to see when the weather is so clear.  Mt. Norikura is the eastern-most mountain in Takayama that borders Nagano. Takayama is about 80km north from the Twin Arch, and Norikura is about 50km directly east from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="gbcameraColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="columnOne"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5295.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5295.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5295_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5295_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5295_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="columnTwo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205205.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205205.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205205.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mt. Ontake is the one bigger one on the right.  Mt. Norikura is on the left. It's pretty amazing that the GB Camera can get so much detail out of something that is over 60km away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Twin Arch is really the only landmark around the area, so you have an impressive view of suburbs after suburbs after suburbs. The view is amazing, especially on such a great day, but there isn't really a whole lot to see. There's the ferris wheel to the north next to the aquarium, but that's really the closest thing. Both Nagoya and Gifu City are so far away, you can't really get any detail other than the skyline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get some more detailed shots with both my regular camera and my GameBoy camera, so I shot a massive panoramic photo of the north with some detailed GB shots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can you find the &lt;b&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; locations of the GB shots in the panoramic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5258_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5258_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5258_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5258_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5258_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205052.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205052.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205052.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205107.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205107.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205107.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205115.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205115.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/20231021_205115.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love this GameBoy Camera so much. I'm using the GameBoy Camera Plus mod created by 2BitToy, which takes the inner circuits from a GameBoy Camera and puts them into a new shell with a CS Mount lens adapter. This allows you to use far more powerful lenses than the original. You can read about it here: &lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/pocket-camera-with-zoom-lens" title="http://theschlock.com/pocket-camera-with-zoom-lens"&gt;/pocket-camera-with-zoom-lens&lt;/a&gt; (April 13th, 2023). I'm using my Analogue Pocket to run it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also in the observation deck is a small cafe. Its signature dish was called Honey Toast. As you can see from the photo below, it is a slice of very sweet toast topped with vanilla ice cream and whip cream, drizzled with chocolate syrup surrounded by almonds and sliced strawberries. It was an excellent breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5282.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5282.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5282_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5282_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5282_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5296.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5296.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5296_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5296_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231022_arch/IMG_5296_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it'd be great to visit in other seasons to see how everything changes. It'd also be great to visit during the summer to get a semi-aerial view of fireworks in the distance. Maybe also great to visit during a sunset. But, I kinda feel like this is a one-time visit kinda place. I think I've seen it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a scan of the pamphlet: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IKrsNjOpuPetWo629s7T4-KUjE0VZFu4/view" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IKrsNjOpuPetWo629s7T4-KUjE0VZFu4/view"&gt;Twin Arch 138 Pamphlet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/twin-arch-138</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/twin-arch-138</link><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category></item><item><title>Cyberpunk 2077</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Three year after its original release, Cyberpunk 2077 has finally become the game it was meant to be from the start. The 2.0 update brings a complete rewrite of progression through leveling, equipment, and other systems. Graphics have been updated for modern consoles and PCs. And a new expansion adds a new story that expands the life of Night City.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231008141136.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231008141136.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231008141136_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231008141136_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231008141136_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Night City is the setting of Cyberpunk, a sprawling multi-leveled metropolis. Depending on where you visit, it can be many things. It's a dark, dank, depressing slum festering with gangs, addicts, and trash. It's a futuristic neon haven vibrant with youth and life. It's a posh urban center of business and industry. It's a crime ridden war zone with constant shoot outs between cops and gangs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No matter where you go, the city is dense. Many citizens live in massive mega buildings that act as their own cities. Stores and other places of interest are often on different levels forcing you traverse Night City's maze of verticality. Streets and highways bend and elevate to different areas. The native GPS in the game is a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sprawling out from its dense centers, the outer edges of Night City has oil fields, solar collectors, and farm protected by greenhouses to sustain the massive amount of resources that fuel the city and its people. Small poor neighborhoods also grow on some pockets. Even further away are the badlands, a rocky desert where little grows and dust storms are common. There are also huge trash fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231009115714.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231009115714.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231009115714_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231009115714_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/cyberpunk/Cyberpunk_2077_20231009115714_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyberpunk depicts a future where many of us think we're headed. Urban centers continue to collect more and more people, and the surrounding environment is ravaged of its resources to sustain them. Singular corporations rule the city and retain most of the wealth, which bleeds its citizens of their lives and dreams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where the story begins as you play as V.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- - - - -&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the new update, I started a new character to see what the game now has to offer, and it's keeping my attention much more than before. I've been streaming it here and there, and taking plenty of photos along the way. I'll keep adding more photos as I continue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I'll start up the DLC, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/cyberpunk-2077</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/cyberpunk-2077</link><category>Games</category><category>Game Specific</category></item><item><title>Shiraki-mine 白木峰</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Shiraki-mine is the highest peak of the mountain range separating the borders of south Toyama and north Gifu. It is one of the tallest mountains in the area at 1596 meters, and on a clear day, you'd be able to view both Toyama and Takayama cities from the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4814.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4814.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4814_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4814_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4814_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a friend coming to visit who was interested in doing a million things, and I had this mountain marked on my map from a while ago. So, we decided to take a look!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pin on my map was for a parking lot pretty close to the peak, but after searching for hiking paths and current conditions, the Hida wilderness website marked the road closed due to a landslide. There's a hiking website (&lt;a href="https://yamap.com/" title="https://yamap.com/"&gt;yamap.com&lt;/a&gt;) where people record their hikes, and the most recent hikes of the mountain seemed to confirm it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using yamap as a guide, there were several places where we could start our hike, but ultimately we planned on starting at the campground where the road had been closed and going from there. Hikes on yamap confirmed this was possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Climb&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took way longer to get to the campground than I had expected. We left a little later than planned, but the winding roads made us move very slowly.  Google Maps said it would only take an hour from my apartment. I think we left around 8:15am and finally made it to the campground at 10:05am. Even though we made two quick stops along the way, it took nearly 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The campground was a nice piece of civilization carved out of the heavy thicket of trees and bushes. There was even a museum, or some kind of cultural hall, that detailed the surrounding nature. We didn't have time for it, though, and went straight on the path forward up the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4658.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4658.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4658_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4658_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4658_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The path itself was just the closed road, so it was pretty easy. We walked passed several dammed and relegated streams coming from above. Some of the cement structures lower in the streams had been eroded away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The climb was steady and kept going and going. It wasn't long before we could see some of the height we had already traveled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4667_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4667_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4667_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4667_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4667_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;45 minutes later, we hit the detour.  We had known that the road was closed due to a landslide, and the sign directed us to take this trail instead. It indicated that it led to the summit, and another hiker of their way down informed us that this was the way to go.  So we went.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at Google Maps, it seems like the trail was about 600 meters.  Certainly not as long as the 3km we had already walked. However, our gradual 20 degree incline significantly spiked to 45 degrees, or more. The course had ropes to help pull ourselves up the climb, but it was still pretty rough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4688.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4688.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4688_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4688_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4688_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As in any marathon, you continue to push through and continue to move. The longer you stop, the longer it takes. But, my partner in climb doesn't do marathons, so we often took some breaks, which ended up being necessary. This trail completely exhausted my supply of water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another 45 minutes later, we reached the trail head and made it back to paved road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4699.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4699.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4699_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4699_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4699_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having gained some significant height, and as the paved road winded around the mountain to gain height, we often had a view that looked down on the path we've traveled. Just 10 minutes later, the top of the trail head looked so small and far away. Another 20 minutes later, even further. One of the best parts about this hike we being able to visually observe the distance we had traveled. We wouldn't have gotten this experience by simply driving to the top. On the other hand, we wouldn't have been dying of thirst and exhaustion either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 30 minutes, we reached the upper parking area at 12:15pm. There was no running water, but there were some jugs of water as to use as an emergency. It did not look safe, so we moved onward and upward. Often there were trails that appeared on the side the road that offered us a shorter path to the top. But, we had already experienced the cost of such shortcuts from the detour earlier, so we continued on the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;45 minutes later, the emergency shelter came in view. We climbed up to it and took a break inside. Nearly to the top!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the shelter gave us our first grand view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4730_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4730_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4730_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4730_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4730_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we stopped for about 10 minutes, and continued along the wooden path. Some of the path had degraded, and other parts were washed away from rain. The path looked like it went back down the other side of the mountain, which we didn't want to do. But, I scouted ahead and the path only dipped a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around the corner, the path connected with the ridge line path. Going to the right, it lead to the peak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summit &lt;span class='ja'&gt;山頂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After nearly 3 hours of walking and hiking, and a total of around 8 or 9 kilometers, we had made it to the top. From the top, we had a 360-degree view of everything around us. The east (first panoramic photo below), the north (second), and the south and west (third).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4768_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4768_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4768_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4768_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4768_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4794_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4794_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4794_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4794_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4794_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4784_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4784_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4784_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4784_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4784_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weather was pretty warm with only a few clouds when we started. But, there was a strong wind at the top. The wind had pulled in the clouds (and later on rain), so a lot of the view was covered. We could still see Toyama to the north, though not a lot of detail. To the south, we saw an area that had to be Takayama. We couldn't confirm it, but it couldn't have been anything else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn't really cold up there, but the wind was pretty strong. My hat blew clear off my head!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the south-west was a Taishido &lt;span class='ja'&gt;太子堂&lt;/span&gt;, a small buddhist shrine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4862.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4862.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4862_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4862_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4862_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder how many buddhist monks hike the mountain to pray here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other notable location at the peak is a pond to the east. The trail maps said it would take about 25 minutes to get there (and another 25 minutes to get back), but looking at the time, we could not afford to go. We needed to get out of the mountains by sundown (5pm-ish), and we were getting close to that limit with the amount of time it would take to descend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Descent&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We left the summit before 2pm and took the paved road all the way down. At the top, the paved road began on a disheveled cracked helicopter pad. Moving down the road, some of it had been completely broken apart and ground into rock, but I think a car could still drive across it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns out, going down the mountain is way more easy than going up. After about an hour, we made it back to the trail head for the detour. We decided to stay on the road this time, and go through construction. We knew how steep and hard the trail would be, and the construction and landslide couldn't be THAT bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4901.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4901.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4901_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4901_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4901_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns out, we were right. The construction and road repair was already complete. If the gate had been opened at the campsite, we could've driven this whole distance. The construction sign we found a little bit later indicated that the road would be open on October 20th, so maybe they still needed to test their repair, or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This road led off in the opposite direction before meeting back to where the detour began. Going down, it took us 45 minutes from where the trail head ended to where it began. This was the same time it took us to climb up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because it went off into another part of the mountain, I started noticing a lot of vines choking and strangling the trees and brush on the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4911.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4911.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4911_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4911_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4911_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so thick. Nothing our size would be able to move through it. Everything was covered with this vine. My friend mentioned that it was probably all one organism, too, that just continued to grow and grow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually we made it through the thicket. We reached the start of the trail head and made it to camp, a bit further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4937.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4937.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4937_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4937_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230930_shirakimine/IMG_4937_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going down the mountain is a bit easier, but the constant stamping of feet on pavement takes it toll on the soles of feet and the hip. But! We arrived and were finally able to refill our water. Another hour of driving through the windy roads, and we were back to civilization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It had a been a while since I had been on a hike, and this one turned into one of the longest hikes I've done in Hida. Much like a marathon, you often question why you ever decided to do it not long after beginning. But you move past that feeling and start enjoying the moment, the movement, the nature, and accomplishment. I need to do some more hiking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was a great hike, even though a bit rough. This would be excellent to do again with absolutely clear weather.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Timeline&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;9:27am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Naratoge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;楢峠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.347515, 137.067080" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.347515, 137.067080"&gt;36°20'51.1"N 137°04'01.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10:05am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sugadaira Campground &lt;span class='ja'&gt;杉ヶ平キャンプ場&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.428121, 137.083210" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.428121, 137.083210"&gt;36°25'41.2"N 137°04'59.6"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:00am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trail Detour (construction)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418338, 137.088122" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418338, 137.088122"&gt;36°25'06.0"N 137°05'17.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11:45am&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;End of Trail&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418701, 137.097612" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418701, 137.097612"&gt;36°25'07.3"N 137°05'51.4"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12:15pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Shiraki-mine Parking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;白木峰駐車場&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418550, 137.104979" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418550, 137.104979"&gt;36°25'06.8"N 137°06'17.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1:00pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Emergency Shelter &lt;span class='ja'&gt;避難小屋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.417257, 137.111692" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.417257, 137.111692"&gt;36°25'02.1"N 137°06'42.1"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1:30pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Shiraki-mine Summit &lt;span class='ja'&gt;白木峰山頂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.415583, 137.112222" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.415583, 137.112222"&gt;36°24'56.1"N 137°06'44.0"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1:45pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Taishido &lt;span class='ja'&gt;太子堂&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.414110, 137.110897" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.414110, 137.110897"&gt;36°24'50.8"N 137°06'39.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2:25pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Shiraki-mine Parking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;白木峰駐車場&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418550, 137.104979" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418550, 137.104979"&gt;36°25'06.8"N 137°06'17.9"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2:45pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trail Detour (end) - skipped, took road&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418701, 137.097612" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418701, 137.097612"&gt;36°25'07.3"N 137°05'51.4"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3:30pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trail Detour (start)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418338, 137.088122" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.418338, 137.088122"&gt;36°25'06.0"N 137°05'17.2"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;4:15pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;walking &lt;span class='ja'&gt;歩く&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Back to car (Sugadaira Camp) &lt;span class='ja'&gt;杉ヶ平&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.428121, 137.083210" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.428121, 137.083210"&gt;36°25'41.2"N 137°04'59.6"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;4:55pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Naratoge &lt;span class='ja'&gt;楢峠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.347515, 137.067080" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.347515, 137.067080"&gt;36°20'51.1"N 137°04'01.5"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5:15pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;by car &lt;span class='ja'&gt;車&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kawai &lt;span class='ja'&gt;河合&lt;/span&gt; 471 Interchange&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="http://google.com/maps/place/36.306396, 137.092159" title="http://google.com/maps/place/36.306396, 137.092159"&gt;36°18'23.0"N 137°05'31.8"E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/shirakimine</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/shirakimine</link><category>Hida Takayama</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Wind Castle 風の城</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In north Toyama, as Hwy 41 goes off into the mountains to connect to Hida, you can find the Wind Castle on a short mountain overlooking the boundary between civilization and mountain-life. Despite traveling through the area numerous times throughout the last 10 years, I've never noticed this structure perched on the hill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5073.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5073.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5073_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5073_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5073_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After parking at the Sarukura Forest Park alongside several barbecue bits, you are presented with 440 steps that ascend to an altitude of 345 meters. It takes about 10 minutes, which isn't so bad unless you aren't prepared for it. As you reach the top, you'll find the wind castle, pictured above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the summit of Sarukura Mountain &lt;span class='ja'&gt;猿倉山&lt;/span&gt;, and from the observation deck, you can see all the way to Toyama Bay on a clear day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took a bunch of photos and put them together into a huge panoramic shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vjU_v7KZ6PzFwT7WJH_ybOiF-fDR_IWq/view" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vjU_v7KZ6PzFwT7WJH_ybOiF-fDR_IWq/view"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/wind_castle_panoramic_hi_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/wind_castle_panoramic_hi_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/wind_castle_panoramic_hi_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hi-Res Panoramic: /wind_castle_panoramic_hi.png (186.5mb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see nearly all of Toyama, and there is a free-to-use binocular scope so you see the airport, sports arena, and other areas in clear view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, around 1558 to 1570, the summit of Sarukura Mountain was the site of the Sarukura Castle &lt;span class='ja'&gt;猿倉城&lt;/span&gt;, but nothing remains today. The military commander at the time was under the command of the ruler of the Hida region to the south. Hida is surrounded by mountains, so there are very few ways of getting up there. This castle was built to monitor any large armies that may be headed up the mountain to attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5012_stitch.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5012_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5012_stitch_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5012_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5012_stitch_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This path can be clearly seen today in the above panoramic. There's an incredible clear view of Hwy 41 coming down from Hida. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It still completely baffles me that I never noticed this place before. Although, I think it's easy to see why I hadn't noticed it before. On my way back home up to Hida, I took some reverse photos looking back at the mountain and the castle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5102.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5102.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5102_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5102_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5102_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5107.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5107.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5107_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5107_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_wind_castle/IMG_5107_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The white castle blends into the sky very easily. If you didn't know it was there, you would never notice it. But, once you know that it's there and where to look, it pops out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's also not a whole lot of information about the Wind Castle online. In fact, my friend and I only found this thing by skimming around Toyama in Google Maps looking for something to do. I wanted to know exactly when they built this thing, and its purpose. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a plaque on the Wind Caste which states the following: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;平成&lt;/span&gt;2&lt;span class='ja'&gt;年度&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;I&gt;Heisei-2 (or 1990)&lt;/I&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;中部通商産業局&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;地域エネルギー開発利用発電モデル事業&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;I&gt;Chubu Bureau of International Trade and Industry Regional Energy Development Utilization Power Generation Model Project&lt;/I&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class='ja'&gt;「風の城&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;風力エネルギー開発利用事業」&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;I&gt;"The Wind Castle - Wind Energy Development Utilization Project"&lt;/I&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;-&lt;span class='ja'&gt;富山県大沢野町&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;I&gt;- Osawano Town, Toyama Prefecture.&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quite a mouthful. Seems like it was built in 1990, although I wanted to find more substantial information online. Eventually I did find a blog post of someone talking about Sarukura castle (explained earlier), and a few other things. In particular, in 1975, as part of Toyama prefecture's 100th year anniversary, a 9.6km trail was opened from Mt. Sarukura to Mt. Kosami Gozen &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小佐波御前山&lt;/span&gt;. It didn't mention anything about the Wind Castle at that time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't find anything that confirmed its opening in 1990. But, it was probably built in 1990 as its architecture and flashy nature seems to fit that time well. Like everything built during the economic high times of the 80s and 90s in Japan, it is definitely showing wear and tear from the years. Some of the windows have been kicked out, and the metal railing has graffiti almost everywhere. One of the door had been kicked in, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've never been, I would absolutely recommend driving up here if you're going to or from Toyama. I will probably return here each time I visit Toyama now. Different weather, different season, and different time of day will all create a new view. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/wind-castle</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/wind-castle</link><category>Japan</category><category>Travel</category></item><item><title>Nishi-cho Taiki 西町大喜</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Recommended as one of the best (or, at least, most significant) ramen restaurants in Toyama, my friend and I went to the original Nishi-cho Taiki location as he continued his month-long vacation in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While traveling to all corners of Japan, my friend had a list of all the best ramen in each city and region. Toyama only one on the list, &lt;b&gt;Nishi-cho Taiki&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They have expanded to three locations in their near 80 years of business, but my friend and I visited the original location. It is a small hole-in-the-wall kinda place near the main shopping area of downtown Toyama. It's also across the street from Toyama's Glass museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5077.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5077.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5077_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5077_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5077_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5079.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5079.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5079_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5079_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5079_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably couldn't even tell it was there unless you knew what you were looking at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside is a thin row of seats with a minimal amount of decoration. Like most traditional ramen places, it was built for speed and efficiency.  Get in, eat, and get out. The other locations look much more spread-out and modern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The signature dish of Nishi-cho Taiki is their Chukka Soba &lt;span class='ja'&gt;中華そば&lt;/span&gt;. At this location, the standard sized bowl was 950&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5084.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5084.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5084_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5084_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5084_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Nishi-cho Taiki established the Toyama-style of Black Ramen with its thick fatty noodles, heavy soy-sauce flavored broth, and numerous amounts of toppings. Taiki's ramen has Chashu (pork), onions, and pepper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything is piled on top, and as indicated by the waitress, you should mix it around a bit before digging in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5088.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5088.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5088_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5088_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5088_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5090.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5090.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5090_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5090_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/IMG_5090_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I've had such heavy meaty ramen. I've been out of the ramen game a little while, and also Takayama's ramen has very thin noodles and thin broth. The standard size is pretty much the perfect amount of ramen.  Yet, they also offered sizes that were 1.5 times and double the standard.  I don't know how anyone could eat those.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the onions and pepper, the ramen had a somewhat hidden, gradually building, and lingering spiciness to it, which was very unique. I always consume everything I order, so I always eat/drink the broth, which is not the Japanese norm. The broth was very dark with the amount of soy-sauce infused in it. Ramen isn't the most healthy food to begin with, but with the amount of soy-sauce included, I would not recommend eating/drinking all of it, like I had. With the amount of onions and pepper in there, too, I needed a lot more water than what they provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thought it was pretty good, but I'm not a fan of Black Ramen. I wouldn't put it very high of a pantheon of ramen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about the restaurant on their website: &lt;a href="http://www.nisicho-taiki.com/" title="http://www.nisicho-taiki.com/"&gt;http://www.nisicho-taiki.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, here's a scan of their pamphlet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/nishicho-taiki-pamphlet.png" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/231001_ramen/nishicho-taiki-pamphlet.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/nishicho-taiki-pamphlet_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/nishicho-taiki-pamphlet_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/231001_ramen/nishicho-taiki-pamphlet_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/nishi-cho-taiki</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/nishi-cho-taiki</link><category>Japan</category><category>Others</category><category>Ramen</category><category>Travel</category></item><item><title>Pokemon Go Raid Counters (updated)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have updated my the codebase for my Raid Counter lists in Pokemon Go. Overall, the calculation method are still based on Gamepress's &lt;a href="https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/comprehensive-dps-spreadsheet" title="https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/comprehensive-dps-spreadsheet"&gt;Comprehensive DPS Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, but now I'm pulling my data from Poke_Miner's &lt;a href="https://github.com/PokeMiners/game_masters" title="https://github.com/PokeMiners/game_masters"&gt;Game Master&lt;/a&gt; file, and also updated the UI to be more visually appealing and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter"&gt;&lt;b&gt;List of General Raid Counters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/220906_pokemon/IMG_0744.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/220906_pokemon/IMG_0744.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/220906_pokemon/IMG_0744.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are two others pages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/custom" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/custom"&gt;Personal Raid Counter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; —  I made a page that uses Pokemon in my game to determine whether or not I can defeat the raid boss using just my two accounts. It's not up to date. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/top" title="http://theschlock.com/apps/pokemon/raidcounter/top"&gt;Top Counters per Pokemon Type&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; —  Another page compares Pokemon of each type against a generic Arceus to see which is strongest within each type, and overall. It's up to date, but I haven't focused on readability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Purpose&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of these pages is to determine which Pokemon are the strongest against Pokemon that appear as raid bosses. It's very helpful to understand which Pokemon are worth catching and leveling to take down these bosses easily. While they almost always can't be defeated with just one person, every bit helps to defeat them with the fewest amount of people as you can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many sites that focus of Pokemon Go offer lists of the best pokemon, but never with enough detail to understand why they're the best and never on a single page with all bosses available in the game. Gamepress's DPS page is a great resource to see how much more powerful one pokemon is than another, but you have to manually search and filter everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2019, I first made this page. At the time, it was use the outputted data from Gamepress to create the page. Whenever there was an update, it would take a LOONGG time to redownload everything. So, last year, I rewrote the backend to do all the calculations itself using the same method as Gamepress. There's more information about here on the previous Project post: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters-old" title="http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters-old"&gt;Previous Post from 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I liked my previous page, but it was unreadable to anyone else. Also, Gamepress almost never updates its backend data, which my page relied on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, this update does two things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, I'm using Poke_Miner's &lt;a href="https://github.com/PokeMiners/game_masters" title="https://github.com/PokeMiners/game_masters"&gt;Game Master&lt;/a&gt; file in Github to get my updates of Pokemon and Moves. This gets updated much more frequently when stuff changes in the game. (At least, I think it does.) Going along with this, all Pokemon data and moves are stored in the database, which makes it MUCH easier to change manually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, I updated the UI. Only I could read it before. Now, I added labels on the numbers, and added images of the Pokemon and more colors, too. The Pokemon images really really pop, and make it super easy to scan the lists. I also added rounded corners, because Fuck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Updates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not completely happy with a lot of the white-on-white text, so I need to fix that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, one of my users complained that he still didn't understand anything, so I was thinking of making pages for each raid boss that showed more detail, such as which moves were available, and pokemon types and weaknesses. I'll get to that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/pokemon-go-raid-counters</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category><category>Internet</category><category>Programming</category><category>Pokemon</category></item><item><title>Fixing and Modding a PS4 Controller</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Through trying to mod my Playstation Classic, I noticed that the triangle button on my PS4 controller didn't work. Some of the other inputs seemed sticky, too. Searching for troubleshooting methods online, one video suggested taking the controller apart to give it a good clean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran through the cleaning procedure, but it was still broken. Such an annoying shame. However, the video mentioned that the button membranes or the button cable ribbon could be damaged. They were pretty cheap on Amazon! Only $3 for replacement membranes and $5 for a new cable ribbon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fixing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;They arrived pretty quickly, so I ran a stream where I tried to fix my controller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class="ratio16by9" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aSA6RM1V_jI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Success!  I was really surprised that it worked so flawlessly so easily. These controllers cost $60 new, so I think it's pretty amazing how a simple $5 part could completely fix it. I wonder how many people throw their controller away or sell it as junk online just because of a problem that a simple $3 or $5 part could fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, fixing this thing was easy. What else could we do?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modding&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking out the buttons is extraordinary simple. They're just plastic pieces siting in a plastic shell. The rubber membranes and cable ribbon underneath do the real work of detecting the button presses. You could put anything on top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found some pretty blue buttons on Amazon that would look nice with the white controller, so I ran another stream where I attempted to replace those buttons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class="ratio16by9" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dD73shUj-uo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned on the stream, there was a bit of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all Playstation 4 controllers are created equal. There have been a few revisions over the years. Of course, I knew this from having to buy the correct button cable film from before, and also noticed that the trigger membranes were different. But, I didn't pay attention when buying the buttons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the buttons are nearly identical across all revisions, the R2 and L2 triggers are not the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3616.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3616.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3616_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3616_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3616_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3617.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3617.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3617_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3617_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3617_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my earlier revision of the controller, the tension and knock back is caused by a spring loaded wire that sits in a pathway on the inner left side of the button. The later revision does something else and has a much longer clip that prevents the button from getting ripped out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3654.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3654.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3654_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3654_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_3654_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think the controller looks better than before, but the R2 L2 buttons are still black. Also, the touch pad and home button are also black. It wasn't a complete conversion to blue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modding, again&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding a complete set of buttons for my controller wasn't easy, but they did exist on AliExpress. And for only $3.  There was no way I was going to find a set of buttons with the exact Blue color, but I could find a full set of White buttons that matched the color of the controller. In the end, only a few buttons could be blue and they would really stand out. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once again, I streamed the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class="ratio16by9" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0PAGyqHwjAQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;..and once again not everything was perfect. The white of the buttons was not the exact same color white as the controller. It was more of a warm white, rather than a slate white. Also, the R2 and L2 buttons were closer, but not exact, so they could not be used. R1 and L1 were also wrong. Replacing the touch pad is more involved than it initially looked, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So many problems, but it wasn't all a waste.  The Home, Share, and Options are the same across all model of controllers, so they fit. And the slight difference in color isn't TOO noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_4623.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_4623.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_4623_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_4623_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230910_ps4/IMG_4623_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it's not a perfect match, I think it looks better than before. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of the face buttons and sticks popping out from the contrast and all the secondary buttons fading into the color of the controller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continuing…&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For now, I'm going to call this closed. It'll take a bit of searching to try and find the exact colors I want for my model of controller.  More money, more time, more hassle. It's 90% of the way there, and that's good enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main goal was fixing the controller in the first place, and even more so, I now have an excellent controller to use for the Switch. I bought an 8bitdo wireless adapter for the modded Playstation Classic, which I had given up on. Using it on the Switch instead, the PS4 controller works amazing. It is a far more comfortable controller to use than the Joy-cons.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/fixing-and-modding-ps4-controller</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/fixing-and-modding-ps4-controller</link><category>Games</category><category>Projects</category></item><item><title>Top 20 Music Tracks</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On Twitter, I came across a post that I could not stop thinking about. It was an innocent post asking people to post their Top 20 favorite music tracks of all time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/twitter_post.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/twitter_post.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/twitter_post.webp" /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/heathensquirrel/status/1693203564703653956" title="https://twitter.com/heathensquirrel/status/1693203564703653956"&gt;https://twitter.com/heathensquirrel/status/1693203564703653956&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tracks that inspire. Tracks that bring joy.  Track that stir emotions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are so many tracks like this in my life that I instantly had some ideas and wanted to flush out the list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The one rule is that you cannot repeat artists in your list.  One track per artist only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top 20 Tracks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's my list.  They are in a general order of 1 to 20, but then grouped by similar sounds and categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="columns tracks"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WtQFqN_-JoA" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WtQFqN_-JoA"&gt;Sasha - Xpander (12” Remaster)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuWAO9QSG2Y" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuWAO9QSG2Y"&gt;Hybrid - Finished Symphony (Original Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7-4-5mv-11I" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7-4-5mv-11I"&gt;Orbital - Halcyon + On + On (Aaron Static 2011 Bootleg)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G5FDls2byWI" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G5FDls2byWI"&gt;Shpongle - Ineffable Mysteries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azNlYul2IoY" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azNlYul2IoY"&gt;M83 - Couleurs&lt;a/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJWlBfo5Oj0" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJWlBfo5Oj0"&gt;Moby - Porcelain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VrDc0W-Epc8" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VrDc0W-Epc8"&gt;Nick Warren - Buenos Aires&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QijkRbjRgBo" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QijkRbjRgBo"&gt;Henry Saiz + Guy J - Meridian (Original Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="columns tracks"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=du9hMQHuBdc" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=du9hMQHuBdc"&gt;Andain - Beautiful Things (Gabriel &amp; Dresden Unplugged)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FOhZ-WeNDNs" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FOhZ-WeNDNs"&gt;Oceanlab - On a Good Day (Above &amp; Beyond Club Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_m3M_7hOMuI" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_m3M_7hOMuI"&gt;Underworld - Loved A Film (Extended Club Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5Se8SqCgnU" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5Se8SqCgnU"&gt;Spooky - Belong (Igor Cold Unofficial Remix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ifJ1W4s-qk" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ifJ1W4s-qk"&gt;Golan Globus - Blazer - Version 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oD8cRAjFB1w" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oD8cRAjFB1w"&gt;Holden &amp; Thompson - Nothing (93 Returning Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PB9Mi_hf7og" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PB9Mi_hf7og"&gt;Juno Reactor - Mona Lisa Overdrive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_hCsuvdPWsk" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_hCsuvdPWsk"&gt;System S.F. feat. ANNA - Look To The Sky (Extended Mix)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="columns tracks"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=40BZyMdDG4s" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=40BZyMdDG4s"&gt;Yasunori Mitsuda - Chrono Cross - Time’s Scar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1L3bkiwU5XQ" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1L3bkiwU5XQ"&gt;Joe Hisaishi - The Legend of Ashitaka (Princess Mononoke)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zSgiXGELjbc" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zSgiXGELjbc"&gt;Josh Boswell - A Glorious Dawn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcJjMnHoIBI" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcJjMnHoIBI"&gt;Weird Al - Eat It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/top20.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/top20.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230829_top20_tracks/top20.webp" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I may have missed something, but I think this is generally correct. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/top-20-music-tracks</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/top-20-music-tracks</link><category>Music</category></item><item><title>Completing the Lego Bonsai Garden</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Lego Bonsai Tree and Lego Tranquil Garden have been two beautiful releases by Lego in recent years that complement each other perfectly. The both do an excellent job of hiding the lego aesthetic while pushing forward the Japanese aesthetic that makes them excellent display pieces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built both of these before on stream. I wrote some words and took some pictures, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/lego-bonsai-tree" title="http://theschlock.com/lego-bonsai-tree"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230416_lego/IMG_2062_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230416_lego/IMG_2062_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230416_lego/IMG_2062_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/lego-bonsai-tree" title="http://theschlock.com/lego-bonsai-tree"&gt;Lego Bonsai Tree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/lego-tranquil-garden" title="http://theschlock.com/lego-tranquil-garden"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6525_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6525_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6525_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/lego-tranquil-garden" title="http://theschlock.com/lego-tranquil-garden"&gt;Lego Tranquil Garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Putting both sets side-by-side shows how the sets can complement each other. Both bases are identical, and the cherry blossom motif uses the same colors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6498.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6498.jpg" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6498_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6498_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230812_lego_garden/IMG_6498_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trees aren't exactly identical, though.  Also, the balance very heavy on the left side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because I loved that Lego Bonsai Tree so much, I had bought a second one for cheap on Yahoo Auctions to make a slightly larger bonsai tree. So, rather than doing that, I could build it as normal and place it on the right side of the garden giving the scene more balance through framing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Building a Second Bonsai Tree&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It only took me an hour to put the set together, which is twice as fast as my previous build. Of course, this time I wasn't building to an audience on Twitch, and I had already done it before, so that accounted for the speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were two things that were different this time:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The feet were different?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first difference was the &lt;b&gt;feet for the base&lt;/b&gt;. These feet were constructed using a 2x2 plate with a bottom technic pin, a technic tube, and a rubber something that went on the tube. These parts were totally different than my other Bonsai Tree and even the Tranquil Garden. The original set were made using a 2x2 plate with a bottom tire peg and a rubber tire. You can see the difference in the right photo below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6557.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6557.jpg" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6557_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6557_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6557_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6564.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6564.jpg" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6564_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6564_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6564_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know why this is different, but you really can't tell in the finished design and it works the same way. I haven't looked into it, but maybe the Chinese version uses the cheaper parts? I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Balance Mod&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I built my first bonsai tree, I used a building mod that claimed to make a more balanced tree, and overall it did. The main branch went down the center of the tree, and two other shorter branches were on both sides. I started doing the same mod to this tree. But after building it, I decided to change. Not all trees have the same shape, so I thought it would look more natural if the trees looked different. I took it apart and went with the standard build.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6576.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6576.jpg" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6576_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6576_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6576_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6582.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6582.jpg" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6582_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6582_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6582_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original design (on the right) is really weird. Nature does have a lot of randomness, but there's still a balance to it. However, there is not a stiff coordinated balance like the mod. Maybe there's a nice in-between, but whatever. In the end, it results in a different tree, as you'd expect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6598.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6598.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6598_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6598_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6598_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On its own, the modded balanced tree looks way better just by itself. The unmodified tree on the left feels like it's missing a patch on the right side. But that's okay because it's just one piece of the overall scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branch Blending&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cherry blossom leaves of the Bonsai Tree and Tranquil Garden are similar, but not the same. Both have white leaves, although they're different pieces. Both use magenta flowers with stud pegs. But for pink flowers, the Bonsai tree uses frogs and the Garden uses stud flowers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted all the leaves of the cherry blossom trees to be more uniform, which meant sharing pieces across all of the leaves. The magenta pieces were fine, but the pink pieces were heavy on the Bonsai tree, light on the Garden trees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing some math, each Bonsai tree has 20 leaves for its tree. The Garden trees have a total of 17. In total, 57 leaves across the three sets. Each Bonsai leaf had 5 frogs, for a total of 200 pink frogs across both sets. That means each leaf should have 3.5 frogs. Each Garden leaf had 4 small flowers, for a total of 58 flower pieces. Easy. Each leaf should have one flower peg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started taking things apart and moving pieces around, and in the end, things looked much better than before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6608.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6608.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6608_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6608_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6608_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Garden trees still look a little sparse. But, that's because the leaves are spread apart more than the Bonsai tree. Outside of other mods, you can't really help it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Light Kit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I bought the second Bonsai tree, I also bought a second light kit. Having installed one previously, it was WAYY easier to put together this time. I knew exactly how I was going to hook everything up and it all came together pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, it came together quite well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6652.jpg" title="http://theschlock.com/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6652.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6652_t.webp" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6652_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/230816_lego_etc/IMG_6652_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Bonsai trees bookend the Tranquil Garden perfectly and create a scene with the tea house slightly peering through the white and pink branches. I ended up switching the position of the Bonsai trees because of the empty patch of the unmodified tree fits well next to the trees from the Garden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looks great during the day with natural light, and looks great at night with the LEDs flipped on. The photo is a little blown out so it makes the LEDs look brighter than the are, but it looks great in person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the only problem is how dim the Garden looks compared to the tree. Again, in person, it's not as bad as the photo, but it's still dark. Maybe I'll look into the LED set for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, I'm really happy how it turned out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>http://theschlock.com/completing-lego-bonsai-garden</guid><link>http://theschlock.com/completing-lego-bonsai-garden</link><category>Toys</category><category>Others</category></item></channel></rss>