<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>One Schlock's Requiem</title><description>One Schlock's Requiem is the personal website/blog  of Jim Hendricks. I'm a former Software Developer from Wisconsin, and now a Teacher of English living in central Japan.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 10:04:55 +0900</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 10:04:55 +0900</lastBuildDate><link>https://theschlock.com/</link><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://theschlock.com/feed.xml"/><category>Japan / Games / Other Stuff</category><item><title>Japan Travel Map Page</title><description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite hobbies is traveling around Japan. I love discovering and learning about new and interesting places and their history. I have lived here for over 12 years now, but it's been almost 19 years since I first came here and became inspired to explore, take photos, and research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been going through a lot of old unsorted, unprocessed photos and unfinished posts of travels. With nearly 200 posts talking about Japanese travel and locations, I wanted to see all these locations on a map. Through doing research about some locations, I found an open source JavaScript mapping library called &lt;a href="https://leafletjs.com/" title="https://leafletjs.com/"&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;, and I've added a page with all these links pinned on a map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the following link to view the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/map" title="https://theschlock.com/map"&gt;Japan Travel Map&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/map" title="https://theschlock.com/map"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250501_map/map_screen_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250501_map/map_screen_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250501_map/map_screen_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Travel Page is a little bit of a work-in-progress at the moment, so the styles and features may be updated or changed in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned about Leaflet from visiting &lt;a href="https://haikyo.info/" title="https://haikyo.info/"&gt;Haikyo.info&lt;/a&gt;. This site is a collection of abandoned places around Japan and whether or not its possible to trespass and explore. I came across the site when trying to find information about the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/red-factory.html" title="https://theschlock.com/red-factory.html"&gt;Red Factory&lt;/a&gt;, an old abandoned factory which was highly rated among ruins explorers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaflet has been super easy to use. Going through their &lt;a href="https://leafletjs.com/examples.html" title="https://leafletjs.com/examples.html"&gt;Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, their quick start guide puts a map on a webpage almost immediately. Plotting points is incredibly simple, too, once you get the geo coordinates. It gets a little more complicated when you want to use layers to filter certain points on the map, but it was really just an extra step. You can take a look at the code, but there's not a whole lot of special things going on underneath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, the Red Factory is one post in a series of posts from 2016 when my friends Fishy and Chaos came to visit. These posts have their own &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/keyword/fishy-chaos" title="https://theschlock.com/keyword/fishy-chaos"&gt;keyword&lt;/a&gt;, so you can view all 8 of the posts from there.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/japan-travel-map-page</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/japan-travel-map-page</link><category>Travel</category><category>Webpage</category><category>Japan</category><category>Programming</category></item><item><title>Battle of Sekigahara 関ヶ原の戦い</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Battle of Sekigahara is considered the most decisive battle in Japanese history. It was fought between the Western Army led by Ishida Mitsunari on behalf of the newly established somewhat traditional government of Japan, and Tokugawa Ieyasu who considered Japan weak to outsiders and wanted to establish a new government. Tokugawa won the battle, and after establishing a new government brought forth 250 years of peace and prosperity. This stability led to a sharp increase in population, education, and overall wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The battle happened on October 21st, 1600.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Leading to the Battle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 1500s, Japan was in chaos. The time is referred to the Warring States period, or Sengoku-jidai &lt;span class='ja'&gt;戦国時代&lt;/span&gt;. It's called this because Japan was in a constant state of civil war. In 1573, Oda Nobunaga led his army to the capital and overthrew reigning Shogun, Ashikaga Yoshiaki. From there, his army spread out conquering the nearby kingdoms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the middle of his conquest, he was betrayed and committed seppuku rather than be captured. This was in 1582. He was succeded by Toyotomi Hideyoshi who continued the conquest, and brought all of Japan together as a single kingdom by 1592. He restored power to the emperor, but he was really the one in charge. In 1593, his second son was born, and planned on succeded him as grand regeant to the emperor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toyotomi died in 1598 leaving behind his 5-year-old son, and a council of regeants to teach and advise him until he was old enough to assume his position. This is where the TV show and novel &lt;b&gt;Shogun&lt;/b&gt; begins. Immediately after his death, the Council of Five Regeants begin scheming and allying to seize control of Japan for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shogun and The Council of Five&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Shogun TV show is slightly different than history, and of course all the names have been changed. The Council of Five had the following members: &lt;b&gt;Tokugawa&lt;/b&gt; Ieyasu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;徳川家康&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Ukita&lt;/b&gt; Hideie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宇喜多秀家&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Maeda&lt;/b&gt; Toshiie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;前田利家&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Uesugi&lt;/b&gt; Kagekatsu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;上杉景勝&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Terumoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利輝元&lt;/span&gt;. Mori only became a member of the council because of his uncle's death a year prior. His uncle was &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Takakage &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川隆景&lt;/span&gt;, who is sometimes considered an honorary member of The Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately after Toyotomi's death, Tokugawa began a series of marriage pacts and campaigns to secure his family, despite it being forbidden by the council laws. Maeda was said to have been part of this conspiracy. &lt;b&gt;Ishida&lt;/b&gt; Mitsunari &lt;span class='ja'&gt;石田三成&lt;/span&gt; was one of the highest level bureacrats in Toyotomi's government. He considered Tokugawa's action a complete insult to Toyotomi's legacy and quickly aligned himself with Ukita, Mori, and Uesugi. He also had powerful friendships with &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Shima&lt;/b&gt; Sakon &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島清興&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Ishida gained the support of many lords of western kingdoms, Tokugawa gained support from the east. One of his strongest allies was &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田長政&lt;/span&gt;, who was perhaps the best military strategist in Japan at that time. He was the chief strategist for Toyotomi. Ishida apparently loathed and often insulted the military commanders, so Kuroda and six other commanders planned to assassinate him. Tokugawa actually quelled their attempt, and later recruited all of them in his Eastern Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several skermishes in the east and west pulled the armies together as they met in Sekigahara on October 21, 1600.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Battle Stage&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/image/hosted/20250322_sekigahara.png" title="https://theschlock.com/image/hosted/20250322_sekigahara.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/20250322_sekigahara_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/20250322_sekigahara_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/image/hosted/20250322_sekigahara_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the battle, a thick fog covered Sekigahara. No one could see more than a few meters in front of them. But with the sunrise, the fog had disspated by around 8am and all the armies could see their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Army led by &lt;b&gt;Tokugawa&lt;/b&gt; is red. They created a "fish scale" battle pattern with the main forces creating a line directly opposing the Western Army. &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Takenaka&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹中&lt;/span&gt; positioned themselves on Okayama hill &lt;span class='ja'&gt;岡山&lt;/span&gt; in the north overlooking the battlefield. &lt;b&gt;Fukushima&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;福島&lt;/span&gt; led the main force on the frontline poised to strike first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Western Army is mainly blue, but also consists of the yellow and green armies at the start of the battle. They are multi-colored because of some key moments in the battle which led to their defeat. The main force was led by &lt;b&gt;Ukita&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宇喜多&lt;/span&gt;, one of the Five Regeants. &lt;b&gt;Ishida&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;石田&lt;/span&gt; positioned himself with &lt;b&gt;Shima&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島&lt;/span&gt; at the most northern on the army line on Sasaoyama &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笹尾山&lt;/span&gt;. Colored in blue, the furthest south is &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷&lt;/span&gt;, Ishida's other close friend. But, the largest army on the southern end of the west army was &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川&lt;/span&gt;, colored in yellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, the Western Army had around 82,000 soldiers compared to the Eastern Army's 88,888. Fearing Ishida's defeat, several lords who pledged support for Ishida did not attend the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Battle Begins&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the fog cleared, it is said that &lt;b&gt;Ii&lt;/b&gt; Naomasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;井伊直政&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Matsudaira&lt;/b&gt; Tadayoshi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松平忠吉&lt;/span&gt; of the Eastern Army ordered their gunmen to take aim and fire on &lt;b&gt;Ukita's&lt;/b&gt; army. &lt;b&gt;Fukushima&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;福島&lt;/span&gt;, frontline battle commander of the Eastern Army and who was promised first-attack by Tokugawa, became enraged and ordered his whole army to quickly join the fight against &lt;b&gt;Ukita&lt;/b&gt;. From Okayama Hill, &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田&lt;/span&gt; noticed that the battle had begun, and fired his flare to signal all frontline Eastern armies to attack the West. The full engagement of the battle began sometime between 8am and 10am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Army moved in to engage the Western Army, and with the frontlines of both armies holding off each other, Tokugawa began advancing his groups from the far east of the battlefield to encourage his troops and also scare his opponents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the while, &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川&lt;/span&gt; stood on the top of Mt. Matsuo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松尾山&lt;/span&gt;, his forces never joining the battle. Prior to the battle, he had made an agreement with Tokugawa through Kuroda. He would betray Ishida and join the fight as a member of the Eastern Army. But, he had yet to make any move. Ishida fired a flare signalling him to attack, but still he stood there with indecision. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, it wasn't until Tokugawa's troops fired some warning shots at him that &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; ordered his troops down the hill and attack &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷&lt;/span&gt;, the nearest of the Western Army. Otani was prepared for Kobayakawa's betrayal, but didn't expect several others to join him. His forces could not withstand their rush attack. Otani committed seppuku in the woods and ordered his retainer to hide his head to prevent it from getting into enemy hands. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the yellow armies were now members of the Eastern Army. Behind the Eastern Army, in the back, marked in green, were forces led by the &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利&lt;/span&gt; clan. They pledged to fight for the Western Army, but were prevented from joining when one of their armies refused to fight. And after seeing Kobayakawa turn, they knew that winning was hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;b&gt;Otani's&lt;/b&gt; forces eradicted, &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa's&lt;/b&gt; betrayal, and &lt;b&gt;Mori's&lt;/b&gt; neutrality, the Western Army had collapsed. The was no way for &lt;b&gt;Ishida&lt;/b&gt; to win. His friend Otani was dead. His other friend, Shima, was missing and presumed killed in battle. Four other battle commanders were also killed. He ordered a retreat. He, Ukita, and a few others escaped from the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Yoshihiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津義弘&lt;/span&gt; and nephew &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Toyohisa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津豊久&lt;/span&gt;, leaders of their forces in the Western Army refused to turn their backs to the enemy to retreat. While the battle had mostly concluded by 2pm, they launched a surprise offensive to the middle of the frontline, piercing through the Eastern Army. And making their retreat to the south. The nephew was killed in this surprise attack/retreat, but Yoshihiro could escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Battle was over. The full length of the battle only took around 6 hours, although the main clash of armies only took place from Kuroda's signal flare to not long after Otani committed seppuku. Of the Western Army's 82,000 soldiers, 23,000 had defected and 35,270 were killed. The Eastern Army only lost 8,000 soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;After the Battle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the fighting ceased, the remaining Western soldiers were either captured or executed. Tokugawa put down a folding stool in the field near his final encampment and performed the post-battle ritual called the Head Viewing Ceremony, or kubi-jikken &lt;span class='ja'&gt;首実検&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This spot and so many other key locations of the battle have been preserved in modern day Sekigahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3079.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3079.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3079_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3079_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3079_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the location where Tokugawa sat as he inspected the heads. Next to this is a plaque which describes the scene:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tokugawa Ieyasu, fresh from his decisive victory at the Battle of Sekigahara, sat here on a folding stool called a shogi to inspect the heads of the enemy commanders his allies presented. The heads, once inspected, were buried in two great mounds along with the corpses from the battlefield. During the Warring States Period, it was customary to mourn the dead of both sides, enemy and ally alike, so this inspection was also a gesture of respect for the dead.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia continues by explaining that the Head Viewing Ceremony was a way of mourning and respecting the dead of both sides, but it was also a way for victorious commanders and soldiers to get recognized for their valor in the battle, and get properly rewarded for it. This scene is illustrated at &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/sekigahara-warland#head-viewing" title="https://theschlock.com/sekigahara-warland#head-viewing"&gt;Sekigahara Warland.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the heads were inspected, they were wrapped in cloth and placed in one of two massive burial mounds along with the corpses of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the site of the Head Viewing Ceremony and Tokugawa's final encampment is the location of the new Battle of Sekigahara museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Battle of Sekigahara Museum&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3086.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3086.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3086_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3086_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3086_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Battle of Sekigahara Museum opened recently in 2020, and while I consider the museum a must visit if you're going to Sekigahara, it is a very uneven experience. I arrived just as the museum opened at 9:30am. Tickets are only 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; which includes a theater experience, if reservations are not full. I was first on the standby list for the film starting at 9:45am. There were only a few reservations ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Museum Theater&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering the theater, you walk down a hallway with projected names of the wall of all those involved in the battle. The first theater is a trapezoidal room with a projected map on the floor. The map begins showing dates and events leading up to the battle. It shows a full map of Japan where Ishida and Tokugawa allies were located, and zooms in on the center of Japan as their forces begin to converge in Sekigahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As everyone entered the room and surrounded the map, the film was introduced by the guide and then it began. It quickly went through the leading dates and events again, and then showed Sekigahara. Each army, their commander, and their position on the map was introduced, and then the battle began as I had described it above. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As each key moments of the battle played out, the armies moved on the map and clashed with their opponents. It was kind of like a strategy game, which became an incredibly effective way of showing how the battle progressed. The soldiers themselves were tiny little colored men, but the commanders of those armies were blown up giants when their key moments took place. They spoke their intentions with emotion and feeling which illustrated some intensity of the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the battle concluded, everyone moved into the next, octogonal theater. This one had theater seating. I sat in the back and the film began showing the same battle, but this time, from the point of view of the ground rather than a birdseye view. The film was projected onto half of the room, giving us a 180 view of the battle. Fans mounted on the ceiling blew air at us and we sweeped around the battle. Lights flashed as gun fire erupted. And the ground shook and rumbled our seats as horses ran past. Once again, each of the key moments of battle were highlighted showing us the emotion of the commanders and their decisions which led to either victory or defeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty hyped experience and incredibly effective at teaching us about the battle and those involved. Prior to the museum, I really only knew about Ishida and Tokugawa, and also knew about Otani committing seppuku. Now I knew about the majority of key commanders in the battle and what they did. I don't think I have ever visited a museum and came out learning as much as I had from this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Museum Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The theater experience is in STARK contrast to the rest of the museum. After exiting the theater, we rode the escalator to the second floor. The second floor exhibit shows the number of soldiers in each of the army, and then displays replica armor of each of the commanders. Shiny new looking armor, obviously not realistic to what they actually wore at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From there, several letters were displayed of correspondence between commanders leading up to the battle. I had no idea what any of these were at the time. They might be more interesting now that I've researched the battle in more detail for these blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the main exhibit of the museum was just a bunch of stuff that wasn't presented with a strong connection to the subject. It was completely different compared with the film on the first floor. At the end of the exhibit, there were some swords and guns that you could pick up to feel their weight, but it felt kinda tacked on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Museum Observatory&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fifth floor gave a 360-degree view of Sekigahara. The museum was in the very center of town and the center of the battle, so you could see everything from this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3101_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3101_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3101_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3101_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3101_stitch_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking east is Mt. Nangu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;南宮山&lt;/span&gt;, the tallest mountain on the right, and in front of that is Mt. Momobukari &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桃配山&lt;/span&gt;. Mt. Nangu was where &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Hidemoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利秀元&lt;/span&gt; stationed his encampment and Mt. Momobukari was where &lt;b&gt;Kikkawa&lt;/b&gt; Hiroie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;吉川広家&lt;/span&gt; stationed his. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not fully detailed above, but Kikkawa fought for the Western Army and was a member of the Mori clan. He secretly made a deal with Kuroda and Tokugawa that if he prevented the Mori clan from attacking, the Mori clan would retain all their lands after battle. Kikkawa kept his word and prevented the Mori clan from attacking, but the Mori had no knowledge of this neutrality. After the battle, Kikkawa was labeled a traitor to the clan, and the Mori was still punished for supporting Ishida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the base of Mt. Momobukari was where Tokugawa stationed his 30,000 men at the beginning of battle. Again, as the battle progressed, his army moved forward to the current position of this photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3095_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3095_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3095_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3095_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3095_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking just a little bit more north to the northeast, you can see Okayama signalling hill. This is where &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田長政&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Takenaka&lt;/b&gt; Shigekado &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹中重門&lt;/span&gt; stationed their troops, and were they lit their flare signifying the begin of the battle for the Eastern Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3117_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3117_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3117_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3117_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3117_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking to the north and the west gives a nice view of Sekigahara. In the distance on the right, underneath the taller mountains is the short Mt. Sasao &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笹尾山&lt;/span&gt;, where &lt;b&gt;Ishida&lt;/b&gt; Mitsunari &lt;span class='ja'&gt;石田三成&lt;/span&gt; set his encampment. At the foot of this mountain is where the Sekigahara Tourism Center and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama" title="https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama"&gt;Exchange Center&lt;/a&gt; can be found. Also, in the fields out front is the monument to the Battle and where some of the battle reenactments take place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the forests to the west is where &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt; stationed his troops, and between Otani and Ishida's camps is where &lt;b&gt;Ukita&lt;/b&gt; Hideie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宇喜多秀家&lt;/span&gt; stationed his troops. The whole of what would become the Western army is lined up in the above photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In front of us, next to the cemetary and monuments is where &lt;b&gt;Tokugawa&lt;/b&gt; Ieyasu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;徳川家康&lt;/span&gt; set his final encampment and where he held the Head Viewing Ceremony to conclude the battle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3123_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3123_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3123_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3123_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3123_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's not a whole lot to see to the south. The Sekigahara Manufacturing Warehouse obscures almost all of the view. But, in the background is Mt. Matsuo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松尾山&lt;/span&gt;, where &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Hideaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川秀秋&lt;/span&gt; stationed his troops, and eventually turned on the Western Army assuring victory for the East. Near the right edge of the photo are the forests where &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt; was stationed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This observation point is an amazing touch to the museum as it shows the real locations of the battle from the film earlier and also shows the scale of the entire field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, nothing really shows the full scale of the field than visiting each of the specific locations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tokugawa Ieyasu's First Encampment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I traveled to Sekigahara, I left my apartment around 6:30 in the morning. I flew down the highway and arrived in Sekigahara around 8:30am. The first place I visited was Tokugawa's first encampment, on the east end of town, at the base of Mt. Mombukari &lt;span class='ja'&gt;桃配山&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2924_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2924_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2924_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2924_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2924_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering the distance from the center of battle, I'm surprised he could see anything that was going on. You can barely see the Museum from here. Okayama, where Kuroda and Takenaka were stationed, obscures the view of Mt. Sasao, where Ishida was. You really can't see anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nearby plaque detailed information about the location:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Eastern Army commander-in-chief Tokugawa Ieyasu's forte was field battles, and in an attempt to lure Ishida Mitsunari and other Western forces out of Ogaki Castle, he spread rumors suggesting he would pass Ogaki, and continue westerly to take Osaka.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Unnerved by this rumore, the Western Army departed Ogaki Castle under cover of darkness on October 20th and headed towards Sekigahara. They were followed closely by Ieyasu and around 30,000 troops before arriving at dawn on the 21st. Ieyasu stationed his troops here at Mt. Momokubari at around 6am. Irritated by early Western forces success, he is said to have drawn his sword on a retainer who had failed to dismount in his presence.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;In order to psychologically upset the enemy, and encourge his own troops, Ieyasu moved his command post to a more central position at around 11am.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Okayama Signaling Hill&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After visiting the Battle of Sekigahara Museum and the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/sengoku-armor-museum" title="https://theschlock.com/sengoku-armor-museum"&gt;Sengoku Armor Museum&lt;/a&gt;, I was ahead of my planned schedule. Okayama was a clear vantage point for the town, so I went there next. Okayama is surrounded by a beautiful bamboo forest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3248.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3248.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3248_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3248_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3248_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the forest is &lt;b&gt;Kotohira Shrine&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金刀比羅神社&lt;/span&gt; with an interesting local past. The plaque reads as follows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;During the Battle of Sekigahara, Lord Ikoma Kazumasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;生駒一政&lt;/span&gt; who had joined the Tokugawa army, set up camp on Okayama as the right wing of the Eastern Army together with Lord Kuroda Nagamasa and Lord Takenaka Shigekado. At this time, Kazumasa hung the statue of the Omononushi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大物主神&lt;/span&gt;, the diety of Kotohira Shrine (from his hometown of Kotohira Town in Kagawa Prefecture, called Sanuki province at the time), which he had been carrying on a pine branch and prayed for victory in the battle.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;After the Battle, the villages are said to have received this statue and worshipped it. It is also said that during the Keio period, the village headman of Sekigahara, Furuyama Ichiya &lt;span class='ja'&gt;古山一八&lt;/span&gt;, renovated the shrine's buldings. After that, the entire village of Sekigahara revered the god of business and the Kotohira-Ko &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金刀比羅講&lt;/span&gt; was organized. Every year on October 10th, a representative was sent to the main shrine in Sanuki (Kagawa pref.) to present a sacred talisman. (This is no longer done.) The shrine buildings were also moved to this current location in 1919.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own unique story to tell from the Battle of Sekigahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just a little bit past the shrine, the bamboo forest opens up to reveal the view of Sekigahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3269_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3269_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3269_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3269_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3269_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could clearly see Mt. Matsuo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松尾山&lt;/span&gt; in the back, and the western forests. At present, you could not see Mt. Sasao &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笹尾山&lt;/span&gt; or anywhere that Ishida would have positioned his troops. Maybe the forest hadn't grown that much at that time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nearby plaque had the following things to say:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;On the morning of the battle, Kuroda Nagamasa and Takenaka Shigekado stationed around 5,000 troops here on Okayama, with its panoramic view of the entire battlefield.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;They lit a beacon at around 8am signaling the start of the battle, and commenced attacking Ishida Mitsunari on Mt. Sasao, but were repelled several times. Nagamasa later took a corps of men to the north of Mt. Sasao and attacked the Western headquarters rear flank.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Around noon Kobayakawa Hideaki and other former Western allies switched allegiances, attacking and bringing the Western forces down. Kuroda's army then destroyed Mitsunari's remaining forces.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Kuroda started at the top of the Okayama, when the battle turned to the East's favor, I'm sure they all left this position to put further pressure on the West and eventually eradicate them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mt. Sasao &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笹尾山&lt;/span&gt; and the Battlefield&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned enough times by now, &lt;b&gt;Ishida&lt;/b&gt; Mitsunari &lt;span class='ja'&gt;石田三成&lt;/span&gt; was the main battle commander of the Western Army, and he stationed himself on Mt. Sasao. This was the northern most point on the battlefield, and also the north tip of the Western Army's lines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3462_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3462_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3462_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3462_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3462_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like Okayama, Mt. Sasao gave Ishida a full view of Sekigahara. Ishida could see all of his armies on the west and also see all the armies of the east coming at him. Okayama's plateau was probably visible at the time, but if not, you could still clearly see any army coming from that location, with the exception of Kuroda's flank attack which went further north, using the forest as cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nearby plaque had the following to say:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mt. Sasao was the perfect defensive position, providing high ground and a panoramic view. Ishida Mitsunari's approximately 6,000 troops departed Ogaki Castle in the dead of the night on October 20th and set up camp here, around 1am on October 21, the day of the battle.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The battle commenced around 8am. Mitsunari's troops, fronted by Shima Sakon, repeated repulsed attacks from the powerful Eastern armies, but were gradually forced to retreat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Western Army fought bravely, despite Shimadzu Yoshihiro, Kobayakawa Hideaki, and Mori Hidemoto failing to enter the battle, greatly reducing the Western Army's total fighting force.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hideaki finally switched allegiances joining the Eastern cause around noon, attacking and annihilating Otani Yoshitsugu's troops, starting a chain reaction that brought the Western Army down. Mitsunari's troops persevered against the advancing Eastern forces, but were finally defeated around 2pm. In the hopes of raising another army, Mitsunari fled west towards Mt. Ibuki.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It says the Shimadzu was unable to join the battle? I don't know what that means, as everything I had seen so far has him in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mt. Sasao was surrounded by battlements preventing horses from the climbing the hill and breaking Ishida's command post. Lines of these battlements were still set up on the path leading to the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3446.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3446.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3446_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3446_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3446_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the base of the mountain, off to the east, is the Sekigahara Tourism Center and the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama" title="https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama"&gt;Exchange Center&lt;/a&gt;. Further out in the middle of the field is the monument to commemorate the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3436.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3436.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3436_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3436_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3436_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's certainly not the middle of the overall battle, but it could be the point where the Eastern Army reached before Ishida consider the battle a complete loss, and retreated in the forest behind Mt. Sasao.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Battlefield Monument plaque had the following to say:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Although the Western Army was initially numerically superior to the Eastern forces, Kobayakawa Hideaki, who had previously pledged to betray his Western allies, remained a spectator to the battle, leaving Ishida Mitsunari to fight valiantly with less troops.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Despite this, the Western Army fought intently with repeated advances and retreats until around noon, when Hideaki finally turned his allegiances to the East and intentionally attacked the Western Army, resulting in its total defeat. It is thought that Mitsunari and Shimadzu Yoshihiro's troops were then overwhelmed by the advancing Eastern Army. With Mitsunari's units soon overrun, the Shimadzu clan retreated from the front lines. Japan's largest ever and most decisive battle was over in a mere half-a-day.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This field is where some of the battle reenactments take place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mt. Matsuo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松尾山&lt;/span&gt; and Kobayakawa's Camp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point in the day, I had visited everywhere on my to-do list except for one place. I left Mt. Matsuo for last because I thought it would take the most amount of time. Compared with all the other locations, &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Hideaki's camp on the top of Mt. Matsuo was about a mile hike. The other locations were as simple as parking the car and walking up the stairs. This one actually took time in additional to the time stopped to take photos. Ultimately, it was only a 30 minute hike from my car to the summit, not really all that far afterall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3732.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3732.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3732_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3732_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3732_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This plaque at the entrance had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mt. Matsuo provided a panoramic view of Sekigahara and was therefore a strategically important position. Kobayakawa Hideaki stationed his troops here the day before the battle on October 20th.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hideaki had formed a pact with Eastern leader Tokugawa Ieyasu prior to this, but failed to take action once the battle commenced. According to some, Ieyasu is said to have fired matchlock guns at Mt. Matsuo to bring about Hideaki's promised defection.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hideaki finally commenced the attack on the Western forces around midday, first defeating Otani Yoshitsugu's troops destroying the Western Army. Hideaki played a major role in the Eastern Army's victory. He was awarded vast territories in Bizen, Okayama after the battle, but died two years later aged just 21.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hike up the mountain wasn't difficult at all compared to other mountains I have hiked before. This particular path probably didn't exist at the time, and the overall mountain may have had several paths more suited for horses and infantry movements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3789_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3789_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3789_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3789_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3789_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The summit did give a great view of the totality of Sekigahara, so Kobayakawa was able to see all the armies engage each other in the middle and see all their movements. You can clearly see Ishida and Kuroda's positions at Mt. Sasao and Okayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above plaque and other research says that Kobayakawa finally made his decision to betray Ishida when Tokugawa fired shots at Mt. Matsuo to force him into a decision. But, other scholars have pointed out that with the chaos of battle and general distance, there would really be no way for him to tell the difference between shots fired at him or anyone else in battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plaque at the top of the mountain had some other insights:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mt. Matsuo, located here on the border between Mino (Gifu prefecture) and Omi (Shiga prefecture) overlooking vital roadways from its 293m summit, has long been recognized as a strategic viewpoint. Prior to the Battle of Sekigahara, Western commander Ishida Mitsunari ordered maintenance work be done to the mountaintop castle as part of the preparations against the Eastern forces. The existing remains of the castle are from the time of these repairs. One day before the battle, Kobayakawa Hideaki led his 15,000 troops here to Mt. Matsuo and entered the castle.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For much of the battle, Kobayakawa remained a spectator to the action taking place below, failing to fight for one side or the other until around midday, when he betrayed the Western side. Attacking Otani Yoshitsugu's forces, Kobayakawa brought about the downfall of the Western ranks, and provided victory to the Eastern Army.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;A large area near the top of the mountain has been flattened, and is surrounded by a low earthen wall. The remains of a masugata gate system to prevent enemy intrusion can also be found. The ruins cover an area of around 400m east to west and 250m north to south, indicating that Matsuo Castle was one of the largest mountain castles in the Mino (Gifu) area.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There used to be so many smaller castles in Japan, especially battle castles perched on mountains at strategic points. Nearly all of those castles are gone now, having been destroyed by whomever took them over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also at the summit were 6 frogs hanging out in a muddy bit of water makin' babies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3851.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3851.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3851_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3851_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3851_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, no matter whether Kobayakawa saw the warning shots or ultimately made the decision on his own after viewing the battle, his troops rode straight down the mountain and into the forest directly north to face the troops of &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Otani's Gravesite and Encampment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Kobayakawa's encampment was the final place I visited in Sekigahara on that day, I went to Otani's encampment in the morning before going to the museum. I made it a point to visit his camp because of his story, but also because they placed his grave in the same forest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2945.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2945.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2945_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2945_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2945_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plaque near the entrance to the forest read as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Otani Yoshitsugu's friendship with Ishida Mitsunari was well known. Mitsunari had confided his intentions to raise an army with Yoshitsugu, who had repeatedly requested he desist. Finally Yoshitsugu joined the Western Amry knowing it would be defeated.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Receiving his orders from Mitsunari, he positioned his troops near here on October 9th. Kobayakawa Hideaki had stationed his toops on nearby Mt. Matsuo, however Yoshitsugu remained wary about the young lord, and prepared himself for Hideaki's possible turning.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;As expected, Hideaki defected around midday and attacked. Yoshitsugu at first fended off Hideaki's repeated assaults, but on being overrun, he committed ritual suicide.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The path through the forest starts at Wakamiya Hachiman Shrine, then branches. The branch to the east leads to a view point through the trees which clearly shows Mt. Matsuo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2987.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2987.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2987_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2987_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2987_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the trees 400 years ago were obviously different, this still gave Otani's troops a view of Kobayakawa's troops and the Mt. Matuso castle. They could carefully study his movements (or non-movements) through the course of the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not far away, the other branching trail led to Otani's campsite. This was on the cliffside overlooking the Wakamiya Hachiman Shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2998.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2998.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2998_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2998_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_2998_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plaque says the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This site was Otani Yoshitsugu's headquarters. From here, it was possible to see Mt. Matsuo, where Kobayakawa Hideaki had stationed his army. Yoshitsugu remained suspicious of Hideaki's intentions and prepared himself accordingly.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Too sick to ride a horse, he is said to have led his men into battle from a palanquin. Yoshitsugu's troops were prepared for Hideaki's attack when he defected around noon. Initially the Otani repelled the powerful turncoat forces, but were overcome owing to Wakisaka Yasuharu and others also turning sides.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It must've been around here or slightly further into the forest where after being told that the battle was hopeless, Otani admitted defeat and committed seppuku.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further into the forest was Otani's grave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3027.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3027.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3027_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3027_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3027_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nearby plaque tells the story of his demise:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Otani Yoshitsugu was overrun following the betrayal of Kobayakawa Hideaki and his followers. Demanding that his head never fall into the hands of the enemy, Yoshitsugu commited ritual suicide and his retainer, Yuasa Gosuke, hid Yoshitsugu's severed head, before encountering Todo Takanori of the Eastern Army. Gosuke offered his own head in return for the location of his master's head never being revealed. Takanori kept this promise and never told Tokugawa Ieyasu the whereabouts of the head.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yoshitsugu's gravestone was erected by the Todo clan. The Yuasa family erected a gravestone to Gosuke besides Yoshitsugu's in 1916.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the gravesite is still regularly attended today. The graves had fresh flowers and were clear of leaves and any other debris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otani's loyalty and death at the cost of his loyalty is ultimately revered. He went into battle probably knowing that it would not turn out well for him, but he still stood by his beliefs in Ishida and his ideals of the Toyotomi government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Near his grave, a monument was built to remind everyone of his sacrafice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3009.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3009.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3009_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3009_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sekigahara/IMG_3009_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plaque reads:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The tactics and strategies of the Battle of Sekigahara were studied by Japan's armed forces during the late 1800's Meiji period, the early 1900's Showa militarization period, and military exercises were conducted on the actual battlefield.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This monument was erected in 1940 by the Fuwa Historical Preservation Society in memory of Otani Yoshitsugu, who's end was seen as the epitome of Bushido.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The summary is as follows: Despite his ignored advice warning Ishida Mitsunari against raising arms, Otani Yoshitsugu allied himself with, and fought hard for the Western forces out of loyalty to his former master, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, whom he served alongside Mitsunari. Being outnumbered and having lost his battle, he sacrificed himself by his own hand in the true Bushido spirit.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Battle of Sekigahara, people ultimately respect Otani and his sacrafice the most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, people seem to hate Kobayakawa, despite his actions causing Tokugawa to win and create peace and prosperity for 250 years. At the museum, each ticket is printed with a warlord. The person behind me in line got Kobayakawa on her ticket, and her date was teasing her the whole time. &lt;span class='ja'&gt;いやだ〜&lt;/span&gt;, she kept saying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Remembrance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason people love this battle and its legacy continues to this day with TV shows, movies, manga, and other media is that the decisive victory completely changing the history of Japan. After the battle and after Tokugawa successfully rooted out the rest of the Toyotomi loyalists, he had complete control over the country, and his dictatorship led to great prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the other big reason for everyone's interest in the battle is also its divisiveness. Tokugawa was an asshole who completely undermined Toyotomi's rule immediately after his death. It was an insult to Toyotomi and Ishida was very outspoken about this. Others who also hated Tokugawa's attitude continued to stoke Ishida into action, and the schemes and political bullshit continued from there. While Ishida was also a bit of an asshole, he represented loyalty and honor. Many of his friends and commanders in the Western Army were the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The battle was ultimately a fight between those loyal to the current ideals of Japan and the strength of someone wanting all the power for himself. It's far different than people remembering something like the American Civil War, which was fought over slavery, something clearly right or wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The TV show, Shogun, portrays Tokugawa as an underdog with Ishida trying to keep all the power for himself, but in reality it seems completely different. Of course, Shogun isn't trying to be completely historically accurate, but it still becomes pro-Tokugawa propaganda. The show really contextualized Japan's xenophobia at the time as the Europeans seemed intent on conquering Japan for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also a 2017 Japanese film based on a 1966 Japanese novel about the Battle of Sekigahara. It won a couple of awards, too, so I would like to see how they portray all the characters. Will they portray them in a neutral manor so the audience must decide which side was right? Or will they portray Tokugawa as a traitor to the current ideals of Japan or Ishida as a foolish conservative?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After visiting the sites and museums, I am more on the side of Ishida in this fight, even though it is clear that his loss was a necessity for Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Revisit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am way more informed about the Battle than I was before having visited these locations, gone through all the photos, and looked up all the information online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, there are several more locations I want to visit, like Mori's encampment on Mt. Nangu, Shimadzu's and Ukita's encampment in the middle of the Western Army, Fukushima's encampment at the head of the Eastern army, some of the other local folklore museums in Sekigahara, and the Sekigahara visitor center at the station. I would also like to visit the Battle museum and Samurai Armor museum again with my now better base of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are so many minor lords who participated in the battle, too, who each have their story. Kanamori Nagachika &lt;span class='ja'&gt;金森長近&lt;/span&gt;, founder of modern day Takayama, also participated in the battle with around 1,000 troops. I wonder if they placed a marker at his position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I definitely want to check out the Battle Reenactment festival, too, so maybe I'll visit all these locations in October, if there's time. We'll see.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 04:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/battle-of-sekigahara</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/battle-of-sekigahara</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Sekigahara Warland 関ケ原ウォーランド</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Sekigahara Warland is an aging "theme park" which celebrates the Battle of Sekigahara. It first opened in 1964 and displays over 200 lifesize concrete soldiers recreating the atmosphere and intensity of the battle. Many of the major lords are present from the battle as well as several minor lords. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3620.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3620.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3620_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3620_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3620_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The park feels like a forgotten relic due to its age and general lack of upkeep or any form of modernization. The concrete figures are a huge mixed bag of quality, from the general inhuman facial details, varying degrees of skin tones (from dark brown to yellow to white to pink), and warped joints (possibly from a lack of precise molding equipment). In addition, many of the key figures of the battle whose appearance is pretty consistent across the other museums in town are very generic here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, there are 60 year old coin machines at the entrance which no longer operate. There's a lecture hall whose doors barely opened. Inside the lecture hall, there's a diorama of the battle which doesn't seem like it works anymore. And the admissions desk was staffed by an apathetic old woman who seemed bothered and took her time selling me a ticket, and said nothing the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It really feels like a burnt out 80s theme park from the movies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3637.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3637.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3637_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3637_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3637_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the concrete figures have nameplates underneath them identifying who the statue is meant to represent. Unfortunately, the education ends there. Warland doesn't offer any documentation on any of the figures in their park beyond a few posted signs. It's nice there is some identification but if you don't know who these people are, there's no immediate way of finding out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Local people probably have a good idea. Also, maybe they offered some kind of tour guide for the park? There was certainly no guide when I visited on this Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mori Clan &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利氏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After entering Warland, there were several named statues on the hillside to the right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3533.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3533.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3533_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3533_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3533_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ankokuji&lt;/b&gt; Ekei &lt;span class='ja'&gt;安国寺恵瓊&lt;/span&gt; was a military monk who was close with &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Takakage, leader of the Kobayakawa clan and who would've been a member of the Five Regeants had he not died before Toyotomi in 1598. The Kobayakawa clan was a sub-faction of the Mori clan, and with Takakage's death, Ankokuji feared the Mori clan would be wiped out with the loss of a great leader. He was happy that &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Terumoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利輝元&lt;/span&gt;succeeded in becoming a regeant giving them the strength to protect their survival, but this forced the Kobayakawa clan against Tokugawa as Mori supported Ishida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ankokuji&lt;/b&gt; Ekei became one of the top commanders of the Mori army and commanded his own army of 1800 troops stationed further east from the battle, planning on attacking Tokugawa's rear. In front of him was &lt;b&gt;Kikkawa&lt;/b&gt; Hiroie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;吉川広家&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3527.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3527.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3527_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3527_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3527_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's this guy. &lt;b&gt;Kikkawa&lt;/b&gt; Hiroie was head of the Kikkawa clan, also a sub-faction of the Mori clan. It is said that through his diplomacy and politics he was able to keep the peace between the sub-factions of the Mori clan after &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Takakage's death. On the day of the Battle, as mentioned above, his army of 4200 was stationed in front of Ankokuji and the whole of the Mori army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mori's retainers supported Ishida and the other Toyotomi loyalists, but it was clear to Kikkawa that they would lose the battle. Kikkawa made a secret pact with &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田長政&lt;/span&gt; of the Tokugawa army that if he prevented the Mori armies from joining the battle, the Mori clan would be spared and be able to keep their domains. So, when the Mori clan gave Kikkawa the order to attack, he refused. And his refusal prevented the rest of the Mori clan from engaging in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3525.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3525.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3525_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3525_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3525_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Mori, by the way, but not &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Terumoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利輝元&lt;/span&gt;, who was one of the Five Regeants. This is his cousin &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Hidemoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利秀元&lt;/span&gt;. Terumoto never joined the battle and stayed in Osaka Castle. Hidemoto was determined to support Ishida of the Western Army and brought 15,000 soldiers of his army to the battle. But, because of Kikkawa's inaction, he was prevented from attacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the battle, the whole secret pact fell apart because Mori never agreed to it. It was only Kikkawa who put forth the idea to Kuroda and Tokugawa. As such, the Mori clan lost 75% of its territories after Tokugawa became Shogun, and they labeled Kikkawa as a traitor. Ankokuji, still fiercely loyal to the Western Army, was executed in Kyoto with Ishida weeks after the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Head Viewing Ceremony &lt;span class='ja'&gt;首実検&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id="head-viewing"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the Battle finished and Tokugawa was the victor, he led the Head Viewing Ceremony. It was necessary for each soldier to bring the head of all his opponents he killed to the commander to pay respects to the fallen enemy and to get properly rewarded for his success in battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3569.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3569.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3569_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3569_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3569_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tokugawa set up his folding chair in the field and his commanders and advisors surrounded him. Here, Tokugawa sits and looks at a head brought to him for inspection. The deceased is identified, and the head is respectfully wrapped in cloth and laid to rest in a mound with his fellow soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few of the commanders around him were as follows. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3571.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3571.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3571_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3571_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3571_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田長政&lt;/span&gt; was the eastern's army chief military strategist. He signaled the start of the Battle which ordered the front lines of the Eastern Army to engage the west. Spotting weaknesses in the Eastern Army, he ordered his gunman to attack Ishida's troops directly, keeping them concentrated in the field ahead. But, more notably, he schemed with both Kobayakawa and Kikkawa to undermine the Western Army's strength and eventually destroy itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3573.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3573.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3573_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3573_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3573_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monnashi&lt;/b&gt; Saburo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;門奈三郎&lt;/span&gt; is a member of the Monnashi clan, a military clan derived from the Fujiwara clan that I don't think existed at the time of the battle. I could not find any information about Saburo himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were many others, but I didn't recognize the names at the time, and I could not find any information about the other names that I did make note of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ishida's Flank&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the above two scenes, the park opened up into the full battle with its various localized skirmishes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3595.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3595.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3595_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3595_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3595_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above, &lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa commanded his troops along with &lt;b&gt;Takenaka&lt;/b&gt; Shigekado &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹中重門&lt;/span&gt; to cover Ishida's flank. Takenaka was 21 years old at the time of the battle, but worked closely with Kuroda to keep the battle concentrated in the field in front of them. After the battle, he captured &lt;b&gt;Konishi&lt;/b&gt; Yukinaga &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小西行長&lt;/span&gt;, one of the top commanders in the Western Army. Konishi was then executed with Ishida and Ankokuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3603.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3603.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3603_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3603_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3603_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shima&lt;/b&gt; Sakon &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島左近&lt;/span&gt;, along known by a few other names, was stationed at Sasaoyama alongside Ishida's army. He was one of Ishida's best friends and Ishida used him as a leading strategist for the Western Army. He was known as one of the bravest generals in Ishida's army, so I'm not sure why they protrayed him as a goofball above. It is said that he was shot by Kuroda's gunman when they attacked, so maybe they modeled him after that moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shima's body was never recovered after the battle, so we don't know if he immediately died of his gunshot wounds, or if he survived and lived a few more years in hiding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3607.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3607.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3607_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3607_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3607_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the main station of Ishida's forces. Ishida was in back, and this guy in the front has a nameplate, but I have no idea who it is. The closest person I could find was &lt;b&gt;Ujiie&lt;/b&gt; Yukihiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;氏家行広&lt;/span&gt;, who used the nickname Kyuuasemon &lt;span class='ja'&gt;久左衛門&lt;/span&gt;. It's not perfect, but the kanji &lt;span class='ja'&gt;氏家久左衛門&lt;/span&gt; is pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ujiie planned on joining the Eastern Army with Tokugawa, but with his kingdom in the path of the Western Army, he returned to his home and his family joined with Ishida. According to Wikipedia, he never joined the battle, so this is further confirmation it's not the right person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the battle, the Ujiie clan was dissolved, and Yukihiro became a ronin. In the shadows, he still supported the efforts of those still fighting against Tokugawa. He fought against Tokugawa in the seige of Osaka Castle in 1614, but committed seppuku when the battle was lost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Field&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the open field, the Shimadzu clan attacks. They are pretty easy to spot with their circled crosses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3618.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3618.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3618_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3618_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3618_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Shimadzu clan army was split into two factions led by &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Yoshihiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津義弘&lt;/span&gt; and nephew &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Toyohisa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津豊久&lt;/span&gt;. Both were fiercely loyal to Ishida and fought with the same intensity. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the distance is &lt;b&gt;Katou&lt;/b&gt; Yoshiaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;加藤嘉明&lt;/span&gt;. Katou was one of the seven generals who plotted to assassinate Ishida after the death of Toyotomi. Kuroda was in this group, too. With the loss of the Korean war, Ishida wrote terrible performance reviews about them, calling them imcompetant for the loss. Tokugawa used this opportunity to shield Ishida from their wraith, but then gained their loyalty when it was clear he would war against Ishida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3648_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3648_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3648_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3648_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3648_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of fighting going on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the front is &lt;b&gt;Fukushima&lt;/b&gt; Masanori &lt;span class='ja'&gt;福島正則&lt;/span&gt;, another one of the seven general alongside Katou and Kuroda. In the Battle, he was given the right to led the Eastern Army against Ishida's Western Army. However, Ii Naomasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;井伊直政&lt;/span&gt; and Matsudaira Tadayoshi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;松平忠吉&lt;/span&gt; had their gunman fire on the Eastern Army prior to the start of the battle, which enraged Fukushima to start the battle immediatley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Futher in the back is &lt;b&gt;Miyamoto&lt;/b&gt; Musashi &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宮本武蔵&lt;/span&gt;, a legendary Japanese swordsman who eventually wrote The Book of Five Rings &lt;span class='ja'&gt;五輪の書&lt;/span&gt; detailing the essence of true swordsmanship in both technique, attitude, and personal philosophy. His ideals led to the creation of modern Budo culture. Scholars believed the he had participated in the Battle of Sekigahara and the creators of Warland thought so, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warland depicts Musashi and his father as fighting for the Western Army, which was the prevailing idea at the time as he was a longtime vassal of the Ukita clan. However, according to Wikipedia, after studying Kuroda's personal records of the battle, scholars have Musashi's father as serving Tokugawa's army instead. Scholars claim that having Musashi fighting for the West was always a romanticized ideal of him being an amazing ronin warrior fighting for the heart of Japan, but facts do not point to this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3677.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3677.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3677_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3677_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3677_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kani&lt;/b&gt; Saizo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;可児才蔵&lt;/span&gt; was a commander in Fukushima's army. According to Wikipedia, he often killed so many men, that he couldn't carry all of their heads with him. As such, after their deaths, he would place bamboo leaves over their cut necks or mouths as his calling card. After the battle, other soldiers counted 17 felled opponents with bamboo leaves on them. His nickname became Bamboo Saizo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa's Betrayal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key moment of the Battle of Sekigahara when Tokugawa's Eastern Army's victory was assured was around Noon when the Kobayakawa clan made their intentions to defect from the Western Army, join the Eastern Army, and attack the southern flank of the Western Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3665.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3665.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3665_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3665_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3665_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Hideaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川秀秋&lt;/span&gt; was only 19 years old at the time of the battle and led the Kobayakawa clan. He brought 15,000 troops to the battle and was stationed on Matsuo-yama overlooking the whole battlefield from the south. As mentioned above, his father, Kobayakawa Takakage, was a high ranking member with the Toyotomi government and the Mori clan. He would've been a member of the Five Regeants, had he not passed away a year before Toyotomi's death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Takakage's death, Hideaki became in charge of the Kobayakawa clan. As Ishida began raising his army against Tokugawa, Tokugawa grew seeds of betrayal with Hideaki. He claimed that Ishida was responsible for the embarassment he suffered for a defeat a few years prior. On the day of the Battle, Hideaki was still indecisive whether or not to go through with his betrayal. It is said that fake gunfire from Tokugawa finally pushed him into riding down the hill and attacking the Western Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3667.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3667.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3667_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3667_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3667_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hiratsuka&lt;/b&gt; Tamehiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;平塚為広&lt;/span&gt; fought for the Western Army against Tokugawa. Hiratsuka was loyal to the Toyotomi family, but was hestitate to enter a war with Tokugawa. Both he and Otani tried to convince Ishida not raise an army against him, but Ishida did not listen. His loyalty brought him and his 600 soldiers to the Battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hiratsuka was the first army in the path of Kobayakawa. He was killed in the attack. His death is often over shadowed by Otani's.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3657.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3657.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3657_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3657_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_warland/IMG_3657_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt; was great friends with Ishida, so it was only natural that he would serve his friend to the bitter end. Even though he tried his best to convince his friend not to war against Tokugawa, he did not abandon him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otani also had leprosy which made him severely ill. In public, he would wear a white hood to cover his diseased face. At the time of the battle, his disease had advanced to the point where he could barely stand and could barely see. After being told that the battle was lost, he committed seppuku.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Warland&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The amount of major people, schemes, intrigue, and shere chaos and death of the battle is pretty incredible. Every major and minor person involved in the battle had some reason for their involvement in the fight and a consequence after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much of this stuff was documented when the park opened in the 1960s, or how much this stuff was taught to the people who visited. In many ways, the main Battle of Sekigahara Museum is an evolution of this site, as it shows the build-up and progression of the battle using film and projectors. In comparison, Warland is a primitive way of showing almost the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, it's still an incredible place. The Battle Museum does show the intensity of the battle, but when you're in the field of around 200 lifesize concrete soldiers, you can feel the scale and chaos of the battle. Being able to walk around and view the individual people involved, and (later) being able to look up who they were, humanizes the battle, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a shame that there isn't more education about all the named people in the park, but I think it's still definitely worth a visit.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 03:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/sekigahara-warland</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/sekigahara-warland</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Sengoku Armor Museum 戦国甲冑館</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Sengoku Armor Museum in Sekigahara is a private collection of real samurai armor. Often museums and other exhibits will use replicas or recreations of the original armor. The owner of this collection only collects and restores original pieces from the Battle of Sekigahara and the Sengoku period in general. Several of the pieces were owned by major lords in the battle, but not necessrily worn in the battle itself. Many of the other pieces were worn by soldiers in the battle, some of which were killed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3218.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3218.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3218_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3218_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3218_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The museum is just north of the main Battle of Sekigahara museum, and currently only takes reservations to view the collection. I emailed the owner the day before visiting, and he replied later in the evening saying I was all set to visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viewing the collection is 800&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, but you could pay more for detailed lectures about each of his pieces and also try on some armor, if you're small enough. There's also an attached shop with some exclusive Sekigahara merch, and a small restaurant where the family will cook an "authentic" samurai meal for you. They also have a pet duck. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was only interested in the armor for this visit, but next time I think I'll go for the lectural experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3158_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3158_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3158_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3158_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3158_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immediately to the right after reception were 9 sets of armor, mostly consisting of foot soldiers. I'm not sure if any of these were used in the Battle of Sekigahara. In fact, the emblem above the middle set of armor is of the Fujiwara clan, which never participated in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fujiwara clan rose to power in the 800s, but another 800 years later at the time of the Battle, I think the clan had mostly been divided and renamed into other factions and eventually bred out of existance. One of their military branches was renamed the Monnashi clan, which did participate in the battle within Tokugawa's Eastern Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The flags in the back have the Ishida emblem on them, and the front foot soldier helmets have &lt;span class='ja'&gt;石&lt;/span&gt; ishi written on them, so maybe those are some of Ishida's men? Although, they fought for the Western Army. Somewhat confusing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3162.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3162.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3162_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3162_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3162_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3173.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3173.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3173_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3173_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3173_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Displayed on tables on the sides of the entrance were assorted pieces of armor used in the battle. The owner noted that some of the pieces had dried blood on them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3176.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3176.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3176_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3176_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3176_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his main room, there were around 25 sets of armor, many of which were related to the lords of the Battle of Sekigahara. He said it was alright if I took some photos, but his workshop with armor currently being restored was off limits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3177.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3177.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3177_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3177_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3177_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the first sections was devoted to &lt;b&gt;Ukita&lt;/b&gt; Hideie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;宇喜多秀家&lt;/span&gt; and his army. The main armor in the back was samurai armor owned by the Ukita clan at the time of the Battle. It's most likely not the armor he wore in the Battle, but it was armor he owned at that time. In the front are two sets of army from soldiers in his army. They are distinctly recognizable because of the Ukita clan emblems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukita was one of the members of the Council of Five Regeants after Toyotomi passed away. He was very close to Toyotomi, so it was natural that he sided with Ishida against Tokugawa. One year after Toyotomi's death, there was an internal rebellion in the Ukita clan which resulted in several key members leaving to join Tokugawa. His army was slightly diminished but was still the largest army within the overall Western Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He survived the Battle of Sekigahara, although most of his army did not. He went into hiding, but was eventually captured and exiled to Hachijo-jima, a tiny volcanic island in the middle of the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3182.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3182.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3182_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3182_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3182_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is armor previously owned by the Otani clan. &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt; was a close friend of Ishida. He was also fiercely loyal and honorable. Despite being inflicted with harsh illness which blinded him, he still brought his army to Sekigahara to fight with Ishida against Tokugawa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, his army was completely overrun when Kobayakawa defected to the Eastern Army in the middle of  battle and attacked his army. They were completely overwhelmed, and thus, Otani committed seppuku to avoid capture and also to show his loyalty to the Western Army. His retainers took and hid his head and armor, so the Eastern Army could not have the satisfcation of his defeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3186.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3186.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3186_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3186_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3186_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above armor belonged to the Maeda family. &lt;b&gt;Maeda&lt;/b&gt; Toshiie &lt;span class='ja'&gt;前田利家&lt;/span&gt; was appointed as one of the Five Regeants after Toyotomi's death. Unfortunately, Maeda was also not in the best of health and died a year later. His son, Maeda Toshinaga &lt;span class='ja'&gt;前田利長&lt;/span&gt; succeded him, but fell into a political trap set by Tokugawa. As such, Maeda could not stand against Tokugawa and he fought for the Eastern Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3188.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3188.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3188_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3188_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3188_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is armor from the Mori clan. &lt;b&gt;Mori&lt;/b&gt; Terumoto &lt;span class='ja'&gt;毛利輝元&lt;/span&gt; was also one of the Five Regeants and pledged his support with Ishida in the Western Army. Mori's army was stationed in the east of the battlefield, and meant to swoop in behind Tokugawa's army and pincer them. However, when he was signaled to attack, he did nothing. After seeing the tide of battle shift heavily against the Western Army, he refused to attack and stayed neutral, sparing his men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He political standing was diminished after the battle by 75%, but faithfully assisted the Tokugawa Shogunate years after the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3189.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3189.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3189_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3189_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3189_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we have armor of the Shimidzu clan. &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Yoshihiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津義弘&lt;/span&gt; and nephew &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Toyohisa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津豊久&lt;/span&gt; were leaders who supported the Western Army. Their numbers were few, but had a fierce honorable spirit. After the battle had been lost, they refused to turn their backs to the enemy. In order to retreat, they ran a final assault on the front lines of the Eastern Army, breaking through, and continuing to escape to the south. Nephew Toyohisa did not survive the escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3190.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3190.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3190_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3190_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3190_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3204.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3204.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3204_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3204_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3204_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were more pieces of armor at the end of the room, but I have trouble identifying which armies they belong to. Some of the armor is pretty distinct, but there really isn't an easy guide to follow for identifying them. I should've taken notes or asked the owner about them, but I hadn't researched anything before visiting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3217.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3217.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3217_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3217_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3217_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These last sets of armor were back near the entrance of the room. I think he mentioned that all of these armor belonged to members of the Tokugawa clan, which makes sense given the above emblem. &lt;b&gt;Tokugawa&lt;/b&gt; Ieyasu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;徳川家康&lt;/span&gt; was one of the members of the Five Regeants and the key agitator which led to the Battle of Sekigahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While TV shows and history sometimes paint him as a glorious unifier of Japan, he is incredibly cold, manipulative, and constantly schemes against his rivals. Immediately after Toyotomi's death, he began scheming a series of marriage pacts to increase his standing, something which was strictly forbidden by Toyotomi. He used other political schemes to blackmail other lords into fighting for him. Any opportunity to increase his standing or decrease the standing of another was immediately taken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it seemed like many people hated the outspoken, garish attitude of Ishida, they hated Tokugawa more. Ishida went to war with Tokugawa to preserve the ideals set forth by Toyotomi. Everyone loyal to the deceased unifier of Japan held their ground, but were ultimately overpowered by Tokugawa's influence and strength.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the battle, everyone loyal to Toyotomi was either executed, exiled, or significantly diminished. With full control of the government, Tokugawa banned weapons, shut down the country, and put to death anyone who would continue to oppose him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On one hand, he was a harsh dictator that people secretly hated and feared. On the other hand, his rule set Japan on a course of extreme prosperity the country had never seen before. The population exploded, literacy exploded, and culture exploded. Japan became a modern beacon of the world, which became quite popular in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3224.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3224.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3224_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3224_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sengoku_armor/IMG_3224_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having better knowledge of the battle and those involved, next time I go back to the museum, I'll have a better idea of what to ask about the armor and be in a better place to take notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The museum itself is really small. Again, calling it a collection is a better term, but it's still a worthwhile visit. The owner speaks English pretty well, so it's easy to have a conversation and talk about the armor and the battle in detail.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 02:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/sengoku-armor-museum</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/sengoku-armor-museum</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Samurai Armor at Sasaoyama Center</title><description>&lt;p&gt;At the base of Sasaoyama in Sekigahara is the Sasaoyama Exchange Center &lt;span class='ja'&gt;笹尾山交流館&lt;/span&gt; as part of the overall Sekigahara Sight Seeing Information Center &lt;span class='ja'&gt;関ケ原観光協会&lt;/span&gt;. The Information Center is basically a government building where tourism for the town is run, but the Exchange Center is open for visitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3346.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3346.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3346_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3346_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3346_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Exchange Center has lots of flyers for places around town, and costume rental. You can pay to wear some goofy samurai armor for 20 or 30 minutes, walk around the area, and pose for photos. Much of this armor is pretty generic, with various clan emblems on them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the back of the Exchange Center, they had some premium costumes and authetic armor on display. Some of the armor was used in ceremonies and festivals in Sekigahara. The more authetic-looking armor were used in reenactments of the Battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3367.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3367.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3367_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3367_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3367_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above armor is a costume of what was worn by &lt;b&gt;Otani&lt;/b&gt; Yoshitsugu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;大谷吉継&lt;/span&gt;, one of the close friends of Ishida Mitsunari, leader of the Western Army. The armor is very distinct as it has no helmet. The cloth was used to cover his disfigured face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otani's forces were positioned in the western forest. At the time of the battle, he was inflicted with severe illness and could barely see in front of him. He committed seppuku after Kobayakawa betrayed the Western Army and attacked them as a member of the Eastern Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3369.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3369.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3369_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3369_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3369_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above costume armor was worn by &lt;b&gt;Fukushima&lt;/b&gt; Masanori &lt;span class='ja'&gt;福島正則&lt;/span&gt;. The bull horns are the most distinct feature of his armor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was one of the most seasoned battle commanders in the Eastern Army and led the front line against the Western Army. He was given personal permission to have the first strike against the Western Army, but Ii Naomasa and Matsudaira Tadayoshi took that away from him when their gunman fired. With their shots, Fukushima aggressively charged Ukita's army signifying the full start of the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3374.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3374.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3374_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3374_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3374_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kuroda&lt;/b&gt; Nagamasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;黒田長政&lt;/span&gt; wore armor similar to this costume. Big 'ol square head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kuroda was Tokugawa's chief military strategist and perhaps the most cunning strategist in all of Japan. His army was stationed on Okayama, north east of the main battlefield and covered Ishida's flank, forcing him into the center of the fight. He also conspired with Kobayakawa to turn him against Ishida, ultimately allowing Tokugawa to win the battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3380.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3380.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3380_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3380_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3380_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next costume armor is of &lt;b&gt;Kobayakawa&lt;/b&gt; Hideaki &lt;span class='ja'&gt;小早川秀秋&lt;/span&gt;. The red robe and trident ornament on the helmet are the most distinguishing features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kobayakawa was only 19 year old at the time of the battle. His army was the second most numerous in the Western Army, consisting of 15,000 troops. His troops stayed at Matsuoyama and did not engage in the battle until he finally made the decision to betray Ishida and attack Otani of the Western Army. As mentioned above, Otani committed seppuku as a result, and the rest of the Western Army quickly fell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of his role in the battle, Tokugawa increased Kobayakawa's standing by giving him all castles and lands previously owned by Ukita, which included Okayama castle and vast territories in Bizen. Although, at 21 years old, he drank himself to death. He had no heir, so Kobayakawa was officially dissolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3384.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3384.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3384_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3384_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3384_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we have a costume simliar to the armor of &lt;b&gt;Shimadzu&lt;/b&gt; Yoshihiro &lt;span class='ja'&gt;島津義弘&lt;/span&gt;. The leaping fox ornament of the helmet is its most distinguishing feature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He and his nephew were members of the Western Army. After the battle had been lost, they refused to retreat by showing their backs to the enemy. So with the little manpower they had left, they charged through the center of the battlefield completely surprising Tokugawa and the eastern armies. They broke through the line and continued charging south to make their retreat. His nephew was killed in the assault, but Yoshihiro made it through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3360.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3360.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3360_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3360_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3360_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the fancy replica armor, they had a few sets of armor that had been weathered to look more realistic. The above armor was made after armor belonging to &lt;b&gt;Katou&lt;/b&gt; Kiyomasa &lt;span class='ja'&gt;加藤&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;清正&lt;/span&gt;, distinctive because its one meter high helmet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Katou was a member of the Eastern Army, but was not in the Battle of Sekigahara. He was battling and defeating Ishida's allies in Kyushu at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3389.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3389.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3389_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3389_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250322_sasao_armor/IMG_3389_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with Katou's armor were a few more pieces. I could not identify the middle armor, but armor on the left is of the Monnashi clan. The Monnashi clan was a military branch of what was left of the Fujiwara clan. The Fujiwara clan came to power around the 800s, but there doesn't seem to be a lot of information about it at the time of the Battle. There was no Monnashi army, and I think this was just a commander in the Tokugawa army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a few other pieces there too, used by actors in the reenactment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a fun surprise to see some of these after visiting the Sekigahara Battle Museum and Sengoku Armor museum. Even though these were costumes, all of the armor in the battle was pretty distinct, so you can usually identify it easily from its main characteristics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/samurai-armor-at-sasaoyama</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Kitayama in Late Winter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On this beautiful sunny Sunday afternoon, I went up to the top of Kitayama and walked around before meeting a client for coffee. Kitayama is one of the most prominent mountains (or hill) in town offering a full view of Takayama and the eastern neighborhood of Sanfukuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the north end of Kitayama is Kitayama Park, which is also the site of where Ayuzaki castle once stood. Kanemori famously stationed himself in this castle during his invasion of Hida. He used this castle as a vantage point to plan his attack on Matsukura castle across town, and finally secure the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2817_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2817_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2817_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2817_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2817_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Directly next to the park is a cemetary. I think there were a few plaques nearby explaining whose remains were entombed in the graves, but I didn't pay close attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall the cemetary is pretty small compared to the size of other cemetaries in Takayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2835.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2835.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2835_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2835_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2835_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing down the mountain is Ichi cafe, where I was meeting my client. This is also where you can park your car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mountain plateaus at this point and you can continue along for another great view of the city, and take the road back down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2847_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2847_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2847_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2847_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2847_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opposite of this great view is where the Kankou Hotel used to be. With prime real estate on the platea of Kitayama, it gave an amazing view. But now, Kankou Hotel has been completely demolished and the site is nothing but a flat dirt area. COVID was perhaps the final nail in the coffin for the Kankou Hotel. It was probably already struggling from the competition of other newer hotels in Takayama. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 10 years, tourism in Takayama has exploded, and with the massive income, new hotels have been built in areas next to the station. Kankou Hotel was so far out of the way, nobody would realistically walk there from the station. They did have shuttle busses, but even then, if someone staying at the Kankou Hotel wanted to walk around Takayama, they'd have to go down the mountain and then go back up when returning. It's so much easier for people to just stay in a hotel at street level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then COVID happened and foreign tourism was completely halted. To make up some of the lost revenue, the Kankou Hotel used its rooms for people infected with COVID during the lockdown. Local people called it the "COVID jail," and its reputation for being a terrible place grew from there, in addition to whatever cleanup the hotel had to do from its infected guests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2872.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2872.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2872_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2872_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250309_kitayama/IMG_2872_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It sucks that such a prominent hotel in the area is now gone, but it's the nature of business.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/kitayama-late-winter</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/kitayama-late-winter</link><category>Japan</category><category>Hida Takayama</category></item><item><title>Ghosts of Tsushima Impressions</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Ghosts takes place in the late 1200s as the Mongolian army of the Yuan Dynasty led by Kublai Khan invades Japan. Having just conquered the pennisula of Korea, they move further south to the island of Tsushima, province of the Japanese empire. Lord Shimura is the jito (or ruler) of Tsushima, holding together the clans of the island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You play as Sakai Jin, Shimura's nephew is the only surviving samurai of the battle of Komoda beach, where the clans of the island led by Shimura met the landing parties of the mongols, and lost. After being revived from your wounds, you awake to the open world of Tsushima, roaming the island to help those in need and gain support to overthrow Kublai Khan, currently occupying Kaneda castle, with your uncle Lord Shimura as captive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224164214.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224164214.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224164214_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224164214_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224164214_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where I'm at in the game so far, around 20 hours into Act 1. There are probably three acts, plus an extra area available the DLC expansion. So far, I think it's been a pretty benign experience, but I have been focusing solely on the open world elements of the game, rather than the story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Story thus Far&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being Samurai is at the heart and soul of Ghosts, and this seems like the direction the story is headed. Ghosts describe Samurai as fearless just warriors who stand up and fight against all odds even at the cost of their lives. However, as a single warrior, you are constantly fighting against these odds. While it is the most honorable route, it is also the most foolish when it is not feasible or possible to win using such direct single-minded tactics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A woman named Yuna had rescued you from Komoda beach. She moves undetected through grass, and cuts down the mongol enemies when they are unready. Moves deemed cowardly and underhanded from the point of view of a samurai. Dishonorable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through gameplay, Ghosts offers you two approaches to every battle: face your enemies head on, or pick off enemies one by one without being detected. There are a few glimpses of Jin struggling with his strict samurai code of honor when relying on stealth techniques too much. Hopefully it'll become core to the story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gameplay&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In most games, stealth is almost always the way to go. Fighting battles head on tend to overwhelm and you end up using more resources. So, it's best to pick off enemies one by one to even the odds before hopping in to finish the squirmish. Why fight five dudes at once, when you can end up fighting either one or two?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ghosts has a nice gameplay solution for this as a Stand Off. Reveal yourself to the enemy and face them directly in a duel. Hold down the button and release right as they strike for an instant kill. This skill can be upgraded to take out three enemies at once, leaving only a few left to deal with after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224002612.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224002612.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224002612_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224002612_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224002612_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It ends up becoming a much faster way of dealing with groups of enemies then using stealth, too. The game gives you a lot of tools and methods of taking down enemies, but I really haven't had a need to learn any of them. Dudes attack, I parry, then slash slash slash. This results in almost all battles ending up into the same battle again and again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exploration&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In open world games, exploration is of absolute importance to me. Once free to explore, I immediately run off into the woods to find secrets, caves, dungeons, and items. Ghosts has plenty of that content. Pieces of map and points of interests reveal as you explore rather than having everything available as you start, which both encourages exploration and doesn't overwhelm with a thousand checkboxes on a to-do list. It allows you to play the game at your own pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of dynamic environments that light up with the sunrise or sunset, like the golden forest of ginko trees and open fields full tall grass blowing in the moonlight. It's not too difficult to get some pretty shots with the amazing &lt;b&gt;Photo Mode&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224150522.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224150522.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224150522_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224150522_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224150522_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, most of the shots end up looking the same. There's a distant visual tone to Ghosts, but none of the environments end up feeling distinct themselves. It's just the same areas with different colored trees or with higher rocks. Many of the buildings are copies of the same models used in other villages. Even the villagers are just copied over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an open world game, it ultimately feels somewhat closed and limited. I feel like I had already hit the boundaries of the world (both literally and creatively) after 5 hours, and these last 15 hours have just been cleanup, making my way through repetitious open world side stories and ticking collectibles off a list. It's all pretty standard boring open world elements. Go here, pick up this, go there, kill this person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparing worlds, Red Dead Redemption 2, which had been released two years prior to Ghosts, was a game that continued to feel alive and fresh for hours and hours, both in story and in environment. Everything in that game felt hand crafted and lived in. People felt real, too. It felt like an actual world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224154410.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224154410.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224154410_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224154410_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224154410_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ghosts feels more like a high quality copy of Assassin's Creed so far with a lot of paint on the outside to distract you from what's underneath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;History&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the release of Shogun last year, I've been thinking about and contextualizing Japanese history more than I had before. Shogun's story focused on a fictional version of Tokugawa and his actions leading to the Battle of Sekigahara. With his win, he assumes control of Japan as shogun ushering in the Edo Period in 1603.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shogun was the title given to the military leader of Japan, who actually executed laws and governship through the words of the Emperor. This term originated in the Kamakura Period of Japan, which is when Ghosts takes place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamakura_period" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamakura_period"&gt;Kamakura shogunate&lt;/a&gt; overthrew the Emperor in 1185 and established themselves as the rulers of Japan. This was the first point in history where the Emperor did not "control" the country. As each territory and kingdom pledged their loyalty, high ranking soldiers within clans of those territories became deputized as samurai, a new kind of soldier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224123313.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224123313.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224123313_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224123313_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224123313_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samurai had more power than standard soldiers as they could execute the will and actions of their lords as they see fit, rather than waiting for orders. At this time, the samurai designation was mostly reserved for members of the ruling class. But over time, more and more soldiers and members of clans became worthy of the title.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, Ghosts takes place around 1274 during the mongolian invasion, at the height of the Kamakura shogunate. Focusing only on military strength and expansion became their downfall as the government never actually produced anything to pay their subjects. The Emperor regained their power in 1333, starting the Muromachi Period. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the need to be suspicious of others and the benefits of working under darkness, breaking the code of samurai, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninja#Predecessors" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninja#Predecessors"&gt;Ninja&lt;/a&gt; spies were officially trained and designated around the mid-1400s as the Emperor was overthrown again, fracturing Japan, and starting the Warring States Period of Japanese history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tactics of Ninja and Shinobi existed before the Warring States Period, but those terms were never used until then, and those actions were always viewed negatively until then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's interesting how these beliefs have been woven into the story of Ghosts. It's a bit unfortunate how the game doesn't contextualize any of this history. But, on the other hand, Ghosts seems to  accurately adhere to it, which is commendable compared to other fairytale stories of samurai made by poorly researched westerners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The developer, Sucker Punch, has a clear reverence of the material and culture. This was even clear from the start when leading up to the announcement of the game at E3 2018. They had &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cornelius_Boots" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cornelius_Boots"&gt;Cornelius Boots&lt;/a&gt;, one of the world's leading masters of the shakuhachi, a traditional Japanese wooden flute, put on a performance. Although, because of the military rule of Kamakura, these performances had diminished greatly at this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224112356.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224112356.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224112356_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224112356_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/ghosts/Ghost_of_Tsushima_20250224112356_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sequel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shogun was one of the main reasons I had become interested in playing through Ghosts of Tsushima. But another reason was because of the sequel announced last year. Sucker Punch unveiled Ghosts of Yotei in September 2024 and announced its release for 2025. I wanted to finish the first game before the new one came out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They announced that Yotei is not a direct sequel to Ghosts of Tsushima, taking place in 1603. This was the time that Tokugawa had just taken control of Japan and began instituting rules upon rules to strictly govern the country and prevent any uprising or opposition to his rule or weakening Japan to foreign entities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was also announced that Yotei takes place in Hokkaido. Prior to 1603, the Japanese (or Wajin) have only occupied the southern area of Hokkaido, while the rest of the island was home to its natives, known as Ainu. Japan wanted to strengthen its hold on Hokkaido (known as Ezo at the time) to prevent any possibly invasion from Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the next hundred years, conflict and bloody battles erupted between the natives and Japanese before the entire island eventually came under Japanese rule. You play as Atsu, a female warrior, probably of the Ainu, through the origin of these conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No idea what time of year it'll take place, but the overall vibe should be a lot of mountain climbing and snow, compared to the sub-tropical island of Tsushima.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continuing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I'm a bit down on Ghosts at the moment, but this is mostly tempering my expectations. I'm really surprised how the environments and interactions feel so old, when the game was released in 2020. This was the height of the Playstation 4, moments before the release of the PS5. Games had already been out by then with significantly more character in their story and engagement in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm right at the edge of the next significant story progression, so I hope things turn around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've taken a bunch of in-game photos, too. You can view them below.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/ghosts-of-tsushima-impressions</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/ghosts-of-tsushima-impressions</link><category>Game Specific</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Keyword Word Cloud Page</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When remaking theschlock.com into its current version, in the background, I added keywords to every post on the site. There was never a good way of surfacing these keywords on posts without the UI getting more cluttered. So, I just left them in the background and used them to populated the previous and next related posts at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After going through tons of old posts with the Site History and again going through posts for the Photo Collage page, I had the idea of creating a Word Cloud for all those keywords in the background. So, here it is, the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/keyword" title="https://theschlock.com/keyword"&gt;Keyword Word Cloud&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/keyword" title="https://theschlock.com/keyword"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250222_keyword/IMG_0483_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250222_keyword/IMG_0483_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250222_keyword/IMG_0483_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on a keyword to view all the posts associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All keywords have been alphabetically sorted on the page, and weights are determined by how many posts use those keywords and how recent the most recent post of that keyword is. The heaviest keywords have more than 25 posts with the most recent one made in the last 10 years. Size goes down a level by halving the total posts. Size also goes down 2 levels each 5 years behind that 10. Categories have been included, too, which makes up the bulk of the heavy keywords.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This page is nice because it can cover more fine-grain groupings of posts that I don't want to set up with categories. I don't want a million categories of only 2 or 3 posts which will almost never have anything new. But, a million keywords? Yeah sure! Let it rain!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This has also been good to grouping posts of a single vacation, like when friends visit or when I go off somewhere. I'm still working on going through some old photos, so more old posts should pop up over time, until I burn myself out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/keyword-word-cloud-page</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/keyword-word-cloud-page</link><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Others</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Kumano Shrine 熊野神社 &amp; Akahogi Park 赤保木公園</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I has been snowing pretty hard in Takayama lately, much like other parts of the world. Takayama is surrounded by nature, forests, and mountains. All of these mountains shield us from the wind, so when it snows, it comes gently and fluffy, and piles up and up without getting blown over. This creates a beautiful frosted landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the constant snow, I wanted to go out and take some photos, and being test week, I had an afternoon available to do some exploring in the snow. There's a shrine at the edge of town nestled into the forest that I thought would be perfect to visit. This is Kumano Shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kumano Shrine &lt;span class='ja'&gt;熊野神社&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0248.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0248.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0248_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0248_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0248_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gate to the shrine is on the literal edge of the forest meeting the open fields. I parked near the side entrance, but then took the long route back down the road and back through the fields to meet this entrance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We received about 1 meter of snow over the past couple of days on top of the snow we already had. The fields and paths to arrive to the gate were pretty deep, but the natural canopy of the forest shielded most of the rest of the path leading to the Shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0286.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0286.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0286_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0286_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0286_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presented a different problem, though. As the hardened tufts of snow in the tall trees got heavier, the branch eventually gave way to drop the snow, whiting out the path forward. The clumps of snow hitting the snow on the ground created the only sound available. A small gust of wind would rustle the branches, and then soft bum, bum, bums would follow, along with me curling up, protecting the camera, and facing away from the snow coming into my face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0308.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0308.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0308_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0308_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0308_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was not difficult to climb the steps and reach the shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Kumano Shrine was officially recognized and protected by the city starting from July 10th, 1975. It is believed to be built around the year 1680. This was almost 100 years after Kanamori conquered the Hida area, and established it as a mountain oasis for his rich friends. Much of this wealth did trickle down improved the area, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shrine was built by artist Ikemori Gengo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;池守源五&lt;/span&gt; and funded by lacquerware artist Narita Sankyu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;成田三休&lt;/span&gt;. Its style was totally fitting of other tradition buildings at the time, and the reliefs were made in the Shunkei lacquerware style, also notable in Hida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0367.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0367.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0367_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0367_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0367_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the Internet, the main hall is the oldest original one still standing in Takayama. There was a hole punctured in the screen of the front door, so I could stick my camera lens through it. The shrine is still used today for Shinto ceremonies in the summer, like all shrines around town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being satisfied with my current stack of photos, I did not break in or walk around the back for more. I continued back to my car using the side entrance, while occassionally getting pelted by falling clumps of snow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0387.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0387.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0387_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0387_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0387_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Akahogi Park &lt;span class='ja'&gt;赤保木公園&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before actually leaving, I remembered there was a small park behind the forest with the shrine. The shrine itself wasn't really deep in the forest. It was in a small pennisula of woods shooting out from the beginnings of the main western forest heading up to Mihakayama &lt;span class='ja'&gt;見量山&lt;/span&gt;. I went hiking up there before in &lt;a href="mihakayama" title="mihakayama"&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a look at the park real quick. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0397.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0397.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0397_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0397_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0397_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The park is an open area, but has a small preserved village next to it. This is the Akahogi Preservation Site, and the main thing it is perserving is a stone age wood furnace. It was discovered in 1954. Later in the 90s, archeologists and members of the historical society began restoring the area to capture the atmosphere of ancient Hida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0406.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0406.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0406_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0406_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0406_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most distinct buildings of ancient Hida are the Gasho-zukuri &lt;span class='ja'&gt;合掌造り&lt;/span&gt;. They are mostly small wooden huts, although they can grow in size. They are very distinct because of their massive heavy thatched roofs which withstand the massive weight of Hida snowfalls. In the middle of the these homes, are fires that warm the whole interior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a few open air museums in the area that have transported many of these buildings into their own town. In Takayama, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/hina-matsuri-in-hida-no-sato" title="https://theschlock.com/hina-matsuri-in-hida-no-sato"&gt;Hida no Sato&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;飛騨の里&lt;/span&gt; is most well known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the Akahogi village, I did not travel too far. I only approached the closest building, which also seemed like the only one open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0419.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0419.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0419_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0419_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0419_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow was deep, but these buildings are built to last. Looking in from the outside, it was completely black. The blinding white of the snow made it difficult to see anything past the door. With all the bear signs around, I was a little bit cautious of a confrontation. But... eh. It's probably fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I jutted inside and was completely sheltered from the snow outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0435_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0435_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0435_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0435_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0435_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was just my imagination, but it felt much warmer inside. Obviously, it offered complete protection of the wind, but it felt more than that. Maybe the straw of the roof retained or created some kind of heat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the middle, was the ancient fire pit, restored from the broken pieces found in the 50s. Nearby, a painted wooden plaque explained the purpose and usage of the fire pit. Obviously, it is pretty self explanatory to modern people, how the surrounding rocks can absorb and hold on the heat from the fire keeping the room warm. Also, how you can use the surface of the rocks to cook meat. The openings in the back and above the door allowed from the smoke the exit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0454.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0454.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0454_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0454_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0454_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, that was the end of my hike. I went back out the way I came, and returned to my car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I parked in front of a building run by the Akahogi Historical Preservation Society. I thought about going in and poking my nose around, but I wasn't sure if it was actually open to the public. I'll come back in the spring for some comparison shots and updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over night, it still continued to snow, and everyone had a chance the next day to show how bad of drivers they are. This included me, too, taking photos from my car while driving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0476.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0476.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0476_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0476_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250220_kumano/IMG_0476_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/kumano-shrine-and-akahogi-park-in-winter</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/kumano-shrine-and-akahogi-park-in-winter</link><category>Japan</category><category>Hida Takayama</category></item><item><title>Small Worlds</title><description>&lt;p&gt;There are many unique museums in Tokyo, but only one has a miniaturized full scale diorama/model of Tokyo-3, chronicling Shinji's arrival and first day in Tokyo-3, as shown in the first two episodes of Evangelion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8680.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8680.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8680_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8680_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8680_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Small Worlds is located in Ariake just east of Odaiba, south-east Tokyo. Subtitled as the Miniature Museum, it has four main massive-scale miniature models, where each single person is about the size of a thumbnail. These four areas are space-themed, fantasy-themed, the Kansai airport, and Tokyo-3. The space and fantasy themed areas are further divided into sub-areas with more focused themes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entry is a little pricey at 3200&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt;, but I think the price tag is worth it for a one-time visit. If you enjoy the museum a lot, they have a 3D scanning studio in the middle of the museum. From the 3D scans, they can print and color a 3D model of yourself. The cheapest one is 6600&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; for a small figure of 1 person, but the price can come down with multiple people. Additionally, you could pay to have your figure be part of the museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I visited on a Friday afternoon, so the museum was pretty empty with only a few visitors. A company or group of people booked the cafe for the full day, so I was unable to visit any exhibits on that floor. Also, occasionally waves of people would rush through the museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Space Theme - Space Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After paying the entrance fee and taking the elevator to 3F, you enter the main exhibits of the museum, starting with the Space Center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8757_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8757_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8757_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8757_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8757_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The area begins with the Apollo Space center. Dozens of American cars line the streets to catch a glimpse of the Apollo rocket being taxied to the launch pad and shot into the space. By searching through all of the cars and crowds, you can find several easter eggs, such as the Men in Black and the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8704.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8704.jpg"&gt;Trimaxion Drone&lt;/a&gt; from Flight of the Navigator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the entire museum, several parts of the models are connected to buttons. When the buttons are pressed, small actions are performed in the model. Fox example, when the MIB button is pressed, the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8711.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8711.jpg"&gt;Men in Black&lt;/a&gt; uses their memory erasers on a crowd of people. Press the Lowrider button, and a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8697.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8697.jpg"&gt;lowrider car&lt;/a&gt; starts pumping up with its hydraulics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving along, we've jumped a hundred or two hundred years in the future, with the space station. The space station has a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8749.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8749.jpg"&gt;control tower&lt;/a&gt; which welcomes spaces shuttles, landing every 30 minutes. Within the space station, the core of galactic transport operates run by the 0123 shipping company. There's also a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8743.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8743.jpg"&gt;food court&lt;/a&gt;, and an octopus sausage &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8744.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8744.jpg"&gt;assembly line&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8746.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8746.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8746_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8746_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8746_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last of the space areas is dedicated to the overall space race. It's a mini-scale museum for the space station's inhabitants showing the development of space travel (witnessed back in the Apollo Space center) to the current age. Visitors peer at the recreations of the original &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8755.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8755.jpg"&gt;moon landing&lt;/a&gt;, and other triumphs of space travel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a fourth, smaller exhibit dedicated to Diaclone, a Tony toy-line of giant robots from the 80s. It's a bit under-developed compared to the scale and unity of the overall space area. Its just a collection of the old toys with the theme song playing on the screen behind it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fantasy Theme - Global Village&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fantasy themed Global Village has five areas, each seamlessly connected, like the space themed area. The area begins with Snow Mine Peaks City.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8762.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8762.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8762_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8762_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8762_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mining village is covered in railways cutting through the mountain into emerald mines. Further up the mountain are snow covered trails with skiers. When hitting buttons, the train cars emerge from the tunnels and come into town. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving away from the mountains into flatter areas is the Dragon Village, a bustling town with many stores, restaurants, and entertainment. Further east, is the Dragon forest, where the dragons and their riders live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dropping down from the high cliffs of dragons and the highlands is Wall Sanctuary Resort on the sea. The stone city seems carved from the cliffs and mountains adjacent to it. Hundreds of tourists enjoy the seaside food while observing the massive mythical creatures in the water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8793.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8793.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8793_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8793_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8793_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I started to notice some answers to a contest. At the opening of Global Village, a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8761.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8761.jpg"&gt;scavenger hunt&lt;/a&gt; was posted. Find all the Treasure boxes in the Global Village and spell the following word: _ _ _ _ o _. The O was pasted in, so that was probably broken. I could find 4 treasure boxes: &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8796.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8796.jpg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8795.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8795.jpg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8794.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8794.jpg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8797.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8797.jpg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You'd think it might be difficult to find such specific things in such a vast detailed world, but the whirring of the gears opening the treasure boxes gave them away. That being said, I could only find 4. I could hear a fifth one near the end. Although, it was always whirring, so maybe it was the broken O. Anyways, I won't give away the answer, but it's pretty obvious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the answer to the puzzle, you go back to the Space Center, whisper the word to the attendant at the concierge and get your prize, a piece of candy. I would have rather gotten a sticker or something non-perishable. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8802.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8802.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8802_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8802_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8802_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading across the bay from the resort is the Royal Capitol, a city embracing modern steam technology to power air craft, robots, and other machines. Above the city, the railways are elevated and move people to and from the large angular buildings. One of my favorite buildings was the library, where several floors of books are exposed to staircases surrounding the outside of the building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, past the capitol, is Zhenshimen City, where nightlife is king. Neon signs line the roads and alleyways of the vibrant town enticing any person or robot to come inside and stay for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8854.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8854.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8854_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8854_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8854_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was by far the most dynamic, detailed, and dense area of the Global Village. Every angle and vantage point looking into the buildings offered something new to be seen and discovered. Those remaining letters had to be in here somewhere, but I could never find them. Some of the buttons and interactions were broken in this area, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Creators Gallery&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before moving onto the third main area, there was an exhibition room for miniature diorama artists to display and sell their works. Many of these models were far more detailed than the Space and Fantasy areas of the museum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were two artists I thought had some amazing models compared to other artists in the gallery. Unfortunately, I forgot to look up the name of this first person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8861.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8861.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8861_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8861_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8861_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They made several full-scale rooms of a restaurant, car mechanic, kitchen, and garage. Some were for display only, not for sale. The ones for sale had a price tag of around $10,000, I think? Given the time, detail, and expertise put into the model, that seems...  I dunno. Maybe accurate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another artist has some beautiful snowy scenes. The scene themselves were mostly flat, built up from the back canvas, but used a lot of lighting and false perspectives to create a scene that has so much depth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8873.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8873.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8873_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8873_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8873_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was smart enough to snap a photo of this guy's information. These scene were created by Miniature artists and YouTuber, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8878.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8878.jpg"&gt;BamBi&lt;/a&gt;. Shit. At least, I think they are. This person's &lt;a href="https://bambini.amebaownd.com/" title="https://bambini.amebaownd.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; has nothing resembling these artworks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kansai Airport KIX&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Creators Gallery brings us to the Kansai airport area, a massive recreation of the airfield surrounding the airport.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8891.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8891.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8891_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8891_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8891_t.webp"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first area to have a day-night cycle. Flights land and take off on a schedule. You can view the schedule from the airport lounge, a real-life recreation of an airport lounge overlooking the model. Every 10 minutes or so, the wall on the far side of the model opens and a plane lands. It then taxies from the runway over to the terminal on the other side of the room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The terminal is full of passengers waiting in various lines, such as check-in, security, and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8910.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8910.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8910_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8910_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8910_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to that treasure scavenger hunt earlier, there is another scavenger hunt that spans across all three main areas so far. Small Worlds has three mascot bears as signature characters, and these three bears are hidden throughout the areas doing various things. Next to them is a letter plaque. View all the letters and create a 7-letter word. Here are some of them: &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8906.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8906.jpg"&gt;Airport Terminal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8925.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8925.jpg"&gt;Airport Control Tower&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8784.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8784.jpg"&gt;Sanctuary Wall Resort&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8755.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8755.jpg"&gt;Moon Landing&lt;/a&gt;. I missed the very first one at reception, but I could figure out the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you have the answer, you can bring it to the 3D print studio and run the lottery. I don't remember what the prizes were, but I got the common prize, a 500&lt;span class='ja'&gt;円&lt;/span&gt; off coupon for a 3D scanned figure of myself. I might consider it if I come back here with friends and they want to make figures of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evangelion Hanger&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we start moving on to the main event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8960.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8960.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8960_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8960_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8960_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next to the 3D print studio, there are some huge Evangelion artifacts from some Evangelion events. Moving along, we reach the Evangelion Hanger, where the three children board their evangelions, and Misato commands Nerv to launch them to the surface to fight the incoming Angel. This runs on a timer, so they are rolled and launched up into the ceiling every 7-ish minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The models are to the same scale as the thumbnail sized people, but compared to us, they are about the size of a toddler. It would be neat to see the evangelion models actually move, but it would seem so stiff and robotic compared to how agile they are in the show. I dunno, there are probably some scenes you could replicate where they don't move too much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tokyo-3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving past the hanger and up the stairs, we emerge into Tokyo-3, starting with Misato's neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8998.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8998.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8998_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8998_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_8998_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The model continues to the hillside, overlooking the downtown area of Tokyo-3. The whole room runs on a day-night cycle. As morning breaks, the song &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ti18DHIHfdc" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ti18DHIHfdc"&gt;2EM09_YAMASHITA&lt;/a&gt; plays from Evangelion 2.0. In the film, this plays as everyone in Tokyo-3 wakes up and starts their day. Next, the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0mOQhNKsl0" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0mOQhNKsl0"&gt;Misato Theme&lt;/a&gt; plays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving over from Misato's neighborhood, we reach the suburbs of Tokyo-3 surrounding Shinji's school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9027.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9027.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9027_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9027_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9027_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9038.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9038.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9038_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9038_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9038_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further east from the school, is a rural mountainous area. I spotted &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9057.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9057.jpg"&gt;Kaji&lt;/a&gt; in front of the station with the suitcase holding Adam. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it is sunset and night in the above photos, in daytime, the next song that plays is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o1Eo3VW693Q" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o1Eo3VW693Q"&gt;Decisive Battle&lt;/a&gt; as an Angel attacks Tokyo-3. The Skyscrapers of Tokyo-3 are lowered into the ground as Eva Unit 1 is deployed to face and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9045.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9045.jpg"&gt;defeat the Angel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wrapping around the mountain leads to the scenic overlook where Misato brings Shinji to show him what he saved by destroying the angel. The song &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWFKZLgly_g" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWFKZLgly_g"&gt;Tokyo-3&lt;/a&gt; plays as the sun sets, and the city emerges from the ground, recreating the scene from the anime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9075.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9075.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9075_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9075_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9075_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9076.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9076.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9076_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9076_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9076_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9087.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9087.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9087_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9087_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_smallworlds/IMG_9087_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, during the darkness of night, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkzkDB1eK8Q" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkzkDB1eK8Q"&gt;EM19_Premix&lt;/a&gt; plays as all the lights from the skyscrapers are extinguished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day starts again as pink lights give rise to the sun, and "Yamashita" plays again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tokyo-3 model is an amazing recreation of those pleasant days in the beginning of Evangelion before humanity and mentality are tore apart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaving Tokyo-3 brings you back to the 3D studio, and more large scale Evangelion models. Continuing on is the workshop. If you arrive early enough in the day, you could join a workshop to build your own model. Going through the workshop, brings you back to the Space Center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, a group booked out the entire 2F cafe, which apparently hold more exhibits, so I didn't get to see any of those, or try any food. But, the Evangelion exhibits were excellent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I spent two hours in Small Worlds. Looking through all of these photos, I feel like there were still plenty of easter eggs that I missed and want to go searching for. But, I am satisfied for now. :)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/small-worlds</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/small-worlds</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Sunset from the Tokyo Metro Building</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Tokyo is full of distinct buildings that make its skyline unique. The Tokyo Metro Building in west Shinjuku is one such building known for its twin towers. It was often depicted in classic anime series (particularly CLAMP series) as a source of power. In reality, it's a governmental building which administrates all the city affairs of Shinjuku and surrounding neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides that, the building serves another purpose which attracts quite a few tourists. Its observation deck is one of the best spots in Tokyo to view the whole city. And for free! I've been here several times before, and wrote about it too &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/tokyo-metropolitan-building" title="https://theschlock.com/tokyo-metropolitan-building"&gt;over 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was in Tokyo for school business, and as school business concluded, it was near sunset and I was near the Metro Building. I met up with another teacher and some of our students, and we walked to the building to catch the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9921_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only was our timing perfect, but because of the completely clear weather we had all weekend, Mt. Fuji was very visible right next to the sun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The clear weather also gave a perfect view of that beautiful Tokyo skyline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_9972_stitch_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of people crowded around the west windows of the observation deck, but it wasn't as crowded as you'd think. I found a spot near a window and kept snapping photos of the sun slowly moving closer and closer to the horizon, until it finally went below the mountains left of Fuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0011_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0036_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0054_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0075_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had fun staring at the sun. It didn't sustain the interest of my students and the other teacher, though, as they were waiting for me on a couch nearby. They were hungry as their school business of the day was just as long as mine. Also, they were in a bit of hurry since they had tickets for an event at 7pm. We had dinner as fast as we could, then I saw them off in a taxi. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contemplating what to do with the rest of my evening, I decided to return to the observation deck and take some night photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0135_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last time I visited the Metro Building was in summer with some college friends in Japan on vacation. One night, we went to the Metro Building to watch the nightly &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5247.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5247.jpg"&gt;projected illumination event&lt;/a&gt;, which happens 3 times a day after nightfall. Visualizations were projected on the east side of the Metro building, which pulsed and moved to music. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_5618_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visualizations matched the architecture of the building, and sometimes it felt like the building was transformed into a circuit board, or blocks which broke away in a fantasy landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, I was on the reverse side of the projection, looking down at the crowd and the projectors shooting up at me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250209_metro/IMG_0139_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looks like the projection is done using 28 projectors on the roof of the assembly building, opposite of the 45-story main building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, viewing the sunset from an observation point in Tokyo was one of the things on my bucket list (which I had forgotten), so I was glad to end the weekend and my business trip with such a beautiful site. Tomorrow, it's back to the blizzard up in the mountains.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/sunset-from-the-tokyo-metro-building</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/sunset-from-the-tokyo-metro-building</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Unicorn Gundam in Odaiba</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In Odaiba, Tokyo's manmade island in southeastern Tokyo, in front of the Diver City shopping mall and entertainment area, is one of Japan's full-scale, 1-to-1 life-sized Gundams. In fact, this is the premiere location of Japan's full-sized Gundams, of which there are 3 now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9162_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2017, the RX-0 Unicorn Gundam occupies this spot. This Gundam is from the anime series and novel, Mobile Suit Gundam Unicorn. As I understand it, Gundam Unicorn was a soft reboot or retelling of the original Gundam story. Or maybe a modern side story set during the time of the original. Made in 2010, it was a breath of fresh air and a return to roots for the franchise after countless spinoffs, sequels, and over-saturation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most iconic of gundams is the original RX-78 model, which occupied this space from 2009 to 2016. It was built to celebrate the Gundam franchise's 30th anniversary. People say that it was replaced with the Unicorn Gundam as a symbol of Japan moving into the future, with their bid for the 2020 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original RX-78 Gundam is still sometimes used for events. It was recently used in front of the Gundam Factory in Yokohama, which closed last year. Now, it might be in Osaka according to Wikipedia. Another full-sized Gundam is in Fukuoka, which was completed in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9152_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After arriving in Tokyo for a business trip, I went to Odaiba to see the Gundam during sunset. The timing ended out working perfectly. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4 times a day, the Gundam performs its transformation sequence. I was able to catch the 5pm one, the last of the day. At night, there was a musical performance, but I wanted to get to my hotel and prepare for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250207_gundam/IMG_9252_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/unicorn-gundam-in-odaiba</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/unicorn-gundam-in-odaiba</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Photo Collage Page</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 25 years, I've been taking photos and displaying them online, here. In fact, displaying my artwork was the original purpose for creating my website in the first place. Over time, the purpose of my website changed. Photography became more important to me than artwork. Then, writing more focused content became more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continue to take a lot of photos with my digital camera, but those photos are all attached to posts and only viewable at the bottoms of those pages. My writing is always put first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I've made a page that puts my photos first: the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo" title="https://theschlock.com/photo"&gt;Photo Collage Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo" title="https://theschlock.com/photo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250203_photo/Screenshot09.02.45_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From here, you can view all the photos I've marked as important or significant. You can click into them and view the corresponding post if it's available, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Diamond Grid Photos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The photos on the Photo page have been individually selected by me, after sifting through most of the over 20,000 images available on the site. While going through photos, I noticed there were many photo galleries in the directory that didn't have blog posts associated with them. Over time, I will add these posts to the site with the attached images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have already added a few of these posts. In particular, I added 2 major clusters of posts. The first cluster was my 2011 trip to Japan with my brother. We traveled around the Kansai region going to Osaka, Kyoto, Nara, and few other cities. The second cluster was my 2014 trip to Okinawa. I visited many war sites and met up with my friend Justin while he was stationed there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These posts are all back dated to when they took place. You can view them using their keyword pages: &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/keyword/osaka-2011" title="https://theschlock.com/keyword/osaka-2011"&gt;Osaka 2011&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/keyword/okinawa-2014" title="https://theschlock.com/keyword/okinawa-2014"&gt;Okinawa 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of these past posts, I have now surpassed 1000 blog entries on the site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Single Photos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the pages I had on a previous version of my site showed off random photos of mine without any real context. These were singular photos that I thought looked nice, so I wanted to those photos on this page too. So, I added a new photo folder on the backend for single photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still continue to take random photos with my camera or my phone when I'm walking around, so I'll continue to add nice looking photos to the Photo page as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Updates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To match the diamond grid motif, image galleries on posts also have the diamond grid, replacing the original square grid. I might add more 45 degree angles in other places, too, to have more things match. We'll see, though. Keeping things simple around here is still important.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/photo-collage-page</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/photo-collage-page</link><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Others</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Mt. Fuji 富士山 from Kofu 甲府</title><description>&lt;p&gt;From where I live, the fastest way to get to Tokyo is to drive. The second fastest way is by bus. Either way, after spending 2 hours driving up and down mountain roads, you reach the expressway onramp in Matsumoto, leading to the Chuo Expressway &lt;span class='ja'&gt;中央自動車道&lt;/span&gt;. It extends from south Nagano prefecture and goes directly to Tokyo in about 3 hours of driving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After traveling an hour on the highway and entering Yamanashi prefecture, Japan's most famous mountain comes into view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mt. Fuji &lt;span class='ja'&gt;富士山&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0831_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_0838_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heading south on the Chuo Expressway gives you a clear view of Mt. Fuji. On a clear day, it is very visible coming in and out of view depending on the trees. The above photos were taken in November a while ago. (Taken on the iPhone while driving)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I escorted one of my students to Narita Airport, so we drove the whole way. Driving to Tokyo ends up being the cheapest way of travel when divided between multiple people not planning on staying multiple days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it was snow storming in my town of Takayama, the weather was pretty fair on the highway, and Mt. Fuji was clearly visible again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_1866_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My student slept through the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We left around 8:30am and arrived at the Chiba Costco at 1:30pm. 5 hours is a pretty good time considering we stopped at a service area for about 20 minutes. After checking him into his flight and seeing him off, I went back westward and stayed the night in Kofu (cheaper than Tokyo).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kofu &lt;span class='ja'&gt;甲府&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kofu is a city directly north of Mt. Fuji in Yamanashi prefecture. If you plan on going to Mt. Fuji from the north, this is the highway exit you take, and then continue south. I've stayed here a few times before planning on going to Mt. Fuji the following day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This morning, Google Maps told me to go west to get on the highway to head back home. It brought me to the Futaba service area &lt;span class='ja'&gt;双葉&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;サービスエリア&lt;/span&gt;. It was an absolutely beautiful clear bright morning, contrasting the snowy skies up in the mountains 3 hours away in Takayama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Service Area has an observation tower giving a clear view of Mt. Fuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8634_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8596_t.webp"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a higher resolution panoramic photo:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250202_mt_fuji/IMG_8606_stitch_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I had gone up here. The Futaba service area is also a scheduled stop on the Bus Route from Takayama to Shinjuku Bus Center, so I have been at the service area many times, just not to this side of the service area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have another business trip to Tokyo this coming weekend, so I'll go up there again and take more photos. :)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/mt-fuji-from-kofu</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/mt-fuji-from-kofu</link><category>Travel</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Site Design History</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It's weird to think, but this year marks 25 years of having some form of Internet home page. It all started with Geocities as a portfolio showcasing work from art school. Then, my site moved to Tripod where I tried making a web comic. And then to its home here at theschlock.com posting game reviews and photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I came across some of my old pages, and I wanted to find a way to surface them again. The actual content is too personal (or problematic), so I couldn't surface the pages in their original form, so I decided to reuse the old designs with all the posts currently available on the site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the current version of the site, I would count 8 distinct versions of my home pages over 4 clear eras of experimentation and learning. FYI, not all the links on these pages are available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Geocities Era&lt;/u&gt; / Microsoft Frontpage&lt;br/&gt;Version 0 - &lt;b&gt;Art Portfolio&lt;/b&gt; (2000, or 1999?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tripod Era&lt;/u&gt; / Microsoft Frontpage&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v1" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v1"&gt;Version 1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Original Version&lt;/b&gt; (June 12th 2000 - April 2002)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v2" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v2"&gt;Version 2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Updated Version&lt;/b&gt; (April 2002 - January 2003)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Domain Era&lt;/u&gt; / Macromedia Dreamweaver&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v3" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v3"&gt;Version 3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Experimental Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (January 2003 - February 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v4" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v4"&gt;Version 4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Clean Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (February 2003 - August 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v5" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v5"&gt;Version 5&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Framed Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - June 2005)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v6" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v6"&gt;Version 6&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Movable Type&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - August 2006)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wordpress Era&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v7" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v7"&gt;Version 7&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt; (August 2006 - March 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Current Era&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history" title="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history"&gt;Version 8&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Tapestry / Java&lt;/b&gt; (March 2014 - present)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Origins&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Internet was an absolute marvel to me. Everyone was spreading out on the net and carving their own corner of it for themselves. Everyone had their own website for their art, for their stupid movies, for their forums, for their ideas. I was in art school, so I wanted to be like all the other artists online, showcasing their stuff. Too bad I was a terrible artist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how to actual make a webpage. I don't remember the details, but it seems like I downloaded Microsoft Frontpage, which generated the code of my original pages, and put together a design based on other pages I liked. Geocities and Tripod offered free hosting, so I put it there and linked to other people's pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Version 0 - &lt;b&gt;Art Portfolio&lt;/b&gt; (Geocities, 2000)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v1" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v1"&gt;Version 1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Original Version&lt;/b&gt; (June 12th 2000 - April 2002)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v2" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v2"&gt;Version 2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Updated Version&lt;/b&gt; (April 2002 - January 2003)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Note: I am unable to retrieve any Geocities data at this time, so I'll try to revisit it later.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Domain&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After art school, I went to a real school and started learning programming. I started meeting more people who also cared about making an online presence for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;November 2002 was when I bought theschlock.com. Also, for that Christmas, I got my first digital camera, and starting taking tons of photos. I wanted to make a site that used my photography more in its design and showcased photos. I started going to more clubs, and wanted to put those photos online, too. I started thinking about having a multipage design, rather than a single landing page with links.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found Macromedia Dreamweaver online which was WAY more user friendly than Frontpage. I could actually edit things in a design view and move them around. It gave me more freedom. This really helped me develop a sense of web-design. I still had yet to fully understand HTML, but Dreamweaver had both design views and code views, so I could watch the code change as I moved things around. After a while, I could take off the training wheels and write the code myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v3" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v3"&gt;Version 3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Experimental Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (January 2003 - February 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v4" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v4"&gt;Version 4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Clean Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (February 2003 - August 2003)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v5" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v5"&gt;Version 5&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Framed Photo Version&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - June 2005)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I messed around with some designs and eventually landed on the last one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blogs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time I landed on that last design, I was living with friends and fellow students who were in web development at school. They also made their own websites, and quite knowledgable about all things Internet. Blogging software started becoming an actual business, and people had begun transitioning from completely custom hobbyist sites into Blogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology had changed too. Making website updates was no longer about directly editing HTML and uploading it. The underlying database would hold all the data, and software running on the server would generate the page. I didn't fully understand this. I had really only just grasped the top layer of web-dev.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my friends loved Movable Type, so I installed it on theschlock.com from his recommendation. I used it in tandem with the Framed version of the site. Moveable Type would handle all the long posts about games and whatever. The Framed version was updated with photos and pictorials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v6" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v6"&gt;Version 6&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Movable Type&lt;/b&gt; (August 2003 - August 2006)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used this site through the remainder of college.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearing the end of college, the Internet and blogging had matured. My site design was pretty "old" for the Internet and MovableType wasn't totally user-friendly to use. By then, Wordpress completely overtook all of independent blogging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to studying abroad in Japan, I downloaded my entire site locally and zipped it. I installed Wordpress on theschlock.com, which completely took over. Wordpress was WAY more user friendly than Movable Type, and I could easily write about everything I was doing in Japan, and show all my photos, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/old/v7" title="https://theschlock.com/old/v7"&gt;Version 7&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Wordpress&lt;/b&gt; (August 2006 - March 2014)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I choose the design from a template, but then changed it slightly to be different. Not all that much, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After graduating, I still continued to use it. Working as a developer, I learned so much about using Java to manage and maintain websites, but I never had the headspace to use it on any personal projects. I had the time, but I already spent all day thinking about websites at work. I needed to decompress at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Version&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the current version of the site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Wordpress was far more user-friendly than my previous versions, it didn't feel special. It didn't feel like it was mine. Wordpress used PHP at the time, which I never liked. PHP feel far too loose and I couldn't understand it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to remake everything from scratch and have complete control over everything on the site in a more modern capacity. I had started laying some initial groundwork in 2012. But then, after moving to Japan and settling in, I finally had the headspace to execute on my ideas completely. I knew exactly what I wanted and exactly how to make what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote about all this in the first post on this version of the site on &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start" title="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start"&gt;March 4th, 2014&lt;/a&gt; as the site went live for the first time. Around 2 months later, the full design was complete. I wrote about that &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start-2" title="https://theschlock.com/a-fresh-start-2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history" title="https://theschlock.com/site-design-history"&gt;Version 8&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Current&lt;/b&gt; (March 2014 - now)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the site I had always wanted. I had complete control over everything on the site, and it was extensible enough to have new things over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running an active website isn't all that easy, though. It was always going down after a couple of days. I kept up with it for nearly 3 years. Then, one day, when I checked on it, the site was gone. Deleted from my host. My host had dropped support, so that was the end of that service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 years ago, with renewed programming interest, I finally brought the site back online, nearly 9 years after its initial launch. I posted about it on &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/website-revival" title="https://theschlock.com/website-revival"&gt;March 9th 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, the online version of my site is a generated mess of static HTML files. Because of this, there should no longer ever be any problems with hosting in the future. There's nothing running on the host, nor any database it's pulling from. It is free from any technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Future&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This design has changed and been refined a little bit over the years, but I doubt there will ever be another complete redesign of the site. The design still holds all the key values I want for written online content, and it's easy for me to add new things and change them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although...  Now that I have a framework for displaying my blogging content with different designs, I could experiment with new designs and see if anything sticks. Or, I could design terrible versions of my site in the same way that much of the blogging sites have turned into.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Revisiting many of these old pages has given me some new ideas, too, so stay tuned. :)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/site-design-history</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/site-design-history</link><category>Webpage</category><category>Programming</category><category>Others</category><category>Updates</category></item><item><title>Modded Console Game Inventory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I created a webpage that catalogues the library of games I have available on modded video game consoles. Last year, I set up a method of playing Playstation 2 games, and created a page that showed off that library of games. That was called the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/playstation-2-game-inventory"&gt;Playstation 2 Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, my modded console collection is going to expand with the release of the Flippy Drive on the Gamecube. I also started looking at Dreamcast mods for fun, and decided to set up a Dreamcast with tons of games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With my modded console collection expanding, the Playstation 2 Game Inventory page has also expanded. I renamed it to the &lt;b&gt;Modded Console Game Inventory&lt;/b&gt; page, and it now displays Gamecube and Dreamcast games. It will probably expand even further in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modded Console Game Inventory Page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2" title="https://theschlock.com/apps/ps2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250123_game_inventory/IMG_8582_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had thought about adding all these games into the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library" title="https://theschlock.com/digital-retro-game-library"&gt;Digital Retro Game Library&lt;/a&gt;, which catalogues far more games and consoles available on the Analogue Pocket and Mister. But, those are more curated lists rather than a full inventory, like this list. As such, I decided to keep them separate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory</link><category>Projects</category><category>Webpage</category><category>Games</category><category>Programming</category></item><item><title>Dreamcast GDemu Software Preparation</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I started thinking about the Dreamcast thanks to a recent playthrough of Crazy Taxi from ADGQ. While many of the games have been released and made available on other consoles and platforms throughout the years, there are still several games orphaned on the Dreamcast. Plus, the authentic feel of the playing the game, and hearing the original sounds and music is often not well replicated elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, and 8bitmods eventual release of their VMU Memcard Pro, I decided to look into Dreamcast mods to determine what it would take to put together a console capable of playing its vast library via hard drive or sd card, similar to the &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/a&gt; set up I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Somewhat surprisingly, it does not seem difficult at all. Many moderns mods are parts replacement for internal components. You still need to open up the console and take things apart, but you aren't soldering any mod chips or replacing capacitors. You just unplug this component, remove it, and plug in this one instead. Very plug and play. Many of these parts are pretty cheap through AliExpress too!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I ordered a bunch of parts this week. My Dreamcast is back in the states, so even though the parts will arrive over the next two weeks, assembly will have to wait until after summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I can prepare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreamcast GDemu&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main mod used in the Dreamcast is the &lt;b&gt;GDemu&lt;/b&gt;. It is a PCB replacement for the entire GD-ROM reader assembly. To install, you need to take out the GD-ROM disc reader, and put this PCB in there instead. The GDemu board has an SD card reader attached to it, and this is where all of the games are stored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8572_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought a SanDisk Extreme 128gb card, Class 10. Game are around 1.2gb each, which I thought would be enough space. But, I'm already getting close to the upper limit of space. A 256gb cards would've been better. I might upgrade later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people online have complained about compatibility, but I think those complaints predate the current version of GDemu. More recent videos and posts have said similar SD cards work just fine for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Format SD Card&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDemu requires the SD card to be FAT-32 format. One person said that using 64k byte cluster sizes can help with readability, too, so I opted for that. (It probably doesn't matter.) Using Diskutil, Macs will format FAT-32 with a cluster size of 32k bytes. So, for the 64k byte cluster size, you can use the following terminal commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;diskutil unmount SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;br/&gt;sudo newfs_msdos -F 32 -c 128 -v VOLUMEID /dev/SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;br/&gt;diskutil mount SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive must be unmounted first before formatting it, then the &lt;code&gt;newfs_msdos&lt;/code&gt; command is used. &lt;code&gt;VOLUMEID&lt;/code&gt; is the new name of your SD card, and &lt;code&gt;SD_IDENTIFIER&lt;/code&gt; is the identifier used in disk utils.  Check &lt;code&gt;diskutil list&lt;/code&gt; for the correct identifier. &lt;code&gt;-F 32&lt;/code&gt; is for FAT-32. &lt;code&gt;-c 128&lt;/code&gt; is for the 64 byte cluster size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(The reasons for 128 with -c is a little complicated. Overall, we want a 64k byte size. In bytes, this is 64x1024 = 65,536 bytes. The SD card has a block size of 512 bytes, so we do 65,536/512, which is 128. This number describes the number of blocks in a cluster.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8592_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, our SD card is in the current format. Now, we need games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To combat piracy, Sega and Yamaha created a new disc format for the Dreamcast called the GD-ROM. GD-ROMs held up to 1gb of information, surpassing the 650mb limits of the CD-ROM. One unique feature of the GD-ROM was that information was "burned" into the CD from the outside in, rather than inside out, like CD-ROMs. Both of these together were expected to make the Dreamcast secure from people burning their own games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within one year after its North American release, this was circumvented. Even though games were on GD-ROMs, the Dreamcast could still read CD-ROMs, so hacker group Utopia created the infamous Utopia disc which forced the Dreamcast to boot in CD-ROM mode. Games could then be burned to CD-ROMs and run nearly identically to the GD-ROMs. Some stuff had to be cut from games to fit into the 650mb CD limit, but many GD-ROMs filled their discs with dummy information anyways.  Much of this dummy information was just pushing the data to the outer edge of the disc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Dreamcast games can be found online in two main formats: GDI and CDI files. GDI is usually preferred as the CDI version could have cut content to fit into 650mb. Although, the problem with GDI files is that they are always 1.1gb or 1.2gb to simulate the full size of the disc. It's possible to shrink these sizes, cutting out the extra content, but that can still cause some compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Game Management&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games are copied to the SD card, but the GDemu requires a specific file and folder structure. You also need files for the GD Menu, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found this amazing &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4"&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; from Derek Pascarella fully describing the software-wide of how to set up and manage games for your Dreamcast using the GDemu. Here's that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjUgXkdiVq4"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; again. The rest of this post is basically going to parrot this video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will need to download 2 things for Games and Menu management. And there's one more thing to download to edit Boxart and Metadata for games in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1) The &lt;a href="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager" title="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager"&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/a&gt; is how you will manage all your games&lt;br/&gt;2) &lt;a href="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu" title="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu"&gt;Open Menu&lt;/a&gt; is the most modern menu used in the Dreamcast to choose your games.&lt;br/&gt;3) The &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;OpenMenu DAT Tool&lt;/a&gt; for editing boxart and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Open Menu DAT Tool is available through the dreamcast-talk forum, which is member only and a little difficult to gain access. The video has a link to their personal Google Drive for the file. The link above connects to my Google Drive, where I also have a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager" title="https://github.com/sonik-br/GDMENUCardManager"&gt;GD Menu Card Manager&lt;/a&gt; works for both Mac and PC. When you open the program, choose your SD card from the menu. You can choose whether to install GDmenu or Open Menu. Any game you want install, just drag into the window, rename to whatever you want, and hit Save Changes at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the GDemu wants each disc in its own folder, numbered starting from 01. The 01 folder is special and it must contain the GDemu menu (GDmenu or openMenu). The Card Manager will copy the correct files for you. From 02, each folder is for a game disc. Again, the Card Manager will manage all these folders for you. When adding new games, you can have them alphabetically sorted, and the Manager will rearrange everything for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some options are missing in the Mac version of the Card Manager. I'm not able to shrink the GDI files for some reason. This is probably using something only available on PC. However, as the video mentions, shrinking GDI files is not a one-size-fits-all hammer solution. For full compatibility, it's best not to shrink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Game Serial Numbers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like Playstation games, Dreamcast games each have a unique identifier. All retail games do this, but hacks, ports, and other self-published indie titles sometimes don't. For example, the Dreamcast port of Divi-Dead and Grand Theft Auto III share the same serial number when added to the card manager, T00001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the game title, you can freely edit serial numbers to whatever you like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250124_gdemu/IMG_8587_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I changed Grand Theft Auto III's serial number to TGTA3. The only thing this disrupts is the boxart and metadata used for Open Menu, and we can fix that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Menu&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Menu Card Manager saves changes to the SD card, it copies all the menu information it has locally to the SD card. On PC, all of its dlls and subfolders are clearly visible. The openMenu files are stored in the following location: &lt;code&gt;tools/openMenu/menu_data&lt;/code&gt;. This is true for the Mac version, too, but all the files are hidden inside of the app. Click on the GDMENUCardManager.app file and "Show Package Contents." From there, the openMenu files are located here: &lt;code&gt;Contents/MacOS/tools/openMenu/menu_data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, there's not much there, but that's where there &lt;a href="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu" title="https://github.com/megavolt85/openmenu"&gt;Open Menu&lt;/a&gt; download comes in. Unzip the latest release and copy all of the contents of &lt;code&gt;menu_data&lt;/code&gt; into the above location. Click on Save Changes in the Menu Manager, and your openMenu is completely up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Boxart and Metadata Changes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Open Menu files we copied to the GD Menu app were 3 DAT files, &lt;code&gt;BOX.DAT&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ICON.DAT&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;META.DAT&lt;/code&gt;. These are file databases which house boxart, game icon, and metadata for all the Dreamcast games. It has all retail games, indie games, and most other ports and hacks. But, it doesn't have everything. And if you changed any serial numbers, it definitely doesn't have those games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing" title="https://drive.google.com/file/d/16sek32schuAnjpluGbAKP9B5jhPulsQF/view?usp=sharing"&gt;OpenMenu DAT Tool&lt;/a&gt; will allow you to edit them. You can add new images (PNG format only) and create the menu icon from that. You can add and edit any metadata for games, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save all the changes back to the DAT files for the Card Manager. And then "Save Changes" in the Card Manager to apply the changes to the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Preparation Complete&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the time being, my preparations are complete. I have loaded my SD card with over 100 discs. You can take a look at what I have available by viewing my &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory" title="https://theschlock.com/modded-console-game-inventory"&gt;Game Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll start getting the physical mods in the mail over the next few weeks. Then after summer vacation, I should have my Dreamcast available to install the mods.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/dreamcast-gdemu-software-preparaation</link><category>Projects</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Lego Botanical - The Four Gentlemen</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Lego has released some new botanical sets to usher in the new year. These two new releases complement the releases from summer last year to create "The Four Gentlemen" of flowers, a classic staple of Chinese art representing ideal virtues and each of the four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8527_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These flowers (or plants) are the Chrysanthemum, the Plum Blossom, the Orchid, and the Bamboo, representing fall, winter, spring, and summer. I built each of these while streaming on Twitch, so take a look at the videos if you'd like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plum Blossom: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3H9yfCzeLI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mini Orchid: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T9UvKT0Djmo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lucky Bamboo: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abEjeij7x2M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Chrysanthemum: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MOQ6zllQfn8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Four Gentlemen or Four Noble Ones originated in Chinese art over 1000 years ago. The Kanji for this is &lt;span class='ja'&gt;四君子&lt;/span&gt;, which reads &lt;i&gt;shikunshi&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span class='ja'&gt;しくんし&lt;/span&gt; in Japanese. Gentlemen, in this context, refers to an individual that exhibits virtues and morality that all people should aspire to. Each of the flowers represents different virtues stemming from their season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Lego release order, the Chrysanthemum &lt;span class='ja'&gt;菊&lt;/span&gt; represents fall. Despite the cooler weather, the flower blooms with bright energetic warm colors. It's generally considered a loner as its virtue is to share joy and shine proudly as yourself withstanding all adversities. It also symbolizes longevity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8521_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8464_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winter is represented by the Plum Blossom &lt;span class='ja'&gt;梅&lt;/span&gt;. Its petals bloom a sharp crimson contrasting the coldest whitest months of the year. Though, not the most beautiful flower, it continues the bloom its best in a time of the year when most other flowers can't survive. As such, the Plum represents inner beauty and humbleness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading into the new year, the Orchid &lt;span class='ja'&gt;蘭&lt;/span&gt; represents Spring. The orchid is a fragile flower, soft in a form and fragrance. It is often referred to as the most inoffensive flower. While Spring often represents new beginning, the orchid symbolizes nobility, friendship, and integrity, enduring life despite its frail form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="columns"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8488_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column twoColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8485_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blazing summer months are represented by the Bamboo &lt;span class='ja'&gt;竹&lt;/span&gt;. Physically, the bamboo is the absolute strongest of the Four Gentlemen, able to bend without breaking against harsh winds and rain. By yielding and not breaking, its virtues are cultivation, integrity, and loyalty. Bamboo is also hollow despite its strength, which also represents tolerance, humility, and open-mindedness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Altogether, the Four Gentlemen say you should be true to yourself, represent yourself with dignity and humility, and also stay true to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/250101_lego/IMG_8539_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Lego sets, these look amazing and pair really well with the full-sized &lt;a href="lego-orchid" title="lego-orchid"&gt;Lego Orchid&lt;/a&gt;, released in the second wave of Botanical sets in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these sets have some form of repetition in their building, but it's really not bad considering each set only takes a full hour to build. The repetitious parts will only take about 5 minutes max. All sets have uncommon building techniques and parts usage that you probably hadn't thought of before. For example, the bulb of Chrysanthemum is created using over 30 lego bananas in different shades of yellow and orange. The flowers of the Mini Orchid use 3 handheld shield pieces, an interesting reference back to the Full Orchid, which uses 3 full-body shield pieces in its flowers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each are fun builds, look great, and are super cheap at only $30 each.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you were going to buy only one set out of them all, it's hard to recommend just one. My favorites are the Bamboo and the Chrysanthemum. Both of these sets look amazing at both a distance and up close. Originally, I skipped the Chrysanthemum because I thought the orange would outshine the others. It does quickly draw the eye, but the subtle perfection of the Bamboo can hold your eye just as long. Even though both are striking, I think they stay in their own lane as part of an ensemble. I think the Mini Orchid is the weakest. The bulbs on the full Orchid look more like flowers and less like Lego than the Mini-version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of them together create a very nice ensemble. There's still room on that shelf for more flowers, so I'm looking forward to the next Botanical sets Lego plans on releasing this year, and beyond.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/lego-four-gentlemen</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/lego-four-gentlemen</link><category>Toys</category><category>Media</category></item><item><title>Okami</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Okami is a legendary game. I feel like everyone knows Okami and everyone loves Okami, but has everyone really played it? I don't think it really gets brought up in conversations past its art style. That's the camp I was in. I really liked the idea of Okami. I even bought it back in the day, but never really played it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Game Awards, an Okami Sequel was announced, which put the original game back on my immediate backlog. With revisiting a lot of classic games lately, I wanted to finally give Okami its shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, it's incredible. (I played through the PS4 version of Okami HD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241229122854_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241228213941_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly 20 years after its original release, its art style still looks fresh and stunning. The heavy thick black inked outlines create imagery invoking Japanese calligraphy and traditional painting matching the fairytale story it tells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story of the game starts like a fairytale, explaining a 100-year-old legend, a battle between the ultimate evil, the 8-headed serpent Orochi, being defeated by a hapless warrior, Nagi, and a wolf. The wolf was killed in battle, so the town erected a statue in her honor. Now, 100 years later, you emerge from the statue, a reincarnation of the wolf and the goddess of the sun, Okami Amaterasu. Someone broke the seal of Orochi, which has released you from the statue, so you now explore the land, cleanse the land of its curse, defeat his minions, and make your way to its layer reenacting the legend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241230002403_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okami is a very standard action adventure game which feels reminiscent of early 3D Legend of Zelda games. Through exploring, more areas of Japan are opened with more secrets and introducing more characters. Story sequences thrust you into exploring dungeons and defeating the monsters within. This results in giving you new weapons and abilities to expand your exploration in the world and also backtracking for previous secrets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The abilities you gain are executed using brush strokes. Hit the R1 button, and the whole scene pulls back to an inking canvas. Move the brush around to create strokes matching your abilities. Return to the scene, and the abilities execute by blooming trees, slashing enemies, and blowing wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much like classic Zelda games, the story really opens up after completing the initial story sequence, the recreation of the 100-year legend. Evil still reigns in further areas of Japan, so you continue to chase after the shadows of the true evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20241231220110_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up until this point, I had not really noticed how much of Okami was steeped in Japanese fairytales. I thought it was telling its own story. I did not know that the story of Orochi and Nagi was an actual Shinto tale until reaching the next section of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When reaching the major city, you meet Momotaro, try to locate Onigashima, also meet Urashimataro, and swim to the bottom of the sea to Ryuguujou (the Dragon Palace), and meet Otohime. You also meet Princes Sakuya, cut from Bamboo. These are all Japanese tales I'm quite familiar film. Momotaro and Onigashima is probably the most well known fairytale in Japan. All the kids here know it. The One-Inch Prince is another Japanese tale that I had read before and never made the connection to Issun, your companion throughout the whole game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not a Japanese fairytale or mythical expert, so many of these things went over my head on their first pass, but it never detracted from the experience for me. All of these stories felt natural within the story of Okami. There are fun references to real lore that really enhance the experience rather than use it as a crutch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250101114445_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was really surprised by Okami. The Japanese mythology, the overall structure and crafted nature of the gameplay and exploration, and the length of the game. I completed a full 100% playthrough in 52 hours. That's the same length as Twilight Princess, which came out a few months after Okami's original release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think a lot of people skipped Okami because the Playstation 2 was waning at that point. The Xbox 360 was released the year prior, and games looked FAR more incredible than the PS2. Okami released in September, and in just a few more months, the Playstation 3 and Nintendo Wii would be released. The future!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I was so busy finishing college in Spring and study abroad in Japan for my final semester in the Fall. When I came back in 2007, I immediately played Twilight Princess and then focused on other games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, as much as the art style is one of Okami's strongest points, cell shading was very divisive at the time. People hated Legend of Zelda Wind Waker because of its art style, and Twilight Princess was finally the realistic Zelda everyone wanted. I think this looked too "kiddy" for the PS2 crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/okami/OKAMI_HD_20250102112322_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm glad that I finally took the time to play through Okami, and I think more people really should do the same. Now that Okami finally has a second chance with this new sequel, I hope people actually buy into it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll be there.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/okami</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/okami</link><category>Game Specific</category><category>Games</category></item><item><title>Most Played Games in 2024</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This was another huge year in gaming for me, although my focus had somewhat shifted from the big platforms. I had begun moving away from Twitch and streaming, while focusing a lot on other gaming projects and other retro games. There were still some huge games this year, but I played a lot of games as more of a distraction from work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My year began with my continuation of playing through classic Zelda games. I had played through Zelda 1 and Zelda 2 at the end of the last year, and I started this year with Link's Awakening and the Oracle games on Gameboy. I finished up the Oracle games before the release of the biggest game this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playstation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games.png" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/ps_2024_games_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Final Fantasy VII Rebirth&lt;/b&gt; was released in February, and it dominating my thoughts for the next two months. It's incredible that with such an expansive and huge game, all aspects felt hand-crafted and refined. Often huge open-world games use a lot of recycled quests or dungeons, using a script to manufacture its quantity. People argue there's too much stuff in Rebirth, but it's all there for the purpose of flushing out characters, lore, and story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both FF7 Remake and Rebirth are amazing examples of the lengths Nomura will go to retell the overall story of Final Fantasy 7 completely, which has been expanded upon over the 25 years since its original release. Everything feels like it's been completely thought out, even though the pacing is perhaps a bit much. I really hope the can stick the landing with the final game in the trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following Rebirth's story, once again, I went back to YouTube and watched a playthrough of the original Final Fantasy 7 to compare the story. It made me really nostalgic for the original playstation, especially Final Fantasy 8. I had always preferred FF8 because of its characters, but I've largely forgotten it all at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started looking into what it would take to play old Playstation and Playstation 2 games, and with several videos on YouTube showing how this was done, I put together a &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2" title="https://theschlock.com/returning-to-the-playstation-2"&gt;PlayStation 2 set-up&lt;/a&gt; to have access to all those games from my high school and college years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This became somewhat cyclical as I played a lot of Earth Defense Force 2 on PS2, then moved back to the PlayStation 5 for the recent release of &lt;b&gt;Earth Defense Force 6&lt;/b&gt;. Both excellent games of running around and shooting gigantic bugs and monsters. EDF6 is probably the best in the series at this point, combining modern graphics and frame rate with the highest variety of enemies in the whole series. I bought the Japanese version to save some money, which ended up being a mistake because I missed out on the campy English performances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the harsh Spring and Summer, I went back to story-driven games with &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/dead-space" title="https://theschlock.com/dead-space"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dead Space&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol" title="https://theschlock.com/the-callisto-protocol"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Callisto Protocol&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, actually taking photos in game and exploring their stories and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nintendo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Switch didn't see a lot of play this year as I took a break from Pokemon and Twitch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='img'&gt;&lt;div class="threeColumns"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_3_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_1_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column threeColumnLast"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2.jpg" title="https://theschlock.com/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" loading="lazy" alt="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" title="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dyreschlock/dyreschlock.github.photos/master/photo/top_2024/2024_Nintendo_Year_in_Review_2_t.webp" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br class="clr" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, in Spring, Nintendo announced a new Zelda was coming in September. We had just gotten Tears of the Kingdom last year, and already we're getting another game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Zelda: &lt;b&gt;Echoes of Wisdom&lt;/b&gt; was the first canon Zelda game where you actually played as Zelda. It featured a creative game mechanic of using objectives in the environment to climb, fight, and explore the world to eventually save Link. Its style immediately identified itself as being developed by Grezzo, who did the &lt;b&gt;Link's Awakening Remake&lt;/b&gt; from a few years ago. As such, I bought that and played through that as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading up to summer, I played through the remake of &lt;b&gt;Super Mario RPG&lt;/b&gt; on Switch. It was interesting playing through both remakes so close to each other along with FF7. Nintendo has an absolute vibrant history of games. Everyone has their own interpretations of those games and how they could best be adapted to today. Mario RPG does almost nothing to modernize itself beyond some quality of life changes to the gameplay. The story, the maps, and the pacing are all the same from the original. Link's Awakening is pretty much the same, too. It's the complete opposite of Final Fantasy 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's obviously no one best approach to remaking games. Would you rather have a gaming experience that reminds you of your childhood by playing a semi-modern version of the old game? Or would you rather have a new experience reliving the old story with the characters and lore you remember? For this year, Final Fantasy has had much more of an impact on me than these Nintendo remakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='title'&gt;&lt;b&gt;Retro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, with cheaper versions being release, I finally bought a Mister. This complements my Playstation 2 and Analogue Pocket for having access to decades of gaming history. Many of these older games still hold up quite well without the need of a remake or new version. I played through &lt;b&gt;Snatcher&lt;/b&gt; for the first time in decades and it's still an incredible experience, and one that I don't think would translate well to a modern remake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel incredible fortunate to have access to all these games from my past. And while I don't always have the time to play, I'm also grateful for the time I do have along with a platform to show them off.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://theschlock.com/most-played-games-2024</guid><link>https://theschlock.com/most-played-games-2024</link><category>Games</category></item></channel></rss>